<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 19:10:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-07-06]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/07/06&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-07-06</h1>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/nrrb/tao-te-ching/blob/master/Ursula%20K%20Le%20Guin.md">Tao Te Ching translated by Ursula Le Guin (1997)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The &quot;Tao Te Ching&quot; by Lao Tzu, translated by Ursula K. Le Guin, explores profound philosophical concepts about the nature of existence, leadership, and wisdom.</li>
<li>Key themes include the importance of simplicity, humility, and acting without effort, emphasizing that true power and wisdom come from aligning with the natural way (Tao).</li>
<li>The text is divided into 81 chapters, each offering insights on how to live harmoniously, lead effectively, and understand the deeper truths of life through paradoxes and metaphors.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40886419">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ursula Le Guin&#39;s version of the Tao Te Ching is not a direct translation but a rendition based on existing translations and transliterations, as she did not know Chinese.</li>
<li>The text&#39;s inherent ambiguity in Classical Chinese allows for multiple interpretations, making it challenging to capture its full meaning in any single translation.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the importance of understanding the philosophical nature of the Tao Te Ching and the limitations of translating such texts without knowledge of the original language.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://radio.garden/">Radio Garden</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Radio Garden allows users to explore live radio stations globally by rotating a virtual globe, offering a unique and interactive experience.</li>
<li>The platform features customizable settings, including font sizes, colors, and themes, and supports various screen sizes and devices for an optimized user experience.</li>
<li>It ensures compatibility with older browsers and includes user-friendly design elements like easy-to-use play buttons and loading animations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40887359">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Radio Garden enables users to listen to global radio stations, but a user-created WinAmp playlist faced issues with many streams going offline.</li>
<li>Radio-browser.info provides a JSON file with approximately 50,000 stations, serving as an alternative for those seeking a comprehensive list of public streams.</li>
<li>Users have shared other alternatives like WebSDR and radiooooo.com, though UK users may encounter restrictions due to copyright issues.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://duckdb.org/2024/07/05/community-extensions.html">DuckDB Community Extensions</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>DuckDB has introduced a Community Extensions repository, simplifying the installation and maintenance of extensions and reducing developer burdens.</li>
<li>Since version 0.3.2, extensions can be installed and loaded with simple commands, supporting various OS and processor architectures, with around six million downloads weekly.</li>
<li>The repository allows developers to publish extensions without handling compilation and distribution complexities, enhancing the developer experience and encouraging community contributions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40885238">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>DuckDB Community Extensions have introduced support for WebAssembly (WASM), enhancing its functionality and performance in web environments.</li>
<li>The shellfs extension allows the use of shell commands for input/output, improving DuckDB&#39;s utility as a command-line tool.</li>
<li>There are concerns about supply chain security due to DuckDB downloading extension binaries, although these downloads are validated using signature checks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1863246">Copy and Paste context menu entries sometimes disabled when they should not be</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bug 1863246 involves the Copy and Paste context menu entries being disabled in Firefox 97 on Windows 10, particularly after bookmarking a page and navigating back and forth.</li>
<li>The issue is a regression found in Firefox 129, and the team is currently working on a fix to address the race condition between processes updating the active browsing context.</li>
<li>Temporary workarounds include clicking the address bar or switching tabs to re-enable the context menu entries.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40886954">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Firefox users are experiencing a bug where the Copy and Paste context menu entries are sometimes disabled, affecting both Windows and Linux platforms.</li>
<li>The issue is hard to reproduce consistently and involves complex interactions between different browser components, leading to frustration among users.</li>
<li>Proposed fixes are in the works, and a future release is expected to address the problem, highlighting the ongoing challenges in maintaining browser functionality.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://differ.blog/p/here-s-how-you-can-build-and-train-gpt-2-from-scratch-using-pytorch-ace4ba">Build and train GPT-2 from scratch using PyTorch</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post provides a step-by-step guide on building and training a GPT-2 language model from scratch using PyTorch, aimed at all levels of Python or machine learning expertise.</li>
<li>It includes practical examples, such as training the model on Taylor Swift and Ed Sheeran songs, with resources like datasets and source codes available on GitHub.</li>
<li>Key components covered are building a custom tokenizer, creating a data loader, and implementing a simple language model, making it a comprehensive introduction to language model training.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40888090">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A blog post discusses building and training GPT-2, a generative pre-trained transformer model, from scratch using PyTorch, a popular machine learning library.</li>
<li>The post has sparked a debate on the effectiveness of learning through text versus video, with some users recommending Andrej Karpathy&#39;s instructional videos for their accessibility and practical insights.</li>
<li>Some users suggest using more established architectures like LLaMA for practical applications, indicating a preference for leveraging existing robust solutions over starting from scratch.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/epic-games-says-apple-stalling-launch-its-game-store-europe-2024-07-05/">Apple okays Epic Games marketplace app in Europe</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40888461">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple has approved Epic Games&#39; marketplace app in Europe, igniting debate over Apple&#39;s control of third-party app stores and its app review process.</li>
<li>Critics highlight concerns about Apple&#39;s revenue reliance on predatory free-to-play games and the requirement for app design changes.</li>
<li>The approval occurs during heightened scrutiny and potential regulatory actions in the EU.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://matklad.github.io/2024/07/05/properly-testing-concurrent-data-structures.html">Properly testing concurrent data structures</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces a Rust library called loom, designed for testing lock-free data structures, and explores its concepts through a toy example.</li>
<li>It highlights the challenges of testing concurrent data structures, demonstrating a broken concurrent counter and various testing methods, including property-based testing (PBT) and managed threads.</li>
<li>The post is significant for its detailed explanation of creating a controlled testing environment for concurrent operations, providing valuable insights for developers working with multithreading and atomic operations in Rust.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40890035">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Testing concurrent data structures in Rust involves detailed modeling of the memory model and tracking thread writes, with libraries like Temper and Loom aiding this process.</li>
<li>Shuttle offers a randomized testing approach, providing probabilistic guarantees for bug detection, while other tools like JetBrains’ Lincheck and Relacy Race Detector are used for Kotlin/Java and C++ respectively.</li>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the importance of reproducible tests and the challenges of ensuring thread safety and synchronization in concurrent programming.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.skeptic.org.uk/2024/07/research-into-homeopathy-data-falsification-fabrication-and-manipulation/">Research into homeopathy: data falsification, fabrication and manipulation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Edzard Ernst, Emeritus Professor of Complementary Medicine, highlights issues of data falsification and manipulation in homeopathy research.</li>
<li>A 2020 study by Michael Frass, claiming homeopathy benefits for cancer patients, was found to have falsified data, confirmed by the Austrian Agency for Scientific Integrity.</li>
<li>Despite recommendations for retraction, the journal has only issued an &#39;Expression of Concern,&#39; leaving the flawed study accessible, prompting calls for stricter measures against researchers producing dubious results.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40885397">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent research into homeopathy has uncovered instances of data falsification, fabrication, and manipulation, raising significant concerns about the integrity of studies in this field.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the deep-seated belief in homeopathy among some individuals, comparing it to flat-earth theories and noting the difficulty in changing such beliefs due to distrust in mainstream medicine and pharmaceutical companies.</li>
<li>The allure of homeopathy and similar pseudosciences is often rooted in the perception of discovering hidden truths ignored by the mainstream, making it challenging to dissuade believers with scientific evidence.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.irrawaddy.com/in-person/interview/war-on-citizens-how-juntas-vpn-ban-is-strangling-communication-in-myanmar.html">VPN ban is strangling communication in Myanmar</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40886689">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A VPN ban in Myanmar is significantly hindering communication, with users facing challenges due to Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) blocking VPNs.</li>
<li>Users are sharing methods to bypass censorship, such as using protocols that disguise traffic, and discussing alternative tools like wstunnel.</li>
<li>The article underscores the importance of ethical journalism when reporting on sensitive regions like Myanmar.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ams.org/notices/201010/rtx101001303p.pdf">Teaching general problem-solving skills is not a substitute for teaching math [pdf]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40890847">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Teaching general problem-solving skills should complement, not replace, the memorization of basic facts and strategies in subjects like math and software engineering.</li>
<li>Modern education often underestimates the importance of memorization, assuming technology can fill this gap, but quick recall of information is essential for efficiency in exams and real-world tasks.</li>
<li>Effective education should balance understanding with memorization to develop both expertise and practical skills.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://benhoyt.com/writings/hash-table-in-c/">How to implement a hash table in C (2021)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive guide on implementing a simple hash table in C, starting with linear and binary search concepts.</li>
<li>It details the use of the FNV-1a hash function and linear probing for collision handling, with an emphasis on resizing the table to maintain efficiency.</li>
<li>The implementation includes an API for creating, destroying, getting, setting, and iterating over items, and a demo program to count word frequencies, highlighting its educational purpose rather than production readiness.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40887806">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Discussion on implementing a hash table in C, with various opinions on using off-the-shelf solutions versus custom implementations.</li>
<li>Key points include the importance of multi-threading behavior, API preferences, and limitations of POSIX hsearch tables.</li>
<li>Notable mentions of reentrant versions, resizing challenges, and memory management issues in hash table implementations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://matija.eu/posts/anxious-generation-safetyism-social-media/">Anxious Generation – How Safetyism and Social Media Are Damaging the Kids</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Anxious Generation&quot; by Jonathan Haidt attributes rising mental illness rates among youth to social media and helicopter parenting, distinguishing social media&#39;s harmful effects from general internet use.</li>
<li>Haidt criticizes overprotective parenting and modern safety measures for limiting children&#39;s independence and resilience, proposing a &quot;Ladder from Childhood to Adulthood&quot; with age-appropriate responsibilities and delayed social media use until age 16.</li>
<li>The book also addresses the negative impact of not exposing children to diverse viewpoints, contributing to a lack of free speech in academia, and advocates for societal changes to counter these trends.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40890534">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article on matija.eu discusses how &quot;safetyism&quot; and social media are negatively impacting children&#39;s social development by limiting outdoor play and increasing screen time.</li>
<li>It highlights that parents&#39; overprotectiveness, driven by fear of legal repercussions, prevents kids from playing outside unsupervised until they are older.</li>
<li>The article also examines how modern infrastructure and societal changes contribute to this issue, with various comments reflecting on personal experiences and broader societal implications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://pme.uchicago.edu/news/uchicago-prof-shirley-mengs-laboratory-energy-storage-and-conversion-creates-worlds-first">First anode-free sodium solid-state battery</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>UChicago Prof. Shirley Meng’s lab has developed the world’s first anode-free sodium solid-state battery, a significant advancement for electric vehicles and grid storage.</li>
<li>This innovation, a collaboration between UChicago and UC San Diego, uses abundant sodium instead of lithium, making it more affordable and environmentally friendly.</li>
<li>The new battery architecture, detailed in Nature Energy, features a current collector made of aluminum powder, ensuring efficient cycling, and could greatly support the transition to renewable energy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40891252">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The first anode-free sodium solid-state battery has been developed, utilizing chromium, which is five times more abundant than lithium.</li>
<li>Chromium&#39;s geochemistry makes it easier to mine, more thermodynamically stable, and less diffusive compared to lithium.</li>
<li>Despite the promising development, the new battery&#39;s energy density, volume, and recharge cycle details are still experimental, and the competitive market poses challenges for commercialization.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RATHbP1bAhI">7-Eleven is reinventing its food business to be more Japanese [video]</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>7/11 in Japan offers a diverse range of fresh foods and collaborations with famous restaurants, unlike its US counterpart known for Slurpees and hot dogs.</li>
<li>The world&#39;s largest convenience store chain is shifting focus to food as tobacco and gas sales decline, leveraging data-driven inventory and sophisticated distribution systems.</li>
<li>American 7/11s are now partnering with Warabeya to offer more localized food options and expanding delivery services, aiming to replicate the excitement of Japanese convenience stores in the US market.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40885925">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>7-Eleven is revamping its US food business to mirror its successful Japanese model, which includes offering fresh food and various services.</li>
<li>The Japanese franchise&#39;s success led it to acquire the American parent company, highlighting the stark contrast between the two markets.</li>
<li>The initiative aims to address inefficiencies in US stores, such as slow-moving inventory, to enhance customer experience and boost regular patronage.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.chzsoft.de/site/hardware/preserving-a-floppy-disk-with-a-logic-analyzer/">Preserving a floppy disk with a logic analyzer and a serial cable</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses preserving 3.5-inch floppy disks using a Saleae Logic 8 logic analyzer and a USB serial cable, as an alternative to specialized devices like Kryoflux or SuperCard Pro.</li>
<li>It explains the process of connecting the logic analyzer to the floppy drive, capturing data, and using a Python script to automate the process and export data in the Supercard Pro (.scp) file format.</li>
<li>The method is tested with an unimportant disk, and the captured data is verified using HxCFloppyEmulator software, with the Python script available on GitHub for further improvements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40887168">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses preserving data from floppy disks using a logic analyzer and a serial cable, highlighting the physical aspects of floppy disk interfaces.</li>
<li>Open-source alternatives like GreaseWeazle and FluxEngine are mentioned as cost-effective and efficient solutions for reading floppy disks.</li>
<li>The discussion includes various tools and methods for handling floppy disks, emphasizing the importance of using high-fidelity methods to avoid media wear.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Tao Te Ching translated by Ursula Le Guin (1997)" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Tao%20Te%20Ching%20translated%20by%20Ursula%20Le%20Guin%20(1997)&subheading=Saturday%2C%20July%206%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/07/06</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-07-06T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-07-05]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/07/05&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-07-05</h1>
<h2><a href="https://aukehoekstra.substack.com/p/batteries-how-cheap-can-they-get">Batteries: How cheap can they get?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40877337">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Lithium iron phosphate (LiFePO4) batteries for home use are currently priced at $89/kWh from reputable Chinese suppliers, with an additional $30/kWh if purchased in the US.</li>
<li>Sodium batteries are available at $130/kWh but are 26% less efficient compared to LiFePO4 batteries.</li>
<li>The post highlights the affordability and efficiency of solar panels and batteries, with some users successfully transitioning their homes to solar power and battery storage, reducing reliance on traditional power companies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://consteval.ca/2024/07/03/initialization/">I have no constructor, and I must initialize</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In C++, if constructors are not provided, the compiler may generate default ones, potentially leading to uninitialized objects.</li>
<li>Default-initialization does nothing for non-class and non-array types, while value-initialization zero-initializes non-class types and then default-initializes.</li>
<li>Relying on compiler-generated constructors can result in undefined behavior; it&#39;s recommended to write custom constructors to avoid these issues.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40880932">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>C++ is complex due to its multi-paradigm nature, supporting various applications like embedded systems, video games, servers, and GUIs.</li>
<li>Alternatives like C and Rust do not cover all use cases of C++, making it a unique but challenging language.</li>
<li>While C++&#39;s complexity is necessary for performance and flexibility, it can be overwhelming for less experienced teams.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jul/04/japan-train-robot-maintain-railway-lines">Japan introduces enormous humanoid robot to maintain train lines</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>West Japan Railway has unveiled a 12-metre high robot mounted on a truck for rail maintenance tasks such as trimming tree branches and painting.</li>
<li>The robot, which can be operated remotely, features large arms that can carry up to 40kg and reach vertically up to 12 metres, aiming to address worker shortages and reduce accidents.</li>
<li>The company plans to expand the robot&#39;s use for various maintenance tasks in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40877648">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Japan has unveiled a large humanoid robot for maintaining train lines, controlled remotely similar to a surgical robot.</li>
<li>The robot, capable of reaching 12 meters on a telescoped crane, is designed for tasks like tree limb removal and inspections.</li>
<li>This innovation aims to address Japan&#39;s aging workforce and labor shortages, despite some skepticism about its efficiency compared to traditional methods.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://eieio.games/game-diary/game-6-get-the-dvd-logo-into-the-corner/">Put the DVD logo in the corner (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Game 6: Put the DVD Logo in the Corner&quot; is an arcade action game created by Margaret Lyons, developed in just 4 days using the PICO-8 platform.</li>
<li>The game was created at the Recurse Center and is available on itch.io, with its code accessible on GitHub. It is a short game (45 seconds) based on a joke.</li>
<li>PICO-8 is a &quot;fantasy console&quot; that mimics 80s consoles, with limitations on graphics, sound, and code size, making it ideal for small, simple game projects.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40883277">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses the Recurse Center, a free residency program for programmers that fosters creativity and personal growth, with the author sharing their experience of creating 8 games in 12 weeks.</li>
<li>There is a notable interest in fantasy consoles like Pico-8, which are praised for their constraints that encourage innovation and quick, fun coding projects.</li>
<li>The conversation includes various references to retro gaming and programming environments, highlighting the community&#39;s appreciation for creative coding within limitations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://factorio.com/blog/post/fff-418">Space Age release date</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Factorio: Space Age&quot; expansion is set to release on October 21, 2024, priced at $35.00, the same as the base game.</li>
<li>New features include space platforms, multi-level rail networks, and planets with unique resources and challenges, such as Vulcanus, Fulgora, and Gleba.</li>
<li>&quot;Factorio 2.0&quot; will be a free upgrade, offering game improvements like smarter robots, new rails, and enhanced terrain generation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40882243">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The release date for Factorio&#39;s Space Age expansion has been announced, generating excitement and discussions about the game&#39;s highly addictive nature.</li>
<li>Users shared personal experiences, warning about the potential for the game to consume significant time and impact daily life, while also recommending similar games and mods.</li>
<li>The community discussed Factorio&#39;s pricing strategy, appreciating the consistent value due to the absence of sales, and expressed both excitement and caution about the immersive gameplay.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://withtelescope.com">I’ve made a cheaper SEO research tool</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author built a custom Keywords Research tool named Telescope, spending $51 over 2 months, compared to $1297 on an Ahrefs subscription over 13 months.</li>
<li>Telescope offers features like Keywords Explorer, Keywords Ideas, Ranked Keywords, and Saved Keywords, with payment options including usage-based subscription or top-up balance.</li>
<li>New accounts receive a free balance to start, and the author seeks feedback on the tool.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40881836">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new, cost-effective SEO research tool named Telescope has been launched, offering significant savings compared to competitors like Ahrefs and SEMrush.</li>
<li>Telescope&#39;s features include Keywords Explorer, Keywords Ideas, Ranked Keywords, and Saved Keywords, with flexible payment options and a free starting balance for new accounts.</li>
<li>User discussions highlight the high costs of existing tools, the potential of Telescope as a SEMrush alternative, and inquiries about backend providers, API availability, and specific market data.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nexdock.com/">NexDock turns your smartphone into a laptop</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NexDock allows users to convert their smartphones into laptops, either through wired or wireless connections.</li>
<li>NexPad enables smartphones to function as tablets, providing a versatile use case for mobile devices.</li>
<li>NexDock XL, an upcoming product, promises to expand the range of NEX devices, enhancing mobile productivity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40877992">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>NexDock aims to transform smartphones into laptops, but users report dissatisfaction due to poor desktop/laptop experiences on smartphones.</li>
<li>Despite the concept&#39;s appeal of upgrading only the phone and not the laptop form factor, execution issues, particularly on the phone side, hinder its success.</li>
<li>Alternatives like older laptops from eBay or devices like the Steam Deck offer better performance and user experience for similar or lower costs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/mohapatrahemant/status/1809135345683841050">I was at AMD in the mid-late 2000s helping design CPU/APU/GPUs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia has surpassed the market capitalization of both AMD and Intel, a significant milestone in the tech industry.</li>
<li>Hemant Mohapatra, a former AMD employee, reflects on the unexpected nature of this achievement, given AMD&#39;s historical position relative to Intel.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40882077">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author, a former AMD engineer, highlights AMD&#39;s strong engineering culture but notes shortcomings in software support and vendor relationships.</li>
<li>Nvidia&#39;s success is attributed to aggressive, sometimes controversial, business practices and a robust software ecosystem, particularly with CUDA.</li>
<li>Dr. Lisa Su&#39;s leadership at AMD has been crucial, and there is ongoing debate about whether Nvidia&#39;s dominance is sustainable or if competitors like AMD and Intel can close the gap.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40878765">Is there any software you only made for your own use but nobody else?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40878765">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users have created various software tools for personal use, ranging from productivity aids to complex automation systems.</li>
<li>Examples include a job board crawler, hydroponic garden manager, personal note-taking app, and a Spotify playlist generator.</li>
<li>These projects often aim to solve specific problems or enhance daily tasks, with some users planning to share their tools eventually.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://chipsandcheese.com/2024/07/04/the-snapdragon-x-elites-adreno-igpu/">The Snapdragon X Elite&#39;s Adreno iGPU</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40878222">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Snapdragon X Elite&#39;s Adreno iGPU initially outperformed mid-range GPUs from Apple, AMD, and NVIDIA in benchmarks but now struggles with modern graphics loads, including desktop gaming.</li>
<li>Qualcomm faces a strategic decision between maintaining its dominance in mobile graphics or pursuing higher-end gaming performance, with persistent issues in Adreno drivers noted by the Dolphin team.</li>
<li>ARM SOC (System on Chip) GPUs from Apple and NVIDIA remain strong, while Intel and AMD integrated GPUs (iGPUs) outperform ARM counterparts, indicating Qualcomm&#39;s need to balance mobile and desktop GPU performance without directly competing with discrete GPUs (dGPUs).</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.brixit.nl/moving-to-a-rtos-on-the-rp2040/">Moving to a RTOS on the RP2040</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>As projects grow in complexity, the Raspberry Pi Pico often surpasses the capabilities of the Arduino IDE, necessitating more advanced tools like an RTOS (Real-Time Operating System).</li>
<li>Martijn Braam is developing a hardware controller for PTZ cameras and video switchers, requiring an RTOS due to software complexity; he evaluated FreeRTOS, Apache NuttX, and Zephyr.</li>
<li>Despite initial challenges with FreeRTOS, such as printf causing hangs and lack of hardware abstraction, it remains the most viable option due to its integration with the pico-sdk.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40879541">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses transitioning to a Real-Time Operating System (RTOS) on the RP2040 microcontroller, highlighting various RTOS options and their suitability.</li>
<li>Key RTOS options mentioned include FreeRTOS, Zephyr, and NuttX, each with its own strengths and weaknesses in terms of support, user-friendliness, and hardware compatibility.</li>
<li>The discussion also touches on alternative development environments like Rust and MicroPython, emphasizing their benefits for embedded development on the RP2040.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://web.stanford.edu/group/mota/education/Physics%2087N%20Final%20Projects/Group%20Gamma/bone.htm">Bone tissue reparation using coral and marine sponges</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have developed a new method for bone tissue repair using coral and marine sponges as scaffolds, leveraging their porosity and calcium carbonate composition.</li>
<li>This method involves preparing the scaffolds to fit the damaged area and using marrow stromal cells (MSC) or stem cells to promote bone regeneration.</li>
<li>Unlike traditional materials like ceramics or alloys, coral and marine sponges avoid stress-shielding, providing a framework that supports proper bone healing and integration.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40878895">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers are exploring the use of coral and marine sponges for bone tissue repair, highlighting an innovative approach in medical science.</li>
<li>The discussion includes personal anecdotes about successful bone repairs using coral fragments, suggesting these materials are effective and cost-efficient alternatives to traditional methods.</li>
<li>The conversation also touches on the importance of bone density and various methods to improve it, such as resistance training and vibration therapy, providing a broader context for bone health maintenance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://vivaldi.com/blog/technology/vivaldi-wont-allow-a-machine-to-lie-to-you/">Why Vivaldi won&#39;t follow the current AI trend?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Vivaldi has decided not to integrate Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT into their web browser, citing concerns over plagiarism, privacy violations, and the generation of inaccurate information.</li>
<li>LLMs analyze vast amounts of data, which can lead to the unintentional regurgitation of copyrighted material and the disclosure of private information.</li>
<li>Vivaldi aims to provide a feature-rich and ethical browsing experience, remaining open to future machine learning advancements that prioritize privacy and usability.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40880322">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Vivaldi&#39;s decision to avoid integrating AI, specifically Large Language Models (LLMs), has generated significant debate among users.</li>
<li>Supporters of Vivaldi&#39;s stance highlight concerns about LLMs&#39; reliability and high energy consumption, while critics argue that LLMs provide valuable features that could benefit users.</li>
<li>The article explaining Vivaldi&#39;s decision has been criticized for appearing biased and dismissive of the potential benefits of LLMs, with many advocating for AI integration to be an optional feature in browsers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://sashalaundy.com/writing/technical-skills/">“Technical” Skills</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The traditional labeling of individuals as &quot;technical&quot; or &quot;not technical&quot; in Silicon Valley undervalues the diverse technical skills across various fields.</li>
<li>Examples like the movie &quot;Free Solo&quot; and Steph Curry&#39;s basketball career highlight intricate technical details often overlooked, similar to skills in marketing, sales, and management.</li>
<li>Recognizing and accurately describing these skills can enrich our understanding of different professions and prevent the perpetuation of power dynamics that undervalue important work.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40879899">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>In software companies, when coders ask if a boss is &quot;technical,&quot; they are inquiring if the boss can code.</li>
<li>The distinction between technical and non-technical roles is common across various fields, emphasizing practical knowledge in specific contexts.</li>
<li>Understanding technical work is crucial for managers to effectively advocate for and make decisions regarding their team&#39;s work.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/978955/">Programming in Unison</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Unison is an MIT-licensed programming language that stores code in a database rather than text files, simplifying distributed programming.</li>
<li>It uses a unique naming system based on hashes, enabling seamless renaming and versioning, and features an abilities system to track code dependencies and interactions.</li>
<li>Designed for cloud computing, Unison offers managed services through Unison Cloud, but faces challenges like the lack of a stable Foreign Function Interface (FFI) and the need for custom tooling.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40882133">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Unison programming language is noted for its ergonomic design and code-in-database approach, which simplifies coding by eliminating long compilation times and the need for Git.</li>
<li>Despite being a young language, Unison offers robust tooling, including Language Server Protocol (LSP) integration and first-class documentation, which enhances the developer experience.</li>
<li>Unison&#39;s method of handling immutable code stored in a database addresses common issues in traditional REPL-based languages, though some users are concerned about modern languages incorporating too many built-in tools.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Batteries: How cheap can they get?" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Batteries%3A%20How%20cheap%20can%20they%20get%3F&subheading=Friday%2C%20July%205%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/07/05</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-07-05T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-07-04]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/07/04&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-07-04</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.arno.org/on-the-origins-of-ds-store">The Origins of DS_store (2006)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>.DS_Store files, commonly seen when transferring files from Mac to Windows, stand for &quot;Desktop Services Store,&quot; originating from a 1999 rewrite of the Mac OS X Finder.</li>
<li>The Finder was split into a user interface (Finder_FE) and core functionality (Finder_BE), with plans to make the backend a public API called Desktop Services, though it was never fully released.</li>
<li>A bug causes excessive creation of .DS_Store files, even without user adjustments, making them a persistent issue for Mac users.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40870357">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around the historical context and technical details of the DS_store file and the &quot;fork&quot; concept in Mac file systems, which includes both resource and data components.</li>
<li>The resource fork in early MacOS stored various application data like icons, menus, and executable code, which posed challenges when transferring files to non-Mac systems.</li>
<li>The transition from MacOS to MacOS X involved significant changes, including the removal of resource forks, which was met with mixed reactions from the user community.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://0x.tools/">Xcapture-BPF – like Linux top, but with Xray vision</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>0x.tools is a set of open-source utilities designed for analyzing application performance on Linux, emphasizing simplicity and minimal dependencies.</li>
<li>Key features include measuring individual thread-level activity and providing eBPF-based tools for system-level and detailed thread activity analysis.</li>
<li>It is designed for safe use in production environments with very low overhead and does not require OS upgrades or heavy monitoring frameworks.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40869877">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Xcapture-BPF is a new tool likened to Linux&#39;s top command but with enhanced capabilities, often referred to as having &quot;Xray vision&quot; for system diagnostics.</li>
<li>Users have shared experiences of using eBPF (extended Berkeley Packet Filter) and BCC (BPF Compiler Collection) tools to debug complex production issues, highlighting their effectiveness in resolving performance bottlenecks and memory leaks.</li>
<li>The discussion includes practical examples of troubleshooting, such as resolving high iowait and page cache issues in containerized environments by enabling direct IO and matching sector sizes on loopback devices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/ais-600b-question/">AI&#39;s $600B Question</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The AI revenue gap has widened from $200B to $600B, raising questions about the industry&#39;s growth expectations.</li>
<li>Key developments include the easing of the GPU supply shortage, Nvidia&#39;s increased data center revenue, and OpenAI&#39;s significant revenue growth to $3.4B.</li>
<li>Challenges such as lack of pricing power, investment risks, and rapid depreciation of older chips persist, but lower GPU costs could benefit startups and innovation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40869461">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Training large AI models like GPT-4 requires significant computational resources, with estimates suggesting 8,000 H100 GPUs running for 90 days.</li>
<li>Meta&#39;s substantial GPU investments could allow them to train multiple GPT-4 scale models annually, potentially commoditizing core AI models and impacting profit margins for AI companies.</li>
<li>The real value in AI may shift towards proprietary data for training, raising potential legal issues and emphasizing the importance of data ownership.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://salykova.github.io/matmul-cpu">Beating NumPy matrix multiplication in 150 lines of C</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A high-performance matrix multiplication implementation in C, following the BLIS design, outperforms NumPy (OpenBLAS) on an AMD Ryzen 7700, achieving over 1 TFLOPS.</li>
<li>The code is simple, portable, and scalable, using only 3 lines of OpenMP directives for parallelization, and targets Intel Core and AMD Zen CPUs with FMA3 and AVX instructions.</li>
<li>The implementation demonstrates that efficient matrix multiplication can be achieved in C without deep assembly or Fortran code, with performance comparable to established BLAS libraries when fine-tuned for specific hardware.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40870345">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A blog post demonstrates outperforming NumPy matrix multiplication using 150 lines of C code, focusing on performance enhancements.</li>
<li>Key improvements include algorithm selection, minimizing kernel round trips, vectorization, cache efficiency, and hardware-specific optimizations.</li>
<li>Discussions in the comments address the fairness of comparing C code to NumPy, suggesting comparisons with other BLAS (Basic Linear Algebra Subprograms) libraries and emphasizing the need for thorough benchmarking and hyperparameter tuning for specific CPUs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://reactormag.com/the-joy-of-reading-books-you-dont-entirely-understand/">The joy of reading books you don&#39;t understand</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article emphasizes the joy and value of reading books that are not entirely understood, suggesting that it&#39;s okay to appreciate a book without fully grasping it.</li>
<li>The author, Molly Templeton, shares personal experiences with complex books like Neal Stephenson’s <em>Baroque Cycle</em> and recent titles such as Alaya Dawn Johnson’s <em>The Library of Broken Worlds</em> and Molly McGhee’s <em>Jonathan Abernathy You Are Kind</em>.</li>
<li>Templeton argues that embracing uncertainty in reading can be liberating and enrich the reading experience, encouraging readers to explore challenging narratives.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40870280">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses the value of reading books that challenge and provoke deep thought, referencing Kafka&#39;s belief that impactful books should &quot;bite and sting&quot; rather than simply entertain.</li>
<li>It highlights different perspectives on reading difficult or complex books, with some readers advocating for immersion without note-taking to enhance understanding and enjoyment.</li>
<li>The conversation includes personal anecdotes and recommendations for books that have left a lasting impression, emphasizing the joy of discovering new insights through re-reading and engaging with challenging material.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.securityweek.com/twilio-confirms-data-breach-after-hackers-leak-33m-authy-user-phone-numbers/">Twilio confirms data breach after hackers leak 33M Authy user phone numbers</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40874341">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Twilio has confirmed a data breach that exposed the phone numbers of 33 million Authy users, leading to increased spam calls and concerns over the reliability of traditional phone networks.</li>
<li>Users are considering alternative communication methods such as FaceTime and Zoom, while also emphasizing the critical role of phone calls in essential services like healthcare and social services.</li>
<li>The breach highlights the need for stronger data protection, better enforcement of anti-spam measures, and recommendations for alternative two-factor authentication (2FA) apps like Aegis, Bitwarden, and Yubikey.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.kitze.io/posts/saddest-just-ship-it-story-ever">The saddest &quot;Just Ship It&quot; story ever (2020)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author shares a personal journey of developing an app, starting in 2018, but delaying its release due to continuous feature additions and learning new technologies like React Native.</li>
<li>Despite abandoning the project after two years, the author later discovered a similar app that succeeded despite being imperfect, leading to mixed emotions.</li>
<li>In 2022, the author finally released a productivity app combining various features like Todos, Habits, Planner, and Goals, and invites readers to join the community on Benji - The Life OS.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40872182">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around the &quot;just ship it&quot; mentality in software development, emphasizing that rushing to meet deadlines can compromise the quality of the software and lead to developer burnout.</li>
<li>There is a debate on whether developers should prioritize company profitability or focus on creating high-quality software, with some arguing that developers are not adequately compensated for extraordinary efforts unless they have a significant stake in the company.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights differing perspectives on job satisfaction, compensation, and the balance between professional integrity and company demands, reflecting broader industry concerns about work-life balance and recognition.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://corecursive.com/building-powershell-with-jeffrey-snover/">Jeffrey Snover and the Making of PowerShell</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Jeffrey Snover, the architect behind PowerShell, shares his journey of creating a command tool that revolutionized Windows system administration, initially facing resistance from a company favoring graphical interfaces.</li>
<li>Key challenges included navigating company restructures, cultural pushback, and building a dedicated team, with significant influence from Bill Gates&#39; push for .NET.</li>
<li>PowerShell&#39;s development, guided by the Monad Manifesto, transformed Windows Server administration and enabled Microsoft&#39;s move to the cloud, showcasing the impact of persistence and vision in driving technological change.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40874013">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Jeffrey Snover, the creator of PowerShell, faced significant opposition and was demoted at Microsoft for pursuing its development.</li>
<li>PowerShell was designed to aid server administration on Windows by calling various APIs, but it faced internal conflicts and some features were lost in newer versions.</li>
<li>Despite its object-oriented approach and .NET integration, PowerShell is seen as verbose and challenging compared to other scripting languages like Python, limiting its adoption outside the Windows ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.firezone.dev/blog/sans-io">Sans-IO: The secret to effective Rust for network services</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Firezone uses Rust and a sans-IO design for its core connectivity library, connlib, to manage network connections and WireGuard tunnels, offering fast tests, deep customization, and high assurance.</li>
<li>The sans-IO design separates policy from implementation using abstractions like <code>Transmit</code>, allowing pure state machines to handle network protocols without direct IO, making the code more flexible and easier to test.</li>
<li>While sans-IO requires custom event loops and state machines, it provides significant benefits such as easy composition, flexible APIs, and improved error handling, despite not being widely adopted in the Rust community yet.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40872020">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses the concept of Sans-IO in Rust, which separates input/output (IO) operations from the main logic, making code more testable and composable.</li>
<li>This approach is particularly beneficial for packet-oriented use cases like QUIC, WebRTC, and IP, where state management can become complex.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights that while this method isn&#39;t new, it offers significant advantages in Rust by simplifying testing and avoiding the pitfalls of traditional async/await patterns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lazamar.github.io/haskell-data-compression-with-huffman-codes/">Building a data compression utility in Haskell using Huffman codes</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post outlines the creation of a data compression program in Haskell using Huffman coding, which handles arbitrary binary files with constant memory for encoding and decoding.</li>
<li>It explains Huffman codes, prefix-free codes, and the process of constructing a binary tree for efficient encoding, followed by the implementation of encoding and decoding functions.</li>
<li>The post also covers handling binary files, serializing/deserializing data, and potential improvements like multithreading and faster code creation, showcasing a practical and efficient data compression utility in Haskell.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40872332">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A discussion on building a data compression utility in Haskell using Huffman codes, highlighting the efficiency of array-based, in-place algorithms for large data sets.</li>
<li>References to significant works, including Moffat and Katajainen&#39;s 1995 paper and the JPEG standard ITU T.81 (1992), which describe array-based Huffman coding.</li>
<li>Insights into Haskell&#39;s performance, with comparisons to other languages like C, C++, and Rust, and the trade-offs between simplicity of implementation and code clarity versus raw performance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://elevenlabs.io/voice-isolator">Voice Isolator: Strip background noise for film, podcast, interview production</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The AI voice generator now supports 29 languages, expanding its accessibility and usability for a global audience.</li>
<li>It offers thousands of voice options, providing users with a wide range of choices for different applications and preferences.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40869421">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Elevenlabs&#39; Voice Isolator tool aims to strip background noise for film, podcast, and interview production, but its pricing model based on &quot;characters&quot; is confusing many users.</li>
<li>Users are discussing various alternatives for speech-to-text (STT) and text-to-speech (TTS) solutions, including open-source options like Whisper and commercial services like Deepgram Nova 2.</li>
<li>There is a notable interest in local and open-source solutions for audio cleanup and transcription, as many find current commercial offerings either too expensive or not effective enough.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40872102">Vision Pro owners, are you still using it?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40872102">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Vision Pro users have mixed experiences, with some praising its media and work capabilities, while others criticize its high cost and limited functionality.</li>
<li>Key features appreciated include screen size, passthrough, eyesight features, and improved Bluetooth peripheral support, but issues like vision discomfort and limited software integration are noted.</li>
<li>The device&#39;s high price point ($3500) and limited release (450k units) have led to a small market, with many users waiting for future revisions or opting for cheaper alternatives like the Quest 3.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://boyuan.space/diffusion-forcing/">Diffusion Forcing: Next-Token Prediction Meets Full-Sequence Diffusion</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Diffusion Forcing is a new training paradigm that combines next-token prediction and full-sequence diffusion models, offering flexible generation and sequence-level guidance.</li>
<li>It achieves significant performance improvements in applications like video prediction, stabilizing infinite rollouts, diffusion planning, and long-horizon imitation learning.</li>
<li>This method allows for stable and consistent video predictions, longer rollouts without sliding windows, and robust handling of non-Markovian tasks with long-term memory requirements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40871783">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper combines sequence masking, essential for Large Language Models (LLMs), with diffusion models by tracking an &#39;uncertainty&#39; level per pixel, treated as &#39;noise&#39; for the diffusion model.</li>
<li>This method is beneficial for tasks like maze solving and controlling a robot arm, as it allows for firming up parts of an image earlier.</li>
<li>The approach models uncertainty in planning and search, enhancing agents&#39; ability to react and generalize, but the paper lacks implementation details and codebase access.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.nelhage.com/post/fuzzy-dedup/">Finding near-duplicates with Jaccard similarity and MinHash</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Jaccard similarity and MinHash are used to identify approximately similar documents in large text collections, such as those used in GPT-3 dataset preparation.</li>
<li>MinHash approximates Jaccard similarity by hashing document features and using the minimum hash value as a signature, allowing efficient comparison of large corpora.</li>
<li>This method is scalable and can be combined with other techniques like HyperLogLog, making it suitable for large-scale text processing applications.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40872438">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses using Jaccard similarity and MinHash for finding near-duplicate data, highlighting their application in various fields such as medical image segmentation and database deduplication.</li>
<li>Several tools and libraries are mentioned for deduplication tasks, including datasketch, rensa, Splink, and gaoya, with insights into their performance and use cases.</li>
<li>The Fellegi Sunter model is noted for its effectiveness in deduplicating people by assigning weights to fuzzy matches and mismatches, improving accuracy in large datasets.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://community.fly.io/t/fresh-produce-region-specific-machines-pricing/20690">Region-specific Machines pricing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Starting July 1st, region-specific pricing for Machines, including additional RAM, will be introduced due to varying infrastructure costs by region.</li>
<li>The price adjustment will be phased in over four months, with final prices set by November; initial invoices will show region-specific line items without price changes.</li>
<li>A bug fix for Machines Shared CPU 1x usage not covered by Free Machines Allowance credit has been implemented, and credits are being reissued.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40873001">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Fly.io&#39;s region-specific pricing has ignited discussions, with some users finding it expensive compared to alternatives like Hetzner, especially for high availability.</li>
<li>Fly.io defends its pricing by highlighting the unsustainability of flat global rates due to high operational costs in certain regions, such as Brazil.</li>
<li>Despite the removal of the hobby plan and some reliability concerns, many users appreciate Fly.io&#39;s features like dynamic request routing and &quot;ops-less&quot; deployments, which they believe justify the higher costs.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="The Origins of DS_store (2006)" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=The%20Origins%20of%20DS_store%20(2006)&subheading=Thursday%2C%20July%204%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/07/04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-07-04T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-07-03]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/07/03&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-07-03</h1>
<h2><a href="https://timharek.no/blog/i-received-an-ai-email">I Received an AI Email</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author received an email from &quot;Raymond&quot; promoting Wisp, a headless CMS, which seemed personalized but was actually AI-generated.</li>
<li>The email was part of a mass outreach strategy using AI to send nearly 1,000 personalized emails to developers with public blogs on GitHub.</li>
<li>The author expresses frustration with this AI-driven approach and considers making their GitHub-mirror private to avoid such spam.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40862865">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An AI-generated email from timharek.no claims success in creating personalized emails using multiple Large Language Models (LLMs) without recipients detecting the AI origin.</li>
<li>This raises ethical concerns about prioritizing attention and engagement over meaningful progress, with some comparing it to engineers focusing on ad tech rather than significant achievements like the moon landing.</li>
<li>The discussion underscores the dual nature of AI in marketing, acknowledging both its potential for misuse in spam and its valuable applications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.engadget.com/proton-launches-its-own-version-of-google-docs-100044471.html">Proton launches its own version of Google Docs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Proton has introduced Proton Docs, a secure alternative to Google Docs, featuring rich editing and collaboration tools with end-to-end encryption.</li>
<li>Proton Docs supports advanced formatting, image embedding, and multiple formats, including Microsoft .docx, and allows real-time collaboration with features like comments and cursor tracking.</li>
<li>This launch is part of Proton&#39;s broader expansion, which includes a VPN, encrypted calendar, and password manager, with Proton Docs becoming available to users shortly.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40864914">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Proton has introduced a collaborative rich text editor, similar to Google Docs, aiming to provide a secure, encrypted alternative.</li>
<li>Users are divided, with some appreciating the new tool and others concerned about Proton expanding its product range instead of enhancing existing services like email and calendar.</li>
<li>Discussions include the open-source nature of Proton&#39;s offerings and comparisons to other services, with some users wary of consolidating all their data within one company&#39;s ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://practical.engineering/blog/2024/7/2/why-bridges-dont-sink">Why Bridges Don&#39;t Sink</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bridges must support loads over clear spaces, requiring strong substructures like piers or abutments to handle concentrated forces.</li>
<li>Foundation piles, driven deep into the ground, provide stability through end-bearing and skin friction, resisting vertical and horizontal loads.</li>
<li>Alternatives like drilled shafts and variations such as continuous flight auger piles and helical piles address specific geotechnical challenges, though all methods have limitations and potential failure risks.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40861520">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bridges remain stable because driven piles are tested for the force required to install them, ensuring they can handle significant loads.</li>
<li>Wooden piles, when preserved in fully soaked ground, can last for centuries, as evidenced by structures in Venice and New Orleans.</li>
<li>Challenges such as soil liquefaction, lateral deflection, and unexpected underground conditions can complicate pile driving, but innovative engineering solutions, like floating bridges and historical examples like the Brooklyn Bridge, demonstrate successful overcoming of these issues.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://hackernews.demo.vectara.com/">I made a search engine for Hacker News</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A Vectara employee has developed an improved search tool for Hacker News (HN) using data from the past six months of stories and comments.</li>
<li>The creator seeks feedback on the new search tool&#39;s effectiveness compared to the current Algolia search used by HN.</li>
<li>This initiative aims to enhance the search experience for HN users by addressing limitations in the existing search functionality.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40860022">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new search engine for Hacker News, built using Vectara, aims to address limitations found in Algolia, covering the last 6 months of stories and comments.</li>
<li>User feedback highlighted the need for additional features like filters, sorting options, and indexing external links, with mixed opinions on its effectiveness compared to Algolia.</li>
<li>The project has initiated discussions on enhancing search relevance and user experience within the Hacker News community.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nextword.substack.com/p/why-ai-infrastructure-startups-are">Why AI Infrastructure Startups Are Insanely Hard to Build</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40862436">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>AI infrastructure startups face significant challenges, including intense competition and high costs, unlike tech giants like Google, Amazon, or Facebook, which evolved into infrastructure providers.</li>
<li>Venture capital investment in AI infrastructure may be misguided, as the true value lies in companies offering tangible, user-friendly solutions rather than just frameworks.</li>
<li>Even successful AI companies like OpenAI lack clear products, emphasizing the need for practical innovations that can transform user interactions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://qntm.org/leap">All I want for Christmas is a negative leap second</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The blog post discusses the concept of a negative leap second, which has never been implemented but could be necessary due to Earth&#39;s faster rotation since 2018.</li>
<li>Leap seconds are added to account for Earth&#39;s irregular rotation, posing challenges to technical systems like Unix time, which struggles with the 23:59:60 timestamp.</li>
<li>There is ongoing debate about abolishing leap seconds by 2035, which would prevent the implementation of a negative leap second, a prospect the author finds disappointing.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40860831">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around the concept of leap seconds, which are added to Coordinated Universal Time (UTC) to keep it in sync with Earth&#39;s rotation, and the potential introduction of a negative leap second.</li>
<li>Various opinions are shared on how to handle time adjustments, including abolishing leap seconds, shifting the prime meridian, and updating time zones periodically.</li>
<li>The debate highlights the complexities and potential issues of timekeeping, such as system synchronization problems, the impact on software, and the historical context of time standards like UTC and TAI (International Atomic Time).</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.mattkeeter.com/blog/2023-01-25-branch/">Do not taunt happy fun branch predictor (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>An attempt to optimize an AArch64 assembly inner loop by eliminating a jump resulted in a 4x slowdown due to mismatched <code>bl</code> (branch with link) and <code>ret</code> (return) pairs, which confused the branch predictor.</li>
<li>Replacing <code>ret</code> with <code>br x30</code> (branch to register) resolved the performance issue, and further optimizations, including inlining and using SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) instructions, achieved significant speedups.</li>
<li>The final optimized SIMD version ran in 94 ns, approximately 8.8 times faster than the original code, highlighting the importance of avoiding asymmetric branching and leveraging SIMD for performance gains.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40866374">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article showcases an optimized code that sums an array of 1024 32-bit floating point numbers in 94 nanoseconds, emphasizing the efficiency due to cache usage.</li>
<li>It discusses the significance of branch prediction and CPU architecture on performance, as well as the complexities of floating-point arithmetic and ensuring deterministic results.</li>
<li>References to past work by Raymond Chen and user comments on SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) instructions, compiler optimizations, and historical CPU behaviors are included.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/07/02/googles-carbon-emissions-surge-nearly-50percent-due-to-ai-energy-demand.html">Google&#39;s carbon emissions surge nearly 50% due to AI energy demand</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google&#39;s carbon emissions increased by nearly 50% compared to 2019, as reported in its 2024 environmental report, challenging its net-zero emissions goal by 2030.</li>
<li>The rise in emissions is primarily due to higher energy consumption in data centers and supply chain emissions driven by AI advancements, with a 17% increase in data center electricity consumption in 2023.</li>
<li>Despite these challenges, Google is committed to reducing its environmental impact through efficient infrastructure and emissions reductions, a challenge also faced by other tech companies like Microsoft due to AI demand.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40859993">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google&#39;s carbon emissions have risen by 13% since last year, primarily due to increased energy consumption in data centers and supply chain emissions.</li>
<li>There has been a 48% increase in emissions compared to 2019, but this rise is not solely attributable to AI, despite some headlines suggesting otherwise.</li>
<li>The increase in emissions has been gradual over the years, and the specific impact of AI on this rise remains unclear.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://jalammar.github.io/illustrated-transformer/">The Illustrated Transformer (2018)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post delves into The Transformer model, which uses attention mechanisms to enhance training speed and performance, surpassing the Google Neural Machine Translation model in specific tasks.</li>
<li>The Transformer model, detailed in the paper &quot;Attention is All You Need,&quot; has implementations in TensorFlow (Tensor2Tensor package) and PyTorch (Harvard’s NLP guide), and is recommended by Google Cloud for their Cloud TPU offering.</li>
<li>The model&#39;s architecture includes encoding and decoding components with self-attention and multi-headed attention layers, allowing it to focus on relevant parts of the input and improve translation accuracy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40861148">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;The Illustrated Transformer&quot; by Jay Alammar is highly praised for its step-by-step explanation of the original transformer architecture.</li>
<li>For visualizing information flow in decoder-only architectures like GPT-3, bbycroft.net is recommended.</li>
<li>Users suggest annotated code from Harvard&#39;s NLP site for a deeper understanding of transformers, emphasizing the importance of grasping underlying mechanics like attention mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/brazil-tech-meta-privacy-data-93e00b2e0e26f7cc98795dd052aea8e1">Brazil data regulator bans Meta from mining data to train AI models</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Brazil&#39;s national data protection authority has prohibited Meta from using data from Brazil to train its AI systems, citing potential risks to fundamental rights.</li>
<li>Meta&#39;s updated privacy policy, which allows the use of public posts for AI training, is not compliant with Brazilian regulations, leading to this restriction.</li>
<li>Meta must comply with this ruling within five days or face daily fines, reflecting similar resistance seen in Europe, while AI training with public data continues in the U.S.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40861057">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Brazil&#39;s data regulator has prohibited Meta from using data to train AI models due to privacy concerns, highlighting ongoing debates on data usage and intellectual property in AI training.</li>
<li>Some propose a compromise allowing the use of publicly available data if the resulting AI models are made public, though ethical concerns and potential exploitation of user data persist.</li>
<li>The effectiveness and enforcement of such regulations are under scrutiny, considering the complexities involved in data auditing and jurisdictional challenges.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-02/apple-to-get-openai-board-observer-role-as-part-of-ai-agreement">Apple poised to get OpenAI board observer role as part of AI pact</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40860363">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple will gain an observer role on OpenAI&#39;s board through a new AI partnership, emphasizing the strategic value of Apple&#39;s user base.</li>
<li>Despite not investing or paying for GPT-4 API calls, Apple ensures stability in its AI partner, while OpenAI accesses a lucrative market.</li>
<li>This partnership underscores the broader implications for the tech industry and the competitive dynamics among AI companies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://community.sonarsource.com/t/sonar-is-destroying-my-job-and-its-driving-me-to-despair/92438">Sonar is destroying my job and it&#39;s driving me to despair</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Sonar, a code quality tool, struggles to keep up with new language syntax, causing frustration among developers, especially with Kotlin.</li>
<li>The default Sonar setup often forces unnecessary code alterations, and customizing rules or allowing exceptions is not user-friendly, particularly under tight deadlines.</li>
<li>Suggestions for improvement include user roles for rule overrides with admin notifications, group consensus for overrides, and a community thread for discussing rule issues.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40859937">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Sonar, a code quality and security tool, is causing frustration for some users due to the extensive justification required for exceptions, especially under tight deadlines.</li>
<li>The main issues stem from organizational and communication problems, not the tool itself, with users citing loss of code coverage credit during refactoring and the need for workarounds.</li>
<li>While Sonar is beneficial for many, particularly junior and senior engineers, its impact on build times and the rigidity imposed by management are common criticisms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adq3334">An epigenetic editor to silence genes</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40859876">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new epigenetic editor has been developed to silence specific genes, potentially preventing diseases by targeting single genes.</li>
<li>Notable genes on George Church&#39;s list for knockout include MSTN for lean muscle growth, SCN9A for insensitivity to pain, and PCSK9 for low coronary disease.</li>
<li>While promising, the complexity of gene therapy is highlighted, with some traits being polygenic and requiring consideration of environmental factors.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/cycling/articles/cxxx568grlwo">Tour de France: How professional cycling teams eat and cook on the road</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>EF Education-EasyPost head chef Owen Blandy adapted to challenges by showcasing flexibility, a key trait in professional cycling.</li>
<li>Modern cycling teams invest in custom food trucks, nutrition apps, and data-driven meal plans, with AI being used to tailor diets for each rider.</li>
<li>Teams follow a five-meal daily plan focusing on high carbohydrates and proteins, with on-bike fuelling including energy bars, gels, and traditional foods like rice cakes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40860364">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Professional cycling teams have significantly evolved their approach to nutrition, emphasizing simple, lightly seasoned meals with fresh herbs and citrus.</li>
<li>Riders use glucose monitoring devices during training to optimize nutrition, though these devices are banned during races, highlighting the importance of personalized nutrition.</li>
<li>Teams face logistical challenges, such as sourcing enough ice and meticulously managing diets to prevent issues like cramps, while doping remains a concern but is less prevalent due to strict testing and monitoring.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40866311">Has anyone successfully pivoted from web dev to AI/ML development?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A senior full-stack web software engineer with 10 years of experience is seeking advice on transitioning to a professional AI role.</li>
<li>The individual has a strong foundation in programming, math, and computer science but anticipates starting from scratch in some AI areas.</li>
<li>They have been self-learning AI, machine learning (ML), and deep learning, and are looking for insights from others who have made a similar career pivot.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40866311">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Many professionals have successfully transitioned from web development to AI/ML roles, often by leveraging existing skills and learning new ones through courses and self-study.</li>
<li>Key strategies include joining AI teams as software engineers, using existing AI APIs, and gradually upskilling in AI/ML techniques.</li>
<li>Practical advice includes taking specialized courses like Fast AI, participating in open-source AI projects, and building a strong portfolio to demonstrate capabilities in AI/ML.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="I Received an AI Email" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=I%20Received%20an%20AI%20Email&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20July%203%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/07/03</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-07-03T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-07-02]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/07/02&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-07-02</h1>
<h2><a href="https://unchartedterritories.tomaspueyo.com/p/why-is-chile-so-long">Why is Chile so long?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Chile&#39;s unique length is due to the Andes mountains, creating a narrow strip of land between the mountains and the Pacific Ocean.</li>
<li>The country&#39;s geography is shaped by the collision of the Nazca and South American tectonic plates, forming the Andes.</li>
<li>Chile&#39;s borders were historically contested, notably in the War of the Pacific, where it gained resource-rich territories.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40856030">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Chile&#39;s unique geography, with the Andes mountains and the Pacific Ocean as natural boundaries, and historical factors have shaped its long and narrow shape.</li>
<li>The country spans diverse climates, from the Atacama Desert in the north to cold southern regions, influencing its centralized population in Santiago.</li>
<li>Chile&#39;s diverse geography also affects its dialect of Spanish, giving it unique characteristics compared to other Spanish-speaking regions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ladybird.org/index.html">Welcome to Ladybird, a truly independent web browser</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ladybird is an independent web browser and engine, initially an HTML viewer for SerenityOS, now supporting Linux, macOS, and other Unix-like systems.</li>
<li>Unique features include no code from other browsers, a singular focus on being a web browser, and no monetization through ads or user data.</li>
<li>An Alpha release is planned for Summer 2026, with development funded by sponsorships and donations, and a team of 4 full-time engineers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40854836">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ladybird is an independent web browser, and its official website is ladybird.org.</li>
<li>Discussions and comments about Ladybird have been moved to a specific thread on Hacker News, which is currently featured on the front page.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/vslavik/diff-pdf">Diff-pdf: tool to visually compare two PDFs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The <code>diff-pdf</code> tool allows users to visually compare two PDF files, highlighting differences if any.</li>
<li>The repository is not actively developed, and users are encouraged to submit pull requests for improvements but should not expect support or new features.</li>
<li>Installation instructions are provided for various operating systems, including Windows, macOS, and several Linux distributions, with detailed steps for compiling from source.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40854319">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Diff-pdf is a tool designed for visually comparing two PDF files, with users discussing its utility and alternatives like ImageMagick, Delta Walker, and Beyond Compare.</li>
<li>Users share scripts and configurations for integrating PDF comparison into workflows, including CI (Continuous Integration) pipelines and git, highlighting practical applications in hardware design and textbook comparisons.</li>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the strengths and limitations of different tools, with preferences split between open-source options and proprietary software based on specific features.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ersei.net/en/blog/fuse-root">Booting Linux Off of Google Drive</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A developer successfully booted Linux from Google Drive using FUSE and custom initramfs, showcasing a novel approach to cloud-native computing.</li>
<li>The process involved using google-drive-ocamlfuse to mount Google Drive and transferring Arch Linux, despite challenges like broken symlinks and slow performance.</li>
<li>This proof of concept, tested on real hardware, highlights future possibilities such as booting Linux off SSH or a Git repository, emphasizing the potential for innovative cloud-native solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40853770">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new method has been demonstrated for booting Linux directly from Google Drive, reminiscent of older network booting techniques like Sun Solaris&#39; wanboot.</li>
<li>This approach leverages modern UEFI (Unified Extensible Firmware Interface) capabilities, which can boot from HTTP, making it possible to load both the initramfs (initial RAM filesystem) and the kernel over the network.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the potential for using similar methods for devices like Raspberry Pi, which can already perform network booting using PXE (Preboot Execution Environment) and other protocols.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://hallofdreams.org/posts/hatetris/">Getting the World Record in Hatetris (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>HATETRIS, a challenging Tetris variant created by Sam Hughes, uses a deterministic algorithm to always give the player the worst possible piece.</li>
<li>The high score in HATETRIS was pushed to 86 points using Rust optimizations, heuristic beam search, and parameter tuning on AWS.</li>
<li>Key lessons include the importance of profiling, effective data structures, substantial hardware for machine learning, and combining heuristics for better results.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40851919">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers on achieving a world record in Hatetris, a Tetris variant that always gives the worst possible piece, highlighting the technical challenges and perseverance involved.</li>
<li>Participants share personal experiences, related projects, and reflections on machine learning, neural networks, and simpler methods like beam search in tackling such complex problems.</li>
<li>The conversation also touches on the enduring appeal of Tetris variations, legal challenges of creating clones, and the impact of the Tetris Effect on developers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://makojs.dev/blog/mako-open-sourced">Mako – fast, production-grade web bundler based on Rust</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Mako, a fast, production-grade front-end build tool based on Rust, is now open source and available on GitHub.</li>
<li>Developed to address build speed issues, Mako has significantly reduced build times, e.g., from 16s to 3.9s for Ant Design Pro.</li>
<li>The project, started in March 2023, was internally released at Ant Group in November 2023 and open-sourced by June 2024.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40853845">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Mako is a fast, production-grade web bundler developed in Rust, designed to enhance the development cycle by efficiently bundling web applications.</li>
<li>It aims to minimize the tradeoff of slower initial load times often associated with bundling, and plans to support the unplugin system for better compatibility with existing ecosystems.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the benefits of bundlers, such as optimal caching and code splitting, and compares Mako to other tools like esbuild and swc, noting the ongoing evolution and competition in the web bundler space.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://two-wrongs.com/code-reviews-do-find-bugs.html">Code reviews do find bugs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The 2015 Microsoft research titled &quot;Code Reviews Do Not Find Bugs&quot; claims that only about 15% of code review comments indicate possible defects, but this statistic is misleading.</li>
<li>Previous research indicates that code reviews and pair programming can find an additional 60% of defects with only a 15% increase in time investment, especially effective on small code chunks.</li>
<li>The Microsoft paper&#39;s thesis is contradicted by evidence showing code reviews&#39; effectiveness in defect detection and learning the codebase, with the real issue being the median review turnaround time of 24 hours.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40851895">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Code reviews are effective in identifying bugs, tech debt, and code smells, contributing to a more maintainable codebase.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the importance of building a supportive code review culture, including practices like using feature flags, breaking down changes into smaller parts, and setting clear expectations.</li>
<li>The debate includes various perspectives on the efficiency and necessity of code reviews, with some advocating for alternatives like pair programming and automated testing to complement or replace traditional reviews.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lunduke.locals.com/post/5812560/ladybird-web-browser-becomes-a-non-profit-with-1-million-from-github-founder">Ladybird Web Browser becomes a non-profit with $1M from GitHub Founder</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Ladybird Browser Initiative, a non-profit founded by GitHub&#39;s Chris Wanstrath and SerenityOS&#39;s Andreas Kling, aims to develop a web browser free from corporate and advertising influence.</li>
<li>With $1 million from Wanstrath and previous funding from Shopify, Ladybird plans to release an alpha version by 2026, focusing on user privacy and open standards.</li>
<li>The initiative has already hired several full-time developers and made significant progress, despite skepticism, aspiring to offer a truly independent browsing experience.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40856791">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ladybird Web Browser has transitioned to a non-profit organization with a $1M donation from GitHub Founder Chris Wanstrath.</li>
<li>Founder Andreas Kling addressed the project&#39;s future, emphasizing optimism despite doubts about developing a new browser without significant funding.</li>
<li>The team aims to support open web standards, maintain a small team for financial sustainability, and keep the project open-source under a permissive license while exploring memory-safe languages for future development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/amateur-mathematicians-find-fifth-busy-beaver-turing-machine-20240702/">With fifth busy beaver, researchers approach computation&#39;s limits</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have determined the value of BB(5), representing the complexity of a simple computer program known as the fifth busy beaver, after decades of effort.</li>
<li>The value was verified using the Coq proof assistant, ensuring mathematical accuracy, and the fifth busy beaver halts after 47,176,870 steps.</li>
<li>This achievement involved a diverse team, including contributions from both amateur mathematicians and experts, and may be the last busy beaver number determined due to the immense difficulty of BB(6).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40857041">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers are approaching the computational limits with the fifth busy beaver problem, which determines the maximum steps a Turing machine with a given number of states can take before halting.</li>
<li>A significant milestone has been achieved with a proof using Coq, a formal verification tool, marking progress in the field.</li>
<li>The fifth busy beaver number, BB(5), has been proven to be 47,176,870 steps, though challenges like the intractable six-rule machine related to the Collatz conjecture remain.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ai.meta.com/research/publications/meta-3d-gen/">Meta 3D Gen</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Meta 3D Gen (3DGen) is a cutting-edge pipeline that generates 3D assets from text in under a minute, excelling in prompt fidelity and quality.</li>
<li>It supports physically-based rendering (PBR) and generative retexturing, outperforming industry standards in both speed and visual quality.</li>
<li>3DGen integrates Meta 3D AssetGen and Meta 3D TextureGen, representing 3D objects in view, volumetric, and UV spaces.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40857517">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta is developing a new tool, Meta 3D Gen, aimed at improving VR content generation, which is currently labor-intensive.</li>
<li>Existing services like Meshy, Rodin, and Luma Labs lack the quality needed for detailed VR models, highlighting the need for better solutions.</li>
<li>The community is hopeful that Meta&#39;s solution will address issues such as poor texture quality and inefficient topology in current 3D model generation tools.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/pretzelai/pretzelai/blob/main/README.md">Adding Mistral Codestral and GPT-4o to Jupyter Notebooks</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Pretzel is a new fork of Jupyter Lab that integrates AI code generation features, addressing the lack of such extensions in the original Jupyter.</li>
<li>Key features include inline tab autocomplete, cell-level code generation, and a sidebar chat, all designed to enhance the coding experience with contextual AI assistance.</li>
<li>Pretzel aims to modernize Jupyter with additional features like real-time collaboration, SQL support, a visual analysis builder, and a VSCode-like interface, making it a comprehensive tool for data scientists.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40857009">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Pretzel is a free, open-source fork of Jupyter Lab, adding AI code generation features for a more integrated and context-aware experience.</li>
<li>Key features include inline Tab autocomplete using Mistral Codestral or GPT-4o, cell-level code generation, and a sidebar chat with context from the current cell or selected text.</li>
<li>Pretzel aims to modernize Jupyter with features like real-time collaboration, SQL support, and a visual analysis builder, distinguishing it from other AI-integrated tools like Noteable, Deepnote, Jupyter-ai, Colab, and CoCalc.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://joinup.ec.europa.eu/collection/open-source-observatory-osor/news/new-open-source-law-switzerland">Switzerland mandates software source code disclosure for public sector</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Switzerland has enacted the &quot;Federal Law on the Use of Electronic Means for the Fulfilment of Governmental Tasks&quot; (EMBAG), mandating open source software (OSS) in public sector bodies.</li>
<li>The law, led by Professor Dr. Matthias Stürmer, aims to reduce vendor lock-in, lower taxpayer costs, and enhance services through increased competition and innovation.</li>
<li>EMBAG promotes transparency and efficiency by requiring public bodies to disclose software source code, unless restricted by third-party rights or security concerns, and allows them to offer additional IT services at cost-covering remuneration.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40852084">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Switzerland&#39;s EMBAG law mandates public sector software source code disclosure, with exceptions for third-party rights or security concerns.</li>
<li>The law aims to promote open-source software (OSS) and allows public bodies to offer related services at cost-covering rates, though critics worry about potential loopholes and unclear enforcement.</li>
<li>This initiative could lead to broader OSS adoption in public services, despite challenges in auditing and compliance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://asteriskmag.com/issues/06/when-rand-made-magic-in-santa-monica">When RAND made magic in Santa Monica</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>RAND Corporation&#39;s golden era, spanning two decades, led to major advancements in nuclear strategy, satellites, systems analysis, and early computing.</li>
<li>Initially a research arm of the Air Force, RAND&#39;s success was driven by a talented, independent, and interdisciplinary team, contributing to fields like game theory, AI, and packet switching.</li>
<li>Over time, RAND&#39;s focus shifted due to strained relations with the Air Force and diversification into social policy research, leading to a decline in cutting-edge science and innovation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40849840">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>RAND Corporation was highly influential during WWII and the Cold War, similar to the peak periods of Google or Bell Labs.</li>
<li>It was a hub for prominent computer scientists and mathematicians, contributing significantly to the field now known as data science, originally termed &quot;Operations Research.&quot;</li>
<li>Despite its historical significance and innovative office designs for collaboration, RAND&#39;s modern recognition has diminished, with its legacy including both groundbreaking research and controversial strategies like those during the Vietnam War.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.brachiosoft.com/en/posts/git/">A Git story: Not so fun this time</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Linus Torvalds created Git out of necessity in 2005 after the free license for BitKeeper, a previously used version control system, was revoked.</li>
<li>Git&#39;s development was inspired by Monotone but aimed to be simpler and faster, quickly gaining contributors and popularity, especially within the Ruby community.</li>
<li>GitHub, launched in 2008, significantly boosted Git&#39;s adoption, leading to its current dominance in the version control market with a 94% share.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40849363">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses the history and evolution of version control systems, particularly focusing on Git and its predecessors like BitKeeper and Mercurial.</li>
<li>It highlights the dominance of Git in the market, with a 94% share according to a 2022 Stack Overflow survey, and debates whether any future system could replace it.</li>
<li>The conversation includes personal anecdotes and opinions on various version control systems, emphasizing Git&#39;s widespread adoption and integration into modern development workflows.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/latino/-great-sadness-venezuela-first-andean-country-lose-glaciers-rcna153784">Venezuela is first Andean country to lose all of its glaciers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Venezuela has become the first Andean country to lose all its glaciers, with the Humboldt Glacier in the Sierra Nevada now too small to be classified as a glacier.</li>
<li>The International Climate and Cryosphere Initiative (ICCI) confirmed this status, noting that Venezuela had six glaciers in the Sierra Nevada, but only the Humboldt Glacier remained by 2011.</li>
<li>Scientists attribute the glacier&#39;s disappearance to climate change and rising global temperatures, with a 2023 study predicting that 83% of the world&#39;s glaciers could disappear by 2100 if temperatures continue to rise.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40850313">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Venezuela is the first Andean country to lose all its glaciers, with the glacier surface shrinking from 2.317 square kilometers in 1952 to just 0.046 square kilometers in 2019.</li>
<li>This drastic reduction underscores the severe impact of climate change on the environment.</li>
<li>The loss has prompted discussions on the accuracy of these figures and the broader emotional and environmental implications of glacial retreat.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Why is Chile so long?" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Why%20is%20Chile%20so%20long%3F&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20July%202%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/07/02</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-07-02T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-07-01]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/07/01&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-07-01</h1>
<h2><a href="https://pikimov.com/">I created an After Effects alternative</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Pikimov is a newly launched web-based motion design and video editor, inspired by Photopea, and serves as a free alternative to After Effects.</li>
<li>It requires no signup, keeps files on the user&#39;s machine, and ensures that projects are not used for AI training.</li>
<li>The creator has a history of developing VJ software for platforms like the Game Boy Advance, Playstation 2, and Raspberry Pi.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40843867">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Pikimov is a new, free, web-based motion design and video editor created as an alternative to Adobe After Effects, requiring no signup or cloud uploads.</li>
<li>The tool has received positive feedback for its potential to challenge Adobe&#39;s dominance, with users suggesting improvements in frame rate limits, bug reporting, and keyframe handling.</li>
<li>Currently, Pikimov supports only Chrome and Edge due to specific web APIs, with future plans to add community features and possibly monetize the app.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.qualys.com/2024/07/01/cve-2024-6387/regresshion.txt">RegreSSHion: RCE in OpenSSH&#39;s server, on glibc-based Linux systems</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A critical vulnerability (CVE-2024-6387) in OpenSSH&#39;s server on glibc-based Linux systems allows remote code execution (RCE) due to a signal handler race condition.</li>
<li>The issue, a regression of CVE-2006-5051, affects OpenSSH versions 3.4p1, 4.2p1, and 9.2p1, and involves exploiting the SIGALRM handler to cause heap corruption and execute arbitrary code.</li>
<li>Mitigation includes applying patches that move async-signal-unsafe code out of the SIGALRM handler or setting <code>LoginGraceTime</code> to 0, though the latter may cause denial of service.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40843778">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Remote Code Execution (RCE) vulnerability was discovered in OpenSSH&#39;s server on glibc-based Linux systems, potentially allowing attackers to gain remote root access.</li>
<li>The fix for this vulnerability was implemented by moving unsafe code from the signal handler to the listener process, making it difficult to backport.</li>
<li>The issue primarily affects 32-bit systems, with exploitation on 64-bit systems believed possible but not yet demonstrated; various distributions have already released patches.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.pipes.digital/docs">Pipes: A spiritual successor to Yahoo Pipes</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Pipes is a visual programming editor for feeds, allowing users to fetch, create, and manipulate feeds using blocks, similar to Yahoo! Pipes.</li>
<li>It supports various input formats, including RSS, Atom, JSON, HTML, and text files, and offers a range of blocks for different feed operations like filtering, merging, and extracting content.</li>
<li>Pipes CE is a free and open-source software (FOSS) under the AGPL license, available on Github, and supports integrations with popular sites like Twitter, YouTube, and Vimeo.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40841980">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Pipes, a project inspired by Yahoo Pipes, recently underwent updates to improve stability, including a shift from text to RSS objects for data transport between blocks.</li>
<li>Server upgrades and reconfiguration of threads and puma workers were implemented to address issues and bottlenecks.</li>
<li>A user suggestion to add a block for AI-generated summaries or images via POST requests is being considered, with some foundational blocks already in place.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mlops.systems/posts/2024-07-01-full-finetuned-model-evaluation.html">My finetuned models beat OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses the evaluation metrics for assessing the performance of finetuned language models (LLMs) in extracting structured data from press releases, with a focus on accuracy.</li>
<li>Finetuned models, including TinyLlama, Mistral, and Solar LLM, generally outperformed OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4 and GPT-4 Turbo in accuracy, despite the complexity and slow pace of evaluations.</li>
<li>The evaluations highlighted the need for a better system to manage the complexity and maintenance, with future steps including non-accuracy-related tests and exploring model serving.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40843848">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Fine-tuned models can outperform general models like OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4 in specific tasks, such as data extraction, creative summarization, question answering, and classification.</li>
<li>The success of fine-tuned models hinges on high-quality training data, making them effective for niche information extraction and accessible to tech enthusiasts.</li>
<li>Fine-tuning smaller models, such as Llama 3 8B, can be more efficient and cost-effective, but using model responses to train new models may violate terms of service for major LLM providers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/cities-need-more-trees/">Cities need more trees</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Johannesburg, once barren, transformed into the &quot;greenest city in the world&quot; after planting millions of trees to combat dust from gold extraction.</li>
<li>Tree planting in Johannesburg was unevenly distributed due to Apartheid, highlighting socioeconomic disparities.</li>
<li>Urban trees provide significant benefits, including reducing the &quot;heat island&quot; effect, acting as sound barriers, enhancing aesthetics, increasing biodiversity, and encouraging outdoor activities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40843720">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Cities are increasingly planting trees and promoting green roofs to combat heat stress and improve urban livability.</li>
<li>Utrecht, Netherlands, and Zurich, Switzerland, are leading examples, while U.S. cities like Portland, OR, have green mandates, and Salt Lake City is exploring xeriscaping.</li>
<li>Trees offer significant benefits, such as cooling urban areas, improving air quality, and enhancing overall livability, despite challenges like private property development leading to tree removal.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ladybird.org/">Welcome to Ladybird</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ladybird is an independent web browser developed by a non-profit, focusing on performance, stability, and security, with an Alpha release planned for 2026.</li>
<li>Initially an HTML viewer for SerenityOS, it now supports Linux, macOS, and other Unix-like systems, and is built entirely from scratch without using code from other browsers.</li>
<li>The project is funded by sponsorships and donations, with no ads or user monetization, and is currently developed by a team of four full-time engineers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40845951">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ladybird, initially an HTML renderer for SerenityOS, is now evolving into a cross-platform browser project.</li>
<li>The project has received a notable $1,000,000 donation from GitHub co-founder Chris Wanstrath, indicating strong financial backing.</li>
<li>The team plans to release an alpha version by 2026, emphasizing modularity and adherence to modern web standards.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Postzegelcode">Postzegelcode</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A postzegelcode is a nine-character code used in the Netherlands as a handwritten alternative to postage stamps, purchased online from PostNL.</li>
<li>Introduced in 2013, the code must be written on mail within five days and has 78.8 trillion possible combinations, making it secure against guessing.</li>
<li>As of December 2020, 590,000 people used postzegelcodes, which now cost the same as traditional stamps.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40839418">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around the use of digital postage codes, known as &quot;postzegelcode,&quot; which can be written on envelopes instead of using traditional stamps.</li>
<li>Various countries, including Germany, Denmark, Norway, and Sweden, have implemented similar systems, allowing users to purchase postage online and write a code on their mail.</li>
<li>The system is praised for its convenience, especially for those who do not frequently send physical mail, as it eliminates the need for physical stamps and adapts to changing postal rates.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/supreme-court-trump-capitol-riot-immunity-2dc0d1c2368d404adc0054151490f542">Supreme Court rules ex-presidents have immunity for official acts</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Supreme Court extended the delay in Donald Trump&#39;s criminal case regarding the 2020 election, reducing the likelihood of a trial before the November election.</li>
<li>In a 6-3 ruling, the court&#39;s conservative majority granted former presidents broad immunity from prosecution for official acts, complicating the prosecution&#39;s case and requiring further analysis at the trial court level.</li>
<li>The decision underscores the court&#39;s significant influence on the upcoming election, with Chief Justice John Roberts emphasizing immunity for official acts and Justice Sonia Sotomayor dissenting, arguing it undermines the principle that no one is above the law.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40847963">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Supreme Court has ruled that ex-presidents have immunity for official acts, sparking debate over potential abuses of power versus the need for presidential protection.</li>
<li>The ruling specifies that immunity applies to actions within constitutional authority but not to unofficial acts, raising concerns about accountability for serious crimes.</li>
<li>Critics, including Justice Sotomayor, worry this decision could impact ongoing and future legal cases involving former presidents.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.alvarorevuelta.com/posts/fft-polynomials">Convolutions, Fast Fourier Transform and polynomials (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Traditional polynomial multiplication has (O(n^2)) complexity, making it inefficient for large polynomials.</li>
<li>The Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) reduces polynomial multiplication complexity to (O(n \log n)) by converting the problem to the frequency domain.</li>
<li>The FFT-based method involves converting polynomials to the frequency domain, multiplying them, and converting the result back, significantly improving efficiency for high-degree polynomials.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40840396">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers around the use of Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) for polynomial multiplication, highlighting its efficiency compared to naive methods.</li>
<li>Key insights include the importance of numerical precision in FFT calculations and the historical context of FFT&#39;s development for polynomial multiplication.</li>
<li>The conversation also touches on practical applications, such as error correction, signal processing, and zero-knowledge cryptography, where FFT-based methods are particularly beneficial.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.gabornyeki.com/2024-07-my-python-code-is-a-neural-network/">My Python code is a neural network</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses embedding programs in recurrent neural networks (RNNs) and how trained RNNs can outperform hand-written algorithms.</li>
<li>It provides a detailed example of detecting program code in messages, comparing simple decision rules, a hand-written algorithm, and an RNN-based approach.</li>
<li>The post highlights the advantages of RNNs, such as encoding state machines, using trainable activation functions, and handling complex tasks with data-driven discipline.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40845304">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the construction of a neural network using Python but lacks details on testing and obtaining training data, which are crucial for ensuring the model&#39;s generalization to unseen inputs.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the Universal Approximation Theorem, which states that neural networks can represent any function to a desired level of accuracy, but emphasizes that learning these approximations is not guaranteed.</li>
<li>There is a debate on whether Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs) are being replaced by transformers, with some arguing that RNNs still have unique advantages, such as constant memory usage, which transformers lack.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40846428">Who is hiring? (July 2024)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40846428">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Various companies are hiring for multiple roles, including remote, onsite, and hybrid positions, across different locations and industries.</li>
<li>Notable companies include Apple, Figma, Charge Robotics, and SmileID, offering positions such as Senior Software Engineer, Senior/Staff Security Engineer, and Senior Frontend Engineer.</li>
<li>Opportunities span across the globe, with some companies offering visa sponsorship and roles in emerging technologies like AI, machine learning, and full-stack development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://carbon-steel.github.io/jekyll/update/2024/06/19/abstractions.html">Programmers Should Never Trust Anyone, Not Even Themselves</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Programmers should maintain a healthy level of skepticism, as writing and verifying code correctness is inherently challenging and often impossible.</li>
<li>Abstractions, while simplifying complex systems, can fail and lead to issues like performance degradation or undefined behavior, as highlighted by Joel Spolsky’s Law of Leaky Abstractions.</li>
<li>To mitigate unknown issues, programmers should verify information, test beliefs, and measure the impact of code changes, while continuously learning about new platforms, languages, tools, and technologies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40842867">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers on the importance of formal verification in programming, emphasizing that programmers should not trust anyone, including themselves, without proof.</li>
<li>Formal verification, though complex and costly, provides stronger guarantees of correctness compared to unit tests, which only cover specific examples.</li>
<li>The debate highlights the trade-offs between the rigor of formal verification and the practicality of unit tests, suggesting that the choice depends on the project&#39;s requirements and resources.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ericpfahl.com/from-pattern-matching-to-unification/">Unification in Elixir</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Unification in Elixir extends pattern matching by allowing variables on both sides of an equation, solving symbolic equations and producing substitution mappings.</li>
<li>Unlike pattern matching, unification can handle partially known values, making it a powerful tool for logic programming in Elixir.</li>
<li>The unification algorithm involves walking terms, testing equivalence, handling variables, and recursively unifying list elements, simplifying variable assignments through substitution.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40840315">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article compares the efficiency of unification algorithms in type inference, focusing on algorithm W and algorithm J.</li>
<li>Algorithm W, used in Hindley-Milner type inference, is less efficient and more error-prone due to the need for composing substitutions.</li>
<li>Algorithm J, which employs a union-find data structure for destructive unification, is simpler and more efficient, with additional insights on unification in pattern matching and compiled pattern matching using decision trees.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/">Google Arts and Culture site I didn&#39;t know existed</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google Arts &amp; Culture offers a wide range of virtual tours and interactive experiences, allowing users to explore art, history, and culture from around the world.</li>
<li>Highlights include virtual tours of famous museums, augmented reality (AR) experiences, and interactive games that make learning about art and culture engaging and accessible.</li>
<li>Special features include the ability to explore Van Gogh&#39;s library, take a 3D tour of Vermeer&#39;s paintings, and participate in a K-Pop dance challenge in collaboration with the V&amp;A Museum.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40840699">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google Arts and Culture is a lesser-known but significant project by Google, offering curated cultural content from around the world.</li>
<li>Users appreciate its high-resolution images and unique features, such as the ability to zoom in closely on artworks and explore various cultural projects.</li>
<li>The platform has been active since 2011 and continues to be a valuable resource for art and culture enthusiasts, despite concerns about the longevity of Google projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.09490">Newswire: A large-scale structured database of a century of historical news</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have created a comprehensive archive of U.S. newswire content from 1878 to 1977 using a deep learning pipeline on image scans from local newspapers.</li>
<li>The dataset includes 2.7 million unique public domain articles, georeferenced, tagged by topic, and linked to Wikipedia, providing valuable information for computational linguistics, social science, and digital humanities research.</li>
<li>The project involved transcribing 138 million structured article texts and using a neural bi-encoder model to de-duplicate articles, ensuring only public domain content was included.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40839830">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A comprehensive database of historical news up to 1978 has been created, reflecting changes in copyright laws, and is available on GitHub, though currently empty.</li>
<li>Users have identified OCR (Optical Character Recognition) errors in the data, underscoring persistent challenges in digitizing historical texts.</li>
<li>The project, despite its issues, is lauded for its scholarly value, with raw scans accessible through the Library of Congress digital collection.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="I created an After Effects alternative" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=I%20created%20an%20After%20Effects%20alternative&subheading=Monday%2C%20July%201%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/07/01</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-30]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/30&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-30</h1>
<h2><a href="https://10maurycy10.github.io/projects/motion_sensor_hacking/">Inside a $1 radar motion sensor</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The RCWL-0516 microwave motion sensor is a low-cost radar module, priced under a dollar, designed for motion detection within approximately 5 meters.</li>
<li>It uses the BISS0001 chip, typically for infrared motion sensing, and operates by mixing transmitted and received signals to detect motion through millivolt-level changes.</li>
<li>The sensor&#39;s performance is variable, working well indoors but inconsistently outdoors, and can be modified for improved range and consistency by using a second module as a receiver.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40834349">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A $1 radar motion sensor can detect subtle movements, such as breathing, using ESP32 boards and works through walls.</li>
<li>By 2024, AI/NPU laptops with Wi-Fi 7 will integrate RF radar and on-device inference to identify human activity.</li>
<li>For DIY projects, a $3 ESP chip can be combined with these sensors for cost-effective solutions, with minimal safety concerns due to the use of non-ionizing radio waves.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/overleaf/overleaf">Overleaf: An open-source online real-time collaborative LaTeX editor</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Overleaf is an open-source, real-time collaborative LaTeX editor available both as a hosted service and for local deployment.</li>
<li>Overleaf Server Pro offers enhanced features for labs and workplaces, including security (SSO with LDAP or SAML) and advanced collaboration tools.</li>
<li>The project uses Docker for deployment, with detailed build instructions and contributions guided by the GNU Affero General Public License, version 3.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40832930">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Overleaf is an open-source, real-time collaborative LaTeX editor, widely used in academia for remote collaboration on papers.</li>
<li>Users appreciate its ease of use, features like commenting and PDF synchronization, and Git integration, though some find Git challenging for synchronous work.</li>
<li>There are requests for additional features such as Pandoc support for Markdown, highlighting areas for potential improvement.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/rauchg/status/1806385778064564622">Chrome is adding <code>window.ai</code> – a Gemini Nano AI model right inside the browser</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Chrome is integrating <code>window.ai</code>, a Gemini Nano AI model, directly into the browser, enhancing its AI capabilities.</li>
<li>This integration is compatible with the AI Software Development Kit (SDK), facilitating easier development and implementation of AI features.</li>
<li>This update signifies a significant step towards more advanced AI functionalities being natively supported in web browsers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40834600">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Chrome is integrating <code>window.ai</code>, a Gemini Nano AI model, directly into the browser, emphasizing local on-device processing for enhanced privacy and security.</li>
<li>The API is experimental and currently behind a flag, sparking discussions about its implications for privacy, security, and future web standards.</li>
<li>While some see potential for enhanced web applications, others are concerned about browser compatibility and potential misuse, with some users preferring simpler browsers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/poundifdef/SmoothMQ">Drop-In SQS Replacement Based on SQLite</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>An open-source, API-compatible replacement for Amazon SQS (Simple Queue Service) has been created, written in Go and distributed as a single binary using SQLite for storage.</li>
<li>The solution offers advanced features like searching, scheduling, observability, and rate limiting, and is compatible with existing SQS applications by simply changing the endpoint.</li>
<li>It supports multiple protocols (AMQP, PubSub) and can be adapted to different storage backends (RocksDB, Postgres), with future plans for distributed and autoscale functionality, and aims to offer a cost-effective hosted queue system.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40837610">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An open-source, API-compatible replacement for Amazon SQS has been developed using Go and SQLite, offering features like searching, scheduling, observability, and rate limiting without requiring app rewrites.</li>
<li>The solution supports Celery, provides better message visibility than SQS, and is pluggable with potential backends like RocksDB or Postgres, capable of implementing multiple protocols.</li>
<li>It is easy to deploy as a single Go binary, with future plans for distributed and autoscale functionality, and feedback is encouraged.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lcamtuf.substack.com/p/weekend-projects-getting-silly-with">Weekend projects: getting silly with C</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40835274">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around undefined behavior (UB) in the C programming language, particularly the misconception that UB can &quot;time travel&quot; or affect code execution retroactively.</li>
<li>The C23 standard includes a footnote clarifying that UB cannot time-travel, addressing confusion caused by previous blog posts and compiler behaviors.</li>
<li>The conversation also touches on various quirky and advanced C programming techniques, such as unconventional uses of switch statements and the implications of volatile keyword semantics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bristol.ac.uk/news/2024/june/prehistoric-pompeii.html">Trilobites killed by volcanic ash</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Exceptionally preserved trilobite fossils from the Cambrian period were discovered in Morocco, revealing previously unknown anatomical details.</li>
<li>The fossils, preserved by volcanic ash over 500 million years ago, show four pairs of head appendages instead of the previously thought three, providing new insights into trilobite feeding mechanisms.</li>
<li>High-resolution X-ray micro-tomography (XRµCT) was used to create detailed 3D models, highlighting the potential of volcanic ash deposits for uncovering well-preserved fossils.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40833645">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Palaeontologists have identified over 20,000 species of trilobites, with sizes ranging from less than two millimeters to over 90 centimeters.</li>
<li>The website trilobites.info is praised for its simple, information-rich design reminiscent of early internet sites, focusing on content rather than modern web design trends.</li>
<li>The discovery of well-preserved &#39;Pompei&#39; trilobites, which are not flattened or deformed, provides significant insights into the ancient past, showcasing every leg arranged as it was in life.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/opendns-suspends-service-in-france-due-to-canal-piracy-blocking-order-240629/">OpenDNS Suspends Service in France Due to Canal+ Piracy Blocking Order</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A French court has mandated Google, Cloudflare, and Cisco to block DNS records that circumvent existing pirate site blockades, following a request from Canal+.</li>
<li>In response, Cisco has withdrawn its OpenDNS service from France, highlighting the impact of legal actions on internet services.</li>
<li>This court order is part of Canal+&#39;s broader anti-piracy campaign, which previously required ISPs to block over 100 pirate sports streaming sites, pushing users to third-party DNS servers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40835117">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenDNS has suspended its service in France due to a court order mandating the blocking of piracy sites, igniting a debate on DNS neutrality and legal compliance.</li>
<li>The compliance of major companies like Google with such orders raises concerns about setting a precedent for DNS manipulation and potential government overreach.</li>
<li>Users may seek alternative DNS providers or VPNs to circumvent these restrictions, highlighting the technical challenges and implications of enforcing DNS blocks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nodicenoglory.com/2021/06/23/the-operational-wargame-series-the-best-game-not-in-stores-now/">The Operational Wargame Series: The best game not in stores now (2021)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Operational Wargame Series (OWS) is a tabletop game simulating combat from 2025 to 2050, developed by Retired Col Tim Barrick and the USMC Warfighting Lab (USMCWL).</li>
<li>OWS features two modules: Assassin’s Mace (INDO-PACOM theater) and Zapad (European theater), using a hex and counter system familiar to hobby gamers.</li>
<li>Currently, OWS is only available through the US Marine Corps Association for DoD offices, with no plans for commercial release, despite its potential appeal to hobby gamers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40833327">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Operational Wargame Series is known for its detailed and time-consuming nature, often taking days or weeks to complete turns.</li>
<li>Despite digital advancements, traditional board wargames remain popular for their tactile and hands-on approach, with games like Command: Modern Operations and Rule the Waves recommended for enthusiasts.</li>
<li>Military organizations continue to use manual wargaming for training purposes, highlighting the importance of comprehending all variables in strategic planning.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://help.figma.com/hc/en-us/articles/17725942479127-Control-AI-features-and-content-training-settings">Figma defaults to train AI models on personal data</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40835793">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Figma defaults to using personal data for training AI models, sparking privacy concerns among users.</li>
<li>Microsoft CEO&#39;s comments suggest that powerful organizations can access internet data for AI training, raising ethical and legal questions, especially under GDPR.</li>
<li>Users are advised to disable the content training toggle by August 15, 2024, to prevent their data from being used.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/how-coffee-helped-the-union-caffeinate-their-way-victory-civil-war-180984502/">Coffee helped the Union in the Civil War</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>During the Civil War, the Union faced a significant coffee shortage, crucial for soldiers&#39; morale and energy, with imports dropping by 40% by 1862.</li>
<li>Liberia, under President Stephen Allen Benson, began exporting coffee to the Union, starting with a 6,000-pound shipment in August 1862, helping to fill the gap caused by the Union&#39;s blockade of Southern ports.</li>
<li>The partnership between Liberian coffee farmers and Northern abolitionists, along with advice from Philadelphia merchant Edward Morris, boosted coffee production, making Liberian coffee vital to the Union&#39;s war effort and contributing to their success.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40834345">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Coffee was a crucial stimulant for Union soldiers during the Civil War, significantly impacting their efforts.</li>
<li>The South used other stimulants like tea, tobacco, and yaupon, but coffee&#39;s influence on the Union was particularly notable.</li>
<li>The discussion underscores the complex relationship people have with caffeine, balancing its productivity benefits with potential dependency and well-being concerns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/06/29/mit-robotics-pioneer-rodney-brooks-thinks-people-are-vastly-overestimating-generative-ai/">Rodney Brooks on limitations of generative AI</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Rodney Brooks, a renowned MIT robotics pioneer, believes that generative AI is often overhyped and cannot match human capabilities.</li>
<li>Brooks argues that AI should focus on specific, solvable problems rather than attempting to replicate human abilities, citing inefficiencies in using generative AI for tasks like warehouse robotics.</li>
<li>He also notes that technological growth is not always exponential, using the iPod&#39;s storage capacity as an example, and suggests that while Large Language Models (LLMs) can assist with tasks like eldercare, they are not a universal solution for all AI challenges.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40835588">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Rodney Brooks discusses the limitations of generative AI, emphasizing that while it can perform specific tasks, it cannot match the full range of human capabilities.</li>
<li>Brooks suggests limiting the scope of AI applications and incorporating manual overrides for unexpected situations, predicting that the business case for exponentially scaling large language models (LLMs) is weak.</li>
<li>The discussion includes analogies comparing LLMs to the iPod, suggesting that like the iPod&#39;s evolution into the iPhone, future AI advancements may integrate more complex functionalities rather than just scaling up existing capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/dev-rejects-cve-severity-makes-his-github-repo-read-only/">Dev rejects CVE severity, makes his GitHub repo read-only</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fedor Indutny has made his popular open-source project, &#39;node-ip&#39;, read-only on GitHub due to a disputed CVE (Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures) report.</li>
<li>This incident underscores a growing issue where open-source developers are bombarded with questionable or bogus CVE reports, causing unnecessary panic and frustration.</li>
<li>The misuse of the CVE system, which is meant for ethical vulnerability reporting, is complicating the lives of developers and contributing to burnout.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40837791">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A developer made his GitHub repository read-only after disputing the severity of a Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) report.</li>
<li>The incident emphasizes that security should be considered as an emergent property of the entire software system, not just individual components.</li>
<li>The situation also highlights the challenges and burnout faced by open-source maintainers, who often receive little material reward for their efforts.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/patagonia-cx-staff-told-to-relocate-or-leave-california-2024-6">Patagonia gave its staff 3 days to decide to relocate or quit</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Patagonia has given 90 customer-service employees three days to decide whether to relocate to one of seven US locations or leave the company, aiming to improve team culture and support business needs.</li>
<li>Affected staff were informed via a town hall meeting and offered $4,000 for relocation costs and extra paid time off, with a deadline of September 30 for those unwilling to relocate.</li>
<li>The decision impacts 90 of 255 customer experience (CX) staff in the US, with some employees expressing disappointment over the perceived shift away from the company&#39;s employee-centric values.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40834305">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Patagonia has given its staff three days to decide whether to relocate or quit due to overstaffing, sparking debate on corporate ethics and employee treatment.</li>
<li>Critics argue this is a disguised layoff, pointing out the generous severance but insufficient $4K relocation package, and the short decision window.</li>
<li>The move is seen as potentially beneficial for H1B visa holders, but has received mixed reactions from employees and observers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://luggagelosers.com/">A live ranking of airlines by how much luggage they are losing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>LuggageLosers.com provides a live ranking of airlines by lost luggage, updated hourly using social media mentions and historical data.</li>
<li>The site tracks all major airlines, adjusting for size differences, and aims to help travelers choose airlines with better luggage handling.</li>
<li>Current top airlines for lost luggage include Aer Lingus, Air India, and WestJet Airlines, with regional and country-specific data also available.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40838290">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A live ranking of airlines by luggage loss reveals Aer Lingus has a 1 in 57 chance of losing luggage, Delta 1 in 497, and Air France 1 in 1,256.</li>
<li>Nationally, India has a 1 in 97 chance, the US 1 in 497, and Japan 1 in 7,734, with variations influenced by check-in airports, airline policies, and national regulations.</li>
<li>The data is sourced from social media posts, raising accuracy concerns, while the US Department of Transportation (DOT) provides more reliable data on mishandled luggage.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.hackster.io/news/an-analog-network-of-resistors-promises-machine-learning-without-a-processor-researchers-say-d9cb0655b7a0">An Analog Network of Resistors Promises Machine Learning Without a Processor</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers at the University of Pennsylvania have created an analog machine learning network using resistors, aiming for more energy-efficient AI.</li>
<li>This new approach eliminates the need for a traditional processor, utilizing a non-linear learning metamaterial based on transistors for complex computations.</li>
<li>Although the current prototype consumes more power than modern digital accelerators, it shows promise in tasks like image classification and XOR operations, with potential for improved efficiency as it scales.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40836183">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers are exploring an analog network of transistors, constrained to the ohmic regime, to perform machine learning tasks without traditional processors.</li>
<li>This approach could potentially offer more efficient, parallel operations compared to digital systems, though practical implementation challenges like maintaining charge on gate capacitors remain.</li>
<li>The concept is generating interest due to its potential to revolutionize neural network computations by leveraging analog components, which could lead to significant advancements in energy efficiency and processing speed.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Inside a $1 radar motion sensor" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Inside%20a%20%241%20radar%20motion%20sensor&subheading=Sunday%2C%20June%2030%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/30</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-30T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-29]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/29&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-29</h1>
<h2><a href="https://pmarca.substack.com/p/the-true-story-as-best-i-can-remember">The story, as best I can remember, of the origin of Mosaic and Netscape [video]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40825033">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A video discussing the origins of Mosaic and Netscape has sparked a forum thread where users share experiences and historical corrections.</li>
<li>A former Project Lead for the Spyglass browser team clarifies that Spyglass Mosaic was developed from scratch, not using licensed Mosaic code.</li>
<li>The thread features nostalgic memories of early internet experiences, including the use of Mosaic, Netscape, and other early web technologies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/WerWolv/ImHex">Imhex: A hex editor for reverse engineers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>ImHex is a feature-rich hex editor designed for reverse engineers, programmers, and users who work late hours, offering a modern interface and extensive functionality.</li>
<li>Key features include a custom C++-like pattern language, integrated disassembler, data analyzer, and YARA rule support, making it a versatile tool for various data manipulation tasks.</li>
<li>The tool supports multiple operating systems (Windows, macOS, Linux) and requires minimal hardware resources, with source code and documentation available for further customization and contribution.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40828493">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>ImHex is a hex editor favored by reverse engineers for its file templates, data type interpretation, and performance with large files.</li>
<li>It is free, open-source, and often compared to 010 Editor, though some users prefer simpler alternatives like Hex Fiend or HxD.</li>
<li>Despite some bugs in its imgui UI and installation issues, ImHex is valued for its capabilities, with discussions highlighting the necessity of OpenGL for modern hardware rendering.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mbuffett.com/posts/programming-advice-younger-self/">A bunch of programming advice I&#39;d give to myself 15 years ago</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fix recurring issues by addressing root causes, such as ensuring UI updates in iOS development happen on the main thread to avoid crashes.</li>
<li>Balance quality and speed based on the environment; prioritize speed in less critical settings and correctness in high-stakes scenarios.</li>
<li>Sharpen your tools by becoming proficient with your editor, OS, shell, and browser dev tools to significantly boost productivity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40829607">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Key advice for programmers includes not taking work personally, understanding the business context, and focusing on problem-solving rather than just technical issues.</li>
<li>Emphasis on practical tips such as simplifying code, prioritizing developer velocity, and balancing between shipping fast and maintaining code quality.</li>
<li>Encouragement to learn functional programming, understand state machines, and make informed decisions on when to build versus buy solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2024/06/28/fxios/">How to waste bandwidth, battery power, and annoy sysadmins</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses inefficiencies in web browsers, specifically highlighting how Firefox for iOS repeatedly requests the same links and incorrectly requests favicons, leading to unnecessary bandwidth and battery usage.</li>
<li>This behavior causes strain on servers and can be particularly annoying for system administrators who manage these servers.</li>
<li>The example provided shows multiple identical requests and an incorrect favicon request, illustrating the problem and its impact on server resources.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40828203">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around the performance and usability of Firefox on iOS and Android, with mixed opinions on its efficiency and features.</li>
<li>Key points include the limitations imposed by iOS requiring browsers to use WebKit, and the recent allowance of third-party browser engines in the EU since iOS 17.4.</li>
<li>Users highlight issues such as slow performance, bugs, and the importance of ad-blocking plugins like uBlock Origin, which significantly enhance the browsing experience on mobile devices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://memorycorruption.net/posts/rce-lua-factorio/">Bytecode Breakdown: Unraveling Factorio&#39;s Lua Security Flaws</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A vulnerability in Factorio&#39;s Lua implementation allowed malicious servers to execute arbitrary code on clients, patched in versions below 1.1.101.</li>
<li>Factorio&#39;s Lua, crucial for game logic and mods, is exposed to network risks due to its deterministic lockstep multiplayer mode.</li>
<li>The exploit path involves hosting a server with malicious Lua code, leading to memory leaks and remote code execution through Lua bytecode manipulation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40830005">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers on the security risks of executing Lua bytecode in the game Factorio, highlighting the need for better documentation and sandboxing.</li>
<li>Factorio has disabled bytecode loading and restricted the debug library due to security concerns, with suggestions for a &quot;Reduced Security Mode&quot; toggle for advanced users.</li>
<li>Participants recommend various security measures, such as using VM isolation, avoiding bytecode in non-embedded systems, and ensuring bytecode verification, similar to Java and .NET environments.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://matduggan.com/a-eulogy-for-devops/">A Eulogy for DevOps</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>DevOps, initially promising to streamline software development and operations, often led to centralized risk and delays due to communication and coordination challenges.</li>
<li>The shift towards DevOps aimed to reduce dependency on specialized technical staff and facilitate last-minute changes, but it resulted in complex and costly systems, despite the introduction of containers and SaaS solutions like Datadog.</li>
<li>The industry is now pivoting towards Platform Engineering and simpler workflows, moving away from complex technologies like Kubernetes to focus on simplicity, stability, and realistic growth expectations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40826236">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses the perceived decline of DevOps, highlighting how the initial goals of speed and efficiency often led to chaotic and unsustainable practices.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the shift towards Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) and trunk-based development, which aims to streamline the deployment process and reduce risks.</li>
<li>The conversation reflects on the evolving roles within tech teams, such as Site Reliability Engineers (SREs) and platform engineers, indicating a move away from traditional DevOps roles.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://visualstudiomagazine.com/Articles/2024/06/27/eclipse-theia-ide.aspx">Open source &#39;Eclipse Theia IDE&#39; exits beta to challenge Visual Studio Code</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Eclipse Foundation&#39;s Theia IDE, after seven years of development, is now generally available, positioning itself as a &quot;true open-source alternative&quot; to Microsoft&#39;s Visual Studio Code (VS Code).</li>
<li>Theia shares much of VS Code&#39;s technology, including the Monaco editor, Language Server Protocol (LSP), and Debug Adapter Protocol (DAP), and supports the same extensions via the Open VSX Registry.</li>
<li>Theia emphasizes flexibility, privacy, and a vibrant open-source community, with contributions from major companies like Ericsson, IBM, and Google, and allows extensive customization without forking the code, suitable for both desktop and cloud IDEs.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40825146">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Open source &#39;Eclipse Theia IDE&#39; has exited beta, positioning itself as a competitor to Visual Studio Code (VS Code).</li>
<li>Users highlight Theia&#39;s extensibility and web browser support, contrasting it with concerns over Microsoft&#39;s control and limited extensibility in VS Code.</li>
<li>Theia aims to offer a customizable IDE framework, providing an open-source alternative with potential benefits over VS Code&#39;s more restrictive API.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://words.filippo.io/dispatches/xaes-256-gcm/">The XAES-256-GCM extended-nonce AEAD</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>XAES-256-GCM is a new AEAD (Authenticated Encryption with Associated Data) algorithm with 256-bit keys and 192-bit nonces, designed for safety, FIPS 140 compliance, and easy implementation.</li>
<li>It is an extended-nonce construction on top of AES-256-GCM, requiring three AES-256 calls per message, with one precomputable, and is supported by common cryptographic libraries and the OpenSSL API.</li>
<li>Third-party implementations are available for .NET 8+, pyca/cryptography, and the Web Cryptography API, with the Go reference implementation being under 100 lines using standard libraries.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40826683">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The XAES-256-GCM extended-nonce AEAD (Authenticated Encryption with Associated Data) is a new cryptographic design that enhances nonce and key management for AES-GCM, addressing nonce reuse issues.</li>
<li>This design uses AES-CBC (Cipher Block Chaining) to derive keys and employs a 192-bit nonce, improving security by preventing nonce collisions, which are catastrophic in standard AES-GCM.</li>
<li>The implementation is currently available in the C2SP reference library, but not yet in the Go standard library, highlighting ongoing development and interest in the cryptographic community.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://rubenerd.com/all-web-content-is-freeware/">All web &quot;content&quot; is freeware</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft’s CEO of AI, Suleyman, in a CNBC interview, claimed that web content has been considered fair use since the 90s, likening it to freeware, which raises legal questions.</li>
<li>The interview discussed the unsustainable financial model of AI and the public&#39;s perception of AI-generated content as low quality.</li>
<li>Generative AI vendors argue that their outputs are fair game, but unlike search engines, chatbots do not link to their sources, making their outputs unreliable and indicating a potential AI bubble.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40828441">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Web content is generally considered copyrighted unless explicitly stated as public domain, making the claim that all web content is freeware legally dubious.</li>
<li>Authors of open-source code are encouraged to add restrictions to prevent their code from being used to train AI, potentially enabling legal action against companies like Microsoft for unauthorized use.</li>
<li>There is ongoing debate about how AI training intersects with copyright laws, with some arguing that current practices fall under fair use exemptions and that regulation should balance protection with innovation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/posts/pay-phone-bandit-baffled-fbi">The &#39;pay phone bandit&#39; who baffled the FBI in the &#39;80s</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In the 1980s, James Clark, known as the &quot;Pay Phone Bandit,&quot; stole up to $1 million in quarters from pay phones across 30 states using custom locksmith tools.</li>
<li>Despite extensive FBI efforts, Clark eluded capture until 1985 when an informer tipped off authorities, leading to his arrest in 1988 and a three-year sentence.</li>
<li>Clark&#39;s unique method involved checking if coin boxes were full and picking locks while pretending to use the phone, leaving minimal evidence of theft.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40827650">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The &#39;pay phone bandit&#39; from the 1980s, who eluded the FBI, was eventually caught due to his appearances on America&#39;s Most Wanted and his habit of paying for hotel rooms with rolls of quarters.</li>
<li>The story highlights the challenges of dealing with large amounts of stolen coins and suggests that the bandit could have laundered the money by opening a laundromat or video arcade.</li>
<li>The case is a nostalgic look back at a time when pay phones were common, and it also touches on the ingenuity and risks involved in such crimes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.propelauth.com/post/nextjs-challenges">It&#39;s not just you, Next.js is getting harder to use</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Next.js&#39; new App Router requires deep internal knowledge for basic tasks and has many opt-out pitfalls, making it harder to use compared to its predecessor, the Pages Router.</li>
<li>The Next 13 release introduced features like Server Components, Layouts, and sophisticated caching, which benefit complex applications but add complexity and unexpected behaviors for simpler projects.</li>
<li>Developers should consider whether the App Router’s complexity aligns with their project needs, as simpler tools might be more suitable for certain use cases, despite Next.js recommending the App Router.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40828610">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Next.js is facing criticism for a difficult development environment, unstable caching, and limitations in its file-based router.</li>
<li>Developers report issues with combining client and server state, complex authentication setups, and a slow, memory-intensive new app router.</li>
<li>Many are considering alternatives like Remix, SvelteKit, or Vue/Nuxt due to these challenges, with the shift towards server-side rendering and React Server Components adding complexity without clear benefits.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://josem.co/how-i-overcame-my-addiction-to-sugar/">How I overcame my addiction to sugar</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author shares a personal journey of overcoming a sugar addiction that began in childhood and persisted into adulthood.</li>
<li>Three key strategies were instrumental: changing the environment, removing sugary foods from the home, and adopting positive habits like regular exercise and hydration.</li>
<li>The post aims to inspire others struggling with sugar addiction by demonstrating that overcoming it is achievable with the right approach.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40829312">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author overcame their sugar addiction by keeping their kitchen stocked with diet soda, meat, cheese, yogurt, and peanut butter, and avoiding treats.</li>
<li>They suggest chocolate lovers opt for 90% or 95% chocolate to prevent overeating.</li>
<li>Others shared similar strategies, such as keeping treats out of sight, switching to healthier snacks, and making gradual reductions in sugar intake, with some finding success through keto diets, fasting, or replacing sugary foods with fruits.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjer3llen42o">Panama Papers: Court acquits all 28 charged with money laundering</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A Panamanian court has acquitted all 28 individuals charged with money laundering in the Panama Papers scandal, citing insufficient evidence to prove criminal responsibility.</li>
<li>Among those acquitted were Jurgen Mossack and the late Ramon Fonseca, founders of the law firm Mossack Fonseca, which was central to the 2016 leak exposing the use of tax havens by the wealthy.</li>
<li>The trial, which lasted 85 hours and included testimony from 27 witnesses, was dismissed partly because evidence from Mossack Fonseca&#39;s servers was not collected properly.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40829653">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Panamanian judge dismissed money laundering charges against 28 individuals linked to the Panama Papers leak, but this decision is specific to Panama.</li>
<li>The legal system in Panama is more favorable to such schemes, unlike other countries where prosecutions continue, including successful cases in the US.</li>
<li>The Panama Papers leak led to significant global actions, including the closure of Mossack Fonseca and various international investigations and recoveries.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://skypath.io">Safe Routes. real time turbulence data, ML predictions with an iPad</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>SkyPath offers a real-time turbulence prediction app using data, PIREP (Pilot Reports), and machine learning to enhance flight safety and efficiency.</li>
<li>Benefits include early turbulence notifications, accurate maintenance records, fuel savings, and cost reductions in insurance and maintenance.</li>
<li>The app is praised by pilots for its accuracy and ease of use, requiring no integration efforts—just download and start using.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40828180">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SkyPath provides real-time turbulence data and machine learning (ML) predictions via iPad, utilizing accelerometers and AWS for data processing.</li>
<li>Pilots find the app beneficial, and there is growing interest in integrating it with more airlines, such as Delta.</li>
<li>The app, which can run in the background using satellite internet, improves with pilot feedback and data correlation, enhancing flight safety and efficiency.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://openloco.io/">OpenLoco: Modern, open source version of the classic transport simulation game</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40827586">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenLoco is a modern, open-source version of the classic transport simulation game, Locomotion, appealing to fans of simpler, older games.</li>
<li>Discussions highlight comparisons with other transport simulation games like OpenTTD, noting differences in complexity, UI/UX, and game mechanics.</li>
<li>OpenLoco retains the original binary heavily, which raises questions about its use of 64-bit libraries and modern mechanics.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="The story, as best I can remember, of the origin of Mosaic and Netscape [video]" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=The%20story%2C%20as%20best%20I%20can%20remember%2C%20of%20the%20origin%20of%20Mosaic%20and%20Netscape%20%5Bvideo%5D&subheading=Saturday%2C%20June%2029%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/29</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-29T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-28]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/28&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-28</h1>
<h2><a href="https://anvaka.github.io/pm/">Software galaxies</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40817852">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Software Galaxies visualizes software projects as dots, representing each program and its complexity, sparking discussions on its challenges and potential improvements.</li>
<li>Users debate the practicality of the visualization, with some suggesting it could serve as an educational tool and others reminiscing about similar tools.</li>
<li>There is interest in expanding the datasets included, such as the Linux Kernel or Java Maven repository, highlighting the project&#39;s artistic and technical achievement.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/justice-department-health-care-fraud-garland-24948b951896d0f265c29ba3fcacf858">200 people charged in $2.7B health care fraud crackdown</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>U.S. Attorney General Merrick Garland announced charges against nearly 200 individuals in a nationwide crackdown on health care fraud, with false claims totaling over $2.7 billion.</li>
<li>The charges include a $900 million scheme in Arizona, where two wound care company owners allegedly accepted over $330 million in kickbacks for fraudulent Medicare billing, resulting in patient deaths.</li>
<li>Authorities seized over $230 million in assets and charged 193 individuals, including 76 medical professionals, with other schemes involving fake addiction treatment for Native Americans and misbranded HIV drugs in Florida.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40815139">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Authorities have charged 200 individuals in a $2.7 billion health care fraud crackdown, highlighting the scale and severity of the operation.</li>
<li>Among those charged, Alexandra Gehrke and Jeffrey King were arrested at Phoenix airport with incriminating books on evading law enforcement, suggesting they were preparing to flee.</li>
<li>The case underscores the importance of evidence like packed bags and specific literature in determining flight risk and influencing judicial decisions on bail and sentencing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.valve.computer/">A modern 8 bit design, built using 1950s thermionic valves</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Valve.Computer is a modern 8-bit computer using 1950s thermionic valves, first operational on May 28, 2021, and now mounted as an art installation.</li>
<li>It uses 1,120 thermionic triodes configured as NOR gates, forming memory registers, an 8-bit ALU, oscillators, and relay drivers, and can run programs like PONG and a 32-bit Fibonacci sequence.</li>
<li>The project, inspired by Bletchley Park, took 18 months to build and is entered for the Turner Prize, highlighting its artistic and technical merits.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40814011">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A modern 8-bit computer built using 1950s thermionic valves has generated significant interest and discussion among tech enthusiasts.</li>
<li>Users shared stories about old hardware, the differences between cold and warm boots, and the complexities of thermionic valves, highlighting both the challenges and dedication involved.</li>
<li>The project was praised for its creativity, evoking nostalgia and emphasizing the importance of supportive partners in pursuing one&#39;s passions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/06/28/supreme-court-chevron-doctrine-ruling">Supreme Court overturns 40-year-old &quot;Chevron deference&quot; doctrine</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40820949">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Supreme Court has overturned the &quot;Chevron deference&quot; doctrine, ending a 40-year precedent that allowed federal agencies to interpret ambiguous laws.</li>
<li>Critics argue this decision may lead to instability, as courts will now interpret ambiguous laws, potentially increasing Congress&#39;s legislative workload and affecting regulatory stability.</li>
<li>The ruling is viewed as a significant shift in the balance of power among the branches of government, with Justice Kagan dissenting that agencies are better suited for interpreting laws due to their expertise.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://imbue.com/research/70b-infrastructure/">Infrastructure setup and open-source scripts to train 70B model from bare metal</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A small team successfully trained a 70 billion parameter model on their infrastructure, surpassing zero-shot GPT-4 in reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The setup involved 4,092 H100 GPUs across 511 computers, connected via a three-tier InfiniBand network, with detailed provisioning, diagnostics, and automated health checks.</li>
<li>They are sharing a comprehensive guide and scripts for setting up similar infrastructure, emphasizing reproducibility, automation, and thorough testing, and are open to hiring.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40816158">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A small team successfully trained a 70 billion parameter model from scratch, outperforming zero-shot GPT-4 on reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>They utilized a high-performance cluster with over 12,000 connections, ensuring seamless operation of all components.</li>
<li>The team is sharing open-source scripts and a guide for infrastructure setup as part of a three-part toolkit, which also includes sections on evaluations and hyperparameter optimization.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/979671/4fb7c1827536d1ae/">Python grapples with Apple App Store rejections</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>An upgrade from Python 3.11 to 3.12 caused some Python apps to be rejected by Apple&#39;s app stores due to the presence of the string &quot;itms-services&quot; in the urllib parser, which is prohibited in sandboxed apps on macOS.</li>
<li>Eric Froemling&#39;s bug report led to a discussion among Python developers about how to accommodate app store review processes, considering solutions like obfuscation and distribution-level patching.</li>
<li>A consensus was reached to add a build-time option called &quot;--with-app-store-compliance&quot; for Python 3.13, which would remove problematic code for app store submissions, highlighting the challenges free-software projects face with opaque review processes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40815130">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Python apps are being rejected from the Apple App Store due to the &quot;itms-services&quot; URL scheme in their binaries, and Windows Defender also flags these apps when built with PyInstaller.</li>
<li>Developers argue that major OS platforms are hindering small developers by requiring costly code-signing certificates, making app distribution challenging.</li>
<li>Alternatives suggested include using Homebrew for Mac apps or free certificates from SignPath for Windows builds, highlighting the broader issue of security-related rejections in app distribution.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://community.frame.work/t/now-available-in-denmark-finland-and-sweden/53690">Frame.work laptop now available in Denmark, Finland, and Sweden</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>DestroyaFramework has announced that their products, including the Framework Laptop 13 and 16, are now available for shipment to Denmark, Finland, and Sweden.</li>
<li>The new Framework Laptop 13 with Intel Core Ultra Series 1 processors is available for pre-order, along with Danish and Swedish/Finnish keyboards.</li>
<li>Keyboards for the Framework Laptop 16 will be available in late July, with email alerts for stock updates available on the product page.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40818422">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Frame.work laptop is now available in Denmark, Finland, and Sweden, featuring proper Danish keyboards, addressing criticisms of Nordic keyboard layouts for coding.</li>
<li>Framework&#39;s modular design allows for easy upgrades and repairs, emphasizing repairability and environmental benefits, though some users note issues with battery life and webcam quality.</li>
<li>Expansion to Norway is complicated by its non-EU status, impacting costs and logistics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/06/27/fcc-rule-would-make-carriers-unlock-all-phones-after-60-days/">FCC rule would make carriers unlock all phones after 60 days</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The FCC proposes a rule requiring carriers to unlock phones 60 days after purchase to simplify the process for consumers.</li>
<li>FCC Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel announced the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) to establish clear, nationwide unlocking rules, with public feedback invited starting July 18.</li>
<li>The rule aims to provide consistency and transparency, making it easier for consumers to switch carriers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40814728">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The FCC has proposed a rule mandating carriers to unlock phones after 60 days, aiming to reduce e-waste and facilitate easier switching between carriers.</li>
<li>The US is distinct in having carrier-locked phones, which gives carriers significant control over phone features and updates, unlike Europe where phones can be remotely locked for non-payment.</li>
<li>The proposal has sparked debate, with some viewing carrier locks as anti-consumer, while others argue they help finance phones for individuals with poor credit.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/3715702/maker-of-rstudio-launches-new-r-and-python-ide.html">Maker of RStudio launches new R and Python IDE</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Posit, formerly known as RStudio, has released a beta version of Positron, a new Integrated Development Environment (IDE) for R and Python, based on Visual Studio Code.</li>
<li>Positron is available for macOS, Windows, and Linux, and is designed to be user-friendly with built-in support for R and Python, eliminating the need for additional extensions.</li>
<li>The IDE includes a data and variable explorer for easy data manipulation and supports other VS Code extensions via the OpenVSX registry, though it is still in early development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40815097">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The maker of RStudio has launched a new integrated development environment (IDE) called Positron, which supports both R and Python.</li>
<li>Despite the new release, RStudio will continue to be developed and maintained, with some R-specific features remaining exclusive to it.</li>
<li>Positron aims to bridge the gap between R and Python, offering a unified environment for data analysis and package development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.apricitas.io/p/the-death-of-nyc-congestion-pricing">The Death of NYC Congestion Pricing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Governor Kathy Hochul announced an indefinite pause on NYC&#39;s congestion pricing scheme, which aimed to charge vehicles entering Lower Manhattan to fund transit projects.</li>
<li>The cancellation, driven by opposition from suburban drivers and concerns about the MTA&#39;s spending efficiency, jeopardizes key infrastructure projects and funding.</li>
<li>This decision underscores broader issues in American cities and infrastructure, highlighting inefficiencies, high costs, and local opposition in public transit investments.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40817079">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>NYC&#39;s congestion pricing plan, intended to reduce traffic and fund public transit, has been stalled by state politics.</li>
<li>Critics cite the MTA&#39;s mismanagement and high costs as reasons against additional funding, while supporters argue it could improve traffic flow and public transit.</li>
<li>The debate underscores broader urban planning and public policy issues, balancing convenience with sustainability.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.flightradar24.com/blog/is-cat-more-common/">Is Clear Air Turbulence becoming more common?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40819784">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Clear Air Turbulence (CAT) incidents are not showing a trend in accident statistics, as the NTSB only reports significant incidents.</li>
<li>Factors such as climate change and increased air travel may contribute to more frequent CAT, but newer planes with advanced sensors and pilot reporting make it difficult to measure accurately.</li>
<li>The jet stream&#39;s behavior, influenced by climate change, also affects CAT frequency, but modern planes are designed to handle turbulence, and pilots are trained to manage it.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40818809">What is the best code base you ever worked on?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40818809">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google&#39;s monorepo is praised for its exceptional tooling, which includes instant creation of mutable snapshots and perfectly reproducible builds on clusters.</li>
<li>Features like instant code search, quick blame and symbol lookup, and extensive presubmit checks ensure high productivity and uniform code/test quality.</li>
<li>The environment enforces consistent style through culture, auto-linters, and mandatory code reviews, making it a standout experience for developers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-02003-6">New ways to catch gravitational waves</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The first direct detection of gravitational waves in 2015 by LIGO and Virgo observatories revolutionized physics, enabling astronomers to &#39;hear&#39; cosmic events.</li>
<li>Current detectors are limited to frequencies between 100–1,000 Hz, but new instruments and techniques aim to detect a broader range, from megahertz to nanohertz frequencies.</li>
<li>Five new methods include Pulsar Timing Arrays, Microwave Telescopes, Atom Interferometry, Desktop Detectors, and Quantum Crystals, each targeting different frequency ranges and promising to uncover more cosmic phenomena.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40820063">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The first generation of gravitational wave detectors failed to detect waves, discrediting Weber&#39;s 1987 claim, but current interferometers like LIGO, Virgo, and KAGRA have successfully detected them.</li>
<li>Gravitational waves confirm Einstein’s general relativity, yet a quantum theory of gravity remains unresolved, with string theory and Loop Quantum Gravity offering potential but challenging explanations.</li>
<li>Future projects like LISA aim to enhance detection capabilities, and public tours of LIGO facilities are available for educational purposes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/parkinsons-link-to-gut-bacteria-suggests-unexpected-simple-treatment">Parkinson&#39;s Link to Gut Bacteria Suggests Unexpected, Simple Treatment</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have identified specific gut microbes linked to decreased levels of riboflavin (vitamin B2) and biotin (vitamin B7) in Parkinson&#39;s patients, suggesting B vitamin supplementation as a potential treatment.</li>
<li>The study, led by Hiroshi Nishiwaki from Nagoya University, found that changes in gut bacteria affected the production of short-chain fatty acids (SCFAs) and polyamines, crucial for a healthy intestinal mucus layer.</li>
<li>The findings, published in npj Parkinson&#39;s Disease, indicate that maintaining a healthy gut microbiome and reducing environmental toxins could help protect against Parkinson&#39;s symptoms.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40818987">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study suggests a connection between gut bacteria and Parkinson&#39;s disease, indicating certain bacterial strains might contribute to the condition.</li>
<li>Discussions have emerged about the potential benefits of supplementing with vitamins like riboflavin (B2) and biotin (B7) to alleviate symptoms.</li>
<li>The study underscores the importance of gut health on neurological conditions but advises that more research is needed and current treatments should not be ignored.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.wits.ac.za/news/latest-news/general-news/2024/2024-06/a-novel-way-to-save-rhinos-.html">The Rhisotope Project: Insertion of radioisotopes into live rhinoceros</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Rhisotope Project at Wits University has begun inserting low doses of radioisotopes into rhino horns to aid in detecting smuggled horns at international borders.</li>
<li>This innovative approach, monitored over six months, aims to deter poaching by making rhino horns detectable and less valuable on the black market.</li>
<li>The project leverages global nuclear security infrastructure and focuses on education and social upliftment, particularly empowering women and girls in rural communities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40819617">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Rhisotope Project aims to deter rhino poaching by inserting radioisotopes into their horns, making them detectable at borders.</li>
<li>Critics argue the method is ineffective due to the slow injection process and weak enforcement of anti-ivory laws, suggesting alternatives like dyeing, toxin infusion, or lab-grown keratin.</li>
<li>The project is currently in the proof-of-concept phase, with ongoing research to assess its viability and safety.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Software galaxies" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Software%20galaxies&subheading=Friday%2C%20June%2028%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/28</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-28T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-27]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/27&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-27</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/cyber-security/south-korean-telecom-company-attacks-torrent-users-with-malware-over-600000-people-report-missing-files-strange-folders-and-disabled-pcs">South Korean telecom company attacks torrent users with malware</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>KT Corporation, a major South Korean telecom company, intentionally infected over 600,000 users with malware to disrupt Webhard&#39;s BitTorrent-based Grid Service, starting in May 2020.</li>
<li>The malware caused issues such as missing files, strange folders, and disabled PCs, and was traced back to KT&#39;s data center.</li>
<li>Authorities have charged 13 individuals, including KT employees, and KT defended its actions by citing network strain and unpaid usage fees, though the unauthorized malware installation led to significant customer problems.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40805099">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>South Korean telecom company allegedly targets torrent users with malware, raising significant privacy and ethical concerns.</li>
<li>The incident highlights ongoing issues with internet service providers (ISPs) in South Korea, including high fees and potential misuse of power.</li>
<li>This situation has sparked discussions about the state of internet freedom and infrastructure in South Korea, which was once known for its fast internet speeds but now faces criticism for outdated practices and government control.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://latenighter.com/news/paramount-axes-comedy-central-website-show-clips-library/">25 years of video clips gone as Paramount axes Comedy Central wesbite</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Paramount has shut down ComedyCentral.com, removing over 25 years of clips from The Daily Show and The Colbert Report, directing visitors to TV providers or Paramount+.</li>
<li>Other shows like The Opposition with Jordan Klepper and Lights Out with David Spade are also affected, with older episodes not available on Paramount+.</li>
<li>This move is part of Paramount&#39;s cost-cutting measures to manage over $14 billion in debt, following similar actions with MTV.com and CMT.com, aiming to streamline sites and drive viewers to Paramount+.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40807032">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Paramount has removed 25 years of video clips from the Comedy Central website, sparking criticism over their management&#39;s perceived undervaluation of the content.</li>
<li>Critics argue that the content could have been monetized or preserved, highlighting the complexities of media rights and regulatory challenges in distributing older content.</li>
<li>The removal is viewed as a cost-cutting measure by Paramount amid financial difficulties, with some lamenting the loss of cultural history and suggesting piracy as a means of preservation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://web.dev/case-studies/google-sheets-wasmgc">Google Sheets ported its calculation worker from JavaScript to WasmGC</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google Sheets has transitioned from JavaScript to WasmGC (WebAssembly Garbage Collection) to enhance performance, particularly for large spreadsheets.</li>
<li>WasmGC supports garbage-collected languages like Java, offering near-native speed on the web, and Google Sheets is among the first to implement it.</li>
<li>Initial performance of WasmGC was slower than JavaScript, but subsequent optimizations have significantly improved its speed, demonstrating its potential to revolutionize web application development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40808820">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google Sheets transitioned its calculation engine from JavaScript to WasmGC, initially experiencing slower performance but later optimizing it to be twice as fast as the JS version.</li>
<li>The move involved significant reimplementation efforts, including devirtualization and leveraging browser APIs, aiming to improve performance and utilize the native V8 garbage collector.</li>
<li>Despite improvements, some users still find Google Sheets slower compared to native applications like Excel, highlighting the ongoing evolution and optimization of web technologies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://thezvi.substack.com/p/on-claude-35-sonnet">Claude 3.5 Sonnet</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40806698">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Anthropic has introduced the Projects feature for Pro and Team users, allowing multiple projects with their own reference materials, enhancing convenience for users.</li>
<li>Claude 3.5 Sonnet is receiving praise for its coding abilities, with users noting it helps expert programmers move faster and is superior to other models like GPT-4.</li>
<li>Users are discussing the practical applications and limitations of Claude 3.5 Sonnet, including its performance in summarization, recommendation tasks, and coding assistance, with some preferring it over OpenAI&#39;s offerings.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://mynor.org/my4th_forthdeck.htm">The Forth Deck mini: a portable Forth computer with a discrete CPU</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Forth Deck mini is a portable Forth computer with a discrete CPU, featuring a 40x4 character LCD, 56-button QWERTY keyboard, and 6.6 Wh LiPo battery with 6 hours runtime.</li>
<li>It includes an 8-bit CMOS logic CPU, 32 KB ROM, 32 KB RAM, up to 256 KB EEPROM, and RS-232 with 4800 baud, reminiscent of 70s and 80s home computers with built-in Basic interpreters.</li>
<li>The device can be assembled using a kit from Budgetronics, excluding the battery and charging circuitry, and is licensed under Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40804122">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Forth Deck mini is a portable Forth computer featuring a discrete CPU built with a few logic chips and an EEPROM, operating on an 8-bit data and address bus.</li>
<li>Enthusiasts are discussing its design, potential modifications, and comparisons to other CPUs like the Novix NC4000, as well as the idea of a Forth-based Factor dialect for scripting.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the challenges of creating modern hobbyist computers with good keyboards and displays, referencing devices like the TRS-80 Model 100 and the AlphaSmart, and mentioning alternatives like the M5Stack Cardputer and the Zorzpad.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2024/06/26/g-s1-6177/brain-waste-removal-system-amyloid-alzheimer-toxins">The brain makes a lot of waste. Now scientists think they know where it goes</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Scientists have uncovered new details about the brain&#39;s waste-removal system, which is essential for maintaining brain health and preventing disorders.</li>
<li>Research published in Nature reveals that slow electrical waves during sleep help push waste-laden fluid from deep within the brain to its surface, where it is absorbed into the bloodstream and removed by the liver and kidneys.</li>
<li>This glymphatic system is crucial for clearing amyloid, a substance linked to Alzheimer&#39;s disease, and impaired waste removal may contribute to various brain disorders like Alzheimer&#39;s, Parkinson&#39;s, headaches, and depression.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40805251">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Scientists have identified that deep sleep plays a crucial role in clearing brain waste, including amyloid proteins, which are linked to Alzheimer&#39;s and dementia.</li>
<li>Research suggests that inducing slow electrical waves in the brain through light and sound stimulation could enhance this waste clearance, though most studies are currently on mice.</li>
<li>Factors such as coffee consumption, exercise, and sleep patterns are also being discussed for their potential impact on brain health.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://fastvoiceagent.cerebrium.ai/">Voice bots with 500ms response times</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Experimentation with voice interfaces and large language models (LLMs) began following the release of GPT-4, highlighting the engaging nature and new challenges of voice interactions with generative AI.</li>
<li>Achieving a 500ms voice-to-voice response time is challenging but possible by hosting transcription, LLM inference, and voice generation together, optimizing data routing, and ensuring good wifi and VRAM caching.</li>
<li>A demo of a 500ms-capable voice bot and a container for deployment on A10/A100/H100 GPUs is available, with current metrics showing a total response cycle of 759ms, indicating rapid AI evolution and potential future simplifications.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40805010">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Voice bots achieving 500ms response times are possible by optimizing transcription, LLM inference, and voice generation processes, along with efficient data routing and caching.</li>
<li>Metrics for voice-to-voice response total 759ms, but future LLMs with native audio capabilities may further reduce this time.</li>
<li>Users highlighted the importance of low latency in AI interactions, especially in customer service, and discussed potential technical improvements like browser support and on-device processing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://fabric8labs.com">Next gen 3D metal printing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fabric8Labs, a San Diego startup, has secured $50 million in Series B financing to advance its electrochemical additive manufacturing technology.</li>
<li>The funding will support the construction of a new 3D printing factory, significantly increasing the company&#39;s workforce.</li>
<li>This investment highlights the growing interest and capital influx into 3D printing startups, driven by innovative manufacturing technologies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40803783">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Next-gen 3D metal printing by Fabric8Labs employs electrochemical methods for precise, fast, and versatile manufacturing, achieving micron-level resolution.</li>
<li>This technique combines additive and subtractive processes, primarily depositing pure metals and some alloys, making it safer and more energy-efficient by avoiding high temperatures and metal powders.</li>
<li>Fabric8Labs&#39; technology is promising for applications such as PCBs (Printed Circuit Boards) and complex internal structures, and the company is exploring commercial opportunities with this unique approach.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lars.ingebrigtsen.no/2024/06/26/a-new-package-for-making-charts-in-emacs-eplot/">Eplot: A new package for making charts in Emacs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A new Emacs package called eplot has been released, designed for creating simple plots directly within Emacs.</li>
<li>eplot addresses limitations found in existing tools like chart.el and Gnuplot, offering features such as sensible Y-axis numbers and SVG gradients.</li>
<li>The package is user-friendly, allowing users to generate plots by typing M-x eplot in a buffer with numbers, and it is documented on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40807923">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new package called Eplot has been released for creating charts in Emacs, a popular text editor among developers.</li>
<li>The package has garnered attention for its simplicity and flexibility, with suggestions to enhance user experience by leveraging Emacs&#39; file- and directory-local variables.</li>
<li>Discussions highlight comparisons with other charting tools like Gnuplot and Matplotlib, noting the strengths and weaknesses of each in the context of Emacs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.joanwestenberg.com/6-months-ago,-i-left-the-bullshit-industrial-complex">6 months ago, I left the bullshit industrial complex</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A former tech PR professional reveals their past in promoting overhyped startups, which funded a lavish lifestyle but led to ethical doubts.</li>
<li>They decided to leave the profitable but morally questionable industry to focus on honest writing about the real human impact of technology and venture capital.</li>
<li>Despite financial and career risks, they find integrity and personal fulfillment in their new path, rejecting the tech industry&#39;s empty promises.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40806930">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author expresses disillusionment with the tech industry, noting a shift from solving human problems to extracting value over the past 25 years.</li>
<li>Key observations include a Reddit post claiming the 90s were peak humanity and a viral quote about AI doing chores instead of creative work, highlighting a nostalgic view of past technological optimism.</li>
<li>Despite concerns about data exploitation and profit-driven motives, there is still hope in open-source communities and innovative hacks, though the relentless pursuit of profit has led to widespread disillusionment.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.govexec.com/pay-benefits/2024/06/federal-whistleblowers-are-entitled-damages-missed-future-pay-court-rules/397638/">Federal whistleblowers are entitled to damages of missed future pay, court rules</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit ruled that federal whistleblowers can receive compensatory damages for future lost earnings if their firing harmed their earning potential.</li>
<li>Deborah Perlick, fired after reporting missing funds, successfully argued for additional compensation beyond back pay, impacting future job prospects.</li>
<li>This ruling sets a precedent for federal whistleblowers, allowing claims for future lost earnings without needing guaranteed future employment, and the case was remanded to the Merit Systems Protection Board for a final decision.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40804489">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A court has ruled that federal whistleblowers are entitled to damages for missed future pay, even without a guaranteed future job, provided there is sufficient evidence of likely future employment.</li>
<li>This decision may encourage more whistleblowers by alleviating concerns about losing future earnings and aligns federal employees&#39; rights with those of private-sector employees.</li>
<li>The case, involving a VA (Veterans Affairs) employee, emphasized that reputational harm affecting future earnings is compensable.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ams.org/notices/199701/comm-rota.pdf">Lessons I Wish I Had Been Taught (1996) [pdf]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40808933">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Lessons I Wish I Had Been Taught (1996)&quot; by Gian-Carlo Rota sparked discussions on Hacker News, with users sharing unique units of measurement like &quot;microcentury&quot; (50 minutes) and &quot;nanoacre&quot; (4 square millimeters).</li>
<li>Conversations also covered lecture durations, attention spans, and the significance of engaging introductions in academic papers, reflecting on Rota&#39;s impactful teachings.</li>
<li>The thread highlighted a recurring interest in Rota&#39;s insights, with users reminiscing about personal experiences and referencing related discussions and resources.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.lawgazette.co.uk/news/post-office-lawyers-held-secret-meeting-with-judge-to-stop-disclosure/5119593.article">Post Office lawyers held secret meeting with judge to stop disclosure</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Lawyers for the Post Office held a secret meeting with a judge in 2013 to prevent disclosure of a report revealing potential issues with the Horizon system to defence solicitors in a criminal trial.</li>
<li>The inquiry heard that prosecuting solicitor Martin Smith admitted he did not comply with his duties and lacked the necessary expertise, raising concerns about past convictions and disclosure practices.</li>
<li>The ongoing inquiry continues to uncover several disclosure issues as the Post Office approaches mediation and reviews of past convictions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40808808">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Post Office lawyers secretly met with a judge to block evidence disclosure, resulting in wrongful convictions.</li>
<li>Public defenders are overwhelmed, managing up to 700 cases annually, which hampers effective defense.</li>
<li>The justice system favors those who can afford private attorneys, underscoring the need for legal reforms and better funding for public defenders to ensure fair trials.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.readmargins.com/p/doordash-and-pizza-arbitrage">DoorDash and Pizza Arbitrage (2020)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Doordash listed a pizzeria without the owner&#39;s permission, leading to issues with cold deliveries and incorrect pricing.</li>
<li>An arbitrage opportunity emerged due to Doordash&#39;s pricing errors, allowing profit from ordering at lower prices and selling at higher restaurant prices.</li>
<li>The article critiques the food delivery business model as inefficient and exploitative, suggesting a more integrated approach like Domino&#39;s might be more sustainable.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40806356">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>DoorDash and similar food delivery services face criticism for unsustainable business models that depend on underpaid labor and high customer acquisition costs.</li>
<li>Critics argue these practices exacerbate economic inequality and suggest taxing accumulated capital to redistribute wealth.</li>
<li>The debate includes concerns about the negative impact on restaurant quality and the ethics of these delivery services, questioning their long-term sustainability and benefits.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/corcel/corcel">Corcel – Use WordPress backend with Laravel or any PHP application</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Corcel is a PHP library built on Eloquent ORM from Laravel, enabling direct data retrieval from a WordPress database, usable with Laravel or any PHP project via Composer.</li>
<li>Key features include support for custom post types, shortcodes, taxonomies, pages, attachments, revisions, thumbnails, options, menus, users, and authentication.</li>
<li>Installation and configuration are straightforward, with auto-registration for Laravel 5.5+ and manual setup for older versions or non-Laravel projects.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40805351">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Corcel enables the use of a WordPress backend with Laravel or any PHP application, proving effective in production environments.</li>
<li>Users have successfully integrated Corcel with Laravel, Filament, and LunarPHP to improve performance, such as rescuing slow WooCommerce sites.</li>
<li>Corcel is praised for its seamless interface with WordPress data, offering a maintainable solution for PHP projects needing to interact with WordPress databases, and is compared favorably to tools like Prismic, Strapi, and Shopify.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="South Korean telecom company attacks torrent users with malware" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=South%20Korean%20telecom%20company%20attacks%20torrent%20users%20with%20malware&subheading=Thursday%2C%20June%2027%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/27</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
