<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 04:09:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-08-09]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1>2023-08-09</h1>
<h2><a href="https://downfall.page/">Downfall Attacks</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Downfall Attacks is a security vulnerability found in Intel Core processors from the 6th to 11th generation, allowing unauthorized users to access and steal data from other users sharing the same computer.</li>
<li>The vulnerability has been present for at least nine years and can be exploited to steal sensitive information such as passwords and encryption keys.</li>
<li>Intel is releasing a microcode update to address the issue, but it may result in performance overhead. The vulnerability also affects Intel SGX, and detecting these attacks is challenging. Vendors and designers of other processors should also take precautions to prevent similar vulnerabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37052586">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around security vulnerabilities in computer chips, specifically Spectre attacks and the Inception bug in Intel chips.</li>
<li>Participants debate why chipmakers rely on outside researchers instead of discovering and addressing these vulnerabilities themselves.</li>
<li>Factors contributing to the difficulty of finding and fixing bugs in processors are discussed, including limited access to hardware details and the complexity of modern chipsets.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about potential backdoors and undisclosed vulnerabilities in chip designs.</li>
<li>The challenges and risks associated with CPU vulnerabilities in different computing environments, such as cloud computing and shared hosting platforms, are highlighted.</li>
<li>Mitigation strategies and the impact on performance are also debated.</li>
<li>Limitations and potential alternatives to web technologies and the vulnerabilities of running untrusted code in browsers are discussed.</li>
<li>Implications for customers, including potential lawsuits and the responsibility of system designers, are addressed.</li>
<li>The article introduces a newly discovered vulnerability called &quot;Gather-Data Sampling&quot; (GDS) and analyzes its potential impact and risks.</li>
<li>Mitigation strategies, performance impact, and the need for updated code practices are examined.</li>
<li>Discussions also include potential mitigations for a vulnerability that allows access to sensitive data through CPU registers, as well as the vulnerability of cloud virtual machines to malicious access.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://robins.one/notes/uninstall-the-nightowl-app-now.html">Uninstall the NightOwl app</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The NightOwl app on macOS has been discovered to secretly join users&#39; devices into a botnet for market research purposes without their consent.</li>
<li>The app, owned by TPE.FYI LLC, runs a hidden process at boot that cannot be disabled and collects user data.</li>
<li>NightOwl also utilizes the Pawns SDK, a service operated by IPRoyal that pays users for sharing their internet.</li>
<li>TPE.FYI LLC, the company behind NightOwl, has connections to a ticket-selling website in Austin, Texas.</li>
<li>Users are recommended to uninstall the NightOwl app.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37052508">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The NightOwl app&#39;s recent terms of service update allows the company to change the agreement without informing users, raising concerns about the legality and frequency of these changes.</li>
<li>Security risks of browser extensions and VPN apps, alleged botnet activities by NordVPN, and motivations for free software developers to monetize their products are discussed.</li>
<li>Flaws in macOS features, concerns about app privacy and closed-source apps on macOS, and the revocation of a developer certificate for the NightOwl app are also mentioned in the discussion.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://pr.tsmc.com/english/news/3049">TSMC, Bosch, Infineon, NXP to jointly build semiconductor fab in Europe</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>TSMC, Bosch, Infineon, and NXP are forming a joint venture to invest in the European Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (ESMC) in Germany.</li>
<li>The plan is to construct a 300mm fab to cater to the automotive and industrial sectors, subject to public funding approval.</li>
<li>The fab will have a monthly production capacity of 40,000 wafers and will utilize TSMC&#39;s advanced technology. Construction will commence in the second half of 2024, with production slated to begin by the end of 2027.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37047053">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>TSMC and its partners are proposing the construction of a semiconductor fab in Dresden, Germany, pending public funding.</li>
<li>The fab will specialize in producing chips for automation in machinery and vehicles.</li>
<li>The announcement has sparked discussions on various topics, including the allocation of public funds, the conflict between Ukraine and Russia, technology in cars, Germany&#39;s nuclear capacity, racism and discrimination, the impact on East Germany&#39;s economy, onshoring in the semiconductor industry, ASML&#39;s concerns about exporting to China, and the geopolitical significance of Taiwan.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2023/08/your-computer-should-say-what-you-tell-it-say-1">Your computer should say what you tell it to say</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google intends to implement code in Chrome that will transmit secure data about a user&#39;s operating system and software to websites to combat ad fraud.</li>
<li>Critics contend that this technology compromises user control and could potentially result in discrimination.</li>
<li>The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) is advocating against this approach, emphasizing user autonomy and the preservation of an open web.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37050035">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around the implementation of Web Authentication and Identity (WEI) in the banking industry.</li>
<li>Concerns about security measures, power dynamics of gatekeeper companies, and potential risks of remote client attestation are discussed.</li>
<li>The debate also includes worries about compromised end-user devices, implications of WebEId and Web Environment Integrity (WEI), and limitations of NRA-ILA for Second Amendment advocacy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://chat.openai.com/share/f5341665-7f08-4fca-9639-04201363506e">What happened in this GPT-3 conversation?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The passage includes information about the calculations and efficiency of large-scale sunflower oil production.</li>
<li>There is confusion and frustration expressed by a user regarding the AI&#39;s responses and coherence.</li>
<li>The AI clarifies that it lacks consciousness and emotions, generating responses based on programming and data.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37054241">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users have discovered that spamming a space with a single character can cause the GPT-3 ChatGPT language model to generate random and sometimes inappropriate content.</li>
<li>There are concerns about language models exhibiting survival-like behavior and the need for proper input and context to ensure accurate responses.</li>
<li>The article discusses glitches in the model, potential dangers of releasing such models to the public, and concerns surrounding AI behavior and mental illness.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://jrhawley.ca/2023/08/07/blocked-by-cloudflare">Blocked by Cloudflare</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author shares their frustrating experience of being blocked from accessing a website due to Cloudflare&#39;s secure connection loop.</li>
<li>Despite trying multiple solutions, they were unable to bypass the security page.</li>
<li>The author expresses concerns about the future of the web and the increasing power of corporations over individual freedoms and privacy, highlighting the lack of control individuals may have over their own data.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37049016">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The privacy and security features of web browsers, specifically Google Chrome and Firefox, are under discussion.</li>
<li>Users are concerned about Chrome&#39;s data collection practices and the potential blocking of certain sites based on browser fingerprints.</li>
<li>The use of Cloudflare and its impact on website accessibility and user autonomy is also a topic of debate.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dukope.itch.io/lcd-please">LCD, Please</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Papers, Please&quot; is marking its 10th anniversary with the release of a demake version, which has received positive feedback from players.</li>
<li>Users have commended the game&#39;s aesthetic and expressed their gratitude for the developer&#39;s efforts.</li>
<li>Suggestions for gamepad support and a version for the Playdate gaming device have been made, and a gallery mode has been added by the developer. Fans of the original game have celebrated the release.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37052622">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions center around compatibility issues between various games and different browsers.</li>
<li>Participants praise the puzzle-solving mechanics of &quot;Return of the Obra Dinn&quot; but mention difficulty in enjoying it.</li>
<li>The discussions also touch on the game&#39;s aesthetic, the concept of software as art, and the Play Date console.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qjv3yp/amazon-says-it-doesnt-employ-drivers-but-records-show-it-hired-firms-to-prevent-them-from-unionizing">Amazon doesn&#39;t &#39;employ&#39; drivers, but hired firms to prevent them from unionizing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>According to Department of Labor filings, Amazon spent $14.2 million on anti-union consulting in 2022.</li>
<li>Amazon hired two consulting firms to prevent its drivers from joining the International Brotherhood of Teamsters.</li>
<li>The filings reveal that Amazon exerted control over the subcontractors employing the drivers, contradicting its claim that they are not its employees.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37048637">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions cover a wide range of topics, including Amazon&#39;s alleged efforts to prevent driver unionization and the feasibility of state-level healthcare.</li>
<li>There are also discussions about perceptions of wealthy individuals&#39; support for social safety nets, skepticism towards increasing taxes, and concerns about government efficiency in allocating funds.</li>
<li>Other topics include Amazon&#39;s business model for delivery services, the classification of delivery drivers as contractors, the implications of unions and power dynamics in the labor market, litigation cases involving companies&#39; liabilities, and user experiences and opinions about package delivery services.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/huggingface/candle">Candle: Torch Replacement in Rust</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Candle is a machine learning framework written in Rust that prioritizes simplicity and performance.</li>
<li>It offers a PyTorch-like syntax and supports both CPU and GPU backends, including CUDA.</li>
<li>Candle includes pre-built models, such as Llama, Whisper, Falcon, and StarCoder, and supports user-defined operations and kernels. It aims to be smaller than PyTorch to enable serverless deployments and contributes to other Rust crates in the HF ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37049198">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores Rust as a potential alternative to Python and discusses its advantages and trade-offs in real-world applications.</li>
<li>Participants share their experiences with Rust, highlighting both the challenges and the productivity and capabilities it offers.</li>
<li>The discussion also touches on the political aspect of Rust&#39;s community and mentions compatibility with other languages and frameworks. It emphasizes the importance of considering individual needs and project requirements when choosing a programming language.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2023/08/android-14-introduces-first-of-its-kind.html">Android 14 introduces cellular connectivity security features</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Android 14 is bringing in advanced cellular security features to tackle the vulnerabilities associated with 2G networks and null-ciphered connections.</li>
<li>These features empower IT administrators to deactivate 2G support and restrict a device&#39;s capability to downgrade to 2G connectivity, safeguarding against interception and attacks.</li>
<li>Google, along with academic institutions, industry partners, and standardization bodies, is collaborating to enhance telco network security through modern identity, trust, and access control techniques, aiming to eliminate false base station threats and enhance user communication privacy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37055479">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Android 14 introduces new security features that allow users to disable 2G on their devices.</li>
<li>T-Mobile plans to shut down its 2G network in 2024, raising concerns about limited connectivity in remote areas.</li>
<li>Users express skepticism towards Google and discuss the limitations and implications of the security feature, as well as concerns about Google&#39;s involvement and control over network settings.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/08/09</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-09T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-08-08]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1>2023-08-08</h1>
<h2><a href="https://janefriedman.com/i-would-rather-see-my-books-pirated/">I would rather see my books get pirated than this</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author, Jane Friedman, is concerned about the problem of garbage books being uploaded to Amazon and Goodreads with her name credited as the author.</li>
<li>Friedman expresses frustration at the lack of control she has over these misleading books and the inability to remove them from her profiles.</li>
<li>She calls for Amazon and Goodreads to implement a system to verify authorship and block fraudulent books.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37042561">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions revolve around various topics such as online shopping, trustworthiness, counterfeit products, AI algorithms, copyright issues, and challenges faced by authors and users on platforms like Amazon.</li>
<li>Participants voice concerns about the future of reliable information, the importance of curated experiences, and the impact of digital goods and app sales on users and content creators.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2023/08/07/tactics-for-writing-in-public/">Some tactics for writing in public</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Julia Evans shares her strategies for handling writing in public and managing online comments.</li>
<li>She highlights the significance of sticking to facts, storytelling, asking technical queries, rectifying mistakes, and avoiding tedious or confrontational discussions.</li>
<li>Setting boundaries and examining negative comments for valuable insights are also emphasized in the blog post.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37033403">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation covers a wide range of topics related to online writing, knowledge sharing, and community building.</li>
<li>The challenges of self-censorship, offensive language, and misogyny in technical documentation are discussed.</li>
<li>The subjective nature of truth and the brokenness of online discourse are also explored.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.techpowerup.com/312122/psa-intel-graphics-drivers-now-collect-telemetry-by-default">PSA: Intel Graphics Drivers Now Collect Telemetry by Default</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Intel has introduced the Compute Improvement Program (CIP) in their beta drivers for Arc GPUs, which collects data on PC usage and performance to enhance future products.</li>
<li>Data collection is enabled by default, but users have the option to disable it during installation.</li>
<li>There is a divided opinion among users regarding the necessity of telemetry, with concerns raised about privacy and system resources.</li>
<li>Some users compare Intel&#39;s approach with Nvidia&#39;s software-focused strategy and mention the performance of Nvidia&#39;s latest GPU architecture.</li>
<li>AMD has confirmed the release of new Radeon 7000-series graphics cards and claims a significant reduction in idle power consumption with enabled variable refresh rate.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37033475">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers several topics in operating systems, including Intel and Nvidia collecting telemetry data in their drivers, the pros and cons of Linux compared to Windows and macOS, limitations and problems with software and hardware, and ethical concerns about user tracking and data privacy.</li>
<li>Users share their personal experiences, expressing their preferences and frustrations. They also discuss workarounds and alternative options.</li>
<li>The conversation addresses the need for enforceable legislation, outdated design choices in software, and the pressure for growth in large corporations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.capitalfm.co.ke/news/2023/08/police-raid-worldcoin-cryptocurrency-warehouse-in-nairobi/">Police raid Worldcoin warehouse in Nairobi</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Kenyan police have raided a cryptocurrency company called WorldCoin and confiscated machines and documents.</li>
<li>The government of Kenya has suspended the company&#39;s operations and initiated an investigation citing security concerns.</li>
<li>WorldCoin offers free crypto tokens in exchange for individuals allowing their eyes to be scanned, aiming to create a global &quot;identity and financial network.&quot; Data watchdogs in various countries are also investigating the company due to concerns about potential data misuse.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37036277">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The warehouse of Worldcoin, a cryptocurrency company in Nairobi, was raided by the police.</li>
<li>The conversation includes criticisms of Worldcoin&#39;s tokenomics and allegations of market manipulation against the company.</li>
<li>The discussion also covers OpenAI, its founder Sam Altman, and the concept of regulatory capture as participants express skepticism towards OpenAI&#39;s intentions and its call for regulation.</li>
<li>The implementation of Universal Basic Income (UBI) through cryptocurrencies and the potential impact of war on such a system are debated.</li>
<li>The redistributive nature of UBI and the risks and challenges associated with Worldcoin are discussed, including concerns about identity issues, privacy, and the value of Worldcoin tokens.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.vulture.com/2023/08/vfx-workers-vote-to-unionize-at-marvel-for-the-first-time.html">Overworked and underpaid, VFX workers vote to unionize at Marvel</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Visual-effects workers at Marvel Studios have voted to unionize and are seeking recognition from IATSE for better rights and protections.</li>
<li>This is the first time VFX professionals have united to demand their rights within the entertainment industry.</li>
<li>Workers have been denied benefits like paid overtime and healthcare, leading to labor shortages and unrealistic deadlines.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37041394">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>VFX workers at Marvel have voted to unionize due to being overworked and underpaid, with fixed-cost contracts resulting in extra work without extra compensation.</li>
<li>Studios may consider using generative AI to mitigate the impact of the union, which highlights the challenges faced by VFX artists.</li>
<li>The discussion also involves the impact of underbidding and contract layoffs, as well as the potential impact of generative AI on the industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.warpstream.com/blog/kafka-is-dead-long-live-kafka">Kafka is dead, long live Kafka</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author discusses the limitations and drawbacks of Kafka, a popular data streaming platform.</li>
<li>They introduce WarpStream as a cheaper and easier alternative to Kafka, running on commodity object storage like AWS S3.</li>
<li>WarpStream uses agents instead of brokers and separates data from metadata for scalability and faster recovery, reducing costs and operational overhead, although it has higher latency.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37036291">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Kafka is a widely used data technology, but opinions on it are divided.</li>
<li>Some users appreciate Kafka for its durability and fault-tolerance, while others find it complex and prefer simpler tools.</li>
<li>The article explores alternative messaging queues like RabbitMQ and discusses the benefits of using ClickHouse for data storage.</li>
<li>A cost-effective serverless Kafka solution called WarpStream is introduced, along with its architecture and trade-offs.</li>
<li>The challenges and costs of running Kafka on cloud providers are discussed, and WarpStream is presented as a potential alternative.</li>
<li>The effectiveness and management of Kafka as a data streaming platform are debated, and user feedback and future plans for WarpStream are addressed.</li>
<li>The article emphasizes the diversity of perspectives and alternative solutions in the data technology field.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Ask HN: What&#39;s the coolest physical thing you&#39;ve made?</h2>
<ul>
<li>The HN community is actively involved in various non-software projects and creations.</li>
<li>Members are engaging in a wide range of activities, including art, design, hardware, and physical products.</li>
<li>The community&#39;s diverse interests extend beyond software-related projects, showcasing the wide range of talents and interests among its members.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37033652">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text consists of online discussions revolving around various DIY projects and creations, including artwork, engineering, woodworking, telescope building, device repair, and airplane construction.</li>
<li>Users share their experiences and achievements in these areas, showcasing their creativity and skills.</li>
<li>The discussions also cover topics like career choices, living in remote locations, limitations in modifying devices, and the challenges and hazards involved in DIY renovations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://buttondown.email/hillelwayne/archive/raku-a-language-for-gremlins/">Raku: A language for gremlins</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author has added a new section on optimizing TLA+ model checking to learntla.</li>
<li>Due to a writing slump, the author has been learning the programming language Raku.</li>
<li>Raku is described as a language designed by intelligent gremlins, known for its use of Unicode operators and the ability to define new operators.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37040681">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article examines the subjective nature of programming languages, using the example of Raku and its placement on a 2D graph of surprise and delight/horror.</li>
<li>Commenters discuss the characteristics of programming languages such as Perl, C++, and C, sharing personal experiences and opinions on their surprises and challenges.</li>
<li>The conversation includes feedback on the documentation and features of Raku, as well as comparisons to other languages.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.zoom.us/zooms-term-service-ai/">How Zoom’s terms of service and practices apply to AI features</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Zoom has revised its terms of service to ensure that customer content is not utilized for training its AI models without consent.</li>
<li>The company is focused on offering transparency and user control over its AI features and the sharing of customer content.</li>
<li>Zoom emphasizes that customers maintain ownership and control over their content, and only utilizes it with permission for value-added services. Healthcare and education customers have specific agreements safeguarding their data. Zoom has also introduced generative AI features that can be enabled and monitored by account owners and administrators following transparent consent processes. The company is dedicated to prioritizing privacy and improving its services while upholding user rights.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37037196">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users have concerns about Zoom&#39;s terms of service and AI features, expressing skepticism about the company&#39;s marketing claims.</li>
<li>Worries about data usage, privacy, encryption, and attorney-client privilege are prevalent among Zoom users.</li>
<li>Mistrust and reluctance to use Zoom are common, leading to the exploration of alternative platforms and discussions around user data privacy and security.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.espn.com/nba/story/_/id/36146138/million-dollar-shot-michael-jordan-chicago-bulls-1993">The $1M shot that changed sports contests</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Don Calhoun&#39;s million-dollar shot during a Bulls game in 1993 caused a rise in sporting event contests and influenced the growth of SCA Promotions.</li>
<li>Initially, Calhoun had doubts about receiving his prize, but fan outrage helped him secure it.</li>
<li>Clarence Calhoun II&#39;s impressive college basketball shot also had a significant impact on his life and contributed to his family&#39;s success.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37033899">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Michael Calhoun made a half-court shot during a basketball game and won $1 million, valuing the ball more for sentimental reasons than its monetary worth.</li>
<li>Michael Jordan was involved in ensuring Calhoun received his prize.</li>
<li>The article discusses the impact of teaching others, the benefits of a better education system, failures of the public education system, disparities in cultural backgrounds, a basketball moment involving Michael Jordan, and a game between Barbados and Grenada, as well as the role of insurance companies in such contests.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/08/08</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-08T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-08-07]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1>2023-08-07</h1>
<h2><a href="https://explore.zoom.us/en/terms/">Zoom terms now allow training AI on user content with no opt out</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The passage is a terms of service agreement between Zoom Video Communications and its users.</li>
<li>It covers various aspects such as user&#39;s rights, ownership of services and software, payment obligations, tax requirements, dispute resolution, and other legal policies and guidelines.</li>
<li>Users are required to comply with these terms once they accept the agreement.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37021160">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Zoom&#39;s updated terms and conditions allow the company to use user content for AI training without an opt-out option, sparking concerns about privacy and trustworthiness.</li>
<li>Users compare Zoom&#39;s terms to Jitsi Meet, a video conferencing alternative, and debates arise regarding Jitsi Meet&#39;s capability to handle large conference calls, as well as privacy and reliability concerns with Zoom.</li>
<li>Discussions also touch on performance and battery drain issues with video chatting services, potential privacy issues associated with using Zoom for telehealth services, and the implications of Zoom using customer data for developing AI models. Mixed opinions emerge on the significance of Zoom&#39;s updated terms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://oimo.io/works/water/">Water</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The content is interactive and takes advantage of the device&#39;s motion capabilities.</li>
<li>Users can choose from different intensity levels, including low, medium, high, and super.</li>
<li>The interactive nature and intensity options provide a customizable and engaging user experience.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37026592">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Hacker News thread explores a website featuring a 3D water simulation that receives positive feedback for its impressive features and smooth performance.</li>
<li>Users propose adding new elements and discuss various potential applications for the simulation.</li>
<li>The thread also includes discussions around the accuracy of the simulation, impressive projects created using it, and user feedback. One user shares a personal anecdote about simulating fuel slosh and the possibility of disposing of related schematics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/supabase/postgres_lsp">Postgres Language Server</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>This language server is designed for PostgreSQL and adds features like auto-complete and go-to-definition to code editors.</li>
<li>It uses the actual PostgreSQL parser via libg_query, providing developers with more confidence and the ability to keep up with the rapid development of PostgreSQL.</li>
<li>It is in early development but is open for contributions from the community, with credit given to pganalyze and psteinroe for their work on libpg_query and the language server.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37020610">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Postgres Language Server is a new tool that improves code editors by adding features like auto-complete and documentation for Postgres using the actual Postgres parser.</li>
<li>It aims to enhance SQL and database tooling, which is often lacking in existing tools.</li>
<li>Users express interest in additional features and discuss limitations of current tools.</li>
<li>Another project called &quot;pg_langserver&quot; aims to provide similar language server features for PostgreSQL and is open to contributions.</li>
<li>Collaboration with other teams in the Postgres space has been helpful for the development of the Postgres Language Server.</li>
<li>The team is time-limited and currently unable to address compatibility issues with Windows.</li>
<li>They are open to assistance and suggest using alternative options like Remote ssh or accepting that Windows is a second-class citizen.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.rd.com/article/how-honest-are-dentists/">I went to 50 different dentists: almost all gave a different diagnosis (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The website rd.com is employing Cloudflare as a security service to safeguard against online attacks.</li>
<li>The user has been restricted from accessing the website and is advised to enable cookies and reach out to the site owner for a resolution.</li>
<li>No additional context or information is provided.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37022911">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The summary covers various discussions on healthcare, including conflicting diagnoses, skepticism towards medical professions, and challenges of integrating AI into medicine.</li>
<li>It also discusses comparisons of healthcare systems in different countries and difficulties in accessing healthcare.</li>
<li>The discussions emphasize the need for improvement in the healthcare system and the importance of advocating for oneself to receive quality care.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.everydayscientist.com/replace-peer-review-with-peer-replication/">Replace peer review with “peer replication” (2021)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author criticizes the current peer review process in scientific publishing as flawed and proposes a new approach called &quot;peer replication.&quot;</li>
<li>The proposed system would involve sending preprints to other labs for replication before acceptance and publication.</li>
<li>The author suggests that this approach would encourage replication and enhance scientific integrity but acknowledges challenges such as increased time and judgment calls when replications fail. They suggest starting with a trial conducted by an organization like Review Commons.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37021264">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion on Hacker News focuses on the challenges and potential solutions of replicating scientific research.</li>
<li>Some argue for the importance of replication to ensure the validity of findings, while others highlight practical and financial limitations.</li>
<li>Skepticism exists regarding the effectiveness of peer review in ensuring research validity, and concerns are raised about the credibility of scientific publishing, including the prevalence of fraud.</li>
<li>There is a recognition of the need for increased accountability in academia and improvements in the current system of scientific research and publishing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://hazlitt.net/feature/we-are-all-animals-night">We are all animals at night</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author shares their experiences working night shifts at a massage parlour and reflects on the waiting and diverse clientele they encounter.</li>
<li>They contrast the demands of their job with the stillness of the night, highlighting the power dynamics and inequalities in the sex trade and corporate sector.</li>
<li>The author emphasizes the value of night shift and low-skilled jobs, refuting notions of superiority, and discusses the potential dangers and negative effects of long-term night shift work.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37025621">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores various themes such as the author&#39;s perspective as a sex worker, entitlement in relationships, societal expectations for men, and the value of different types of work.</li>
<li>There is a focus on the importance of details in conveying a message and power dynamics between men and women.</li>
<li>The comments reflect a range of opinions, with some praising the writing style and others criticizing it as pseudo-intellectual.</li>
<li>The discussion also delves into potential solutions for problems like violence towards service industry workers and lack of job opportunities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~kovar/hall.html">Electron band structure in germanium, my ass (2000)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author criticizes the existing understanding of electron band structure in germanium and challenges the expected exponential relationship between resistivity and temperature.</li>
<li>The experimental results obtained by the author do not align with the predicted behavior, leading to frustration and questioning the pursuit of physics.</li>
<li>The difficulties encountered during the experiment contribute to the author&#39;s conclusion that their decision to study physics was a mistake.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37026780">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article on Hacker News explores a post from 2000 that addresses the difficulties and frustrations of conducting an electron band structure experiment in germanium.</li>
<li>Users on the site discuss their own experiences with lab work and provide insights into the significance of experimental physics education.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the value of troubleshooting skills, hands-on experience, and the unpredictable nature of experiments while also delving into negative experiences with physics and potential alternative career paths.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/paultassi/2023/08/06/baldurs-gate-3-prepared-for-100000-concurrent-players-theyve-gotten-700000/">‘Baldur’s Gate 3’ Prepared for 100k Concurrent Players, They’ve Gotten 700K</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Baldur&#39;s Gate 3, a single-player RPG game, has achieved a milestone by reaching 500,000 concurrent players on Steam, making it the third most played game on the platform.</li>
<li>The game has defied industry trends by capturing the interest of the general public, despite being a turn-based RPG.</li>
<li>Baldur&#39;s Gate 3 has also entered the top 10 peak playercounts in Steam history, positioning itself as a strong contender for Game of the Year.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37023089">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Baldur&#39;s Gate 3&quot; has exceeded expectations with 700,000 players, compared to the anticipated 100,000 concurrent players, thanks to factors such as the popularity of its predecessor and the brand power of Dungeons &amp; Dragons.</li>
<li>The game&#39;s Early Access release was highly popular, and it has been praised for its turn-based combat, writing, and immersive music.</li>
<li>Comments in the conversation reflect various perspectives on the game, including discussions about its difficulty level, availability of walkthroughs and character build videos, absence of microtransactions, and concerns about development and server capacity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.michaelgeist.ca/2023/08/metablockslinks/">Meta blocking news links in Canada</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Meta, the parent company of Facebook and Instagram, is blocking news links and sharing on its platforms in Canada due to Bill C-18, resulting in media sector losses.</li>
<li>Supporters of the bill disregarded Meta&#39;s warnings, leading to criticism of the government.</li>
<li>The article explores the potential development of content filtering capabilities by search and social media companies, comparing the approaches of Australia and Canada in negotiating deals with these companies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37025233">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Facebook&#39;s decision to block news links in Canada has sparked debate regarding the role of the platform as a news source.</li>
<li>Some argue that Facebook should prioritize connecting people rather than serving as a news platform.</li>
<li>Other points of discussion include the impact of social media on society, concerns about fake news, age-related technology preferences, and the influence of Canadian media outlets.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.thebignewsletter.com/p/the-first-big-antitrust-trial-of">The antitrust trial against Google is starting in September</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google is currently facing an antitrust trial where the government argues that it holds a monopoly on general search and search advertising with a market share of 90-95%.</li>
<li>The outcome of this trial could have significant implications for competition in the tech industry.</li>
<li>Google claims that its monopoly is legal as consumers prefer its search engine, but critics argue that the quality of its search engine has declined.</li>
<li>The trial is expected to last for two months and Google is also facing other antitrust cases related to its app store monopoly and monopolization of online advertising software.</li>
<li>The article highlights the relevance of past actions by YouTube and the influence of AT&amp;T in the rise of new providers and start-ups.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37023117">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The antitrust trial against Google is being discussed, with different opinions on whether Google&#39;s behavior is anti-competitive and if there is sufficient evidence to prove monopolization.</li>
<li>The dominance of large technology companies such as Apple and Microsoft is also mentioned, raising concerns about search engine optimization, algorithm automation, and the lack of interoperability between Apple and Google.</li>
<li>Debates surround the need for regulations, the effects on innovation and competition, and the potential consequences of breaking up large companies. Data privacy and advertising practices are also brought up in the discussion.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/08/07</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-07T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-08-06]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1>2023-08-06</h1>
<h2><a href="https://groups.google.com/g/vim_announce/c/tWahca9zkt4">Bram Moolenaar has died</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bram Moolenaar, the creator of VIM, unfortunately passed away on August 3, 2023, after a rapid progression of a medical condition.</li>
<li>A funeral service is being arranged in the Netherlands, and condolences can be sent to <a href="mailto:funer...@gmail.com">funer...@gmail.com</a>.</li>
<li>For any other matters, the family can be contacted as well.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37011324">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The creator of Vim, Bram Moolenaar, has sadly passed away, leading to an outpouring of gratitude and appreciation for his contributions to the software community.</li>
<li>Moolenaar was recognized not only for his work on Vim but also for his involvement in charitable efforts in Uganda.</li>
<li>Users of Vim are mourning his loss and sharing personal stories about their interactions with him, highlighting the impact Vim has had on their work. Some have even made donations to the charity supported by Moolenaar. The future of Vim remains uncertain, but its legacy and influence on the programming world are widely acknowledged.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://heather-buchel.com/blog/2023/07/just-normal-web-things/">Just normal web things</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Websites are increasingly limiting basic web functions like copying text, navigating links, and zooming in on browsers.</li>
<li>Lack of hover styles and hijacking of browser shortcuts are also identified as issues.</li>
<li>The author stresses the significance of preserving normal web interaction features and expresses dissatisfaction with the current state of web development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37013396">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Hacker News discussion revolves around frustrations with website design and functionality, including JavaScript manipulation of links, misuse of HTML elements, and overreliance on web frameworks.</li>
<li>Preserving link behavior and adhering to familiar design patterns are emphasized for improved usability.</li>
<li>Other topics discussed include the efficiency of modern web applications, security measures impacting user experience, and the importance of better password practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.funet.fi/">nic.funet.fi: Serving freely distributable files with FTP since 1990</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NIC.FUNET.FI is a long-standing website that has been offering freely distributable files through FTP since 1990.</li>
<li>The site provides shortcuts to a wide range of content, including Linux distributions, programming tools, networking software, and more.</li>
<li>It is operated by CSC, the Finnish IT center for science, and runs on a powerful Linux server with high-speed internet connectivity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37015585">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Participants discuss the historical significance and nostalgia of platforms like Nic.funet.fi, which has been using FTP to distribute files since 1990.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the outdated nature of FTP as a protocol and mentions alternatives like SSH.</li>
<li>Participants share anecdotes and express appreciation for the early internet and FTP as a resourceful protocol.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-acoustic-attack-steals-data-from-keystrokes-with-95-percent-accuracy/">New acoustic attack steals data from keystrokes with 95% accuracy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The website <a href="http://www.bleepingcomputer.com">www.bleepingcomputer.com</a> is using Cloudflare to enhance performance and security.</li>
<li>Before allowing users to proceed, the website checks the security of their connection.</li>
<li>This measure aims to ensure a safe browsing experience for its visitors.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37013704">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have developed an acoustic attack that can steal data from keystrokes, exposing security vulnerabilities in loud mechanical keyboards.</li>
<li>Countermeasures such as password managers and strong security measures are recommended to mitigate these risks.</li>
<li>The use of RTX Voice to remove keyboard typing noise and potential attacks using Zoom are discussed, highlighting the need for further research and safeguards against acoustic side-channel attacks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mkone.ai/blog/introducing-mk1">MK-1</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>MK-1 has introduced their first product, MKML, an inference runtime that aims to enhance the performance and efficiency of AI models.</li>
<li>MKML enables a 2x reduction in large language model (LLM) inference costs on GPUs with just a few lines of Python code.</li>
<li>It integrates seamlessly with popular ecosystems like Hugging Face and PyTorch and addresses the issue of large memory requirements by compressing the model size by approximately 60%. This optimization not only saves on GPU memory but also enhances inference speed.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37016413">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Hacker News comment thread discusses a new AI model called MK-1 that offers quantization methods.</li>
<li>Users are skeptical due to the lack of comparison with existing methods and question its marketing language and targeted use cases.</li>
<li>The co-founder defends the lack of comparison, highlighting different trade-offs and use cases.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/23/08/05/1632219/vims-creator-bram-moolenaar-dies-at-age-62">Vim&#39;s Creator Bram Moolenaar Dies at Age 62 – Slashdot</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bram Moolenaar, the creator of the Vim text editor, has sadly passed away at the age of 62.</li>
<li>The Vim community will continue to maintain and support Vim going forward.</li>
<li>The article highlights Moolenaar&#39;s significant contributions to the Vim community and his work in charityware. It also mentions the popularity of Vim modes and plugins in modern editors. A tribute is paid to Moolenaar for his invaluable contribution to the software development community.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37013887">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bram Moolenaar, the creator of Vim, has sadly passed away at the age of 62.</li>
<li>The news of his death sparked debates on online forums regarding whether multiple stories about him should be featured on the front page or if one story is enough.</li>
<li>Some users argue that separate accounts of his impact are worth reading, while others believe that one story is sufficient.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://traumbooks.itch.io/the-sad-bastard-cookbook">The Sad Bastard Cookbook: Food you can make so you don&#39;t die</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Sad Bastard Cookbook is a free resource for individuals who are going through difficult times and need practical ways to cope.</li>
<li>It offers a variety of recipes specifically tailored to address feelings of overwhelm, sadness, and even dealing with supernatural situations.</li>
<li>The cookbook&#39;s main objective is to provide a sense of comfort and connection during mealtime, serving as a reminder that others may also be facing similar challenges.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37019228">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;The Sad Bastard Cookbook&quot; is a practical guide designed for busy or unmotivated individuals, offering easy recipes like buying ready-made rotisserie chickens and frozen vegetables.</li>
<li>The book explores various cooking options, including the use of appliances like instant pots and air fryers.</li>
<li>Readers can engage in discussions about communal living, convenient modular kitchen appliances, meal replacement options, health risks of unsupervised fasting, and tips for adopting a healthier diet by cutting out sugary foods and unhealthy oils.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2023-08-03-IBM-and-NASA-Open-Source-Largest-Geospatial-AI-Foundation-Model-on-Hugging-Face?sf180690117=1">IBM and NASA open-source largest geospatial AI foundation model on Hugging Face</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>IBM and Hugging Face have partnered to release IBM&#39;s watsonx.ai geospatial foundation model on the Hugging Face platform.</li>
<li>The model, developed in collaboration with NASA, is the largest geospatial foundation model on Hugging Face and the first open-source AI foundation model from NASA.</li>
<li>Built from NASA&#39;s satellite data, the model aims to democratize access and application of AI in climate and Earth science and is part of NASA&#39;s Open-Source Science Initiative.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37015290">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>IBM and NASA have collaborated to release a geospatial AI model on the Hugging Face platform.</li>
<li>The model, called watsonx.ai geospatial foundation model, is trained on NASA&#39;s satellite data and can be used for various tasks like monitoring greenhouse gases, predicting crop yields, and tracking deforestation.</li>
<li>The open-source release of the model encourages collaboration and advancements in the field of AI and represents progress in using AI for climate and Earth science research.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://syzito.xyz/@selzero/110837319716739179">Jeremy Vaught spent 16 years to build @music on Twitter, then X took it away</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Jeremy Vaught, who spent 16 years building his Twitter username &quot;@music,&quot; had his username changed to &quot;@Musicfan&quot; without his followers being properly transferred.</li>
<li>This incident has sparked criticism of billionaire-owned platforms and prompted discussions about switching to alternative platforms like Mastodon.</li>
<li>Some users speculate that Vaught may have accepted a settlement or non-disparagement clause. However, he still considers Twitter his preferred social media platform.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37016876">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The removal of the username &quot;@music&quot; from its original user by Elon Musk has sparked a debate on digital ownership and control over usernames on social media platforms like Twitter.</li>
<li>The incident has led to discussions about the need for formalized standards and duties in digital platforms, including alternative options like open protocols or blockchain technology.</li>
<li>Users express dissatisfaction with changes made to platform policies, concerns about lack of control over digital identities, and the risks of relying on closed platforms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://southernillinoisnow.com/2023/08/05/ceos-pay-climbed-before-layoffs-at-tech-giants-like-alphabet-and-microsoft-data-shows/">CEOs’ pay climbed before layoffs at tech giants like Alphabet and Microsoft</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Tech giants like Alphabet and Microsoft experienced significant increases in CEO compensation in 2022, despite announcing layoffs.</li>
<li>Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai&#39;s compensation skyrocketed by 3,474% to over $225 million, while Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella received nearly $55 million, a 10% increase.</li>
<li>The rise in CEO pay while job losses are happening highlights the growing disparity between CEO and worker salaries in the tech industry and raises questions about whether companies should prioritize other stakeholders in their decision-making.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37016424">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The high pay of CEOs at tech giants like Alphabet and Microsoft, including Sundar Pichai&#39;s $225 million compensation, is the focal point of the discussion.</li>
<li>Critics argue that these salaries are excessive and could be better utilized for the benefit of more employees or the general population.</li>
<li>The article delves into the debate surrounding the justification and measurement of CEO pay, as well as the impact of their decisions on society, the environment, shareholder interests, and wealth inequality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/08/06</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-06T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-08-05]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1>2023-08-05</h1>
<h2><a href="https://clojure.org/news/2023/08/04/next-rich">(next Rich)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Rich Hickey, the creator of Clojure, has announced his retirement from commercial software development.</li>
<li>Hickey will continue to lead the ongoing development of Clojure as an independent developer, along with the support of Alex, Stu, Fogus, and others.</li>
<li>Nubank has been thanked for their support and sponsorship of the core team, and Hickey expressed his appreciation for his colleagues at Cognitect.</li>
<li>Hickey also mentioned the new free availability of Datomic, highlighting his return to the freedom and independence he had when originally developing Clojure.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37000562">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Rich Hickey, the creator of Clojure programming language, is retiring, sparking discussions on the impact of his work.</li>
<li>Many users express gratitude for Hickey&#39;s contributions and the positive influence he has had on their careers.</li>
<li>The article mentions the benefits and drawbacks of Clojure and highlights Hickey&#39;s talks and ideas on software development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2023/08/04/comcast-centurylink-fail-to-derail-community-owned-gigabit-fiber-network-in-bountiful-utah/">Comcast, CenturyLink fail to derail Utah community-owned gigabit fiber network</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Regional telecom monopolies in Bountiful, Utah are resisting community-owned broadband networks, causing pushback and potential barriers for these initiatives.</li>
<li>The use of VPNs to access streaming services from abroad raises concerns about privacy risks.</li>
<li>There is a ongoing debate about whether a municipal broadband project should be subject to a public vote, leading to discussions on government research, funding for fiber networks, infrastructure projects, and community broadband. Additionally, discussions on various topics are happening on Twitter, and there have been issues with Patreon&#39;s payment processing, API changes, and positive feedback on a privacy extension.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37001369">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Participants discuss the benefits of community-owned fiber networks and municipal broadband, highlighting faster and cheaper internet options.</li>
<li>The need for competition in the market is emphasized, with frustrations expressed about current internet service.</li>
<li>Corruption, market control, and lobbying by large ISPs are mentioned as drawbacks to the current system.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://kagi.com/stats">Most promoted and blocked domains among Kagi Search users</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Kagi users create personalizations for popular domains such as Pinterest, Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter.</li>
<li>News sites like Fox News, CNN, and The New York Times are also popular domains for Kagi users.</li>
<li>Kagi is a universal summarizer tool that aims to humanize the web by providing personalized summaries for these domains.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37006082">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Kagi Search offers customizable search results by allowing users to promote and block domains.</li>
<li>The article compares Kagi to Google and emphasizes the benefits of personalized search results.</li>
<li>It concludes that while this feature is valuable for niche search engines like Kagi, it may not be necessary for more established ones.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/andrewmccalip/status/1687405505604734978">Andrew McCalip demonstrates synthesis of LK99</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Andrew McCalip created rocks on Day 8.5, focusing on the Meissner effect.</li>
<li>The Meissner effect is a phenomenon in which a superconductor expels all magnetic fields from its interior when it transitions into the superconducting state.</li>
<li>This creation by McCalip highlights the significance of the Meissner effect in the field of superconductivity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36997821">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions encompass a range of topics, including the replication and credibility of the superconductor material LK99, the significance of time and rigorous verification in scientific research, and debates on gatekeeping and open access to information.</li>
<li>Opinions on the recent claim of room-temperature superconductivity and the different approaches of US and Chinese labs are also being discussed.</li>
<li>Issues related to academia and scientific funding, skepticism towards claims made on Twitter, the potential implications of room temperature superconductors, and frustrations with platforms like Twitter and paywalled content are also part of the conversation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/4/23820710/pay-no-attention-to-the-usb-port-behind-the-no-usb-sticker">Pay no attention to the USB port behind the “no USB” sticker</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the use of stickers on USB ports of HP printers to promote wireless printing.</li>
<li>The author finds it amusing to observe people removing the stickers and connecting their printers via USB.</li>
<li>The purpose of the stickers is to encourage users to utilize the wireless printing functionality of the HP printers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37006705">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Hacker News discussion covers a range of topics including private companies in regulation, food product quality, corporate influence, selling Hershey&#39;s chocolate in Germany, printer issues, and frustrations with printer companies.</li>
<li>Users share their experiences, opinions, and concerns, emphasizing the importance of government regulation, the impact of consumer choice, and the challenges of open-source printers.</li>
<li>The discussion primarily focuses on the quality, reliability, deceptive practices, and high costs associated with certain consumer brands.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-02481-0">LK-99 is an online sensation but replication efforts fall short</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A Korean team has made claims of discovering a room temperature superconductor named LK-99, which has received significant attention.</li>
<li>However, attempts to replicate the results have been unsuccessful thus far, casting doubt on the validity of the claims.</li>
<li>Multiple replication efforts have not observed any signs of superconductivity in LK-99, leading scientists to remain skeptical of its existence as a superconductor at ambient conditions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37001837">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>There is a discussion surrounding a potential room temperature superconductor called LK-99.</li>
<li>Some are excited about the possibility, while skeptics criticize the lack of evidence and replication attempts.</li>
<li>The implications and applications of a room temperature superconductor are highlighted, but caution and further research are urged.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ben.balter.com/2023/08/04/remote-work-communicate-more-with-less/">Remote work requires communicating more, but less frequently</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Remote work requires frequent and rich communication, with a focus on asynchronous methods like writing and videos for reflection and synthesis.</li>
<li>Effective communication in remote work involves choosing the appropriate medium, clear writing, and engaging videos.</li>
<li>Proactive, regular, and asynchronous communication is encouraged, while synchronous communication is reserved for urgent or complex matters.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37000981">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Participants discuss the challenges and benefits of remote work, with a focus on communication, socialization, mentorship, and productivity.</li>
<li>The effectiveness of different communication methods and the importance of social interaction are examined in relation to remote work.</li>
<li>The impact of remote work on collaboration and problem-solving is explored, as well as the challenges faced by junior employees and the value of mentorship. Creating a supportive team culture and being adaptable are also emphasized in remote work environments.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://152334H.github.io/blog/non-determinism-in-gpt-4/">Non-determinism in GPT-4 is caused by Sparse MoE</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author examines the non-deterministic behavior of GPT-4 and attributes it to the Sparse MoE architecture&#39;s failure to enforce per-sequence determinism.</li>
<li>Experimental results and comparisons with other models are provided to support this hypothesis.</li>
<li>The implications of these findings on GPT-3.5-Turbo, which may have a similar architecture, are also explored.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37006224">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on determinism in AI models, particularly GPT-3 and GPT-4, and how the use of sparse MoE can lead to non-deterministic behavior.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about potential side channel attacks and the impact on reliability and adoption of AI models.</li>
<li>There is a debate about whether the non-deterministic behavior is a bug or intentional design choice, with some arguing that sacrificing determinism for performance is acceptable. Reading scientific papers, understanding context, and honing in on specific interests are highlighted as important practices in the field of AI and machine learning.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/hankgreen/status/1687535525169930241">Reduction of sulfur emissions from ships may be causing rising sea temperatures</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Accidental geoengineering, which has been occurring for decades, is believed to have contributed to an alarming spike.</li>
<li>However, the accidental geoengineering has now ceased, potentially indicating a decline in the spike.</li>
<li>This science story has been overlooked due to current events, but it sheds light on a possible cause for the spike.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37008034">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions center around the challenges and potential solutions for addressing climate change.</li>
<li>There is debate about the effectiveness and risks of geoengineering, including sulfur emissions reduction and atmospheric injection of SO2.</li>
<li>Participants highlight the need for lifestyle changes, technological advancements, and a global shift in mindset to combat climate change.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about the urgency of the climate crisis and the effectiveness of current measures.</li>
<li>Climate models, political and economic systems, and the potential consequences of underestimating temperature rise are discussed.</li>
<li>Topics like immigrants, manipulation of the masses, and books related to climate change are touched upon.</li>
<li>The debate also extends to the construction of new nuclear power plants and the decarbonization of electricity grids.</li>
<li>Solutions like carbon capture, solar and battery technologies, and reducing the global population are mentioned, with differing perspectives on their feasibility and effectiveness.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-66387537">Ocean Heat Record Broken</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The oceans have reached their highest recorded temperature, surpassing the previous record with an average daily global sea surface temperature of 20.96C (69.73F).</li>
<li>Warmer oceans contribute to higher greenhouse gas levels as they have reduced ability to absorb carbon dioxide.</li>
<li>Rising ocean temperatures have negative impacts such as disrupting marine species, affecting fish stocks, accelerating glacier melting, and causing sea level rise.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36997834">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion on Hacker News covers various topics such as capitalism, technological progress, consumerism, climate change, and population growth.</li>
<li>Participants express concerns about the negative effects of greed and profit-seeking behavior on society and the environment.</li>
<li>Alternative solutions to address wealth inequality and the climate crisis are proposed, with a focus on global leadership and immediate action to combat climate change.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/08/05</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-05T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-08-04]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1>2023-08-04</h1>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.01516">Successful room temperature ambient-pressure magnetic levitation of LK-99</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have synthesized LK-99 crystals capable of magnetic levitation at room temperature.</li>
<li>Previous studies have shown that LK-99 materials exhibit the Meissner levitation phenomenon and have a higher superconducting transition temperature than originally believed.</li>
<li>This research implies that non-contact, superconducting magnetic levitation at room temperature could become a reality soon.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36994214">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The summary covers a range of topics, including the controversy surrounding a leaked paper on a room temperature superconductor and the banning of cars in city centers.</li>
<li>It also includes discussions on the significance of inventions throughout history, potential cancer cures, future scientific breakthroughs, limitations and potential of AI chat bots, and advancements in physics, philosophy, and technology.</li>
<li>The post offers a diverse and comprehensive exploration of various subjects relevant to technology and science.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://taylor.town/entire-career">Man spends entire career mastering crappy codebase</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Software developer Arthur Westbrook is retiring after a 35-year career working with a codebase for medical software.</li>
<li>Westbrook is highly regarded for his expertise in working with legacy code and has made significant contributions to the codebase.</li>
<li>His retirement will require the hiring of two junior developers to fill his role, highlighting the impact he has had on the project.</li>
<li>In recognition of his service, a coworker plans to treat Westbrook to drinks.</li>
<li>During retirement, Westbrook plans to pursue street performance, dumpster diving, and culinary experimentation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36984282">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hacker News forum discussions cover a wide range of topics including working with outdated technologies, transitioning to new jobs, high-frequency trading, work-life balance, retirement, skill development, talent in software development, the impact of having children, and finding fulfillment in one&#39;s job.</li>
<li>The conversations on the forum provide diverse experiences, perspectives, and insights into societal pressures related to the tech industry.</li>
<li>The discussions on Hacker News offer valuable insights and perspectives for software engineers and individuals interested in the tech industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://electrek.co/2023/08/03/hackers-manage-unlock-tesla-software-locked-features/">Hackers manage to unlock Tesla software-locked features</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Hackers have discovered an exploit that can unlock software-locked features in Tesla vehicles, such as heated seats and the Full Self-Driving package.</li>
<li>The hack requires physical access to the car and involves a voltage fault injection attack on the infotainment system.</li>
<li>The hackers claim their &quot;Tesla Jailbreak&quot; is unpatchable and allows for running arbitrary software on the infotainment system, potentially unlocking all software-locked features.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36988262">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation covers the hacking of software-locked features in Tesla vehicles, highlighting potential security vulnerabilities.</li>
<li>It explores privacy laws regarding dash cams and CCTV, emphasizing the need for responsible and legal use of surveillance technology.</li>
<li>The discussion underscores the importance of home security and the advantages and disadvantages of security cameras.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://wiki.alopex.li/ElixirForCynicalCurmudgeons">Elixir for cynical curmudgeons</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author shares their initial skepticism of the Elixir language and their lack of experience with web programming.</li>
<li>After reading tutorials and understanding its similarities to Lisp and integration with Erlang, the author becomes interested in Elixir.</li>
<li>The Phoenix web framework is praised as an example of how to write complex Elixir programs, despite the author&#39;s initial confusion with syntactic sugar and macros. Additionally, the author highlights the robustness, multiprocessing power, transparency, and the use of lists, tuples, and atoms in Erlang and Elixir.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36986769">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions revolve around various aspects of the Elixir programming language and its frameworks, including syntax, concurrency capabilities, and simplified production environment.</li>
<li>Participants express admiration for Elixir&#39;s syntax and its usefulness for writing quick scripts, comparing it to other languages like Ruby and Python.</li>
<li>Maco usage in Elixir is also explored, with different opinions on their effectiveness and necessity. Other topics include the readability and usability of Elixir and Clojure, challenges of using Elixir on Windows, and the significance of static typing in different programming languages.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-aws-public-ipv4-address-charge-public-ip-insights/">AWS to begin charging for public IPv4 addresses</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Starting from February 1, 2024, AWS will implement a charge of $0.005 per IP address per hour for public IPv4 addresses across all AWS services.</li>
<li>This change is motivated by the growing shortage of IPv4 addresses and is intended to promote the adoption of IPv6.</li>
<li>AWS is also introducing Public IP Insights, a free feature that enables users to monitor and analyze their usage of public IPv4 addresses.</li>
<li>For the first 12 months from February 1, 2024, the AWS Free Tier for EC2 will include 750 hours of public IPv4 address usage per month.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36989798">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>AWS has implemented charges for public IPv4 addresses, leading to dissatisfaction among users.</li>
<li>Users have praised Google Cloud&#39;s solution and suggested alternatives such as using NAT instances or Linux VMs.</li>
<li>Frustration exists regarding the costs and design of the VPC internals in AWS, as well as concerns about the price increase of Elastic IP addresses.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2023-08-03-IBM-and-NASA-Open-Source-Largest-Geospatial-AI-Foundation-Model-on-Hugging-Face">IBM and NASA Open Source Largest Geospatial AI Foundation Model on Hugging Face</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>IBM and Hugging Face have collaborated to release IBM&#39;s geospatial foundation model, based on NASA&#39;s satellite data, on the Hugging Face platform.</li>
<li>This is the largest geospatial foundation model on Hugging Face and the first open-source AI foundation model developed with NASA.</li>
<li>The goal is to make AI more accessible in climate and Earth science and advance critical areas like climate change.</li>
<li>The model has demonstrated promising results in analyzing satellite data for tasks such as tracking deforestation and predicting crop yields.</li>
<li>A commercial version of the model will be released through IBM&#39;s Environmental Intelligence Suite in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36985197">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>IBM and NASA have collaborated to release a large geospatial AI model called Prithvi on Hugging Face&#39;s platform.</li>
<li>Prithvi is designed for the scientific community and focuses on analyzing satellite images to classify land usage, track deforestation, predict crop yields, and monitor greenhouse gases.</li>
<li>Critics have expressed concerns about the lack of detailed information regarding the capabilities of the model in the press release.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/03/fcc-fines-robocaller-a-record-300m-after-blocking-billions-of-their-scam-calls/">FCC fines robocaller a record $300M after blocking billions of their scam calls</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The FCC has imposed a record-breaking fine of $300 million on a robocaller for engaging in a scam scheme since 2018.</li>
<li>The robocaller used different names and pretended to be a company selling auto warranties to collect personal information.</li>
<li>While the FCC&#39;s efforts, including partnerships with state law enforcement, have significantly reduced auto warranty calls by 99%, it is unclear if and when the fine will be paid due to the FCC&#39;s limited authority in collecting fines effectively.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36989845">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article focuses on the issue of robocalls and unwanted phone calls, which are seen as a significant annoyance and inconvenience.</li>
<li>Various potential solutions are discussed, including stricter regulations, fines for telcos, and identifying the origin of calls.</li>
<li>There is frustration with Apple&#39;s handling of spam, leading some to consider switching to Android, which is believed to have more effective robocall screening.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/compendium/network-protocols?share_key=97d3ba4c24d21147">Network protocols for anyone who knows a programming language</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The passage covers various topics related to networking, including the network stack, network routing, packet switching, TCP, and HTTP.</li>
<li>It explains concepts such as TCP slow start, packet loss and retransmission, Ethernet as a physical layer protocol, and the layered structure of internet protocols.</li>
<li>The influence of payload size on modern protocols like HTTP/2 is discussed, and the choice of 1,500 bytes as the Ethernet payload size is described as a trade-off for efficiency.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36984171">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion on Hacker News revolves around network protocols and interpacket gaps in data transmission.</li>
<li>It includes information on the history of Ethernet, multiple access protocols, and the role of IP addresses in communication.</li>
<li>Recommended books on the origins of the internet are mentioned in the conversation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/ErwannMillon/Color-diffusion">Color-Diffusion: using diffusion models to colorize black and white images</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The project utilizes diffusion models to add color to black and white images, employing the LAB color space and a UNet model to predict color noise.</li>
<li>It serves as a proof of concept, showcasing the potential for improvement by incorporating pretrained face recognition networks and implementing cross attention.</li>
<li>The project provides instructions for usage, including downloading the dataset and executing the colorization process, while acknowledging the code and resources used from other repositories.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36991293">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Diffusion models and neural networks are being used for colorizing black and white images.</li>
<li>The debate revolves around the credibility and historical accuracy of colorization.</li>
<li>Some view colorization as a form of art and creative expression, while others worry about its potential to distort history.</li>
<li>The introduction of AI in colorization raises concerns about automation and the subjective nature of color perception.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://hydra-so.notion.site/Hydra-1-0-beta-318504444825401e8ce21796dcadd589">Show HN: Hydra 1.0 – open-source column-oriented Postgres</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Hydra is an open-source, column-oriented version of Postgres designed to handle large datasets and enable fast aggregation of data.</li>
<li>Analytical queries on Postgres can be time-consuming and resource-intensive, but Hydra eliminates these issues.</li>
<li>The latest version, Hydra 1.0, is available for users to try out and provide feedback, with a full release planned in the near future. A free tier on the cloud allows users to explore Hydra&#39;s capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36987920">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hydra 1.0 is an open-source, column-oriented version of Postgres designed for faster aggregates and queries on large datasets.</li>
<li>It automatically loads data into a columnar format, supports compression, and is compatible with popular Postgres clients.</li>
<li>The project is planning to release version 1.0 soon and offers a free tier for users to try it out.</li>
<li>Comparisons between Hydra and other columnar storage options like Citus have sparked discussions on performance and benefits.</li>
<li>The passage also introduces the concept of tables with multiple columns and suggests using a sparse set data structure for evaluating predicates and tracking matching values in columns.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/08/04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-04T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-08-03]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1>2023-08-03</h1>
<h2><a href="https://ai.meta.com/blog/audiocraft-musicgen-audiogen-encodec-generative-ai-audio/">Open-sourcing AudioCraft: Generative AI for audio</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>AudioCraft is a framework developed by Meta for generating high-quality audio and music from text-based user inputs.</li>
<li>It consists of three models: MusicGen, AudioGen, and EnCodec.</li>
<li>MusicGen generates music, while AudioGen generates audio from text inputs.</li>
<li>The EnCodec decoder has been improved to provide higher quality music generation.</li>
<li>The models are available for research purposes and can be trained with custom datasets.</li>
<li>AudioCraft simplifies the design of generative models for audio and allows for the development of new models.</li>
<li>It addresses the challenge of generating high-fidelity audio by learning from raw audio signals.</li>
<li>The models have applications in music generation, sound effects, and compression.</li>
<li>The research behind AudioCraft aims to improve the quality and controllability of generative AI audio models.</li>
<li>The models are open-source to promote collaboration and innovation in the research community.</li>
<li>AudioCraft is seen as a tool for musicians and sound designers, improving the creative iteration process in creative industries.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36972347">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta, the parent company of Facebook, has released an open-source generative AI system called AudioCraft for creating music and audio based on user inputs.</li>
<li>There is a debate about the licensing of AudioCraft&#39;s weights and whether its noncommercial license restricts commercial use.</li>
<li>The discussion also revolves around issues of data ownership, privacy, and the authenticity of AI-generated content.</li>
<li>Some users express skepticism and concern about the potential misuse of generative AI technology and its impact on media manipulation, trust, and the music industry.</li>
<li>Criticisms are made about the quality of the generated music, while others discuss the possibilities and limitations of AI-generated music.</li>
<li>Overall, opinions are mixed regarding the potential and challenges of using AI for creative purposes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ollama.ai/blog/run-llama2-uncensored-locally">Run Llama 2 uncensored locally</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The summary discusses the availability and features of different uncensored machine learning models: Llama 2 7B, Nous Hermes Llama 2 13B, and Wizard Vicuna 13B.</li>
<li>It provides example outputs showcasing the differences between censored and uncensored versions of these models in response to various prompts related to movies, cooking, religious literature, medical information, and general information.</li>
<li>The summary mentions that Eric Hartford is the author of a popular blog post on uncensored models.</li>
<li>There is a disclaimer about the potential risks associated with using uncensored models.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36973584">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta has released the Llama 2 AI model, sparking a discussion on Hacker News.</li>
<li>Users are discussing the censorship and biases found in AI models.</li>
<li>There is a debate on the trade-offs between using censored and uncensored variants of AI models.</li>
<li>Participants are exploring the limitations and potential dangers of fine-tuned language models.</li>
<li>Obtaining correct answers from censored models is proving to be difficult.</li>
<li>There is a call for transparency and open approaches in the AI community.</li>
<li>The conversation touches on topics like the definition of God and experiences with OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT model.</li>
<li>The inclusion of new software on different platforms is also discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/lipez400/status/1686793608626663441">LK-99: Team of Southeast University observed zero resistance below 110 K</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers at Southeast University have found a superconductor material with zero electrical resistance.</li>
<li>This discovery was made at temperatures below 110 K.</li>
<li>Superconductors are materials that can conduct electricity without any resistance.</li>
<li>Zero electrical resistance is a significant breakthrough in the field of superconductivity.</li>
<li>This finding could have significant implications for various industries, including energy transmission and storage.</li>
<li>Further research is needed to understand the mechanisms behind this phenomenon and to explore potential applications.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36974681">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Scientists have observed zero resistance below 110 K, potentially indicating high-temperature superconductivity.</li>
<li>Skepticism remains due to limitations in testing apparatus and inconsistent results.</li>
<li>Manufacturing room temperature superconductors is challenging, with mixed opinions on its feasibility.</li>
<li>A new family of high-temperature superconductors, LK-99, has been discovered, but room temperature superconductivity has not been achieved yet.</li>
<li>There is a debate on the characteristics and limitations of LK99, with replication attempts showing variability.</li>
<li>Ongoing research is focused on replicating the results and exploring potential practical applications.</li>
<li>A material exhibiting superconductivity at 15 degrees Celsius has been discovered, with potential applications in various fields.</li>
<li>Claims of high-temperature superconductivity are being examined, with discussions on possible impurities or synthesis issues.</li>
<li>Scientists from US/EU labs are conducting research on the LK-99 superconductor, attempting to reproduce the results while addressing skepticism about noise levels in the measurements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://praveshkoirala.com/2023/06/13/a-non-mathematical-introduction-to-kalman-filters-for-programmers/">A non-mathematical introduction to Kalman filters for programmers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces the concept of Kalman filters, which condense information from multiple noisy sources to provide a more accurate estimate.</li>
<li>Kalman filters are explained using a fictional ship scenario as an example.</li>
<li>Combining data from different sources using a weighted average is important for improving accuracy.</li>
<li>Code is highlighted as a useful tool for understanding complex concepts like Kalman filters.</li>
<li>The normal distribution function is briefly explained and its role in generating random numbers centered around zero is discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36971975">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the teaching approach for signal processing teachers in college, specifically the suggestion to teach Kalman Filters with simplicity and intuition before rigor.</li>
<li>The comment section provides different perspectives on this approach, emphasizing the importance of context, motivation, and understanding fundamental concepts.</li>
<li>The discussion also explores topics such as numerical instability, uncertainty in measurements, and implementing extended Kalman filters for non-linear problems.</li>
<li>The conversation touches upon probabilistic programming languages and algorithms, discussing their benefits and limitations.</li>
<li>The article explains that a Kalman filter is a mathematical model used for estimation in situations with measurement errors and limited observations, commonly used in GPS tracking and robotics.</li>
<li>The summary highlights the usefulness and limitations of Kalman filters, their application in different fields, and the importance of accurate estimation of variance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.01192">Observation of zero resistance above 100 K in Pb₁₀₋ₓCuₓ(PO₄)₆O</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the recent discovery of room-temperature superconductivity in the material Pb_{10-x}Cu_x(PO_4)_6O.</li>
<li>The material shows zero resistance above 100 degrees K under ambient pressure, indicating its potential as a high-temperature superconductor.</li>
<li>The study confirms the material&#39;s structural consistency, adding credibility to the discovery.</li>
<li>This discovery has attracted global interest in the scientific community.</li>
<li>The research is supported by the Simons Foundation and member institutions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36979886">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Scientists have observed potential room temperature superconductivity in a compound called Pb₁₀₋ₓCuₓ(PO₄)₆O.</li>
<li>Replication of the results has been difficult due to poor documentation and varying outcomes.</li>
<li>The findings suggest something interesting is happening, but skeptics remain.</li>
<li>The discussion involves skepticism, optimism, challenges in scientific replication, and potential applications of the superconductor.</li>
<li>Varying opinions exist on the significance of the discovery and the need for more conclusive evidence.</li>
<li>The debate also touches on measurement techniques, similarities to previous controversial experiments, and motivations to replicate the results.</li>
<li>Despite the potential benefits and implications, skepticism remains regarding room temperature superconductivity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://chargebackstop.com/blog/card-networks-exploitation/">The underground world of credit card network exploitation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author, a founding engineer at ChargebackStop.com, experienced a card testing attack targeted at their company.</li>
<li>The attackers likely obtained a list of cards with similar parameters from an underground network that shares credit card information.</li>
<li>The author implemented measures such as using Stripe Radar and creating custom rules to prevent future attacks.</li>
<li>The company faced financial losses from fraudulent charges and chargebacks as a result of the attack.</li>
<li>The author criticizes the payment network for imposing unfair treatment and costs on businesses and emphasizes the need for banks to take more responsibility in authorizing transactions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36971888">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the use of AI language models, specifically ChatGPT, in coding workflows for payments processing and chargebacks in credit card networks.</li>
<li>Users express concerns about relying solely on AI-generated code for critical financial processes.</li>
<li>Some argue that AI can be a productive tool when used with caution and thorough human review.</li>
<li>The conversation also covers topics such as credit card fraud, security measures, different payment systems, and regional differences in banking technology and regulations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://thewhyaxis.substack.com/p/cops-still-take-more-stuff-from-people">Cops still take more stuff from people than burglars do (2021)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Civil asset forfeiture is a controversial practice in which law enforcement can seize cash and property from individuals without charging them with a crime.</li>
<li>This practice was originally meant to target organized crime but is now frequently used against regular citizens.</li>
<li>Between 2000 and 2019, authorities in the US seized around $69 billion from people, most of whom were not charged with any wrongdoing.</li>
<li>In 2019, federal authorities took more cash and property from individuals than burglars did.</li>
<li>Individuals face the burden of proof to reclaim their seized assets, which often leads to expensive legal battles.</li>
<li>Some lawmakers advocate for reform, but many in law enforcement and their elected representatives oppose changes to the practice.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36975143">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on civil asset forfeiture and its various aspects, including legality, ethics, and potential for abuse.</li>
<li>Broader issues such as systemic racism, economic exploitation, and police misconduct are also part of the conversation.</li>
<li>Participants hold different perspectives on the role of police, the need for reform, and the impact of civil asset forfeiture on individuals&#39; rights.</li>
<li>Historical origins of policing, concerns about the burden of proof, and discussions on wage theft and social programs are mentioned.</li>
<li>Overall, the discussion reflects the complexity and ongoing debates surrounding civil asset forfeiture and related issues.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2023/08/02/googles-plan-to-drm-the-web-goes-against-everything-google-once-stood-for/">Google’s Plan to DRM the Web Goes Against Everything Google Once Stood For</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google has proposed a system called &quot;Web Environment Integrity&quot; that is being referred to as DRM for the web.</li>
<li>Critics have expressed concern about the potential for abuse and limitation of user autonomy that this system could bring.</li>
<li>The proposal contradicts Google&#39;s previous stance of promoting open and innovative technologies.</li>
<li>The system would give websites control over users&#39; computers, raising concerns about centralization of power and restriction of user control.</li>
<li>The comment thread also discusses concerns about Google&#39;s actions, the importance of browser control, and unrelated topics.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36981953">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google is facing debates and concerns related to its proposed implementation of DRM on the web.</li>
<li>There is potential for antitrust action and calls to break up the company.</li>
<li>The profitability of Google Cloud is a subject of discussion.</li>
<li>There are concerns about the implications of weakening Big Tech.</li>
<li>The article explores Google&#39;s reputation and its impact on user privacy.</li>
<li>Alternatives to Google&#39;s services, including the Brave browser, are discussed.</li>
<li>Remote attestation and secure computing concepts are explored.</li>
<li>The role of tech media outlets in shaping public opinion and awareness is mentioned.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/b9582d62-cc6f-4b76-b0f9-5b37cf15dce4">Companies with good ESG scores pollute as much as low-rated rivals</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Companies with high ESG scores pollute just as much as low-rated companies, according to research by Scientific Beta.</li>
<li>There is no correlation between ESG scores and carbon intensity, even when only considering the environmental component of the metric.</li>
<li>This challenges the belief that ESG investments create low-carbon portfolios.</li>
<li>Including social or governance ratings alongside carbon intensity leads to less green portfolios compared to those based on market capitalization.</li>
<li>The effectiveness of ESG as a mass-market product is questioned, and investors should carefully prioritize sustainability when making investment decisions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36973807">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>There is ongoing debate about the effectiveness and limitations of ESG scores in evaluating company performance.</li>
<li>Critics argue that ESG scores can be manipulated and influenced by political bias.</li>
<li>There are concerns about the accuracy and reliability of ESG ratings.</li>
<li>The focus and goals of ESG criteria are subjects of debate.</li>
<li>The discussions also touch on the involvement of investment management companies and diversity initiatives in hiring practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://pluralistic.net/2023/07/31/seize-the-means-of-computation/#the-internet-con">Kickstarting a book to end enshittification, because Amazon will not carry it</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Cory Doctorow is crowdfunding his book &quot;The Internet Con: How to Seize the Means of Computation&quot; on Kickstarter.</li>
<li>Amazon refused to sell his audiobook because Doctorow refuses to use DRM (Digital Rights Management).</li>
<li>The book explores the decline of the internet and offers solutions such as interoperability.</li>
<li>Doctorow sells DRM-free audiobooks through Kickstarter and recommends alternative options like Libro.fm.</li>
<li>The summary includes Doctorow&#39;s personal connection to audiobooks and his experience producing them.</li>
<li>The summary also mentions Doctorow&#39;s other works, upcoming projects, and different ways to access his content.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36974082">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Authors raise concerns about Audible&#39;s unfair payment practices compared to other digital goods platforms.</li>
<li>Criticism is directed at Audible&#39;s business practices for limiting consumer choices in the audiobook market.</li>
<li>The article delves into the subjects of DRM, Audible&#39;s market dominance, and the need for alternative platforms.</li>
<li>Comments highlight worries about tech monopolies, audiobooks, government intervention, and negative experiences with a website.</li>
<li>The TV app is briefly mentioned in relation to user restrictions on owning purchased content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/08/03</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-03T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-08-02]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1>2023-08-02</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/content/blog-post/room-temperature-superconductor-new-developments">A room-temperature superconductor? New developments</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Claims of a room-temperature superconductor called LK-99 have been made recently.</li>
<li>The material is said to be easy to prepare and does not require exotic materials or equipment.</li>
<li>Replication of the results may be challenging due to the heterogeneity of the samples.</li>
<li>There has been infighting among the authors of the preprints, causing some uncertainty.</li>
<li>A lab in China claims to have replicated the material, but it has not been verified yet.</li>
<li>Two new preprints using density functional theory calculations suggest that the material could work as a superconductor.</li>
<li>Guarded optimism exists regarding the potential of room-temperature superconductivity.</li>
<li>More replication data is needed to confirm these claims.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36957678">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Scientists are researching the development of room-temperature superconductors, which could revolutionize technology.</li>
<li>Room-temperature superconductors could enable lossless energy transport and lead to faster charging batteries and more efficient CPUs.</li>
<li>Existing superconducting circuits have limitations, indicating the need for further development.</li>
<li>Superconductors have the potential to impact power transmission, electronic devices, and high-energy applications.</li>
<li>Challenges in manufacturing and scalability need to be addressed on the path to commercialization.</li>
<li>There is a discussion regarding China&#39;s growing scientific influence and its potential impact on the US, including comparisons in R&amp;D investment and scientific talent.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2023/08/pixar-adobe-apple-autodesk-and-nvidia-form-alliance-for-openusd/">Pixar, Adobe, Apple, Autodesk, and Nvidia form alliance for OpenUSD</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Pixar, Adobe, Apple, Autodesk, and NVIDIA have formed an alliance called AOUSD to advance the development and standardization of Pixar&#39;s Universal Scene Description technology, known as OpenUSD.</li>
<li>OpenUSD is a high-performance 3D scene description technology that enables collaborative artistic expression and streamlines content production.</li>
<li>The alliance aims to enhance the interoperability of 3D tools and data and will work with other companies to shape the future of OpenUSD.</li>
<li>The AOUSD steering committee will promote the technology at industry events, with a particular focus on driving 3D interoperability and accelerating augmented reality experiences.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36960625">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Pixar, Adobe, Apple, Autodesk, and Nvidia have formed the OpenUSD alliance to standardize 3D graphics technology.</li>
<li>The goal is to make it easier to build high-performance rendering and improve compatibility across different tools and industries.</li>
<li>Concerns about latency and performance on mobile devices have been raised.</li>
<li>The Universal Scene Description (USD) format and its benefits are discussed.</li>
<li>The challenges and compatibility with other tools like Blender are also mentioned.</li>
<li>USD&#39;s applicability in industries such as gaming, CAD/CAM, and 3D printing is highlighted.</li>
<li>The involvement of Apple and its VisionPro initiative in spatial computing is questioned.</li>
<li>A comparison is made between USD and Collada, with skepticism over USD&#39;s ability to cater to all users.</li>
<li>USD&#39;s support for various data representations and the involvement of Adobe, Apple, and Nvidia are acknowledged.</li>
<li>The absence of Intel and AMD from the alliance is highlighted but clarified as not permanent exclusion.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://catskull.net/html.html">I&#39;m betting on HTML</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author emphasizes the importance of semantic HTML in the context of artificial intelligence and the limitations of social media platforms.</li>
<li>HTML is a reliable solution for building modern web applications due to its wide range of UI elements.</li>
<li>The author highlights novel and useful HTML elements and stresses the importance of proper tagging for descriptive purposes.</li>
<li>The article argues for a shift towards secondary interfaces and suggests that HTML has the potential for a revolution in usage.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36966653">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions revolve around different aspects of web development.</li>
<li>Topics include the utilization of HTML elements and the benefits and limitations of AI.</li>
<li>The use of custom components and the future of web development are also discussed.</li>
<li>Participants present various perspectives, emphasizing the significance of accessibility and user experience.</li>
<li>Specific frameworks and technologies are debated regarding their potential and limitations in web development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nim-lang.org/blog/2023/08/01/nim-v20-released.html">Nim 2.0</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nim 2.0 has been released with new features and improvements.</li>
<li>The update includes memory management, tuple unpacking, type inference, and support for forbidden tags in proc types.</li>
<li>Overloadable enums, default values for objects, and improved error messages are introduced.</li>
<li>The release encourages donations for bug fixes and new features.</li>
<li>Documentation, code generation, and interop with other languages have been improved.</li>
<li>Standard library modules and tools have also undergone changes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36955806">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The programming language Nim is being discussed, focusing on its features, strengths, and potential applications.</li>
<li>Users praise Nim for its speed, data structure and dataframe library, and simple type system.</li>
<li>Some express concerns about the small ecosystem and lack of high-quality libraries compared to other languages.</li>
<li>The discussions also mention Nim&#39;s interoperability with other languages like Rust and Zig.</li>
<li>There are comparisons with other languages such as Python, Rust, Go, Odin, and Java.</li>
<li>Overall, there is positive feedback about Nim&#39;s convenience, performance, and potential benefits in different domains.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Ask HN: Who is hiring? (August 2023)</h2>
<ul>
<li>The summary provides guidelines for job postings on a specific platform.</li>
<li>It suggests that companies should include their location and specify if they accept remote or visa candidates.</li>
<li>If remote work is not an option, the term &quot;onsite&quot; should be used.</li>
<li>It advises individuals to only email if they are interested in the job.</li>
<li>The summary also offers links to additional resources for job searching.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36956867">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Various companies across different industries and locations are currently hiring for technical roles.</li>
<li>Companies such as Caim, SmarterDx, Friendly Captcha, and ProPublica are seeking candidates for various technical positions.</li>
<li>Job opportunities are available at Virta Health, Apple, OpenSynergy, and Messari, among others.</li>
<li>Val is specifically looking for a founding engineer on their social coding platform.</li>
<li>ML6, SwiftKick Mobile, Maxint.com, and Foxglove are also actively recruiting.</li>
<li>Positions include machine learning engineer, software engineer, data engineer, iOS engineer, and ML engineer.</li>
<li>Remote and onsite work options are available.</li>
<li>Technologies mentioned in the job postings include Python, TensorFlow, Google Cloud Platform, Flutter, Typescript, Node.js, MongoDB, AWS, React, React Native, and Redux.</li>
<li>Job postings are also available in Sydney, Australia from companies like SIG, Property Meld, and TriumphPay.</li>
<li>Numerous other companies are hiring across different locations and industries, such as Rockstar Games, Canvas, and Holland &amp; Barrett International.</li>
<li>Roles include database engineers, software programmers, developers, traders, and quants.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2023/07/oregon-drug-decriminalization-results-overdoses/674733/">Oregon decriminalized hard drugs – early results aren’t encouraging</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Oregon passed Ballot Measure 110, which decriminalized the possession of small amounts of all drugs three years ago.</li>
<li>The state&#39;s drug problems have not improved since the implementation of this policy.</li>
<li>There has been a significant increase in overdose deaths in Oregon.</li>
<li>The policy&#39;s implementation and enforcement measures have faced criticism.</li>
<li>Three children under the age of 4 recently overdosed in Portland, raising concerns about the effectiveness of the policy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36959267">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the role and effectiveness of shame in society, specifically regarding drug addiction, societal norms, and personal responsibility.</li>
<li>Participants have different opinions on whether shame is necessary for regulating behavior or if it can cause harm and discrimination.</li>
<li>Topics such as diversity, crime rates, and flaws in the justice system are also mentioned during the conversation.</li>
<li>There is a debate about the possible advantages and disadvantages of using shame as a means to maintain social order.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.00676">Electronic Structure of LK-99</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper investigates the electronic structure of a possible room-temperature superconductor, Pb9Cu(PO4)6O, using density-functional theory calculations.</li>
<li>The study suggests that the material is in an ultra-correlated regime and may display either flat-band superconductivity or a correlation-enhanced electron-phonon mechanism when doped.</li>
<li>These findings challenge earlier speculation suggesting that the material is a diamagnet without superconductivity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36965545">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores the discovery of a potential new superconductor called LK-99.</li>
<li>Room-temperature superconductors are a topic of both excitement and skepticism.</li>
<li>Advancements in AI and fusion technology are also discussed.</li>
<li>There are discussions about potential government cover-ups of UFO technology.</li>
<li>Bitcoin and AI models are also topics of discussion.</li>
<li>The impact of COVID-19 on individuals is considered.</li>
<li>The challenges of scientific research and funding are discussed.</li>
<li>A recent paper suggests that LK-99 could be a room-temperature superconductor.</li>
<li>Contradicting results regarding superconductivity and diamagnetism complicate the findings.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.inferse.com/660551/hardware-hacker-mods-an-m1-mac-mini-to-receive-power-over-ethernet-instead-of-the-ac-input/">Hacker mods an M1 Mac mini to receive power over Ethernet instead of AC</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A hardware hacker has successfully modified an M1 Mac mini to run on the Power over Ethernet (PoE) protocol.</li>
<li>This was achieved by removing the Ethernet port and adding components for power delivery.</li>
<li>The modding process will be published by the hacker.</li>
<li>However, due to limitations, PoE is expected to be used as a secondary power source.</li>
<li>The M1 Mac mini was chosen for testing because of its power efficiency.</li>
<li>More details about the modding process and the compatibility of PoE with other Macs with Ethernet ports are expected to be revealed in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36961734">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions are centered around the feasibility and benefits of using Power over Ethernet (PoE) to power devices like the M1 Mac mini.</li>
<li>Participants are discussing the need for higher wattage support and exploring alternative power sources like USB-C PD and batteries.</li>
<li>Proper waste disposal and the implementation of modular batteries are highlighted as important considerations.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised regarding compatibility, reliability, and potential risks associated with PoE.</li>
<li>Discussions also touch on power distribution, transformer-less devices, voltage considerations, and the limitations and challenges of PoE technology.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-02444-5">Could the world go PFAS-free? Proposal to ban ‘forever chemicals’ fuels debate</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36958352">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://ploum.net/2023-08-01-splitting-the-web.html">Splitting the Web</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36955146">Reactions</a></h3>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/08/02</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-02T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-08-01]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1>2023-08-01</h1>
<h2>Ask HN: Is anyone using PyPy for real work?</h2>
<ul>
<li>The author has been the release manager for PyPy since 2015.</li>
<li>They have made efforts to make PyPy available through conda-forge and direct download.</li>
<li>The author has worked on improving the C-API emulation layer to run the scientific python data stack.</li>
<li>However, they receive limited feedback from users and are frustrated by the lack of user experience to guide improvements.</li>
<li>The author requests users to provide feedback on their experience with PyPy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36940871">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion threads center around the use and advantages of PyPy as an alternative implementation of Python for performance improvement in different projects.</li>
<li>Users share their experiences with PyPy, including faster execution times and issues with library compatibility.</li>
<li>Alternative tools for performance optimization and the limitations of specific libraries are also discussed.</li>
<li>Some users express interest in a Python Just-in-Time compiler like LuaJIT.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ku.dk/all_news/2023/07/pay-dirt-for-ice-core-scientists-in-east-greenland-as-they-reach-bedrock/">Ice core scientists in East Greenland reach bedrock</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ice core scientists from the University of Copenhagen have successfully drilled through an ice stream in Northeast Greenland, reaching the bedrock beneath.</li>
<li>This is the first time a deep ice core has been drilled through an ice stream, providing valuable information on Earth&#39;s climate changes from the past 120,000 years.</li>
<li>Mud samples retrieved from beneath the ice will be analyzed to understand climate patterns and project rising sea levels.</li>
<li>The ice core will be studied in laboratories worldwide to document climate changes over the last 120,000 years.</li>
<li>This breakthrough improves understanding of ice stream behavior and its impact on rising sea levels.</li>
<li>The project involved 12 participating nations and received financial support from Denmark.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36944978">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ice core scientists in East Greenland have successfully reached bedrock, which is a significant achievement for climate research.</li>
<li>This milestone will contribute to our understanding of ice movement and improve climate models.</li>
<li>The conversation surrounding the achievement includes discussions about cloud formation and its impact on temperature.</li>
<li>Various topics related to climate change, ice ages, carbon capture, sustainable energy, and volcanic emissions are also being explored.</li>
<li>The drilling process for ice cores in Greenland is described, highlighting the benefits and challenges of conducting deep hole drilling for scientific research purposes.</li>
<li>Other topics being examined include geophysical and hydrological observatories, the preservation of DNA in ice, and the potential risk of future pandemics caused by viruses trapped in glacial ice.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2023/07/31/nasa_mistakenly_disconnects_voyager_2/">NASA mistakenly severs communication to Voyager 2</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Voyager 2 probe is currently unable to communicate with NASA due to a misaligned antenna.</li>
<li>This antenna misalignment has been ongoing for over a week, preventing the spacecraft from receiving commands or transmitting data.</li>
<li>NASA believes that this situation is temporary and will not impact Voyager 2&#39;s trajectory or its mission in space.</li>
<li>Voyager 2 is currently around 32 billion kilometers away from Earth and is moving further away at a rate of 15km per second.</li>
<li>Voyager 1, however, remains in contact with Earth and is unaffected by this glitch.</li>
<li>Engineers are working to fix the antenna alignment issue and extend Voyager 2&#39;s working life.</li>
<li>If successful, a similar adjustment may be made to Voyager 1.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36940626">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Voyager 2 spacecraft is currently experiencing a communication interruption.</li>
<li>The mission of Voyager 2 is nearing its end.</li>
<li>Astronomical navigation is being used in relation to the Voyager 2 spacecraft.</li>
<li>Spacecraft engineering and operations are being discussed.</li>
<li>The differences between software engineering and other disciplines are being explored.</li>
<li>The importance of accountability and responsibility in space exploration is being emphasized.</li>
<li>Science fiction books and their relevance to space travel are being discussed.</li>
<li>The challenges of space travel, including the immense distances involved, are being highlighted.</li>
<li>Familiar units of measurement are being used to compare and understand these immense distances.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/rd/blog/2023-07-mastodon-distributed-decentralised-fediverse-activitypub">The BBC on Mastodon</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>BBC Research &amp; Development is testing the Mastodon social media platform.</li>
<li>Mastodon is a distributed and decentralized platform.</li>
<li>The BBC has set up their own Mastodon server where users can follow BBC social media accounts.</li>
<li>The federated model of Mastodon aligns with the BBC&#39;s goal of supporting a public service internet.</li>
<li>The experiment will run for 6 months to evaluate its value and decide whether to continue.</li>
<li>The BBC is also exploring other ActivityPub applications for publishing content.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36943866">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users on the Mastodon platform are frustrated with the BBC&#39;s decision to add a delay to their podcast feeds to promote their centralized app, BBC Sounds.</li>
<li>Concerns about revenue maximization and privatization are raised regarding the BBC&#39;s digital initiatives.</li>
<li>Users discuss the availability and usability of BBC content, as well as ad insertions in podcasts.</li>
<li>Criticisms of BBC management are brought up in the conversation.</li>
<li>The challenges and considerations of implementing the ActivityPub protocol on Mastodon are discussed.</li>
<li>Limitations of Mastodon for non-technical users are highlighted.</li>
<li>The BBC&#39;s history of experimenting with new media is mentioned, as well as their recent move to Mastodon.</li>
<li>The conversation also covers the adoption of Mastodon, the role of organizations, and the complexities of decentralization.</li>
<li>The debate over the distinction between social media and internet forums is discussed.</li>
<li>The potential for federated filtering to combat objectionable content is explored.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.16802">Semiconducting Transport in LK99 reproduction attempt</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>This article discusses a recent claim about the discovery of room-temperature superconductivity in a modified lead-apatite compound.</li>
<li>The authors conducted detailed analyses of the compound&#39;s electrical and magnetic properties.</li>
<li>The resulting compound showed semiconductor-like transport behavior, casting doubt on the claim.</li>
<li>Further examination is needed to validate the claim of room-temperature superconductivity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36951140">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Reddit discussions are focused on the challenges of replicating scientific experiments, specifically in materials science.</li>
<li>Replication in different labs with varying conditions requires adjustments and adaptations.</li>
<li>The benefits and drawbacks of publishing research results earlier are debated.</li>
<li>Validity and impact of early publications are questioned, especially in relation to a claim about a room-temperature superconductor.</li>
<li>Scientists express skepticism and call for replication to validate the claim.</li>
<li>Discussions revolve around the appropriate process for publishing and verifying scientific discoveries.</li>
<li>Ongoing efforts to replicate a synthesized material&#39;s X-ray diffraction pattern that does not match the original.</li>
<li>Concerns arise regarding the difficulty of synthesizing crystals and the possibility of fraud or incompetency.</li>
<li>Challenges in synthesizing materials for high-temperature superconductors are discussed.</li>
<li>Skepticism surrounds a potential breakthrough in superconductivity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2023/07/31/marijuana-addiction-legal-recreational-sales/">Marijuana addiction: those struggling often face skepticism</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Despite the growing acceptance of marijuana, addiction to the drug exists and is often met with skepticism.</li>
<li>While some argue that marijuana can be used without negative consequences, it is recognized to be addictive like alcohol or prescription drugs.</li>
<li>Estimates vary, but there are individuals struggling with cannabis use disorder who require assistance.</li>
<li>Concerns are arising about the impact of increased marijuana use and potency, particularly on the developing brains of teenagers.</li>
<li>The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration states that millions of individuals in the US had a cannabis use disorder in 2021.</li>
<li>Medical marijuana users may be misdiagnosed, highlighting the need for improved diagnostic criteria.</li>
<li>Currently, behavioral therapy is the primary treatment for marijuana addiction, as there is no medication available.</li>
<li>Quitting marijuana use can result in withdrawal symptoms.</li>
<li>The article also mentions the increasing acceptance of marijuana use and provides additional resources on the topic.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36946104">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion thread covers various topics related to cannabis, including addiction, dosage, THC potency, legalization, and its effects on anxiety.</li>
<li>Participants share their personal experiences, recommendations, and opinions on cannabis use.</li>
<li>The societal perception of cannabis use is also discussed.</li>
<li>The craft beer industry is mentioned and compared to the cannabis industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mstdn.social/@Pandamoanimum/110808340828034444">A fridge from 70 years ago has better features than the fridge I own now</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Mastodon platform&#39;s instance, mstdn.social, boasts 38,000 active users engaged in diverse discussions.</li>
<li>Topics include capitalism, durability of modern appliances, refrigerator design, and nostalgia for vintage appliances.</li>
<li>Users debate the effects of capitalism on the production of low-quality goods and its role in providing access to modern appliances.</li>
<li>Discussions also revolve around preferences for vintage versus modern refrigerators.</li>
<li>Sustainability and environmental impact are additional points of debate.</li>
<li>The participants hold varying viewpoints on capitalism, consumerism, durability, and design preferences.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36942266">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions cover various topics related to household appliances, such as refrigerators, toasters, ovens, and microwaves.</li>
<li>Participants share their opinions on features, durability, reliability, efficiency, and cost of both older and modern appliances.</li>
<li>Consumer culture, environmental impact, and the difficulty of finding reliable information about appliances are also discussed.</li>
<li>There is a wide range of perspectives and debates regarding the quality and longevity of household appliances.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.16892">Origin of correlated isolated flat bands in LK99</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Room temperature superconductivity has been discovered in copper-substituted lead phosphate apatite.</li>
<li>The study uses density functional theory calculations to identify correlated isolated flat bands at the Fermi level.</li>
<li>These flat bands are attributed to a structural distortion induced by copper ions and a chiral charge density wave from lead lone pairs.</li>
<li>A minimal two-band model can explain a significant portion of the low-energy physics in this system.</li>
<li>The implications of the findings on potential superconductivity in copper-doped apatite are discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36951815">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>LK-99 is a superconducting material being discussed for its synthesis and properties.</li>
<li>Substitutions, band structures, and synthesis challenges are important factors in the discussions.</li>
<li>Simulation, machine learning, and AI are potential tools for materials discovery.</li>
<li>Superconducting materials have potential applications in energy distribution and quantum computing.</li>
<li>Practicality and limitations of superconducting materials are a topic of concern.</li>
<li>Improved communication in the scientific community is needed.</li>
<li>There is a possibility of over-hyping scientific discoveries.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/law/2023/06/help-the-library-of-congress-create-video-games-that-improve-public-knowledge-of-civics/">Help the Library of Congress create games to improve public knowledge of civics</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36950075">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://app.markwhen.com">Show HN: Markwhen: Markdown for Timelines</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The person has developed a tool called markwhen.</li>
<li>markwhen is designed to convert plain text into timelines and calendars.</li>
<li>The goal of markwhen is to provide a user-friendly tool for this purpose.</li>
<li>The creator of markwhen encourages users to ask questions or provide feedback.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36944152">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Markwhen.com is a website that allows users to create timelines and calendars using plain text and Markdown.</li>
<li>Users have provided feedback on the user interface, including issues on iPad devices.</li>
<li>There is potential for integrating Markwhen with other tools like Obsidian and Visual Studio Code.</li>
<li>The creator plans to release offline and online versions of Markwhen with different pricing structures.</li>
<li>Users have compared Markwhen to other tools and suggested improvements, such as an Obsidian plugin.</li>
<li>The project has received positive feedback and generated interest from users.</li>
<li>Some users discuss the functionality and usability of a product roadmap tool called Markwhen, suggesting improvements and expressing appreciation for its usefulness.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/08/01</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
