<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:38:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-14]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-14</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://mullvad.net/en/blog/2023/9/13/bug-in-macos-14-sonoma-prevents-our-app-from-working/">Bug in macOS 14 Sonoma prevents our app from working</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Mullvad VPN application is currently experiencing compatibility issues with macOS 14 Sonoma due to a firewall bug that disrupts proper traffic filtering.</li>
<li>This bug may lead to leaks under specific settings, posing a potential security risk for users.</li>
<li>While the issue has been reported to Apple, no remedy is available yet; therefore, users are recommended to stay on macOS 13 Ventura until a fix is presented.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37498979">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users are encountering problems with the networking functionalities of the macOS 14 Sonoma beta version, possibly because of a bug in the macOS firewall.</li>
<li>There&#39;s a discussion around potential remedies and alternative VPN services to rectify the issue, indicating dissatisfaction with macOS&#39;s stability and usability, and Apple&#39;s closed approach.</li>
<li>Users are questioning the utility of reporting bugs to Apple, indicating issues with the testing suite and the handling of user feedback.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://meduza.io/en/feature/2023/09/13/the-million-dollar-reporter">Meduza co-founder&#39;s phone infected with Pegasus</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Galina Timchenko, co-founder and publisher of Russian news outlet Meduza, has become the first Russian journalist reported to be infected with Pegasus spyware, which was developed by NSO Group.</li>
<li>The Biden administration blacklisted NSO Group in 2021, barring it from accessing American technologies due to concerns around misuse and regulatory oversight.</li>
<li>Meduza, Access Now, and Citizen Lab together investigated the incident, exposing widespread Pegasus misuse and reinforcing concerns on governmental surveillance and targeting of journalists, opponents, and activists.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37496589">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate topics encompass Pegasus spyware utilization against journalists, vulnerabilities of various operating systems, state-sponsored hacking concerns, and difficulty in finding unbiased news sources.</li>
<li>There&#39;s a discussion on the effectiveness of security measures and differing approaches to consuming news, alongside criticisms directed towards media outlets for bias and lack of accountability.</li>
<li>References to geopolitical situations, including the role of Western states in the Ukrainian conflict, highlight the broader context and implications for the tech and information sectors.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://shreevatsa.wordpress.com/2010/06/04/dont-mess-with-a-genius/">Don’t mess with a genius (2010)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The text highlights Isaac Newton&#39;s tenure as the Warden of the Mint in England, where he actively pursued counterfeiters.</li>
<li>It emphasizes his successful endeavors in catching many counterfeiters, with a particular emphasis on his arch-nemesis, William Chaloner.</li>
<li>Newton&#39;s significant contribution to the Great Recoinage signifies his remarkable contribution to maintaining currency integrity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37501231">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Hacker News discussion thread provides varied perspectives on Isaac Newton&#39;s life, encompassing his conflicts, association with alchemy, crusades against counterfeiters, and his contributions to calculus.</li>
<li>Participants in the thread debate Newton&#39;s individual character and scientific contributions, with some exhibiting skepticism and others defending his reputation.</li>
<li>The article also uncovers the human aspect of Newton, highlighting our cognitive biases that can lead even highly intelligent people to fall prey to scams and manipulation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://caoyuan.scripts.mit.edu/ir_spec.html">A DIY near-IR spectrometer</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Yuan Cao has developed a budget-friendly do-it-yourself (DIY) near-infrared (near-IR) spectrometer possessing a resolution of 6 nm.</li>
<li>The spectrometer operates using a diffraction grating and photodiodes amongst other components; it measures the spectral resolution and wavelength of light.</li>
<li>In addition to discussing challenges related to noise reduction and interference, Cao also talks about calibration, the spectrometer&#39;s dynamic range, and measuring transmission spectra. They may reveal more spectra in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37498142">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An individual has developed a low-cost self-made near-infrared spectrometer, with possible usage in diverse sectors.</li>
<li>The creator is keen on fabricating affordable spectrometers for third world countries, aiming to aid in the identification of fake drugs.</li>
<li>The text emphasizes the challenges in calibrating and certifying these instruments, and highlights the lack of robust articles on platforms such as Hacker News.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://retool.com/blog/mfa-isnt-mfa/">When MFA isn&#39;t MFA, or how we got phished</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Retool, a platform for creating internal tools, faced a spear phishing attack that led to unauthorized access to 27 cloud customer accounts, revealing the vulnerability of the system to social engineering attacks.</li>
<li>The attack took place when an employee succumbed to an SMS-based phishing attack and provided multi-factor authentication (MFA) codes, which subsequently compromised company&#39;s VPN and internal admin systems.</li>
<li>Retool recommends improving security, such as avoiding the storage of MFA codes in the cloud, promoting employee training and the use of hardware security keys for MFA, and adopting defense-in-depth strategies. The company is now collaborating with law enforcement and a forensics firm to probe the incident.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37500895">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Hacker News discussion encompasses aspects like being cautious of calls/messages requesting personal information, the necessity to validate caller identities, and the need for standard reverse-authentication systems.</li>
<li>Participants discuss the strengths and limits of different security measures including password encryption, multi-factor authentication, and biometrics, and share instances of mishandling fraud issues.</li>
<li>Issues like the use of deepfake technology in security breaches, the protection of digital assets, and the overarching agreement on the requirement of user-friendly, robust security solutions are also detailed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://kraktoos.com/posts/dont-use-discord-as-forum/">Don&#39;t use Discord as your Q&amp;A forum</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author discourages the use of Discord as a Q&amp;A (Question &amp; Answer) forum for projects, citing its chaotic nature, subpar search and discovery features, and potential discontinuity risk.</li>
<li>The text suggests better alternatives like dedicated community forums, reputable websites like Stack Overflow or Reddit, and Git-based issue tracking systems.</li>
<li>The author emphasizes the significance of meticulously selecting a platform for Q&amp;A purposes, acknowledging its impact on the project&#39;s progress and community interaction.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37502258">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The primary focus of the debate is around the use of Discord as a Q&amp;A forum, with views varying on its efficiency versus platforms like GitHub issues, dedicated forums, and mailing lists.</li>
<li>Discord&#39;s informality and ease of use are praised, yet limitations in searchability and organization are highlighted. Choice of platform depends on individual needs, such as control, cost, ease of setup, and demographic trends.</li>
<li>Talk around potential obsolescence of traditional forums and mailing lists, and the possibility of a more comprehensive platform with indexed search engines, nested replies, and voice functionality, were also mentioned.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://fly.io/blog/skip-the-api/">Skip the API, ship your database</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>LiteFS is a globally distributed SQLite database, originally designed to distribute data geographically, ensuring quick response times.</li>
<li>The novel use of LiteFS was discovered, enabling it to replace API layers between services. This is achieved by distributing the complete database to client-side, allowing SQL queries and data joining per client&#39;s requirements.</li>
<li>The replicas are read-only, necessitating an API for data updates. While it has some constraints, this technique can be beneficial in situations where conventional APIs are inadequate.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37497345">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the concept of utilizing databases as APIs, outlining the potential challenges and obstacles of this method.</li>
<li>The discourse recommends using API contracts and tools like views and stored procedures for managing changes in software systems. It also addresses such topics as the viability of downloading entire databases during initial page load, the difficulties in implementing a database-per-user model, and the issue of vendor dishonesty in serverless computing.</li>
<li>An emphasis is placed on the benefits and drawbacks of using databases as APIs, including the practice of using views and table renaming in PostgreSQL for schema modifications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/content/blog-post/uselessness-phenylephrine">The Uselessness of Phenylephrine (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author states that phenylephrine is a less effective decongestant compared to pseudoephedrine given its extensive metabolism in the body.</li>
<li>Phenylephrine is purportedly being sold as an alternative to pseudoephedrine, due to restrictions imposed on pseudoephedrine for its potential use in illegal methamphetamine production.</li>
<li>The article concludes with a recommendation for the FDA to reconsider the sale of phenylephrine, suggesting it does not warrant its current listing.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37499106">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores topics like drug regulation, addiction, methamphetamine production, and the effectiveness of different medication including decongestants.</li>
<li>Issues like impact of regulations on drug availability, the role of law enforcement, social interventions, privacy concerns and limitations of pharmaceutical drugs are also debated.</li>
<li>Factors like the placebo effect, lifestyle changes, and individual responses to medication, showcasing the complexities and challenges associated with drug regulation and medication potency, are highlighted.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://fennel-lang.org/rationale">Why Fennel?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fennel is a programming language based on the Lua runtime, aiming to offer a simpler and more concise syntax by removing complexities found in Lua.</li>
<li>This language improves upon elements like global variable management, tables, loops, functions, and introduces features such as pattern matching and destructuring of data structures.</li>
<li>Fennel is compatible with extant Lua libraries and tools, and incorporates a macro system to extend the language with new syntactic forms.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37497131">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post centers on using Fennel, a programming language, in Neovim and Hammerspoon configurations, appreciated for its brevity and superior ergonomics over Lua.</li>
<li>Comparisons are made between Lua and other languages that compile to Lua like Moonscript and Yuescript, accentuating the benefits of Fennel&#39;s arity checks which Lua lacks.</li>
<li>It broaches the topic of indentation versus delimiter-based languages and the practical use of Lua in different contexts, and includes references to a Fennel&#39;s website and the current availability of applications for YC Winter 2024.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.eff.org/press/releases/appeals-court-upholds-publicresourceorgs-right-post-public-laws-and-regulations">Appeals court upholds right to post public laws online</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A federal appeals court ruled that technical standards incorporated into public law can be shared without risking copyright infringement, reflecting the view that laws belong to everyone and should be accessible free of charge and without registration.</li>
<li>The case was initiated by nonprofit Public.Resource.org, represented by the Electronic Frontier Foundation, against private bodies that create codes and standards.</li>
<li>The court ruled in favor of Public.Resource.org, marking it a triumph for public access to the laws, mainly due to the nonprofit, educational nature of its use of the standards.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37498473">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An appeals court has determined that publishing public laws online does not infringe copyright and is regarded as fair use.</li>
<li>This case raises awareness about inaccessible legislation and questions about copyright protections, spotlighting instances of copyright laws that require payment for access.</li>
<li>The discourse also involves the incorporation of private standards into laws without compensation, and highlights the varying practices from different countries regarding the availability of legal texts and standards.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://paladin-t.github.io/bitty/">Bitty Engine: An itty bitty game engine</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bitty Engine is a cross-platform game engine with built-in editors, allowing user-friendly programming in Lua, accompanied by features like a debugger, API documentation, and various editing tools.</li>
<li>Capable of creating standalone binaries, the engine can be utilized for both non-commercial and commercial purposes. It&#39;s available for platforms like Windows 7, MacOS 10.7, or Ubuntu 14, with low system requirements.</li>
<li>The Bitty Engine, distributed on Steam and Itch, is identical in terms of features on both platforms, and a trial version is available on Steam.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37497956">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article highlights the excitement around the recent launch of the Bitty Engine, with discussion centered on game and engine development tips and the application of JavaScript/TypeScript in game engines.</li>
<li>The potential of physical games with embedded computers and the rising popularity of Lua in game development are also discussed.</li>
<li>Lua&#39;s key benefits, such as easy incorporation into code bases, simplicity of learning, compatibility with C and C++ engines, along with the high-performance LuaJIT alternative, are underlined. &quot;Fantasy consoles&quot; is also a topic of conversation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adh2458">Earth beyond six of nine planetary boundaries</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The update to the planetary boundaries framework reveals that six out of nine boundaries have been exceeded, suggesting that the Earth is currently outside the secure range for human operation.</li>
<li>The text introduces a concept called &quot;novel entities&quot; that could potentially disrupt core boundaries, and emphasizes the need for transformations to enhance production impacts and regulate demand.</li>
<li>It highlights the human activities&#39; impacts on the ocean and terrestrial ecosystems, including the effect of deforestation and climate change on carbon stocks and global land temperature, and underscores an urgent need for action to prevent irreversible environmental damage.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37500752">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The passage debates the delicate balance between environmental concerns and economic or national security interests, particularly on the topic of climate change.</li>
<li>The impact of meat consumption on climate change is discussed, emphasizing the need for sustainable food production and adopting plant-based diets.</li>
<li>Technological solutions, use of renewable energy sources, and effects of temperature extremes on survival rates are also covered as potential issues and remedies in managing the environment.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://prize.hutter1.net/">Hutter Prize for compressing human knowledge</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Hutter Prize is a competition that rewards participants for creating software that can compress large files to smaller sizes, aimed at advancing data compression tech.</li>
<li>Participants are required to submit both their final compressed files and source code for evaluation, promoting transparency in processing.</li>
<li>The article mentions Alexander Rhatushnyak, a software engineer, who has made substantial contributions to data compression contests, showcasing successful participants to inspire and guide new entrants.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37502329">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The main discussion focuses on the role of compression in artificial general intelligence (AGI), highlighting both lossless and lossy compression&#39;s value, limitations, and correlation to intelligence.</li>
<li>There&#39;s mention of the growth and implications of GPU accessibility on AGI research, along with some historical perspectives.</li>
<li>The conversation ends with a reference to the application process for Y Combinator&#39;s Winter 2024 program, a funding scheme for start-ups.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://docs.lantern.dev/blog/2023/09/13/hello-world">Lantern – a PostgreSQL vector database for building AI applications</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Lantern is a vector database extension for PostgreSQL aimed to support the development of AI applications, featuring capabilities like generating embeddings and parallel index creation.</li>
<li>The project positions itself as an enterprise solution developed atop PostgreSQL, exploiting its extensive user base and data storage functionalities, and claims to surpass similar extensions in key performance metrics.</li>
<li>Lantern is open-source with a roadmap of future features including a cloud-based variant, industry-specific templates, version control, and improved vector support. The project invites community involvement and contributions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37499375">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Lantern, a new PostgreSQL vector database extension, has been launched; it boasts advanced features and performance metrics that surpass those of similar extensions.</li>
<li>The extension aims to improve AI application development and encourages collaborative contributions. Users have expressed concerns about performance and index updates, leading Lantern to plan future optimizations.</li>
<li>Despite being slightly faster than pgvector and enhancing application development and user experience, Lantern has drawn concerns about intensive resource usage. Lantern Cloud, their own hosted solution, is planned, even though current incompatibility with Supabase exists.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/09/13/spacex-no-longer-taking-losses-to-produce-starlink-satellite-antennas.html">SpaceX no longer taking losses to produce Starlink satellite antennas</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>SpaceX will no longer bear the cost of Starlink antennas sold with its satellite Internet service as part of a move to enhance the company&#39;s profitability.</li>
<li>The consumer Starlink antennas are sold for $599 each, while prices for high-demand customers can vary from $2,500 to $150,000 each.</li>
<li>SpaceX&#39;s success has been tied to the reduced production costs for the terminals, which now cost less than $600 each to manufacture.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37498830">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SpaceX has managed to cut the production costs of its Starlink satellite antennas, enabling faster expansion and more affordable services in both rural and densely populated regions.</li>
<li>While Starlink&#39;s revenue for 2022 fell short of projections, the company has demonstrated significant progress in performance and growth, and there&#39;s ongoing debate about the density benefits of the Starlink constellation and its possible expansion into developing nations.</li>
<li>The recent sale of the company’s satellite internet hardware to rural Canadians and the expected advancements in RF chip design, which could further reduce antenna system costs, hint at the possible commodification of phased array technology.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://explosion.ai/blog/against-llm-maximalism/">Against LLM Maximalism</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article addresses the difficulties of efficiently utilizing Large Language Models (LLMs) in Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks and suggests dividing the issue into modular components with LLMs as one component.</li>
<li>The use of supervised learning is recommended for particular tasks, and tools such as spaCy and HF Transformers are recognized as beneficial for labeling data and training NLP models.</li>
<li>The author also notes the utility of Prodigy, an annotation tool, for model-assisted workflows and concludes by stressing the significance of specific policies over broad reasoning abilities or background knowledge for practical tasks.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37495873">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article emphasizes on integrating large language models (LLMs) with natural language processing (NLP) tasks for dataset creation or augmentation to boost supervised models, rather than relying solely on LLMs.</li>
<li>It details the limitations of current NLP infrastructure and the prospective advantages of employing LLMs for effective text representation and classification tasks. Transfer learning and smaller models can enhance accuracy and mitigate delay.</li>
<li>The discussion extends to the importance of evaluating machine learning components, the difficulty associated with it, and potential implications and cons of AI and Web3 technologies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://go.dev/blog/wasi">WASI Support in Go</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Go 1.21 has introduced a new port for the WebAssembly System Interface (WASI) syscall API via the new GOOS value, wasip1. This enables developers to run Go code compiled to WebAssembly directly, bypassing the need for a JavaScript execution environment.</li>
<li>Despite the advancement, there are limitations including the absence of support for network sockets in the wasip1 API. However, extensions from hosts like Wasmer and WasmEdge and a third-party library, stealthrocket/net, could be utilized for network functionality.</li>
<li>Future directions for Go include exporting Go functions to WebAssembly and compatibility with the evolving WASI API, and developers have channels such as Gophers Slack and the Go issue tracker to contribute.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37498820">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The GoHacker News conversation revolves around introducing WASI support in the Go programming language, touching upon hurdles such as exporting WebAssembly functions, performance, and binary size.</li>
<li>Discussion participants suggest enhancements for Go&#39;s WebAssembly performance, drawing comparisons with Rust and .NET, while underlining the advantages of utilizing WebAssembly and WASI for optimizing Go applications.</li>
<li>Despite concerns about security vulnerabilities when using WebAssembly for plugins and desktop apps, participants generally perceive WebAssembly (WASM) as a tool to facilitate code interoperability and minimize dependency on hardware and operating systems.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/gamedev/comments/16hnibp/unity_silently_removed_their_github_repo_to_track/">Unity silently removed clause that let you use TOS from version you shipped with</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Unity, a widely-used game development platform, faced criticism for quietly eliminating a GitHub repository that monitored its terms of service changes.</li>
<li>Users express worry about the platform&#39;s transparency, fearing covert fee increases, resulting in doubt about Unity&#39;s reliability and potential legal ramifications.</li>
<li>There are ongoing debates concerning Unity&#39;s management issues, its potential collapse, the impact on users and the gaming community, and dissatisfaction with alterations to licenses and fees.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37499731">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Unity, a game development platform, has subtly altered its terms of service, leading to user charges for product installations and new fees—even if they halt using Unity for future projects.</li>
<li>These changes have generated user unrest and mistrust, due to perceptions of the change as unfair and ill-conceived, and concerns about fees for multiple installs and retroactive charges.</li>
<li>Discussion extends to the challenges of open and free products backed by commercial companies, Unity&#39;s struggle to generate revenue, and doubts regarding its business model&#39;s transparency and financial condition.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.computerenhance.com/p/game-development-post-unity">Game Development Post-Unity</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Unity, a widely-used game development engine, is revising its license terms to implement a notable fee per unit, raising concerns in the developer community.</li>
<li>This change in Unity&#39;s licensing terms is driving some developers to think about transitioning to different engines, including Godot, Unreal, Defold, and RayLib, each offering distinct features, user-friendliness, and scripting language supports.</li>
<li>Casey Muratori is soliciting insights from developers about their experiences with these alternative engines to facilitate informed decisions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37503351">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate in game development circles revolves around engines like Unity, Unreal Engine, Godot, and Blender. Unity&#39;s shift towards revenue generation through advertising is criticized due to stability concerns and developer dependence.</li>
<li>Godot is highlighted as a potential alternative but struggles to compete with Unity&#39;s robust ecosystem. The comparison and debate extend to the popularity and pricing models of Unity, Unreal Engine, and the use of Blender in the indie game industry.</li>
<li>Discussion also includes the decline of the Blender Game Engine, the use of Python in game development, and concerns about Unity&#39;s royalty structure. Advocacy for a revenue-sharing model similar to Unreal&#39;s is also explored.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/09/13/marvel-vfx-artists-unanimously-vote-to-unionize.html">Marvel visual effects artists unanimously vote to unionize</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Marvel Studios&#39; visual effects (VFX) artists have unanimously voted to unionize with the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE), a first for a solely VFX-focused team.</li>
<li>This move towards unionization arises amidst dual labor strikes from Hollywood writers and actors. The artists hope to negotiate for fair pay, health benefits, and a secure work environment in response to increased workloads and strict deadlines.</li>
<li>With the unionization vote now ratified, VFX workers will enter into collective bargaining talks with Marvel Studios, although ongoing negotiations with other labor groups may delay these discussions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37502892">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Visual effects artists working for Marvel have unanimously decided to form a labor union.</li>
<li>This news has sparked conversations on Hacker News, a social news website focused on technology and entrepreneurship.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-14T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-13]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-13</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37484135">Fine-tune your own Llama 2 to replace GPT-3.5/4</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author discusses the practicalities and benefits of fine-tuning open-source LLMs (Language Learning Models), which involves training pre-existing models on specific tasks leading to a more controlled model performance.</li>
<li>Fine-tuning, in comparison to prompting, can result in faster responses and reduced inference costs. The author claims their fine-tuned model performs akin to GPT-4, a high performance language model, while being significantly more cost-efficient.</li>
<li>The author references a tool named &#39;OpenPipe&#39; which is an open-source product aimed at aiding engineers in adopting fine-tuning practices with ease.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37484135">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation focuses on the application of open-source Language Learning Models (LLMs), primarily Llama models, for diverse tasks, emphasizing their cost-effectiveness and performance compared to GPT-3.5.</li>
<li>The dialogue also discusses crucial matters like data security, infrastructure requirements, alternative services, and the challenges present when using varying models.</li>
<li>The significance of input/output pairs for fine-tuning datasets and the prospective advantages of purpose-built LLMs are also brought into light.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2023/09/apple-debuts-iphone-15-and-iphone-15-plus/">iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Plus</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple has revealed the release of iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Plus, boasting a fresh design, upgraded cameras, advanced performance and safety features, charging options, and sustainability elements.</li>
<li>Pre-orders will go live in September, available in five diverse colors, with an array of trade-in offers and added accessories for these new models.</li>
<li>Alongside the phones, Apple has launched new accessories, software updates, and emphasized their environmental initiatives. Details about pricing, connectivity, and regional availability are included.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37485290">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion pivots around various aspects of the iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Plus, including USB-C compatibility, the swift pace of tech advancement, and a comparison of USB-C with Lightning cables.</li>
<li>Views diverge on subjects such as the switch from Lightning to USB-C, the durability of Apple cables, and the pros and cons of USB-C versus Lightning.</li>
<li>The potential influences of government regulation on charging port standards also emerge as a focal point of the debate, demonstrating the broad consumer perspective on technological implementations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bitsaboutmoney.com/archive/the-waste-stream-of-consumer-finance/">Credit card debt collection</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article delves into the link between industrial waste stream and the debt collection industry, underscoring system flaws such as infringement of debtor rights and sale of debts without sufficient documentation.</li>
<li>Debt collection firms leverage automated processes to collect from debtors likely to pay, using tactics like persistent calling, indicating a profit-driven industry short on moral integrity.</li>
<li>Recommendations for improvements are presented, but the complexity of the problem poses a barrier to progress.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37490241">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Hacker News thread discusses various financial issues, including the pros and cons of credit and debit cards, debt collection practices, and challenges faced by the less affluent and homeless populations.</li>
<li>It delves into areas such as medical billing, wasteful practices in the software industry, and systemic flaws within the American consumer finance structure.</li>
<li>There is a broader divide in opinions regarding the value and impact of credit cards, underscoring a need for better regulation and a fairer financial system.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://earthly.dev/blog/shutting-down-earthly-ci/">We built the fastest CI and it failed</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Earthly, a company specializing in CI/CD (Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery) tooling, faced hurdles while introducing its product, Earthly CI, mainly due to migration costs and skepticism from potential customers.</li>
<li>The company learned that a direct go-to-market strategy was ineffective, instead recognizing that developers needed to discover and adopt their tools independently, leading to a shift in approach.</li>
<li>Due to errors such as not building incrementally and ignoring early feedback, they had to shut down their CI (Continuous Integration) component, reflecting the importance of user feedback and incremental development in tech product launch.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37481513">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discourse focuses on the challenges, and key considerations associated with continuous integration (CI) systems, including the failure of a company named Earthly.</li>
<li>There&#39;s a comparison of features and usability within open-source CI/CD platforms such as GitLab, GitHub, and Azure DevOps, with topics like caching in build systems, CI process feedback, and rebuild decision-making being highlighted.</li>
<li>The consensus is divided, stressing the important balance between specific features and simplicity in CI/CD systems. The discussion also contemplates the efficacy of advertising, demos, and trust building in promoting new developer tools.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.unity.com/news/plan-pricing-and-packaging-updates">Unity plan pricing and packaging updates</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Unity Technologies is introducing a change in pricing and packaging of their Unity software commencing from January 1, 2024. The updates include a new Unity Runtime Fee based on game installations, applicable only to games hitting certain revenue and install benchmarks.</li>
<li>Unity will enhance their subscription plans with extra features such as cloud-based asset storage, Unity DevOps tools, and AI at runtime without increasing the cost. It also appears Unity Personal will remain available to all users irrespective of their revenue generation.</li>
<li>By November, new tools and services are to be added to Unity&#39;s subscription plans without a surge in seat pricing. Unity Plus will be phased out for new subscribers, current ones, however, will have the chance to upgrade to Unity Pro.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37481344">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Unity, a game development platform, has made updates to its pricing and packaging, and introduced new DRM (Digital Rights Management) requirements, sparking concerns among developers.</li>
<li>Developers&#39; reactions to the pricing and fee changes have been mixed, leading some to consider switching to alternative platforms like Godot, which could potentially alienate Unity&#39;s independent developer base.</li>
<li>The post also includes a comparison between the Unity and Unreal game engines, discussing their respective advantages and disadvantages.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ethz.ch/en/news-and-events/eth-news/news/2023/09/from-zero-to-one-hundred-in-0-956-seconds.html">New world record with an electric racing car: From 0 to 100 in 0.956 seconds</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A new world record for electric vehicle acceleration has been set by students from ETH Zurich and Lucerne University of Applied Sciences and Arts with their hand-built racing car, mythen.</li>
<li>The car accelerated from 0-100 km/h in 0.956 seconds over a 12.3-meter distance, surpassing the previous record by over a third.</li>
<li>The students developed and optimized the car&#39;s components for weight and traction, marking the third time the Academic Motorsports Club Zurich (AMZ) has held this particular world acceleration record for electric cars.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37482517">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions cover a wide array of topics related to electric vehicles, such as electric racing cars, aerodynamics, hub motors, superchargers, electric go-karts, Tesla acceleration, and EV performance.</li>
<li>Highlights of the conversations include reflections on acceleration records, advantages of electric motors, changing priorities in performance cars, future benchmarks and standards, and safety concerns.</li>
<li>These discussions underline the development and growth in the field of electric vehicles, signifying their increasing importance and prominence in the automotive industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20230911-00/?p=108749">Any sufficiently advanced uninstaller is indistinguishable from malware</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post highlights crashes with Explorer due to the use of a detouring technique in an uninstaller program.</li>
<li>The author discourages the use of detouring and code injection within software development, proposing alternate methods for file deletion and cleanup on the Windows system.</li>
<li>Potential issues with invoking the Windows Script Host are also discussed, with a recommendation for different tactics.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37491862">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion encompasses a wide range of topics, including uninstalling programs, software failures, operation of HTA and JScript in Windows, and issues with installer systems.</li>
<li>There are in-depth discussions on different operating systems, their individual features, the problems they possess, their limitations, and possible solutions.</li>
<li>Specific topics, like a bug in a Linux driver installer, limitations of Windows in deleting executable files, and file management across different operating systems, are also explored.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/sweden-digital-education-backlash-reading-writing-1dd964c628f76361c43dbf3964f7dbf4">Sweden brings more books and handwriting practice back to its tech-heavy schools</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Sweden is moving away from digital-centric education toward traditional teaching methods, like paper books and handwriting, due to concerns about screen time and falling reading skills.</li>
<li>Though UNESCO advocates for the right blend of technology in education, it stresses the vital role of in-person, teacher-led learning.</li>
<li>The shift in Sweden&#39;s approach might also be politically and ideologically motivated, contrasting other countries like Germany, which is lagging in digitalization efforts in education.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37479472">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate primarily centers on the role and impact of technology in education, with some expressing concerns about distractions from in-depth learning and advocating for limited-functionality devices.</li>
<li>Participants also emphasize the importance of traditional learning methods like handwriting and books, as well as good nutrition and physical well-being for better cognitive functioning.</li>
<li>A significant part of the discussion explores the relevance and advantages of handwriting in the digital era, reflecting a multitude of views on technology and learning strategies in education.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37482216">Why does Google rank the real Python documentation below content farms?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author raises a concern about the ranking of official Python documentation in Google searches, which appears lower than sites like GeeksforGeeks, W3Schools, and Tutorialspoint.</li>
<li>These other sites, referred to as content farms, are perceived by the author to deliver low-quality material compared to the official Python documentation.</li>
<li>The post questions the credibility and reliability of Google&#39;s algorithmic selection in prioritizing these content farms over authentic sources of information.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37482216">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users express dissatisfaction with Google&#39;s search results for Python documentation as content farms often rank higher than official sources, perceived as less user-friendly and exaggeratedly detailed.</li>
<li>There is a debate whether Google should tweak their algorithm to prioritize user-preferred sites or maintain the existing one considering factors like user clicks, highlighting the struggle between user preferences and ad revenue in Google&#39;s business model.</li>
<li>Suggestions offering solutions include the use of alternative search engines, refined search techniques, and prioritizing high-quality content over content farms or websites loaded with advertisements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2023/09/apple-unveils-iphone-15-pro-and-iphone-15-pro-max/">Apple iPhone 15 Pro and iPhone 15 Pro Max</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple launched the latest iPhone models, the iPhone 15 Pro and iPhone 15 Pro Max, incorporating a titanium design, advanced camera features, and the new A17 Pro chip for improved performance.</li>
<li>The iPhones, available for pre-order on September 15 and officially released on September 22, boast upgraded video capabilities and improved wireless performance.</li>
<li>Apple also revealed the Apple Watch Ultra 2 and emphasized its continuous effort towards sustainability through the creation of carbon neutral products.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37485271">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions cover multiple perspectives of gaming on Apple devices, from the potential of the iPhone 15 Pro and iPhone 15 Pro Max to concerns regarding freemium games and microtransactions.</li>
<li>There are also concerns about the decline of quality in mobile gaming, Apple&#39;s gaming initiatives, its approach to gaming and the limitations of gaming on iPhones.</li>
<li>The potential entrance of Steam in the iOS market has intrigued many, with varied opinions ranging from scepticism to optimism about Apple&#39;s impact on the gaming industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.sony-semicon.com/en/news/2023/2023090701.html">Sony develops energy harvesting module from electromagnetic wave noise</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Sony Semiconductor Solutions has innovated an energy harvesting module capable of transforming electromagnetic wave noise into power, providing a stable supply for low-power IoT sensors and communication devices.</li>
<li>The module is designed compact for facile installation and can be used in a wide range of applications, and can also detect alterations in harvested voltage to identify the status of a device.</li>
<li>The intention is to use this cutting-edge technology to help build a sustainable IoT society, efficiently utilizing the constant electromagnetic wave noise produced by various electronic appliances.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37480512">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Sony has pioneered a new technology designed to generate power by extracting energy from electromagnetic noise.</li>
<li>Geared towards powering low-energy devices, this technology is adaptable and applicable to a broad array of use-cases, particularly those not requiring continuous connectivity.</li>
<li>The innovation in Sony&#39;s solution resides in its simplicity and compact form-factor, making it ideal for use in Internet of Things (IoT) devices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://makelinux.github.io/kernel/map/">Interactive Map of Linux Kernel</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The summary discusses the various components and functions of the Linux kernel like virtual memory, threads, processes, storage devices, networking, file systems, device drivers, interrupts, and system calls.</li>
<li>It gives attention to specific drivers and subsystems within the kernel, including HID class drivers, network device drivers, and storage drivers, highlighting their importance.</li>
<li>Also mentioned is the version of the kernel, core 5.1, and a reference to the Linux kernel map explaining system functionalities, layers, interfaces, and hardware access.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37490623">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An interactive map of the Linux Kernel, visualizing its structure and elements, has been featured in the article.</li>
<li>The map, created with SVG and comes with keyboard control for navigation, has been commended for its accuracy and utility, even as some users proposed enhancements.</li>
<li>The map is regularly updated and contains links to more maps related to the Linux Kernel within the same website.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/danhockenmaier/status/1701608618087571787">The way that Jensen Huang runs Nvidia: 40 direct reports, no 1:1s</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Jensen Huang, Nvidia&#39;s CEO, maintains a unique managerial style, favoring a flat organizational structure and empowerment over traditional hierarchical methods.</li>
<li>Instead of conducting one-on-one meetings, Huang prefers all discussions and decisions to occur in a group setting, emphasizing collective involvement.</li>
<li>Despite being a CEO, Huang abstains from giving career advice to his employees, potentially as part of his unique management approach.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37486882">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discourse covers several topics including the pros and cons of 1:1 meetings, communication dynamics within a firm, the importance of self-awareness, feedback skills, and data-based leadership.</li>
<li>Nvidia is referenced as an entity promoting collective accountability and transparency, not favoring 1:1 meetings.</li>
<li>There&#39;s a degree of contention, with some lauding the effectiveness of 1:1 meetings, while others challenge their usefulness, proposing different communication strategies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/vitalik-buterin-reveals-x-account-hack-was-caused-by-sim-swap-attack">Vitalik Buterin reveals X account hack was caused by SIM-swap attack</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ethereum&#39;s co-founder, Vitalik Buterin, exposed that his Twitter account was compromised due to a SIM-swap attack, where the perpetrator gained control of his T-Mobile account.</li>
<li>Buterin cautioned that phone numbers are insecure for password resets and advocated users to dissociate their contact numbers from Twitter accounts.</li>
<li>Elsewhere in the crypto world, Bitget, a crypto derivatives platform, has announced a new $100 million fund to expand its ecosystem and support regional exchanges, media, and analytics firms, aiming to diversify services and amplify the native crypto ecosystem for global users.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37479774">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate addresses a range of security vulnerabilities in areas like Google accounts, Android apps, trust eroding factors, ideological hijacking, and challenges met by cryptocurrency users.</li>
<li>Persistent themes include criticism towards SMS-based 2FA&#39;s weakness, the rising threat of SIM swapping attacks, and the urgent demand for stronger authentication systems.</li>
<li>Other focal points encompass backup codes for 2FA, internal tools of T-Mobile, and Twitter&#39;s password reset protocol, alluding to potential safety concerns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://til.simonwillison.net/django/building-a-blog-in-django">Notes from building a blog in Django</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post provides a step-by-step guide to constructing a blog using Django, with PostgreSQL for managing accounts, teams, and billing.</li>
<li>It explains the primary features of a blog, including the models used in Django, the views and URL setup, the Atom feed, social media cards, and how to carry out testing.</li>
<li>The blog that has been built using these processes can be accessed at the provided link.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37482220">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the advantages of Django for basic CRUD applications and static site generation, along with complex applications examples created with Django.</li>
<li>Users provide a positive outlook towards Django and its abilities in web development but also acknowledge the benefits of static site generators. They discuss trade-offs between using frameworks like Django and static sites.</li>
<li>There&#39;s a debate around using dynamically generated pages or static pages for blogs—arguments made for both approaches—and mentions of performance issues with WordPress. Other tools and services like GitHub actions, Digital Ocean, and CMS options like Wagtail are also discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-death-of-unity">The Death of Unity</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author critically assesses Unity, a renowned game engine, remarking a decrease in quality and introduction of new business models adversely affecting developers.</li>
<li>Unity&#39;s eroding features, continuing stability issues, and new price structure amp up costs for developers; these changes are predicted to strike indie and smaller developers the hardest.</li>
<li>The author advises that Unity&#39;s actions could limit innovation, lessen third-party offerings, and potentially drive users away from their product, implying a brief-sighted approach.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37486431">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article voices concerns over Unity&#39;s new pricing model, with speculations that it could negatively affect developers and Unity itself.</li>
<li>The discourse suggests alternatives to Unity, such as Unreal Engine and Godot, while discussing the future of Unity and the game development industry.</li>
<li>The text underscores the importance of game design and accessibility above the choice of game engine, looking into the role of hardware limitations and development time.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://godotengine.org/article/godot-developer-fund/">The New Godot Development Fund</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Godot Engine has launched the Godot Development Fund with the objective of obtaining consistent funding and securing the project&#39;s future.</li>
<li>This fund aims to hire additional developers and upgrade the engine, and all donations directly support these improvements. The approach decreases reliance on one-time grants from corporations, aligning focus towards the needs of the community.</li>
<li>The developers acknowledge the significance of community support and encourage sharing the fund link to propagate its reach and influence.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37481872">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Godot game engine has instigated a new development fund, aiming to bolster its ongoing development.</li>
<li>Users voice distinct perspectives on Godot&#39;s standing against Unity, with some advocating improved C# support, while others favor GDScript.</li>
<li>Conversations encompass topics like open-source development benefits, hurdles experienced by small open-source teams, Unity&#39;s latest price alterations, and their possible repercussions on Godot&#39;s funds and reputation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://thepalindrome.org/p/how-large-that-number-in-the-law">How large is that number in the Law of Large Numbers?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>This piece discusses the mathematical principle of the law of large numbers and its practical applications, noting that the sample average aligns with the expected value as sample size grows.</li>
<li>The piece underscores that the rate of convergence depends on the sample variance, meaning the spread of the data points from their average value.</li>
<li>With real-world examples involving dice rolls and a lottery, the article emphasizes creating an understanding of variance when applying the law of large numbers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37480561">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides an in-depth exploration of statistical analysis topics, focusing on interpreting p-values, applying the Law of Large Numbers, and evaluating distribution deviations.</li>
<li>The piece emphasizes the significance of assisting the scientific community to better understand statistics and improve the analysis and presentation of results.</li>
<li>It underscores the necessity to consider the specificity of the phenomenon under study and the appropriate sample size, while pointing out certain inconsistencies in the representation of the data.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://resobscura.substack.com/p/simulating-history-with-chatgpt">Simulating History with ChatGPT</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the innovative use of large language models (LLMs) like ChatGPT as teaching aids in history classrooms, highlighting their potential to boost humanities education.</li>
<li>There are concerns about the potential for cheating and the assurance of historical accuracy when using these models.</li>
<li>The author provides an example of using ChatGPT for a historical simulation assignment in a medieval history class, which reported high student engagement.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37480155">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the potential application of ChatGPT in simulating historical environments for educational use and incorporating games and simulations to teach transferable skills.</li>
<li>It discusses the differences and financial aspects of various religious institutions like temples, churches, and mosques, with a focus on the complexities of religion.</li>
<li>It emphasizes concerns about bias in language models, the need for critical thinking skills, and raises an ethical question on the development of intelligent machines, referencing the Macy Cybernetics Conference and an incident involving a monkey.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/23911027/mystery-blue-lights-morocco-earthquake/">‘Blue lights’ flash in sky moments before Morocco earthquake</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Blue lights, known as earthquake lights or EQLs, were observed in Morocco before a devastating earthquake, mirroring similar incidences in Turkey, Japan, China, Italy, and Mexico.</li>
<li>The cause of EQLs is not yet determined, though some scientists speculate they could be linked with the energy release from shifting lithospheric plates.</li>
<li>The earthquake in Morocco, measuring 7.2 in magnitude, resulted in significant damage and the loss of 2,900 lives. Efforts for relief and rescue are currently in progress, with contributions from tourists as well.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37484352">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The blue lights seen before an earthquake in Morocco were due to failures in power lines or transformers, rather than a natural phenomenon.</li>
<li>Probable reasons for these lights could be power lines shorting resulting from quake vibrations or the piezoelectric effect in rocks.</li>
<li>The post underscores the necessity of media literacy and using verified information sources, as the reliability of certain news sources, notably tabloid newspapers, was questioned.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-13T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-12]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-12</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://marhamilresearch4.blob.core.windows.net/gutenberg-public/Website/index.html">The Project Gutenberg Open Audiobook Collection</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Project Gutenberg and Microsoft are collaborating to develop a large collection of free, open audiobooks using advanced neural text-to-speech technology.</li>
<li>The motive behind this project is to democratize access to superior-quality audiobooks and promote literature accessibility.</li>
<li>However, there might be issues such as errors, offensive language, or inappropriate content in some audiobooks, which do not mirror the views of the collaborating entities. The users can report these problems via a specified link.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37466027">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Hacker News discussion revolves around AI-generated audio in audiobooks, with users lamenting the lack of emotional expression and debating the impact of AI on various industries and society.</li>
<li>Users discuss the affordability and accessibility of these audiobooks and question the quality of AI-generated audio, its potential market dominance, pronunciation issues, and audio clip structuring. They also mention alternative platforms for free or human-read audiobooks.</li>
<li>The topic also ventures into AI&#39;s usage in rewriting texts for language learners and making obscure books more reachable. Views range from skepticism to an acknowledgment of AI&#39;s potential to widen the audience, albeit with a preference for accurate labeling of AI-generated content.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37470318">Why did Visual Basic die?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author, possessing nearly three decades of software development experience, holds the view that no technology to date matches the development experience offered by Visual Basic in the 1990s.</li>
<li>They express concern over Microsoft&#39;s decision to abandon Visual Basic and the apparent lack of a suitable successor.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37470318">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the decline in popularity of Visual Basic (VB) and VB.NET due to reasons such as Microsoft&#39;s focus on .NET and the rise of web technologies.</li>
<li>It delves into the limitations and challenges in programming in VB.NET, the hurdles in transitioning from VB6 to VB.NET, and the demand for a more expressive language and advanced functionality.</li>
<li>The conversation also covers topics such as the dwindling popularity of Microsoft Access, the quest for its alternatives, the pros and cons of using Excel, and a comparative analysis between older technologies like VB and modern tools like React and Power Apps.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://renegadeotter.com/2023/09/10/death-by-a-thousand-microservices.html">Death by a Thousand Microservices</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article questions the perceived necessity of microservices for scalability, stating that successful companies have managed with simpler systems.</li>
<li>It points out the challenges that microservices bring, including code duplication and decreased developer productivity.</li>
<li>The piece suggests starting with a monolithic architecture, or a mixture of a monolith and branch services, hinting at an industry shift away from microservices towards more practical solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37477095">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article debates the merits and demerits of utilizing microservices in software development, discussing additional engineering overhead and the complexities of managing large databases.</li>
<li>It underscores the complications involved in debugging and maintaining distributed microservices, and concerns about the trend being potentially driven by inexperienced engineers for resume padding.</li>
<li>The forum showcases varying views on employing microservices versus monolithic systems, emphasizing that decisions should be based on an organization&#39;s specific needs, recognizing the trade-offs and challenges of both architectural styles.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://phylactery.org/antimirov/">Calculate the difference and intersection of any two regexes</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The given regular expressions contain features like concatenation, alternation, and kleene star, but lack advanced features like anchors, zero-width assertions, back references.</li>
<li>For additional information on these expressions, the summary recommends exploring a specific website.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37470285">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article delves into multiple tech topics such as string class hierarchies, Haskell&#39;s tagged union types, and the role of linear algebra in practical applications.</li>
<li>It explores the challenges and complexities linked to the use of regular expressions, including the configuration of an Internet Protocol (IP) filter via RegEx.</li>
<li>It touches on logical tasks implementation using Low-Level Managers (LLMs) and discusses the concept of attaining Artificial General Intelligence (AGI).</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://antimatter15.com/splat/">Real-Time 3D Gaussian Splatting in WebGL</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The text discusses a 3D viewer which uses WebGL for interface rendering. This viewer supports navigation through mouse or arrow keys.</li>
<li>It operates at 22 frames per second (fps), implying smooth performance and real-time user interaction.</li>
<li>The source code for this 3D viewer has been made available by Kevin Kwok on Github, a platform where developers upload and share their software projects.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37470611">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces a WebGL-based real-time 3D Gaussian splatting technique, covering challenges related to control scheme, rendering sharp edges, and ellipsoid projection.</li>
<li>Gaussian splatting is a rendering technique using colored shapes, optimized for specific viewing distances. It&#39;s beneficial for procedural or generated content, but limited for dynamic scenes.</li>
<li>The discourse involves the potential benefits of incorporating spherical harmonics, commonly used in systems like smoke, fire, clouds, and flowing water, into this rendering technique.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/lauriewired/status/1700982575291142594">The SHA256 for this sentence begins with: one, eight, two, a, seven, c and nine.</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>LaurieWired&#39;s tweet from Sep 10, 2023, provides the starting alphanumeric characters for the SHA256 hash of a certain sentence.</li>
<li>SHA256 refers to a specific type of cryptographic hash function. It is commonly used to verify data integrity through producing a unique, fixed-size 256-bit (32-byte) hash.</li>
<li>The provided alphanumeric characters would be the initial segment of this unique hash, generated from a specific sentence.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37465086">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text highlights the discovery of a sentence with a unique SHA256 hash, prompting discussions on collision probability and ways to find similar collisions.</li>
<li>It expounds on the difficulty of finding collisions in SHA256 hashes and explains the linkage between hash size and collision difficulty, alongside techniques to expand the search space.</li>
<li>There are discussions on the self-referential property of hash functions, its implications, and its connection to Bitcoin mining. Also mentioned are the potential risks of brute forcing hashes on SSL, signing, and Bitcoin.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mastodon.energy/@Sustainable2050/111039159882536261">In Germany, 27 are in &#39;preventive detention&#39; b/c they might do climate protests</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Mastodon.energy is a server tailored to professionals and academia, focused on discussions about energy transition initiatives including policy, infrastructure, technology, journalism, and science.</li>
<li>The platform&#39;s recent discussions revolve around the preventative detention of climate activists in Bavaria, Germany, who may protest at the car industry exposition IAA in Munich.</li>
<li>The detention, which can last up to 60 days, has been criticized by members on the server who have drawn parallels with similar cases in other countries, viewing it as an attempt to criminalize climate activism.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37471048">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses various topics including the incarceration of individuals in Germany due to participation in climate protests.</li>
<li>It also highlights the debates on the efficiency and acceptability of disruptive protests, and concerns about police prioritization and potential misuse of power.</li>
<li>Additional issues include discussions on employment practices, generational wealth, home ownership, and preventive detention and trial delays in the context of climate change activism.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/2023/09/11/right-data-ownership-big-tech-google-meta-competition/">The right to data ownership is the only way to take on Big Tech</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the rising power of giant technology companies, implying they have become more influential than nation states in setting the political agenda.</li>
<li>The author argues that competition enforcement by governments has been largely ineffective in checking the dominance of these tech giants.</li>
<li>It is suggested that ensuring data ownership rights could be the only effective means to counter the influence of Big Tech and experimenting with capitalism might be necessary.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37465972">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The central discussion points in the article involve the significance of data ownership, concerns regarding privacy, and the influence of major tech corporations.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about the lack of individual control over personal data, the monopolistic practices of companies, and the potential dangers of data accumulation and misuse.</li>
<li>Recommendations include development of legal frameworks, regulation of tech giants, and enhancement of transparency along with user control over data, acknowledging the need for better data collection and privacy mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ucsb.edu/2023/021198/wifi-can-read-through-walls">WiFi can read through walls</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers at the University of California, Santa Barbara, have devised a technology that images still objects, including reading the English alphabet through walls, using WiFi signals.</li>
<li>The technique leverages the Geometrical Theory of Diffraction and the Keller cones for tracing object edges, ensuring high-quality imagery.</li>
<li>The team has rigorously tested this technology, expressing confidence in its potential to pioneer new avenues in Radio Frequency (RF) imaging.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37469920">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>This summary delves into discussions and potential technologies related to the 6G mobile network, Wi-Fi surveillance, load-bearing constructions, and object detection using Wi-Fi signals.</li>
<li>Privacy concerns and possible misuse of technologies emerge as significant themes throughout these discussions.</li>
<li>There is an emphasis on the futuristic potentials and challenges tied to these tech fields.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://newsroom.heart.org/news/high-blood-pressure-while-lying-down-linked-to-higher-risk-of-heart-health-complications">Blood pressure should be measured lying down: study</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The new research presented at the American Heart Association&#39;s Hypertension Scientific Sessions 2023 links high blood pressure while lying down to an increased risk of heart-related conditions and premature death.</li>
<li>The study, which incorporated data from over 11,000 adults, found that individuals with high blood pressure, either when seated or lying down, faced the highest risks. However, even those who had high pressure only when lying were at comparable risk levels.</li>
<li>The type of blood pressure medication taken did not impact the level of risk. Therefore, researchers suggest blood pressure should be measured while lying flat on the back for a more accurate assessment of cardiovascular disease risk.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37471354">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions revolve around blood pressure management and monitoring, which include experiences with medications, lifestyle changes, and devices for blood pressure measurements.</li>
<li>Participants engage in debates about the frequency and accuracy of blood pressure readings and discuss the external factors that can impact these readings such as stress and physical activity.</li>
<li>The importance of professional medical consultations, the perception of misinformation in online discussions, and the caution needed in following non-medical advice are underscored. For instance, lying down when checking blood pressure is recommended for individuals with specific risk factors.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/goddard/2023/webb-discovers-methane-carbon-dioxide-in-atmosphere-of-k2-18b/">Webb Discovers Methane, Carbon Dioxide in Atmosphere of K2-18B</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NASA&#39;s James Webb Space Telescope has detected methane and carbon dioxide in the atmosphere of the exoplanet K2-18 b, reinforcing the possibility that this planet may harbor a water ocean beneath its hydrogen-rich atmosphere.</li>
<li>These findings suggest that K2-18 b could potentially host life, aligning with the current theories proposing the planet as a Hycean exoplanet, a type considered favorable for extraterrestrial life.</li>
<li>In addition to methane and carbon dioxide, the telescope&#39;s observations hint at dimethyl sulfide, a molecule generally produced by life, further asserting the potential for life on K2-18 b.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37468342">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>NASA&#39;s James Webb Space Telescope detected methane and carbon dioxide in the atmosphere of exoplanet K2-18b, indicating potential signs of life.</li>
<li>The distance to the exoplanet makes communication challenging, taking an estimated 124 years, highlighting the difficulties of interstellar travel and current propulsion system limitations.</li>
<li>The detection of dimethyl sulfide is mentioned as an additional potential sign of life on exoplanets, although some experts maintain a skeptical viewpoint.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://911realtime.org:443/">9/11 in Realtime</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The document summarizes the events on September 11, 2001, encompassing the last communication of Flight 11 with air traffic control, the plane crashes into the World Trade Center and the Pentagon, and the structural collapse of the towers.</li>
<li>It also sheds light on President Bush&#39;s reaction alongside various media briefings and addresses throughout the day.</li>
<li>A new initiative &quot;9/11 in Realtime,&quot; a multimedia experiment, is introduced to aid students in comprehending the events of that day.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37467077">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The summaries encompass varied discussions and personal experiences linked to the 9/11 attacks, involving stories from individuals directly affected.</li>
<li>The topics range from the long-term impact on society and civil liberties, debates concerning complacency, speculation about the attacks, to the role of journalism and public reactions.</li>
<li>As consequences of the attacks, discussions also include the invasion of Afghanistan and Iraq, racial tensions, violence, propaganda, and the transformation of the United States&#39; political climate.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/releases/tag/1.52.0">uBlock-Origin – 1.52.0</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>This post discusses the most recent release of uBlock, an open-source software.</li>
<li>The content provides installation instructions for varying browsers to accommodate the stable build of this new release.</li>
<li>It outlines a comprehensive list of rectifications and modifications incorporated in this update, making it a potential point of interest for tech enthusiasts.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37472994">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article highlights the release of uBlock-Origin version 1.52.0 and the subsequent user feedback.</li>
<li>There is ongoing user discussion comparing uBlock-Origin and uMatrix, along with voiced concerns about uBlock-Origin&#39;s limitations.</li>
<li>Pending browser support review for Firefox and alternatives to uBlock-Origin for the Safari browser are also topics of interest in the article.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.casino.org/news/mgm-resorts-suffers-cybersecurity-attack-system-outage-reported/">MGM is down, cybersecurity attack ongoing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>MGM Resorts International has suffered a cybersecurity attack causing a disruption to their system, affecting various IT assets such as mobile apps, credit card machines, and reservation systems.</li>
<li>The specifics of the attack including the possibility of a ransom demand are yet to be clarified.</li>
<li>Neither the company&#39;s operations in Macau, China are impacted by this incident nor is it the first of such occurrences, as MGM Resorts underwent a similar data attack in 2019.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37470801">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>MGM Resorts is currently experiencing a system outage due to a cybersecurity attack which has impacted services such as their app, ATMs, and kiosks.</li>
<li>The details and consequences of the attack are still being investigated, however, it is speculated that it could be linked to the upcoming F1 races happening in Las Vegas.</li>
<li>The company is working with specialists and law enforcement to handle this issue, but the incident has already caused considerable disruption for both guests and staff, causing worries about compensation for those affected.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://pcwalton.github.io/_posts/2013-06-02-removing-garbage-collection-from-the-rust-language.html">Removing garbage collection from the Rust language (2013)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author advocates for eliminating garbage collection from the Rust language, citing complications with familiarity, simplicity, and adaptability in its current memory management system.</li>
<li>They suggest prioritizing owning pointers and confining reference counting to a specific role, which would simplify the understanding of memory management for beginners while still providing options for dynamic memory management.</li>
<li>The author highlights Rust&#39;s potential in low-level programming and posits that it could be a suitable choice for high-performance web server software.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37465185">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around multiple aspects of Rust programming language, such as the elimination of garbage collection, balancing between single and multi-threaded runtimes, and advantages of Rust&#39;s asynchronous architecture.</li>
<li>The features including the use of generics and the &quot;box syntax&quot; are addressed, and the implication of Rust&#39;s nonexistent garbage collection on code writing is scrutinized.</li>
<li>There are comparative examinations of Rust with other languages and their type systems, along with mentions of the Redox operating system and languages having garbage collectors.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/09/x-sues-calif-to-avoid-revealing-how-it-makes-controversial-content-decisions/">X sues Calif. to avoid revealing how it makes “controversial” content decisions</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Elon Musk&#39;s X Corp. has sued to hinder California&#39;s content moderation law, AB 587, which mandates social media platforms to submit a service report detailing their content moderation practices to the state attorney.</li>
<li>X Corp. claims the law infringes on the First Amendment and imposes extensive financial penalties for non-compliance.</li>
<li>Concerns about the law&#39;s potential to negatively impact online users and restrict free speech have been raised by tech groups and policy experts.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37467607">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>There is an ongoing debate regarding the rights of companies, specifically social media platforms like Twitter, related to free speech and content moderation.</li>
<li>Key points discussed include whether companies should have similar rights as individuals under the US Constitution, the effects of government regulation on free speech, and the clarity of content moderation practices.</li>
<li>The debate also includes potential ramifications of censorship and legal challenges of applying state laws to social media platforms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://comsci.blog/posts/intuitive-harris">Intuitively Understanding Harris Corner Detector</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a straightforward understanding of the Harris corner detection algorithm&#39;s operation.</li>
<li>It distinctly presents how gradient calculations, Gaussian blur, and thresholding techniques are implemented in the algorithm.</li>
<li>The developed code can identify corners in an image without the use of complex mathematical computations or approximation techniques.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37466302">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers on the Harris Corner Detector, a fundamental algorithm in computer vision for recognizing distinct features.</li>
<li>While not the most advanced, the Harris Corner Detector is still utilized in specific applications, for instance, visual Simultaneous Localization And Mapping (SLAM).</li>
<li>Other algorithms including Scale-Invariant Feature Transform (SIFT) and Machine Learning (ML) techniques that are progressing in the feature detection domain were also discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp">YouTube-dl fork with additional features and fixes</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>yt-dlp, a fork of youtube-dl, introduces new capabilities while maintaining alignment with the original project, supporting age-gated content, livestream downloads, and subtitle extraction.</li>
<li>It offers multiple paths, portable configuration, and self-updating capabilities with detailed information about installation, dependencies, file management, and post-processing tasks.</li>
<li>The guide includes examples for diverse use cases with options for customisation, network settings, authentication and format selection, and mentions extraction and post-processing plugins with a note on potential risks.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37474066">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the debate surrounding a fork of YouTube-dl, called yt-dlp, that allows users to download videos from various internet platforms amid the DMCA (Digital Millennium Copyright Act) controversy.</li>
<li>The conversation also puts a spotlight on the limitations of centralized video hosting platforms like YouTube and the advantages of decentralized platforms like PeerTube.</li>
<li>A significant part of the discussion is about the impact these downloading tools have on content creators’ revenue, with divergent opinions on viewers&#39; rights versus potential losses due to piracy and ad-blocking software.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://petewarden.com/2023/09/10/why-nvidias-ai-supremacy-is-only-temporary/">Nvidia’s AI supremacy is only temporary</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia&#39;s supremacy in machine learning (ML) may wane as the industry focus shifts from training to inference, implying a likely return to traditional CPU platforms like x86 and Arm.</li>
<li>Inference, i.e., the application phase of ML models, is underemphasised currently compared to training, but its importance is expected to grow.</li>
<li>The article sources its arguments from “Pete Warden&#39;s Blog” for context and provides a timeline for these predicted changes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37467585">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores Nvidia&#39;s significant hold over the AI hardware market and the potential competition from companies such as AMD, Groq, and Mojo.</li>
<li>The discussion delves into factors such as software support, industry standards, and pricing, that might impact Nvidia&#39;s market dominance and profitability.</li>
<li>While Nvidia has a strong foothold now, the article concludes that there&#39;s an opportunity for other companies to challenge their position, especially with potential growth areas like AI chatbots and CPU usage in AI inference.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://antonz.org/interactive-api-tutorials/">Beyond OpenAPI</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article delves into the application of HTTP protocol in crafting interactive tutorials for APIs (Application Programming Interfaces).</li>
<li>It showcases the GitHub Gists API via presented code snippets, illustrating its functionality.</li>
<li>The piece also introduces the &#39;codapi-js&#39; library utilized for interactive documentation and creating code playgrounds.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37466207">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article emphasizes the importance of API documentation and introduces the &quot;four-document types&quot; model to improve the OpenAPI specification.</li>
<li>It mentions an array of tools and frameworks for better documentation, and applies the same documentation principles to other domains.</li>
<li>It discusses the limitations of the DITA framework and suggests supplementing reference documentation with conceptual or task-based documents, touching on topics like containerization, sandboxing, and OpenAPI.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/12</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-12T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-11]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-11</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.ctrl.blog/entry/windows-system-components-default-edge.html">Microsoft has not stopped forcing Edge on Windows 11 users</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The default web browser settings in Windows 11 remain unchanged, despite claims in a blog post that Microsoft would consider users&#39; browser preferences.</li>
<li>Misunderstanding stemmed from a recent Windows 11 Insider preview build changelog, leading many to believe Microsoft had conceded to regulatory pressures.</li>
<li>In-depth testing reveals that Windows 11 persistently proposes Microsoft Edge as the default browser, overriding the user&#39;s chosen browser. Initial reports of changes were misinterpreted and widely circulated in the media, with no official confirmation from Microsoft.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37461449">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The main discussions revolve around user dissatisfaction with Microsoft Edge&#39;s intrusive attempts to be the default browser, and limitations with the Windows operating system.</li>
<li>There is a notable desire for more browser diversity with users expressing concern over Google&#39;s dominance, and some prefer alternative browsers like Chromium or Brave.</li>
<li>Users mention alternative operating systems like Ubuntu, Arch Linux, and custom Windows distributions, meanwhile, discussing different tools such as Emacs and VSCode.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dougseven.com/2014/04/17/knightmare-a-devops-cautionary-tale/">Knightmare: A DevOps Cautionary Tale (2014)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The piece recounts the fall of Knight Capital Group, a financial services firm that went under in less than an hour due to unsuccessful deployment of their automated trading system.</li>
<li>It highlights the imperative nature of fully automated and repeatable deployments in the DevOps realm.</li>
<li>The importance of correct configuration management and testing in software deployment is also stressed.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37459495">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation is focused on the 2014 Knightmare incident where a DevOps failure caused significant financial losses for Knight Capital due to non-backwards-compatible code writing and lack of a kill switch.</li>
<li>Participants underscore the necessity of automated systems, kill switches, and risk management to prevent such issues, indicating the importance of cross-collaboration between software and finance sectors.</li>
<li>The dialogue also addresses the risks associated with high-frequency trading, the aftermath of deployment errors, and the importance of correct frameworks, automation, and accountability within the finance industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://public.wmo.int/en/media/press-release/earth-had-hottest-three-month-period-record-unprecedented-sea-surface">Earth had hottest 3-months on record; unprecedented sea temps &amp; extreme weather</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The past three months have been the hottest on record for Earth, replicating a climate change pattern that&#39;s caused extreme weather events and unprecedented sea surface temperatures.</li>
<li>August 2023 emerged as the warmest August ever recorded, contributing to this year becoming the second warmest on record, trailing only 2016.</li>
<li>Scientists attribute these record-breaking climatic conditions to climate change and call for urgent action to prevent dire environmental consequences.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37455534">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions cover the urgency and need for action against climate change, discussing potential solutions and its various implications including extreme weather events, human related global warming, and the potential consequences of climate change.</li>
<li>Significant topics include geo-engineering, political implications, effects on agriculture and food production, and the responsibility of different nations in managing climate change.</li>
<li>There are debates around denial of climate change, emissions reduction efforts, with an overall sense of concerned urgency about the future impacts of climate change, suggesting diverse opinions and perspectives.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/eduard-permyakov/peredvizhnikov-engine">Peredvizhnikov Engine: Lock-free game engine written in C++20</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Peredvizhnikov Engine is a lock-free game engine written in C++20, designed on the actor model of concurrent computation, allowing parallel logic development and inter-thread synchronization isolation.</li>
<li>The engine is fault-tolerant, guaranteed to persist even if worker threads are killed, includes lock-free algorithms, and is GPLV3 licensed but can be licensed differently if permitted by the creator.</li>
<li>Currently, the engine only supports Linux, and requires Clang++ 16 for building.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37456471">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Peredvizhnikov Engine, a lock-free game engine written in C++20, uses a unique Benaphore technique for message queueing that improves performance levels.</li>
<li>Key debate points in game development are consistent performance, synchronization among multiple players, the intricacy of current hardware and software, and the Peredvizhnikov Engine&#39;s limitations including debugging challenges and no Windows support.</li>
<li>A substantial discussion is also devoted to the distinction between mobile games and PC/console games, emphasizing the advantage of utilizing a library like SDL versus platform-specific layers for constructing a game engine.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://devnonsense.com/posts/how-does-linux-nat-a-ping/">How does Linux NAT a ping?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The writer has undertaken experiments to understand how Network Address Translation (NAT) functions with regards to ICMP packets in a Linux environment.</li>
<li>They&#39;ve delved into the structure and mechanics of ICMP echo and echo reply messages, along with the implementation of the &#39;ping&#39; command and the randomness of its ICMP identifier selection.</li>
<li>Utilizing a tool called &#39;bpftrace&#39; for tracing kernel functions, the author observed and confirmed modification in the source and destination IP addresses in ICMP packets due to the NAT process.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37455621">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The articles explore a range of topics related to Network Address Translation (NAT), IPv6, and the use of ping for peer-to-peer networking, including how Linux deals with NAT and pinging.</li>
<li>The advantages, challenges, and restrictions of existing NAT and IPv6 configurations, as well as potential solutions for improving peer-to-peer communication, are discussed.</li>
<li>While there seems to be a variety of viewpoints and concerns regarding these technologies and their implementation, the articles aim to provide a comprehensive view of the topic.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://steele.blue/geofence-pizza-ordering/">I wired up my bike&#39;s GPS to order me pizza during a gravel race</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Matt Steele connected his bicycle&#39;s GPS to make advance pizza orders from Casey&#39;s General Store while participating in a gravel race using a script activated when his bike exited a geofence.</li>
<li>On his first attempt, there was a false positive failing to order the pizza. However, after enhancing the script, Matt successfully ordered a pizza after the race.</li>
<li>Despite the challenges faced, Matt gained valuable lessons and aims to use the pizza ordering functionality in future races. The project&#39;s source code is publicly available on GitHub, an online hosting platform for software development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37454766">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text focuses on a story about a cyclist who wired their bike&#39;s GPS to allow pizza ordering during a race, which sparked a debate about potential misuse of food ordering service APIs, such as a money-laundering scheme.</li>
<li>It discusses the difficulties of endurance racing, particularly about fueling the body, and the IFTTT-style hacks developed by users to integrate food ordering.</li>
<li>The article also mentions a trend of random user blocking by websites, possibly to comply with GDPR or to cut costs, with the adoption of geo-blocking by retail companies to prevent threats and reduce bandwidth usage. Cloudflare&#39;s free DDoS guard is identified as a possible reason for this trend.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.karl.berlin/static-site.html">“Make” as a static site generator (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author shares their positive experiences using the static site generator, Karl Bartel Home Projects, for creating and hosting websites, highlighting its speed, simplicity, and flexibility.</li>
<li>They discuss various functionalities such as adding headers to HTML files, copying unchanged files, and the possibility of converting markdown content into HTML.</li>
<li>They propose convenience features like serving the site locally, automatically rebuilding on file changes, and uploading directly to GitHub Pages.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37454853">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article delves into methods and tools for creating and managing static websites, including the use of Makefiles, shell scripts, and static site generators, discussing their advantages and disadvantages.</li>
<li>It touches on using Nix, Conda, and Docker for compute environment management, discussing the challenges and strengths associated with these tools.</li>
<li>Personal blogging value, the use of heredocs and plaintext to HTML compilers for website generation, and limitations of current web technology regarding consistent styling across platforms are also discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2023/09/new-jfk-assassination-revelation-upend-lone-gunman">New JFK assassination revelation could upend the lone gunman theory</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Former Secret Service agent Paul Landis alleges the discovery of a bullet in President Kennedy&#39;s limousine on the day of his assassination, potentially opposing the Warren Commission&#39;s &quot;Lone Gunman&quot; theory.</li>
<li>The possible presence of an additional bullet raises doubts about the official account of the incident and could demand a reconsideration of established conclusions.</li>
<li>Another key claim comes from Special Agent Richard Landis, who suggests a bullet was left on a stretcher at the hospital, contradicting the commission&#39;s assertion that the bullet originated from Governor Connally&#39;s stretcher.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37454707">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion overviews online debates about JFK&#39;s assassination and associated conspiracy theories, with topics ranging from CIA involvement to Warren Commission&#39;s report credibility.</li>
<li>The single-bullet theory&#39;s validity, classified document withholding, and human memory fallibility serve as key debating points in the evaluation of witness testimonies.</li>
<li>The discourse also highlights the role of individuals&#39; behavior, availability of video evidence, and how these theories&#39; relevance in today&#39;s politics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://littleblah.com/post/2019-09-01-senior-engineer-checklist/">A Senior Engineer&#39;s Check-List (2019)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The website offers a comprehensive checklist designed to assist senior engineers in their career progression and success, containing key tasks and principles.</li>
<li>It covers diverse topics such as leadership, hiring practices, technology, networking, and the cultivation of professional relations, recognising the business facets of their roles.</li>
<li>They are guided on handling challenging situations, work prioritization, continuous learning, maintaining open-mindedness, enforcing accountability, and discouraging system over-complication.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37458283">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversations involve various aspects of a senior engineer&#39;s role, responsibilities, and hurdles, such as decision-making, mentorship, people management, ambiguity, communication, problem-solving, understanding business nuances, and diverse skill requirements.</li>
<li>There exists a disagreement over the importance of experience versus evidence-based decision-making, showing that different perspectives exist within the field.</li>
<li>The discussions underscore the multi-dimensional nature of senior engineering positions and the necessity for a mix of technical expertise, experience, and effective leadership skills.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2023-09/msg00713.html">Goodbye to Thien-Thi Nguyen</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Thien-Thi Nguyen, a renowned hacker, artist, and writer who made substantial contributions to GNU programs and free software packages, has unfortunately passed away.</li>
<li>Nguyen was recognized for his work on GNU Emacs, GNU Taler, and GNU Go. He was also the author and maintainer of various Emacs packages.</li>
<li>His departure signifies a considerable loss to the free software community as his contributions were invaluable.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37457796">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Thien-Thi Nguyen, a well-regarded member in the Emacs and GNU Guile communities, has sadly passed away.</li>
<li>Individuals from these communities are expressing their grief and sharing memories associated with him.</li>
<li>Discussions are ongoing about the contributions he made through his projects and the significant impact he had on the community.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.usgs.gov/faqs/why-ocean-salty">Why is the ocean salty? (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The ocean&#39;s salinity, approximately 3.5% of the seawater&#39;s weight, is due to rain eroding land rocks, thus transferring salts and minerals into rivers and eventually into the ocean.</li>
<li>The most prevalent ions in seawater are chloride and sodium.</li>
<li>Both the USGS (United States Geological Survey) and NOAA (National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration) provide further resources for understanding the ocean&#39;s salinity and related subjects.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37459371">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions examine various aspects of the ocean&#39;s high salt content, such as the accumulation of sodium and chloride ions.</li>
<li>Topics include the function of calcium in sustaining life, potential consequences of desalination, and the applications of sodium and chlorine.</li>
<li>Additional points of discussion cover the chemical composition of seawater and the implications of ocean salinity on climate and marine life.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://benhoyt.com/writings/awk-make/">The Awk book’s 60-line version of Make</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author details the utility of the Make program, a tool for building software projects, specifically discussing a simplified version created using the AWK programming language.</li>
<li>Emphasized is the forthcoming second edition of the AWK book, featuring CSV support and an amended Make program version.</li>
<li>While recognizing AWK&#39;s usefulness in specific tasks, the author argues that Python is a more appropriate language for this type of program and provides a link to their GitHub repository hosting the source code.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37460815">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author shares their journey creating a variant of Make utility with Awk, a scripting language, and a failed attempt to modify GNU Awk.</li>
<li>Readers engage in debates over the use of Awk in comparison to other scripting languages, discussing its strengths and weaknesses.</li>
<li>Alternatives like pawk.py and rp receive mentions as possible tools, along with the concept of writing one-liners in Awk or creating a more streamlined Python version influenced by Awk.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ad8e.pages.dev/curve">New Bézier curves for vector graphics</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the difficulties of using Bézier curves, highlighting issues such as determining the proper placement and length of control points.</li>
<li>A mathematical solution is proposed that uses the local properties of curves - position, direction, and curvature - to manage the curve&#39;s shape, permitting easier drawing and alignment; it also solves inherent issues, like representing circles and maintaining curvature continuity.</li>
<li>The piece additionally touches on the limitations and tradeoffs of this proposed solution, hinting at potential future developments in the field.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37457051">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the use, advantages, and challenges of Bézier curves in graphic design and animation.</li>
<li>It proposes alternative curves like quadratic Beziers, hinting at potential limitations of Bézier curves, notably their inefficiency in accurately representing circles.</li>
<li>There&#39;s a spotlight on the ongoing discourse and investigation of different methodologies pertaining to vector graphics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.euronews.com/green/2023/08/30/fact-check-is-air-conditioning-making-cities-hotter">Is air conditioning making cities hotter?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A recent study suggests that air conditioning units amplify city temperatures, with waste heat during heatwaves significantly increasing outdoor temperatures by over 2 degrees Celsius.</li>
<li>Air conditioners are under debate due to their contribution to the heatwaves issue, as they emit hot air outside and consume substantial electricity, releasing planet-warming gases.</li>
<li>As global air conditioner usage is predicted to triple by 2050, the study recommends alternatives like cultivating green spaces, enhancing building insulation, and educating people on maintaining cool during heatwaves.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37455382">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation touches on a variety of topics including the influence of air conditioning, the advantages of trees and solar panels in managing temperature, and the effectiveness of swamp coolers and reflective rooftops.</li>
<li>Emphasized is the necessity for alternative solutions, taking into account multiple factors, to attain effective temperature control and environmental sustainability in urban contexts.</li>
<li>Discussions range from the benefits and costs of solar installations, the impact of such technologies on urban heat islands, to the challenges of urban overpopulation, and the environmental implications of food production and transportation in cities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/Yifan-Song793/RestGPT">RestGPT</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The RestGPT project is a sizeable language model that interacts with RESTful APIs in order to manipulate real-world applications like film databases and music players.</li>
<li>RestGPT uses a planning and executing framework to call APIs and analyze the responses.</li>
<li>The project presents RestBench, a test set for measuring the performance of RestGPT, and the code, data, and instructions for setting up and operating the system are accessible under an open-source license.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37462125">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The central discussion is about the distinction between RestGPT and other language models, with considerations about their understanding and capacity to handle real-life situations.</li>
<li>The conversation covers the potential of language models like ChatGPT in home automation, personal assistants, and in DevOps, contrasting them with the limitations of virtual assistants like Siri regarding natural language understanding and context.</li>
<li>There is a focus on the need to challenge NVIDIA&#39;s monopoly in GPU support, suggesting a necessity for competition in the field. The use of ChatGPT, Noteable, and GOFAI techniques with language models are also discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://domains.google/">Google no longer offers new domain registrations</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>As of September 7, 2023, Google Domains has stopped providing new domain registrations.</li>
<li>Squarespace has acquired all domain registrations and customer accounts from Google Domains.</li>
<li>Existing Google Domains customers are required to transition their domains to Squarespace.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37455574">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google has transferred its domain registration service, Google Domains, to Squarespace. This development sparked discussions and raised concerns about Google&#39;s strategies and the future allocation of its resources.</li>
<li>Other domain registrar options like Porkbun, Namecheap, Dynadot, Cloudflare, Nearlyfreespeech, and Gandi are suggested. Concerns exist about the new management of Gandi, while Google Cloud&#39;s domain management service, Cloud DNS, remains unaffected. Conversely, concerns about the future of Google Cloud Platform (GCP) are noted.</li>
<li>This transition highlights the issues of trust, reliability, and risks in relying on single companies for various services. Attention is drawn to the need for considering alternative providers and Google&#39;s comparative domain management.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://designsystem.digital.gov/">A design system for the federal government</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The US Web Design System (USWDS) is a tool for the federal government that aids in creating accessible and mobile-friendly government websites.</li>
<li>It offers components, patterns, design tokens, and utilities for designing and implementing user experiences.</li>
<li>USWDS is an active open source community offering support to various government agencies and websites.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37459341">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The US government has enacted the US Web Design System (USWDS) in an effort to modernize government websites and enhance digital services, mirroring similar initiatives in other countries.</li>
<li>The discussion remains divided on the success of these projects, with core areas of contention involving usability, minimalist design, and the worth of standard systems and icon libraries.</li>
<li>Debates surface around the use of public domain and GPL licenses in government operations, upon which concern and speculation are raised about employing existing icon systems and the expected technology maintenance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.simplemobiletools.com">A group of open source Android apps without ads and unnecessary permissions</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Simple Mobile Tools is a project featuring a range of basic open-source, ad-free Android apps with customizable colors offering alternatives to existing Android apps.</li>
<li>The project includes apps like Simple Gallery Pro, Simple Calendar Pro, Simple Contacts Pro, Simple Notes Pro, and Simple File Manager Pro.</li>
<li>The apps have collectively garnered over 70 million downloads and maintain an average rating of 4.6, indicating high user satisfaction.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37463662">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users are expressing discontent with app stores that offer apps with ads and in-app purchases, advocating for ad-free applications available at a fixed price.</li>
<li>They are sharing experiences and features of various file browsing apps, and consider alternatives like Nintendo consoles or curated app stores for a cleaner user experience.</li>
<li>The debate also covers challenges and strategies of monetization for digital products with a stated desire for more transparency and better options to support software creators sans advertisements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://henrikwarne.com/2023/09/10/what-i-have-changed-my-mind-about-in-software-development/">What I have changed my mind about in software development</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author shares his evolving views on topics in software development such as commenting in code, unit testing of private methods, and the use of Integrated Development Environments (IDEs) and debuggers.</li>
<li>The author also discusses the advantages of remote work and utilizing ChatGPT, an AI language model developed by OpenAI, for certain tasks.</li>
<li>The importance of collaboration and openness to new ideas in software development is underscored in the post.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37457208">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://scitechdaily.com/90-reduction-scientists-discover-natural-molecule-that-eradicates-plaques-and-cavities/">The molecule DIM reduces biofilms causing dental plaque: study</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have discovered a naturally occurring molecule, DIM, capable of reducing dental plaque and cavities by up to 90%.</li>
<li>DIM works by disrupting the biofilm of bacteria that cause cavities, and it could be used to enhance oral hygiene products like toothpaste and mouthwash.</li>
<li>In addition to this breakthrough in dental health, the article also discusses various other scientific advancements and studies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37455106">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers found a molecule, DIM, which can reduce dental plaque, leading to the creation of a probiotic tablet to compete with detrimental mouth bacteria.</li>
<li>Commercialization of such products has been hindered due to uncertainty about their effectiveness and concerns over their long-term persistence.</li>
<li>The article discusses reasons for the limited traction of this innovation, skepticism on its effectiveness, pros and cons of oral hygiene practices and products and the potential influence of dental societies on approval and promotion of new treatments.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/11</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-11T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-10]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-10</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://benchmarks.llmonitor.com">Asking 60 LLMs a set of 20 questions</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The person developed a script designed to test basic reasoning, instruction following, and creativity of over 60 models.</li>
<li>The responses were stored in a SQLite database, offering unprocessed results for review.</li>
<li>This project aims at evaluating the performance of these models in actual, real-world workflows.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37445401">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around diverse aspects of AI language models, with a focus on their performance, limitations, and scope for enhancement.</li>
<li>Members exchange personal experiences and views on the accuracy, consistency, and applicability of these models in different scenarios, also discussing transparency and bias issues.</li>
<li>The discourse suggests the profound complexities, challenges, and potential benefits involved in the adoption of AI language models in varying domains.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.chemistryworld.com/news/lithium-discovery-in-us-volcano-could-be-biggest-deposit-ever-found/4018032.article">Lithium discovery in US volcano could be biggest deposit ever found</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A formidable lithium deposit, potentially the world&#39;s largest, has been discovered along the Nevada-Oregon border, which could significantly contribute to the global supply of lithium.</li>
<li>The deposit, housed in an unusual claystone in a volcanic crater, contains an estimated 20 to 40 million tonnes of lithium, nearly double that found in lithium-rich minerals.</li>
<li>This discovery, if leveraged efficiently, could materially impact the worldwide lithium market—altering prices, ensuring supply security, and influencing geopolitical dynamics.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37450915">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion emphasises lithium production aspects, including availability, refining and recycling challenges, and environmental impact, highlighting the need for specific skills and procedures for efficient battery manufacturing.</li>
<li>China currently leads in lithium refining, with noted viable lithium companies in the US. The conversation mentions the complexities and challenges related to recycling aluminum and calls for improved recycling rates for lithium.</li>
<li>The concern over the environmental footprint of lithium mining is countered by its vital role in electrification and combating climate change, with geopolitical implications. Calls for further research into eco-friendly extraction are linked to opposition to a proposed lithium mine in Nevada.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bricknerd.com/home/every-type-of-plastic-used-by-lego-5-20-22">Every type of plastic used by LEGO (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>This article outlines the various plastics LEGO employs, delving into their characteristics and applications.</li>
<li>LEGO&#39;s plastic compositions are trade secrets, underscoring the firm&#39;s endeavors to create eco-friendly materials.</li>
<li>The piece speculates on potential future materials for LEGO bricks, demonstrating continuous innovation in this field.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37444268">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides insight into the types of plastics used by LEGO, including discussions on storage, preservation, aging, and brittleness.</li>
<li>It raises questions about the environmental consequences of LEGO&#39;s use of plastics and potential greenwashing, despite the company&#39;s sustainability objectives.</li>
<li>The potential risk of microplastics and concerns about food safety in relation to LEGO lunchboxes are addressed, with suggestions for regular disassembly and washing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://thomask.sdf.org/blog/2023/09/09/memories-from-old-lan-parties.html">Memories from old LAN parties</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author brings a nostalgic insight into LAN parties from the 2000s, highlighting experiences with Windows operating systems, hardware modifications, and gaming practices.</li>
<li>The narrative recalls unique incidents like the necessity to reinstall Windows, hard drive theft, the use of cracks for pirated games, and the development of LAN technology over time.</li>
<li>The article takes a humorous and retrospecting lens towards the complexities and peculiarities of previous LAN gaming experiences.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37451518">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion reflects on the nostalgia and fond memories associated with LAN (Local Area Network) parties during the 90s and early 2000s.</li>
<li>Participants reminisce about their experiences in playing games, configuring computers, and the thrill and challenges of LAN gaming.</li>
<li>The conversation underscores the elements of camaraderie, competition, and pleasure that LAN parties fostered.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/scottbez1/smartknob">SmartKnob – Haptic input knob with software-defined endstops and virtual detents</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>SmartKnob is an open-source input device utilizing a brushless gimbal motor and magnetic encoder for precise control, offering customization for detents and endstops.</li>
<li>The development of this project is still ongoing and necessitates advanced soldering capabilities.</li>
<li>SparkFun Electronics manufactures and provides the suggested motors, and a Discord community exists for users to converse about their builds.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37448659">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SmartKnob is an open-source hardware project that has created a haptic input knob with software-defined endstops and virtual detents, praised for its potential in areas like music instruments, control panels, and simulators.</li>
<li>Despite the enthusiasm, some are expressing concerns about protection against voltage generated by the user&#39;s rotation of the knob.</li>
<li>The project is well-documented with a polished design and the creator is open to feedback and contributions for improvement, indicating an ongoing evolution in response to user needs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/live-blog/morocco-earthquake-kills-600-devastates-historic-sites-live-updates-rcna104208">Morocco earthquake kills more than 1,000</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A series of devastating earthquakes hit Morocco, leading to considerable loss of life and infrastructural damage.</li>
<li>The Moroccan King has enacted search and rescue teams, and the international community including the U.S. and Pope Francis have offered support and condolences.</li>
<li>Humanitarian groups and multiple countries are providing aid and assistance, as the process of searching for survivors and evaluating the level of damage continues.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37445284">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The deadly earthquake in Morocco has instigated an extensive discussion focusing on earthquake preparedness, visa policies for US immigrant professionals, and housing infrastructural concerns in quake-prone areas.</li>
<li>A controversial topic within the discussions is the claim made by a researcher who believes they can predict earthquakes based on planetary influences, drawing skepticism due to insufficient supporting scientific evidence.</li>
<li>The debate also ventures into the impacts of tourism on affected communities and the contention surrounding borders and immigration rights.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/europe/?url=https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/layoffs-google-microsoft-meta-amazon-hiring-low-paid-h1b-workers-after-us-layoffs-report-10605301.html">Google, Meta, Amazon hiring low-paid H1B workers after US layoffs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Top tech companies like Google, Meta, Amazon, Microsoft, Zoom, Salesforce, and Palantir have been applying for thousands of H1B worker visas this year, even while conducting mass layoffs.</li>
<li>Despite laying off employees, these companies still filed applications for H1B visas aiming to hire roles such as software engineers and researchers, reportedly focusing on lower-paid tech workers from overseas.</li>
<li>The layoffs have impacted many current workers on H1B visas, including those from India, highlighting a conflicting strategy of staff reduction while still seeking to hire foreign talent.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37444386">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around large tech companies, including Google, Meta, and Amazon, being scrutinized for allegedly hiring low-paid H1B workers after laying off local US employees, potentially as a strategy to depress salaries.</li>
<li>The conversation sheds light on the issues faced by H1B workers such as challenges related to language barriers, perceived bias in the hiring process, and concerns about their overall treatment, leading to calls for reform.</li>
<li>An extension of the discussion ventures into broader debates around prioritization of citizens in hiring practices, the value of American lives, and the role of national boundaries.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wellness/2023/09/08/public-restrooms-hard-find-comic/">Public restrooms are hard to find in America</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article highlights the challenge of locating public restrooms in America, a situation that particularly affects people with medical conditions.</li>
<li>Public restroom shortage impacts various groups including individuals with bowel conditions, the homeless, older adults, and pregnant individuals.</li>
<li>The article underscores the necessity of accessible restrooms for people who urgently need them.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37446083">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The main focus of the discussion is the availability and accessibility of public restrooms in urban areas of the United States, with specific mention of issues such as homelessness, drug use, and vandalism.</li>
<li>There is a debate on broader socio-economic factors, including inequality, civic responsibility, and the role businesses play in providing public facilities.</li>
<li>The conversation takes a comparative angle, referencing European countries and discussing how mental health care and terrorism impact public restroom facilities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://awealthofcommonsense.com/2023/09/the-u-s-housing-market-vs-the-canadian-housing-market/">The U.S. housing market vs. the Canadian housing market</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the significant difference between the United States and Canadian housing markets, with a 142% real increase in Canadian housing prices since 2005, compared to the U.S.&#39;s 26% surge in the same period.</li>
<li>The divergence is further noticeable when factoring in disposable income, where U.S. incomes have kept up with rising housing costs, yet Canadian incomes have lagged.</li>
<li>The central argument is that affordability in the housing market, while problematic in the U.S., is profoundly worse in Canada.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37446790">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>There has been a notable upsurge in Canadian housing prices, making homeownership increasingly challenging for young people and working individuals.</li>
<li>Elements such as government policies, investor impact, stagnant wages, and immigration are reported as factors contributing to this housing affordability crisis.</li>
<li>Various solutions are proposed including fast-tracked development, increased social housing funding, tax reforms, and balanced immigration policies, yet the absence of effective solutions and political stalemate is criticized.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.livescience.com/health/cancer/crispr-used-to-reprogram-cancer-cells-into-healthy-muscle-in-the-lab">CRISPR used to &#39;reprogram&#39; cancer cells into healthy muscle in the lab</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Scientists have successfully leveraged CRISPR technology to transform cancer cells into healthy muscle cells.</li>
<li>This breakthrough could pave the way for new possibilities in gene-editing therapies for cancer treatment.</li>
<li>CRISPR, or Clustered Regularly Interspaced Short Palindromic Repeats, is a gene-editing tool allowing researchers to precisely alter DNA sequences and modify gene function.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37444477">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Scientists have utilized CRISPR gene editing technology to transform cancer cells into healthy muscle cells in a laboratory setting.</li>
<li>This method could potentially pave the way for new treatments for muscle-degenerating diseases.</li>
<li>However, there are still hurdles to surmount, primarily safeguarding that the technology doesn&#39;t inadvertently inflict harm on healthy tissues.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-10T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-09]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-09</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://bun.sh/blog/bun-v1.0">Bun v1.0.0</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bun 1.0 is a toolkit designed to streamline JavaScript and TypeScript development, replacing multiple tools and offering compatibility with existing Node.js applications.</li>
<li>It comes with TypeScript, JSX support, and inbuilt Web APIs, making it a capable JavaScript runtime that can reportedly handle more requests per second than Node.js.</li>
<li>Additional features include WebSockets support and package management. The company that developed Bun 1.0 is situated in San Francisco and is currently recruiting staff.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37434117">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion is centered on Bun, a tool in the Node.js ecosystem that supports both CommonJS and ES modules, with users highlighting both pros and cons.</li>
<li>The conversation also sheds light on using Discord and GitHub as communication platforms for open-source projects.</li>
<li>The tool Bun is compared to other tools like Deno and Vite, with additional concerns raised regarding its stability and licensing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bitbashing.io/async-rust.html">Maybe Rust isn’t a good tool for massively concurrent, userspace software</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author clarifies the purpose of Async Rust, a programming language focusing on modern concurrency, differentiating between parallelism and concurrency and outlining the limitations of code-splitting.</li>
<li>Mutex-based concurrency is deemed detrimental due to risks of race conditions and deadlocks; thus, use of channels - or queues - for inter-thread communication is advised. However, for high-level concurrency problems, threads might not suffice, prompting Rust&#39;s &quot;async/await&quot; model.</li>
<li>Despite these advantages, Async Rust presents challenges, such as ensuring compiler safety of objects and ubiquitous use of Arc (Atomic Reference Count). The suitability of Rust&#39;s massively concurrent userspace software application remains questionable.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37435515">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discourse covers diverse subjects around programming in Rust such as memory safety, concurrency, graphics development, productivity, and memory management.</li>
<li>Participants&#39; shared experiences shed light on the advantages and challenges of using Rust and its applicability for various use cases.</li>
<li>The interaction also provides comparisons with other languages like Python and Go, and discusses multiple programming concepts like inheritance and abstraction, offering a view into Rust&#39;s strengths, weaknesses, and continuous efforts for enhancements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mtlynch.io/aardvarkd/">Aardvark&#39;d: The Fog Creek documentary, 18 years later</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post analyzes the documentary &quot;Aardvark&#39;d&quot;, which tracks interns at Fog Creek Software and includes interviews with accomplished tech industry personalities.</li>
<li>It focuses on the state of independent software development in 2005, including the foundation of Y Combinator and the genesis of Reddit.</li>
<li>It provides criticism for the film&#39;s lack of resolution, highlights the release of a video course on improving software creation, and offers links to both the documentary and the course on YouTube.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37433186">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides detailed commentary on &quot;Aardvark&#39;d,&quot; a documentary by Fog Creek, offering corrections and added context from film participants.</li>
<li>It explores multiple themes, such as Fog Creek Software&#39;s history, its product-related challenges and victories, and its relocation from Boston to Silicon Valley.</li>
<li>A significant portion of the discussion revolves around the widespread use of Atlassian&#39;s JIRA and the prevalence of functional specifications in software development, offering a nostalgic look into technology&#39;s evolution.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://procreate.com/dreams">Procreate Dreams</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Procreate Dreams is a newly launched animation app, designed for creating hand-drawn animations, motion graphics and more.</li>
<li>The app features multiple tools such as drawing, painting, audio and video editing, stage creation, live motion and effects, keyframes, real-time rendering, onion skins, and text and type animation.</li>
<li>The application, which is compatible with iPad and Apple Pencil, will be available for purchase from November 22 at a price of $19.99 USD.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37434918">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Procreate app, known for its quality and affordability, has excited users with the launch of its Procreate 5X version, introducing a new animation feature.</li>
<li>The upcoming Procreate animation app, Dreams, has elicited mixed reactions, with some users displaying enthusiasm while others question the need for adverts.</li>
<li>Amid positive feedback for the iPad app, discussions have surfaced regarding the potential development of Procreate for Android tablets.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://growth.design/case-studies/apple-privacy-policy">Apple vs. Meta: The Illusion of Privacy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article investigates the tactics employed by Apple and Meta to gather user data under the guise of providing privacy.</li>
<li>It delves into the role of psychology and user experience (UX) techniques in data collection strategies.</li>
<li>While these companies claim to protect user privacy, their underlying methods might contradict these assurances.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37433495">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article raises privacy issues centered around tech companies including Apple, Meta (Facebook&#39;s new name), and Google, with users and advertisers expressing concerns over targeted advertising and data collection.</li>
<li>There&#39;s a debate on the ethical implications of various tech companies&#39; data practices, with some criticism aimed at Apple&#39;s control over user data, while others commend Apple&#39;s privacy measures in comparison to other industry leaders.</li>
<li>The dialog also touches on the use of facial recognition technology and intrusive ads, emphasizing the broader need for privacy protection and more transparency from all tech companies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/typesfast/status/1700092765798048093">Flexport is rescinding a bunch of signed offer letters</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Flexport, a business entity, has withdrawn job offers from workers who were set to commence work on Monday.</li>
<li>The company&#39;s CEO, Ryan Petersen, voiced his regrets over the incident.</li>
<li>This decision was necessitated by problems encountered with the hiring processes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37433681">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Flexport, a logistics firm, attracted criticism for retracting job offers and discontinuing job postings, leading to a debate about its hiring practices and the ramifications of abrupt job exits.</li>
<li>The discourse on Hacker News encapsulates a broad spectrum of issues, including labor rights, employer loyalty, and the effects of layoffs, emphasising the moral dilemmas associated with rescinded job offers.</li>
<li>The conversation also sheds light on the benefits and drawbacks of remote work, sparking comparisons between the feasibility of working from home versus on-site office execution.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://emoji.fly.dev">Emoji Generator with AI</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>EmojiGen is an open-source emoji generator hosted on Replicate, allowing users to design and create custom emojis.</li>
<li>It extends its functionality by permitting users to fork the app on GitHub, specifically enabling the creation of unique emoji such as a floppy disk sandwich, a burning GPU, and various pop culture icons.</li>
<li>Users can generate emojis, download, and subsequently utilize them in platforms like Slack, fostering a more personalized messaging experience.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37433523">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article reviews an AI-powered emoji generator, with user feedback revealing concerns about biases and potential for integration into chat platforms.</li>
<li>The discussion also centers on Fly.io, a website service, with mixed feedback revolving around issues like reliability, data loss, and connection, alongside positive experiences and competitive pricing.</li>
<li>The limitations of the emoji generator, particularly regarding accuracy and biases, prompts a broader conversation about the responsibility of AI model creators in tackling these biases.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/8/23864538/turbotax-intuit-ftc-deceptive-practices-free-tax-filing">FTC judge decides Intuit’s ‘free’ TurboTax ads misled consumers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has ruled that Intuit, TurboTax&#39;s parent company, misled consumers by advertising its tax filing service as &quot;free.&quot;</li>
<li>Following the ruling and a $141 million payout after an FTC lawsuit, Intuit is now required to clearly disclose any terms that limit its free product offerings.</li>
<li>In light of difficulties encountered while trying to locate Intuit&#39;s actual free filing service, Free File, IRS is developing a government-supported free filing service set to pilot in the 2024 tax season.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37437311">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around users&#39; dissatisfaction with the TurboTax product from Intuit because of undisclosed fees, deceptive promotions, and a lack of transparency.</li>
<li>Alternative tax filing options like FreeTaxUSA and Cash App Taxes are suggested as more transparent and cost-effective solutions.</li>
<li>Topics of lobbying influence, corruption in the tax system, misleading advertising, and calls for system reform highlight the larger context of these user complaints and hints at the need for significant changes in the tax filing system.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/news/2023/bees-struggle-to-find-flowers-because-of-air-pollution">Bees struggle to find flowers because of air pollution</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A new study by the UK Centre for Ecology &amp; Hydrology and various universities reveals that air pollution hinders bees&#39; ability to find flowers as ozone degrades the scent of flowers.</li>
<li>The study found a reduction of up to 90% in honeybees&#39; odor recognition ability, indicating potential adverse effects on wildflower abundance and crop yields, as bees play a crucial role in pollination vital for food security.</li>
<li>The research also indicates that ozone may affect other odor-influenced behaviors of insects, such as mate attraction, enforcing the need for action on air pollution to safeguard food production and biodiversity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37434381">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Air pollution is purportedly causing a reduction in bee activity and difficulty in locating flowers, contributing to the decline of insect populations. Additional factors might include traffic and noise pollution, and a decrease in bee resources.</li>
<li>Some participants noted an increase in bee activity and wildlife, potentially due to favorable conditions or efforts to foster insect-friendly environments.</li>
<li>Discussions pointed out the possible impact of pollution on bee attraction to specific plants, hints of evolutionary pressure leading to bee adaptation to pollution, and an innovative solution to vehicular pollution through a catalytic converter.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://maizure.org/projects/decoded-gnu-coreutils/">Decoded: GNU Coreutils (2018)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The report covers MaiZure&#39;s project to demystify GNU coreutils version 8.3, specifically designed for beginner programmers.</li>
<li>Major pillars of the article are the overview of completed phases and deep dive into the design and features of utilities, encompassing information about the decoding framework applied for each utility and the prevalent concepts.</li>
<li>Also, it features insights into utility maintenance, updates, and processes for contributing to the project.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37439535">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion primarily centers on the &quot;yes&quot; command within the GNU Coreutils, highlighting the trade-offs between a program&#39;s efficiency and conciseness.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the advantage of using C programming language in writing system utilities, as this choice can lead to enhanced performance.</li>
<li>A notable irony is pointed out, that lengthy codes can sometimes be found in programs designed to perform no significant task.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/09</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-08]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-08</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2023/09/blastpass-nso-group-iphone-zero-click-zero-day-exploit-captured-in-the-wild/">NSO group iPhone zero-click, zero-day exploit captured in the wild</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple has released an update to address a zero-click vulnerability discovered by Citizen Lab, which was leveraged to deploy NSO Group&#39;s Pegasus spyware.</li>
<li>The exploit chain, known as BLASTPASS, could compromise iPhones running the latest iOS version without victim interaction. In response, Apple issued two CVEs (Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures), identifiers for publicly known security risks.</li>
<li>Users are recommended to update their devices and enable Lockdown Mode, potentially blocking this attack. This incident underscores the targeting of civil society organizations and the need for their cybersecurity support.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37425007">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around the NSO Group, an Israeli cybersecurity company, criticized for selling zero-click, zero-day exploits for iPhones, with concerns that authoritarian states employ their software to monitor and suppress activists and journalists.</li>
<li>Matters such as Apple&#39;s Lockdown Mode limitations, iMessage security, the efficacy of security measures, and the need for stronger protections to address vulnerabilities are considered, including the potential ramifications of iPhone region-locking.</li>
<li>The debate includes suggestions for strengthening security like fuzzing, using memory-safe languages (such as Rust), overcoming sandboxing limitations, and the importance of ethical considerations and regulatory measures in the cybersecurity industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/09/googles-widely-opposed-ad-platform-the-privacy-sandbox-launches-in-chrome/">Chrome now tracks users and shares a “topic” list with advertisers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google has introduced a new ad platform in Chrome called &quot;Privacy Sandbox,&quot; which monitors user activity to customize a list of advertising topics for websites.</li>
<li>While Google posits this as a necessary alternative to third-party tracking cookies—planning to block these by late 2024—critics suggest envisioning a world without targeted ads.</li>
<li>Chrome users have the ability to control this feature through their browser settings, offering some degree of agency over the process.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37427227">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discourse encompasses numerous topics concerning web browsers such as privacy issues, tracking practices, effects on competition, new feature and ad introduction, browser performance, and the necessity for stricter regulations.</li>
<li>The conversation extends to possible alternatives to mainstream browsers like Google Chrome, bots on websites, the security and ease of use trade-off, user agent strings, and Google&#39;s treatment of user data.</li>
<li>These discussions underscore the prevailing debates and concerns about web browsers and user privacy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.kagi.com/small-web">Kagi Small Web</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Kagi, a web search platform, has introduced Kagi Small Web, an innovative initiative focusing on boosting the visibility of the &#39;Small Web,&#39; described as the non-commercial segment of the internet.</li>
<li>This new service collects fresh data from handpicked blogs, displays it within their search results, and also offers an RSS feed. It is open-source and includes a specially curated list of almost 6,000 verified websites. Kagi Small Web&#39;s goal is to give a more personal search experience, spotlight lesser-known aspects of the web, and stress the significance of the Small Web.</li>
<li>Kagi has also unveiled the Kagi Small Web website, a platform operating without JavaScript to enable user interactions like appreciation of posts and note-taking. Users can access Kagi Small Web via an RSS feed or API, and provide feedback or contribute through various platforms.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37420281">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Kagi, a minor web search engine, has introduced a novel feature, &quot;Small Web&quot; explicitly showcasing content from independent blogs and websites.</li>
<li>Although Kagi is applauded for its user-friendly UI, dedication to privacy, and value, there is some criticism regarding its incorporation of links to centralized platforms such as Twitter, leading to suggestions for substitutes like Mastodon or federated, libre software choices.</li>
<li>Despite uncertainties about scalability and business models, there&#39;s a general sense of enthusiasm and endorsement for Kagi&#39;s new initiative.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tailscale.com/blog/mullvad-integration/">Mullvad on Tailscale: Privately browse the web</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Mullvad, a privacy-focused Virtual Private Network (VPN) service, has teamed up with Tailscale to provide Tailscale customers the use of Mullvad&#39;s VPN servers. This partnership enhances user privacy and security during web browsing.</li>
<li>Tailscale, which creates a private internet environment, acts as a coordination layer between devices and Mullvad&#39;s network edge, guaranteeing end-to-end encryption and privacy.</li>
<li>Although Tailscale knows users&#39; identities, it does not share personal information with Mullvad, further emphasizing privacy. This partnership allows for various uses of Mullvad exit nodes with Tailscale.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37420053">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The central theme of the article revolves around Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) and web proxies, highlighting their potential risks and different perspectives on their usage.</li>
<li>It includes a detailed focus on the integration of Tailscale and Mullvad, two VPN services, discussing their benefits and limitations.</li>
<li>There&#39;s an emphasis on privacy, censorship issues, and the usage of VPNs to access restricted content on the internet.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.google/threat-analysis-group/active-north-korean-campaign-targeting-security-researchers/">North Korean campaign targeting security researchers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google&#39;s Threat Analysis Group provides an update on a North Korean campaign targeting security researchers who focus on vulnerability research and development.</li>
<li>The government-supported actors use 0-day exploits, establish rapport with their targets via social media, and then send malicious files using encrypted messaging platforms.</li>
<li>The group has created a Windows tool capable of downloading and executing unspecified codes from an attacker-controlled domain. Google is presently taking measures to protect its users and disseminate outcomes within the security community.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37420831">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>North Korean hackers have been targeting security researchers with malicious code via GitHub, raising concerns about the safety of using open-source code.</li>
<li>The discussions delve into potential threats, including compromised maintainers, the misuse of GitHub stars, and questions surrounding the attribution of cyber attacks to North Korea.</li>
<li>The conversation also explores the training, recruitment tactics, and living conditions of North Korean hackers, sparking debates about the credibility of security intelligence reports and the risks these hackers present.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2023/09/07/copilot-copyright-commitment-ai-legal-concerns/">Microsoft will assume liability for legal copyright risks of Copilot</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft&#39;s new Copilot Copyright Commitment defends customers from lawsuits over copyright infringement related to the use of Microsoft&#39;s Copilot services or their generated output.</li>
<li>The commitment applies to paid versions of Copilot services and mandates customers to use content filters and refrain from generating any infringing materials.</li>
<li>Microsoft&#39;s move aims to stand behind its customers, take responsibility for any legal issues from its product use, and ensure the promotion of AI goals, copyright respect, competition, and innovation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37420885">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft has pledged to bear any copyright risks pertaining to its Copilot AI tool amid user worries about potential copyright infringement and the impact on the broader code repository.</li>
<li>There is ongoing debate around the legality and fair use of generative AI in content creation, with particular focus on its intersection with copyright law and the need for legal clarification.</li>
<li>Discussions have also emerged on the liability related to using Copilot and how enforceable Microsoft&#39;s commitment really is. The discourse contains diverging opinions, with some questioning the copyrightability of certain code snippets and others emphasizing respect for intellectual property.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mullvad.net/en/blog/2023/9/7/tailscale-has-partnered-with-mullvad/">Tailscale Has Partnered with Mullvad</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Tailscale has entered into a collaboration with Mullvad VPN, letting their customers utilize both services in tandem.</li>
<li>This partnership allows Tailscale customers to reach their devices via Tailscale&#39;s mesh network and send outbound connections through Mullvad VPN&#39;s WireGuard servers.</li>
<li>The collaboration provides users with a higher degree of functionality and versatility.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37420382">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Tailscale has entered into a collaboration with Mullvad, a firm entrenched in the arena of internet security and privacy.</li>
<li>The specific details of this partnership and what it may entail are currently undisclosed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://textual.textualize.io/blog/2023/09/06/what-is-textual-web/">Textual Web: TUIs for the Web</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Textual Web is a project converting Textual-supported terminal applications into web apps, removing the necessity for firewall and port configurations.</li>
<li>It simplifies sharing applications through URLs, making web app development more attainable for Python developers lacking web development experience.</li>
<li>Future updates aim to incorporate additional web platform APIs and support for constructing terminal, web, and desktop apps from the same codebase. Right now, the Textual Web project is in public beta.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37418424">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the concept of Textual User Interfaces (TUIs) and how it compares to Graphical User Interfaces (GUIs), shedding light on their potential coexistence.</li>
<li>It highlights some tools, like AutoCAD and Emacs, that provide both TUI and GUI options, indicating the flexibility in the user interface design.</li>
<li>The Textual app, a TUI development framework for Python, is introduced, and some users&#39; experiences and views on Textual are presented, providing an actual application and reaction to TUIs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.modular.com/blog/mojo-its-finally-here">Mojo is available for local download</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Mojo, a high-performance programming language tailored for AI developers, is now ready for local download. It integrates with Python, enabling the use of the complete Mojo feature set, including compiler features and IDE tools.</li>
<li>The Mojo Software Development Kit (SDK) offers tools like the Mojo Driver, a Visual Studio Code Extension, and Jupyter Integration. It allows developers to harness Python performance and access the Python ecosystem in a seamless manner.</li>
<li>Future plans for Mojo include open sourcing some parts of the language for further development and improvement.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37421529">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation focuses on Mojo, a programming language, with concerns regarding its licensing model, closed-source nature, and unclear future in open-sourcing.</li>
<li>Users are reluctant to invest time in Mojo due to its closed-source aspect and the uncertainty about the creators&#39; openness.</li>
<li>Opinions are divided on Mojo&#39;s syntax style, performance, and its effectiveness compared to Python for programming and machine learning tasks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-09-07/grindr-loses-nearly-half-its-staff-to-strict-return-to-office-rule">Grindr Loses Almost Half Its Staff on 2-Day RTO Requirement</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The LGBTQ dating app, Grindr, has witnessed about 45% of its workforce resigning after it enforced a rigid back-to-office policy amidst unionization plans.</li>
<li>Grindr&#39;s policy required employees to work in-person for two days a week or risk being terminated.</li>
<li>Consequently, approximately 80 out of 178 employees had to resign due to disagreeing with the company&#39;s new strategy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37421241">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>This summary discusses certain issues, namely staff cuts at Grindr and allegations of improper handling of employees and potential security threats.</li>
<li>It notes Elon Musk&#39;s claim that Twitter advertising revenue declined due to the Anti-Defamation League (ADL) and Center for Countering Digital Hate (CCDH).</li>
<li>The summary also delves into the discussion on the expenditures incurred in managing a software company, the distinction of businesses as software companies, and their capability to adapt to market requirements via software subscriptions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/08</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-07]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-07</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/770e58b1-a299-4b7b-a129-bded8649a43b">UK pulls back from clash with Big Tech over private messaging</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The UK government has decided to withdraw from its conflict with Big Tech companies regarding access to private messaging.</li>
<li>This decision follows their proposed regulations meant to protect children from harmful online content, highlighting a potential clash between safety and privacy concerns.</li>
<li>The government&#39;s backtracking reflects concerns about potential impacts on end-to-end encryption and message privacy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37408196">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The UK government has been criticized for allegedly misrepresenting its stance on accessing encrypted messages, with critics arguing the proposed Online Safety Bill undermines encryption. This is proposing some secure messaging platforms to consider leaving the UK in order to preserve their security measures.</li>
<li>The government denies retreating in the encryption dispute, insisting it is dedicated to child safety. However, this has sparked debates on client-side scanning, privacy implications, data mining, end-to-end encryption, and backdoor access.</li>
<li>The government&#39;s plan to delay the scanning of messaging applications for harmful content until it becomes technically feasible is met with criticism. The potential impact of quantum computing on encryption, and vulnerabilities of different encryption methods, are also contentious topics amongst the public.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://smolsite.zip/UEsDBBQAAgAIAMYVIVfaTMb/VQIAANwDAAAKAAAAaW5kZXguaHRtbHVTUW+bMBB+Lr/ilq1i0wo4BGghJA/t9lBpk6Zpm6Y91cEOeAPMbCeEbv3vO0OjZdIK4mTuvvt8+vw5r0xTr5284pStc22Gmq+djWQD/HI2tPhRKrlrmVfIWqoMnm/HZ3laEg0teQY7Vb+cMWpoNiYCvS9fH5r64nxxg0voBTPVyp2HLlRclJXBdeLCXvD+Wh5WLgEC8xBsDrtavXIrY7osCPq+9/uFL1UZhIQQy+ueL94ibUdNBWzlvo/AT9MbjFEUQ4QxQrIYSOHHcWh5sRLbmKb7yCfhTQIxluIxJoB/kBTeBPbmHoJtTNMv+N03CVwVBKtRYpltHsbqE+QFAYv1LBhz3lj5H/mVZXdhK+p65Z6HC3bJYkanhCc7WggzoC5+9JhSu5qvXL7nrWTMDSYNrBy4mr1aOlvZGm9LG1EPGWjaak9zJfCsGqpK0WYo71V3WDoPTsFbwxUe8FlHGRNteVLrFLeFv+eLhx4S+y6ds6MLLol9lyf9IbHtZ4YfzNErU+rByYPJVXkweszJrbus4+brW+NqoKAbWWth+DOEzNeOk3frT5XQ0Fey5mArqIDRIFotGAdTcfj88R2iu0ewhEpqA4PcKY1O1BOmkE1D0aC1aNGf3c4AiqcGU+HEyIUbf7v9YLXlF3BNsSmJgLeFxC2EuQBsBYMy4A/QrRVsZi2p0ZPHgf170QWz7DiIwqvzAjAH3puv33+moGXDjzjckfGDb68bNEMtS+l3bYl4XlTyCeq7gpp/SX7DBifFQT2vV7QDcjdDgced82ASFhfTnXb+AFBLAQIeAxQAAgAIAMYVIVfaTMb/VQIAANwDAAAKAAAAAAAAAAEAAACkgQAAAABpbmRleC5odG1sUEsFBgAAAAABAAEAOAAAAH0CAAAAAA==">Host a Website in the URL</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author has recently developed a technology demonstration - commonly known as a &#39;tech demo&#39; - for their web server library, described as entertaining yet functionally pointless.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37408150">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion encompasses various projects and ideas for website hosting and content sharing through URLs, including web server libraries, TinyURL, data URIs, gzip compression, base64 encoding, and zip files.</li>
<li>It touches on the pros and cons of these methods, addressing issues such as commercialization, security risks, file size limits, and liability for shared content.</li>
<li>Numerous techniques and examples illustrate the innovative potential of these methods, highlighting the shared insights from those in the comment section.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/jqlang/jq/releases/tag/jq-1.7">jq 1.7</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The open source software tool, jq 1.7, has been released, marking a revival of the project after a five-year pause and introduction of new admins and maintainers.</li>
<li>The 1.7 release brings a range of updates and enhancements including improved documentation, platform compatibility, changes to the Command Line Interface (CLI), and language enhancements.</li>
<li>The post acknowledges the contributors to the project and provides a link for a full review of changes made in this update via a changelog.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37412698">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article covers diverse views on the efficacy of the programming language JQ in parsing JSON files.</li>
<li>Some users commend JQ while others critique its query syntax as unintuitive, favoring solutions like Python instead.</li>
<li>While the value of JQ is recognized, opinions differ regarding its usability, with some users suggesting alternatives for managing JSON data.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/blog/2023/09/results-of-major-technical-investigations-for-storm-0558-key-acquisition/">Results of technical investigations for Storm-0558 key acquisition</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft has shared the results of its investigation into the Storm-0558 actor who used a consumer key to breach OWA and Outlook.com.</li>
<li>Findings reveal that a crash dump in April 2021 contained the signing key, later shifted to the debugging environment within the corporate network. Hereafter, a Microsoft engineer&#39;s corporate account was compromised by the actor to gain this key.</li>
<li>Microsoft also discovered a library error that let the mail system accept enterprise email requests signed with the consumer key, which the company has since rectified.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37408776">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text summarises security breaches and vulnerabilities at Microsoft, including compromised credentials, unauthorized access to sensitive data, mishandled key material, and potential weak spots in the authentication system.</li>
<li>The incidents have sparked debates surrounding Microsoft&#39;s security measures and structural issues, questioning the potential risks and consequences of cyber attacks.</li>
<li>Emphasizing the need for reinforced engineering systems, data security, log retention policies, and third-party investigators, the discussion criticizes Microsoft&#39;s management of these incidents.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://joearms.github.io/#2013-11-21%20My%20favorite%20Erlang%20Program">My favorite Erlang program (2013)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author developed a program named &quot;Universal Server&quot; in the Erlang language, demonstrating its versatility as it can be configured to become any specific server.</li>
<li>They extended this by creating a factorial server and combining these servers in a test program, further exemplifying Erlang&#39;s efficacy.</li>
<li>Utilizing the Planet Lab research network, the author implemented a gossip algorithm, allowing the network to transform into different servers, further illustrating the dynamic nature of the Erlang language and its utility in network applications.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37413908">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions focus on the Erlang programming language, its concurrency model, and hot-reloading capabilities.</li>
<li>Benefits of choosing Erlang over other languages such as Go have been highlighted.</li>
<li>Security issues, Erlang&#39;s comparison with other distributed systems, and the necessity for a canonical example program are other topics discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/beetle-grows-termite-back-steal-food">Beetle grows ‘termite’ on back to steal food</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Scientists have discovered a new species of rove beetle that mimics the physical appearance of termites to trick them into providing food.</li>
<li>The beetle resembles termites&#39; body segments and features closely, enabling it to evade detection within termite nests.</li>
<li>Instead of consuming termite eggs or larvae, the beetle likely mimics their behavior, &quot;begging&quot; for food and thus securing itself a constant source of sustenance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37412772">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An Australian beetle has evolved to mimic termites for food theft, creating an ongoing evolutionary arms race between the two species.</li>
<li>Much of the conversation concerns the validity of evolutionary theories, including debates about the accuracy of &quot;just-so stories&quot; and speculation on the reasons behind mimicry.</li>
<li>The post includes discussion on gene theft, the effectiveness of the beetle&#39;s mimicry, and possibilities of other organisms evolving to mimic different species.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://monthlyreview.org/2009/05/01/why-socialism/">Why Socialism? (1949)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Albert Einstein advocates for socialism as a resolution to societal crises, emphasizing the importance of a supranational organization to mitigate potential conflict.</li>
<li>He denotes a marked distinction between the social behavior of humans and animals, arguing that our present economic system promotes self-interest and disparity.</li>
<li>Einstein suggests that socialism, combined with an education structure centered on social objectives, could address societal issues, although he does recognize its inherent challenges and emphasizes the significance of free and open discussion on these matters.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37407331">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers broad economic topics, namely socialism, capitalism, labor, and unemployment, touching on the challenges of implementing socialism and Marx&#39;s value theory.</li>
<li>Dialogue includes the interaction between labor and capital, the effect of unemployment on capitalism, and critiques of varying economic systems.</li>
<li>Additionally, the conversation acknowledges the inherent complexities within economic theories, the challenges of an effective value measurement system, and varying perspectives towards potential solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://once.com/">37signals Introduces &quot;Once&quot; - Buy software one time</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author points out a shift in business software models, transitioning from owning software to subscribing under the Software as a Service (SaaS) model.</li>
<li>They contend that while SaaS has been financially rewarding for software vendors, this trend appears to be subsiding with the enhancement of self-hosting technology and organizations&#39; desire for greater control.</li>
<li>The author introduces &quot;ONCE&quot;, a forthcoming series of software tools that can be owned indefinitely with a single payment, signifying a potential post-SaaS era and planned to be unveiled in late 2023.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37408929">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>There&#39;s an ongoing debate between subscription pricing models and one-time payments for software, spurred by concerns over difficult cancellations, cumulative costs, and continuous need for updates.</li>
<li>The announcement of a &quot;Once&quot; pricing model by 37signals incites mixed reactions, with some users appreciating the one-time payment option, while others express skepticism and criticize the language used in the announcement.</li>
<li>Discussions also feature concerns about long-term software support, compatibility, the limitations of the SaaS (Software as a Service) model, and the benefits of self-hosting.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://ephemeralp2p.durazo.us/2bbbf21959178ef2f935e90fc60e5b6e368d27514fe305ca7dcecc32c0134838">This page exists only if someone is looking at it</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ephemeral P2P is a peer-to-peer content sharing platform; users register the hash of the content they want to share, and this content is retrieved and passed on by a server when others visit the corresponding link.</li>
<li>The platform, using Elixir and Phoenix framework, explores the potential of peer-to-peer transactions via browser websockets and the concept of content-addressed web.</li>
<li>This application does not sanitize shared HTML content; however, no private information is included in the exchange.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37410630">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers on a learning-based toy app for Elixir, Phoenix, and websockets, which brought up the potential of browsers&#39; peer-to-peer capabilities for truly distributed networks.</li>
<li>Participants debated the merits and challenges of ephemeral peer-to-peer content sharing on the web, including customizable open-source clients, the potential of WebRTC, and the currently prevalent centralized platforms.</li>
<li>Ideas for server caching enhancement, provision for non-JS enabled clients to view pages, handling network glitches, and potential for using this technology in web hosting were also debated, highlighting both limitations and benefits.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/ogham/exa">Exa Is Deprecated</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The exa project is an open-source tool designed as a contemporary substitute for the &quot;ls&quot; command, offering additional features and improved defaults.</li>
<li>This tool employs color coding to differentiate file types and is well-informed about symlinks (symbolic links), extended attributes, and Git, a distributed version control system.</li>
<li>The exa tool is characterized by its small size, high speed, and compatibility with macOS and Linux systems; the post includes information on installation procedures and methods of developing and testing the tool using Vagrant, a tool for building and maintaining portable virtual software development environments.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37416430">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The users are having a dialogue about various command-line utilities, primarily focusing on the &quot;ls&quot; command and its alternatives like &quot;exa&quot; and &quot;lsd&quot;, debating their strengths and weaknesses.</li>
<li>The conversation also gravitates towards the significance of open-source developers in conveying their status, exploring the possibilities for forks and rewrites in software.</li>
<li>They also delve into the balance between stability and innovation in software development, illustrating the trade-offs involved.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/07</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-06]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-06</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37392676">I’m an FCC Commissioner proposing regulation of IoT security updates</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>FCC Commissioner Nathan Simington is stressing the need for security updates for IoT devices, highlighting common vulnerabilities and a shortage of timely manufacturer support.</li>
<li>The FCC proposes a cybersecurity labeling program for connected devices, with security update support disclosure as a key criterion.</li>
<li>Commissioner Simington encourages public feedback on this proposal to help in decision-making, with a submission deadline of September 25th, 2023.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37392676">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>FCC Commissioner Nathan Simington proposed regulations aiming for manufacturers to provide security updates for IoT devices for a specific period post-purchase.</li>
<li>The FCC has launched a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking for a cybersecurity labeling program, highlighting the value of public comments in decision-making.</li>
<li>Topics in discussion include the challenges of remote update mechanisms, probing IoT devices for vulnerabilities, the cooperative framework between researchers and companies, the role of government in IoT security, and concerns about cybercrime.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/opentffoundation/opentf">OpenTF repository is now public</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The opentf repository on GitHub is a developing project gearing up for its first alpha release. OpenTF is an open-source tool used for infrastructure management, utilizing high-level configuration syntax.</li>
<li>OpenTF comes with several features like infrastructure as code, execution plans, a resource graph &amp; automated changes. The repository also contains OpenTF Core, the command line interface, and the principle graph engine.</li>
<li>OpenTF repository includes a guide for contributors detailing how to compile OpenTF as well as how to submit bug reports or enhancement requests. The repository is licensed under Mozilla Public License v2.0.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37392581">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The OpenTF repository has been publicly launched on GitHub, inciting conversations about the employment of binary search and PRs (Pull Requests) to detect and rectify coding issues, worries about the merging process, and potential licensing problems in the Terraform fork.</li>
<li>There have been discussions about likely trademark issues that may cause confusion with other products within the OpenTF project, and the frustration caused by licensing changes in Terraform.</li>
<li>Various opinions have been voiced on the licensing decisions made by HashiCorp, focusing on the expectations of users and competitors, and there&#39;s palpable concern about the future of open-source projects and possible dissuasion for businesses.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/__silent_/status/1698345924840296801">Rockstar is selling cracked game copies on Steam</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&#39;</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37394665">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Rockstar Games is allegedly selling cracked versions of games on Steam, stirring discussions around potential copyright violation and the efficacy of digital rights management (DRM) protocols.</li>
<li>The discussion includes points on the legality of derivative works, distribution of cracked software, and various gaming industry&#39;s copyright protection strategies, highlighting the controversial takedown of a Star Trek fan project.</li>
<li>The dialogues revolve around the rightful ownership of cracked software, with some users arguing that Rockstar should have avoided DRM, while others critiquing the company for sharing pirated binaries.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/measuredco/puck">Puck – Open-source visual editor for React</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Puck, the newly developed tool, merges the adaptability of a traditional CMS (Content Management System) with the command granted by a headless CMS, empowering content teams to author using actual React components.</li>
<li>Puck can function either as an independent editor or on the foundation of an existing headless CMS and is compatible with Next.js, an open-source development framework.</li>
<li>The author is welcoming feedback for continued improvements, indicating plans for future updates to Puck.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37391848">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Puck is an open-source visual editor for React which enables content teams to build web pages using React components. It can function with an existing headless Content Management System (CMS) or as an autonomous tool.</li>
<li>The creator of Puck plans to add support for multi-column layouts and new plugins following positive feedback for its user-friendly design and versatility. Users have proposed improvements and expressed interest in utilizing Puck for their projects.</li>
<li>The author discusses the merits and drawbacks of Puck, comparing it to alternatives such as Storyblok, Vue Designer, and grapesjs, and mentions Builder.io as another visual React builder.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/EmNudge/watlings">Learn WebAssembly by writing small programs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Watlings&quot; is a GitHub repository under active development aiming to assist users in learning WebAssembly (Wasm) through hands-on fixing of small programs.</li>
<li>The project is open to contributions with users invited to file issues and make pull requests, utilizing Node 16+ and NPM for compilation and testing.</li>
<li>The repository provides instructions for setup and usage, and recommends tools like the official WebAssembly Binary Toolkit and VSCode with the WATI extension for an optimal coding experience. The methodology focuses on learning by doing with minimal explanations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37393820">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussed articles concentrate on WebAssembly (WASM) and its utilization in web development, covering the benefits of using WASM for heavy workloads despite its limitations like lack of access to the Document Object Model (DOM) and limited tooling.</li>
<li>Various programming languages, frameworks, and tools compatible with WASM are also reviewed, expanding its usability in the coding spectrum.</li>
<li>Additionally, they share experiences and opinions on WASM&#39;s potential, providing insight into its practicality and future in web development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://httptoolkit.com/blog/android-14-breaks-system-certificate-installation/">Android 14 blocks all modification of system certificates, even as root?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Android 14 restricts the ability to alter trusted certificates even on rooted devices, aiming to increase security by enabling Google to revoke the trust of problematic certificate authorities.</li>
<li>This move could impact privacy, impede the adoption of new certificates, and cause difficulties for new certification authorities like Let&#39;s Encrypt.</li>
<li>As a workaround, users can use Android 13 for debugging HTTPS traffic and HTTP Toolkit for examining and debugging Android traffic while alternative solutions for network traffic interception on Android are being discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37391521">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Dialogues cover a range of tech topics, including Android 14 changes that prevent system certificate alteration, secure communication and authentication for banking applications, and the utilization of cardTAN for authentication.</li>
<li>There&#39;s discussion around challenges with closed-source software, restrictions imposed by tech companies, the future of open hardware, HTTPS privacy issues on iOS, and the effects of Android 14 on Let&#39;s Encrypt certificates and user CA certificates on Android devices.</li>
<li>Topics also include potential implications of hardware attestation, compatibility of rooted devices with apps/services, varying operating systems&#39; control and security, and concerns on governmental surveillance and control, illustrating the friction between security, control, and user freedom in the tech sphere.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/deadbeefsociety/sshfs">A currently maintained fork of SSHFS</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>This is a spin-off of the SSHFS project which permits users to connect with a remote filesystem using SFTP, a secure file transfer protocol.</li>
<li>The original SSHFS is unmaintained now, prompting the creation of this fork aiming to resolve issues, accept pull requests, and provide necessary support and updates until a separate rust fork is prepared.</li>
<li>Developed using C, Python, Shell, Meson, and Emacs Lisp languages, the project is open to contributions and encourages users to report bugs on their GitHub issue tracker.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37390184">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion on Hacker News centers around alternative tools for remote file access such as SSHFS, TRAMP, and SFTP, along with user experiences and preferences regarding these tools.</li>
<li>The potential cessation of SSHFS is debated and the author provides resources on SFTP-over-WS, discussing further alternatives like rclone mount, Nautilus, and NFS over Wireguard.</li>
<li>Other topics addressed include open-source software project maintenance, build automation config files, package management for various programming languages, and comparisons between cloud storage platforms. User frustration concerning the lack of standardization and configuration inconvenience in various programs is also voiced.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.fast.ai/posts/2023-09-04-learning-jumps/">Can LLMs learn from a single example?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fast.ai researchers found that large language models (LLMs) can rapidly memorize examples from datasets after a single exposure, defying typical expectations.</li>
<li>This discovery could potentially influence how LLMs are trained and utilized.</li>
<li>The research team proposes solutions such as dropout and stochastic depth techniques, and the use of diverse datasets during training to deter models from forgetting. They encourage further dialogue on this topic via Twitter.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37399873">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post investigates the capacity of language models (LLMs) to learn from one example, their tendency for catastrophic forgetting, overconfidence, and utilization of inference during the training process.</li>
<li>It explores how altering specific neurons in LLMs can affect their performance, underscores the value of human-curated data, and debates limitations of synthetic data usage.</li>
<li>Lastly, it delves into the efficiency of LLMs in data memorization and the potential benefits of integrating long context windows.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://redeem-tomorrow.com/if-you-can-use-open-source-you-can-build-hardware">If you can use open source, you can build hardware</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author emphasizes the benefits and accessibility of creating hardware products utilizing open-source code and microcontrollers, highlighting the ease and flexibility of various boards and software ecosystems like Arduino, MicroPython, and CircuitPython.</li>
<li>The author underlines the convenience of using a two-wire serial data standard called I2C and cable standards such as StemmaQT and Qwiic, which simplify the building process.</li>
<li>They also draw attention to the advent of 3D printing and Computer-aided Design (CAD) tools that facilitate manufacturing custom enclosures for hardware projects, encouraging readers to delve into DIY electronics creation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37395096">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The summary discusses the difficulties and limitations of creating hardware using open-source resources, such as bridging the gap between prototyping and developing production-grade hardware.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the DIY character of open-source hardware projects and highlights the significance of safety measures, proper measuring tools, and guidance for successful execution.</li>
<li>It touches on the complexities of hardware design, the use of 3D printing, and the problems encountered while designing and prototyping, closing with the challenges and criticisms of constructing hardware projects without access to proprietary schematics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.gsa.gov/about-us/regions/region-7-greater-southwest/region-7-newsroom/greater-southwest-feature-stories-and-news-releases/gsa-announces-sale-of-federal-helium-system-assets-06222023">The Federal Helium reserve is for sale</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The General Services Administration (GSA) has publicized its plans to sell the Federal Helium System assets, as directed by Congress, which includes properties, equipment, mineral rights, and a helium storage reservoir.</li>
<li>The sales process, which is expected to last between 8-9 months, will involve the engagement of industry stakeholders to ensure an efficient transfer of assets.</li>
<li>Detailed information on this process is available on the GSA website, where interested parties can also submit their bids within the given timeframe. The GSA provides procurement and shared services for the federal government and manages a real estate portfolio and technology services.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37391584">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The US Federal Helium reserve is being privatized, sparking controversy and raising concerns about the rationale of selling this valuable resource.</li>
<li>Questions are being raised about helium&#39;s limited supply and potential scarcity, its extensive usage across industries, and potential environmental implications of its extraction from natural gas.</li>
<li>Fears abound that the sale could result in a future shortage of helium, adversely affecting sectors like healthcare and scientific research.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/06</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023-09-05]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/14">2023-09-05</a></h1>
<h2><a href="https://vscodium.com">VSCodium – Open-source binaries of VSCode</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>VSCodium is a free and open-source substitute for Microsoft&#39;s Visual Studio Code (VS Code), driven by the community and offering binaries of VS Code devoid of the proprietary license and telemetry/tracking.</li>
<li>Ease of access to the MIT-licensed VS Code is made more convenient thanks to VSCodium, with options to download directly or install through package managers across multiple platforms like Windows, Mac OS, and Linux.</li>
<li>VSCodium also provides a Flatpak app installation option and detailed documentation for users transitioning from Visual Studio Code.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37381335">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation discusses different topics including software trust, open-source project vulnerabilities, and Microsoft&#39;s practices, in addition to alternate software considerations.</li>
<li>Participants emphasized key aspects such as verification, supply chain security, data privacy, digital rights management (DRM), licensing, and extension compatibility.</li>
<li>The discussion underscores the stress between proprietary practices and the open-source ethos observed in applications like Visual Studio Code.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://vgel.me/posts/c500/">Writing a C compiler in 500 lines of Python</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The text discusses a C compiler written in 500 lines of Python targeted towards WebAssembly, which can successfully compile and run simple C programs despite some limitations.</li>
<li>It provides an insight into the different modules and classes used in this compiler, the mechanisms for controlling flow, and how it deals with global declarations.</li>
<li>The compiler employs WASM instructions and structured control flow to handle loops and conditionals effectively.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37383913">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article delves into the complexity of creating a C compiler with Python, highlighting the distinctive characteristics of the C language, comprehension of scalar data types, and managing languages with infix notation.</li>
<li>It touches upon eliminating the need for less mainstream platforms by targeting modern architectures, alongside discussing the negative and positive aspects of undertaking programming-related tasks.</li>
<li>The narrative also explores the merits of university education, creating unique programming languages, and domain-specific languages, providing resources for crafting dynamic languages, and discusses the actual definition of a compiler.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/tv-museum-will-die-in-48-hours-unless-sony-retracts-youtube-copyright-strikes-230904/">Sony sends copyright notices to TV Museum about shows 40 to 60 years old</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Museum of Classic Chicago Television, a non-profit that preserves historical TV content, may close within 48 hours due to Sony&#39;s copyright strikes.</li>
<li>These copyright claims, filed by Sony for TV shows from 40 to 60 years ago, have jeopardized the museum&#39;s status on YouTube, where it has run since 2007.</li>
<li>Rick Klein, the founder of the museum, is urgently attempting to settle the copyright issues to prevent the project&#39;s termination.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37379272">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discourse entails multiple themes such as copyright infringement, archiving platforms, impacts of copyright laws on content creators, data hoarding, automated takedowns, and the autonomy of platforms to manage content.</li>
<li>The discussion examines the distinction between matters of fact and law, the role of judicial powers to overlook certain laws, and politicians&#39; comprehension of internet technologies.</li>
<li>It highlights the debate over entities&#39; rights to decline hosting content, watermarks&#39; usage, preservation of dated works, and the human involvement in copyright takedown processes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://telecom.csail.mit.edu/judy-sammel.html">Get a cable modem, go to jail (1999)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author recounts a personal experience about being incorrectly charged with cable fraud by Comcast@home, leading to a criminal summons.</li>
<li>Despite facing hurdles with Comcast and the court system, the charges were dismissed, after which the author suggested improvements to Comcast&#39;s procedures to avoid similar situations.</li>
<li>The author calls for clearer roles for customer support and received an apology from Comcast; the author&#39;s criminal record was consequently expunged.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37386397">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The forum loosely relates to personal anecdotes as a broadband technician, touching upon subjects like gun safety and legislation, gun ownership in distinctive countries, and theft of cable and infringement of copyrights.</li>
<li>Discussions extend to experiences with service providers, the theory of a free market, and the expense associated with felony defense.</li>
<li>Participants present diverse opinions on these issues, emphasizing the complexities and difference in perspectives entailed within these topics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://cs.stanford.edu/people/zjl/tide.html">Tidal energy is not renewable</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The list encompasses several scientific papers discussing diverse topics, including theories of low and high-temperature superconductivity, superfluids, and electron tunneling.</li>
<li>The importance and limitations of LK-99, the explanation behind Brownian motion, and the processes that drive Crookes radiometers are also examined.</li>
<li>The list challenges misconceptions in thermodynamics, explores the possibility that Earth&#39;s magnetic field is a superconductor, discusses why tidal energy isn&#39;t renewable, and presents ways to understand relativity and derive E=mc2.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37383283">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores the renewable nature of tidal energy, exponential growth in energy consumption, and the feasibility of future energy projects, such as a Dyson sphere or swarm.</li>
<li>Key topics include obstacles to sustainability, population growth, fertility rates, strategies to meet future energy demands, and energy consumption&#39;s impact on environmental stability and economic development.</li>
<li>Other areas covered are the persistence of inequality, effects of energy extraction on Earth&#39;s rotation and climate, influence of wind patterns on energy generation, and the dynamics of the real estate and oil production industries.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/lambertjamesd/portal64">Portal 64 – A demake of Portal for the Nintendo 64</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The GitHub repository &quot;portal64,&quot; created by lambertjamesd, is a demake of the game &quot;Portal&quot; tailored for the Nintendo 64 console, with code, assets, and related documentation included.</li>
<li>The summary provides a guide on constructing the project using the Modern SDK, Blender, and various other tools, and it also outlines future tasks, features, and current bugs.</li>
<li>This repository has accrued a large number of stars, watchers, and forks, highlighting its popularity among users, and the project operates under the MIT license.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37381407">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Portal 64, a project aiming to demake the game Portal for the Nintendo 64 console, is currently under development. Its GitHub repository currently lacks visual updates, per user feedback.</li>
<li>A debate surfaced, focusing on energy efficiency versus ecological impact in manufacturing and disposing of old hardware. Some argue for energy-efficient technology, while others support the utilization of existing hardware due to ecological reasons.</li>
<li>Related topics expanded to include digital preservation, backward compatibility, and complexities of game development. The creator is known for successful N64 demakes using the N64 SDK, noted for compatibility with original hardware.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/oscilloscope-watch-ships-after-10-years">Oscilloscope watch ships after 10 years on Kickstarter</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37385811">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>After a 10-year wait, the oscilloscope watch, which measures electrical activity and also serves as a timepiece, has started shipping to backers.</li>
<li>The watch&#39;s release stimulated discussions around nerve conduction studies and electromyography, crowdfunding risks on platforms like Kickstarter, and experiences with other technological items such as the Ultimate Hacking Keyboard.</li>
<li>Conversations also revolved around the intricacies involved in designing the oscilloscope watch, its accuracy, and its pre-release sales strategy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://louison.substack.com/p/i-built-a-plane-spotter-for-my-son">I built a plane spotter for my son in minutes</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author rapidly created a plane spotting tool using ChatGPT, a powerful technology, and adapted it into a web app that provides real-time notifications of nearby flights based on user location.</li>
<li>The author emphasizes the potential for technology to convert ideas into reality quickly, suggesting a future focused on creative insights and effective machine communication.</li>
<li>Pondering the future, the author hypothesizes the possibility of machines becoming highly intelligent, prompting humans to meditate and generate innovative queries.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37379801">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The dialogue revolves around the use of AI language models like ChatGPT for producing code and associated ethical issues, such as intellectual property and attribution.</li>
<li>Participants express contrasting views on the utility of ChatGPT, from its efficacy in generating quick code snippets and prototyping to concerns about originality, accuracy, and potential misuse.</li>
<li>The author underscores the limitations of ChatGPT for programming tasks and emphasizes having realistic expectations, cautioning against sole reliance on it for extensive projects or critical functions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ikrima.dev/dev-notes/homelab/zfs-for-dummies/">ZFS for Dummies</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article is a comprehensive guide designed to help understand and utilize ZFS, outlining its key components.</li>
<li>The guide offers information on managing ZFS pools and file systems, along with creating snapshots and mounting datasets.</li>
<li>The article includes additional links for deeper understanding and further study on ZFS.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37387392">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article &quot;ZFS for Dummies&quot; gives advice to beginners on how to effectively use and optimize ZFS, a file system, while addressing potential issues and backup solutions.</li>
<li>Commenters back-and-forth on the subject of ZFS&#39;s configuration and functionality, with general consensus that its default settings are apt for most users.</li>
<li>The piece also contains a debate regarding licensing issues of ZFS and its compatibility with other open source licenses, albeit opinions deem legal repercussions as improbable.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/georainbolt/status/1698553197684777069">Geo Guesser identifies the location and seat number from an aerial shot</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A Twitter user, Rainbolt, shared their flight information, including coordinates and destination, on the social media platform.</li>
<li>The user was heading towards Dallas, Texas.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37383245">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Geo Guesser refers to individuals skilled in identifying locations and seat numbers from aerial images.</li>
<li>While concerns exist about AI potentially misusing or outperforming this skill, others view AI as a tool to augment Geo Guessing capabilities.</li>
<li>The discussion also delves into skepticism regarding AI, alternative approaches, AI training methods, chess, and Elon Musk&#39;s ownership of certain websites.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/09/05</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-05T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
