<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:09:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-31]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/31&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-31</h1>
<h2><a href="https://chadaustin.me/2024/01/truecolor-terminal-emacs/">Making Emacs Look Nice: Using 24-bit Color in Terminals</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author aims to improve the visual appeal of Emacs by implementing 24-bit color in terminals.</li>
<li>The article delves into the history of ANSI escape codes and the patch that enabled 256 colors in xterm.</li>
<li>Challenges associated with terminal compatibility and setting the appropriate TERM values are discussed.</li>
<li>The author suggests developing a library that includes a contemporary terminfo database for terminal emulators.</li>
<li>This terminfo database would support advanced features like 24-bit color and URL links and could be retrofitted to older programs.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39189881">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores topics regarding terminal applications like Emacs, such as the complexities of utilizing 24-bit color and the limitations of terminfo.</li>
<li>Users compare terminal-based Emacs with GUI options, discussing the challenges of editing remote files and the pros and cons of different terminal emulators.</li>
<li>The conversation also delves into terminal color standards, the use of SSH wrappers, and the benefits of using tmux for session persistence.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ubicloud.com/use-cases/github-actions">Open-Source x64 and Arm GitHub Runners Provide Cost-Effective and Secure Cloud Alternative</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ubicloud is an open source cloud platform that offers an alternative to traditional cloud providers.</li>
<li>It supports GitHub Actions and claims to reduce its cost by 10x.</li>
<li>Each job runs in a clean and isolated virtual machine, ensuring security and isolation. Additionally, users receive 1,250 free build minutes per month for each account.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39191870">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around cloud platforms, CI/CD, GitHub Actions, and alternative options.</li>
<li>Participants focus on Ubicloud, an open-source cloud platform that provides an alternative to conventional cloud providers and supports Linux runners for GitHub Actions.</li>
<li>Topics highlighted include pricing, performance, caching, and the use of macOS for development, as well as alternative platforms, licensing requirements, and the launch of GitHub Actions for different operating systems.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2024/01/29/well-thats-everyone-senator-wyden-letter-confirms-the-nsa-is-buying-us-persons-data-from-data-brokers/">Politicians Silent on Data Brokers&#39; Role in Privacy Threat: Commenter</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The commenter points out that politicians who criticize social media for threatening privacy often ignore the role of data brokers in facilitating surveillance of the public.</li>
<li>The commenter argues that this silence indicates that politicians are being dishonest and using fear tactics.</li>
<li>The post highlights the hypocrisy and lack of transparency in political discourse surrounding privacy and social media.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39189481">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around the NSA&#39;s acquisition of personal data from data brokers and its impact on Fourth Amendment rights.</li>
<li>There is a debate over whether personal data still belongs to individuals once shared with third parties and the need for more transparency and awareness of data collection practices.</li>
<li>The conversation analyzes the power dynamics between corporations, the government, and individuals regarding data ownership and privacy, and discusses the implications of government surveillance and the potential misuse of personal data.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/quickemu-project/quickemu">Quickemu: Simplifying Virtual Machine Management for Windows, macOS, and Linux</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Quickemu is a virtual machine manager that simplifies creating and running optimized virtual machines for Windows, macOS, and Linux.</li>
<li>It supports features like clipboard sharing, file sharing, USB pass-through, and SSH port forwarding.</li>
<li>Users need to meet requirements and install dependencies to use Quickemu, which provides options and commands for configuring virtual machines, including disk preallocation, network setup, and USB redirection. Helpful resources and guides are available for virtualization with QEMU/KVM and Windows/macOS guests.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39188432">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers around virtualization management tools, such as virt-manager, Quickemu, and Proxmox, comparing their user-friendliness, GUI options, and limitations.</li>
<li>Topics covered include software configuration, security measures, GPG signing, certificate pinning, and establishing trust in downloading files.</li>
<li>The conversation also explores the risks and benefits of tweak utilities, code-explaining tools, and running virtual machines on different operating systems, emphasizing the importance of usability, security, and trust in software.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24054862/apple-vision-pro-review-vr-ar-headset-features-price">Apple Vision Pro: Impressive VR Experience with Limitations</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Apple Vision Pro is a virtual reality headset that aims to bring augmented reality and spatial computing to consumers.</li>
<li>However, it faces competition from existing VR headsets and has drawbacks such as a high price tag, inconsistent tracking, and a heavy design.</li>
<li>The headset is praised for its display technology and video passthrough, but it also has limitations in terms of field of view, motion blur, and color reproduction.</li>
<li>The hand and eye tracking system is advanced but has challenges in terms of precision and ease of use.</li>
<li>Overall, the Vision Pro offers a unique and impressive experience, but it may not be suitable as a primary computing device and can be isolating.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39190506">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article and comments delve into Apple&#39;s Vision Pro virtual reality headset and its potential impact on different markets.</li>
<li>There is mixed feedback on the device, with some praising its features and others highlighting its limitations.</li>
<li>The discussion also touches on Apple&#39;s approach to entering new industries, concerns regarding data security, and the future prospects of smartphones and wearable computing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://stratechery.com/2024/intels-humbling/">Intel&#39;s Struggle: CEO Takes Action to Reshape Future</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Intel is facing challenges and a decline in stock price due to a lack of investment in the future and failure to keep up with market changes.</li>
<li>The company&#39;s CEO, Pat Gelsinger, is focused on improving manufacturing and competing with rivals like AMD.</li>
<li>Intel is making progress in its advanced manufacturing strategy and has partnered with UMC to produce chips, aiming to enhance its foundry services and scale up relationships at a lower cost.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39197619">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Intel is facing challenges due to past research and development failures and a negative impact on its stock price.</li>
<li>There is optimism about Intel&#39;s recovery and progress in catching up with competitors, emphasizing the importance of investment in research and development and diversifying manufacturing capabilities.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about Intel&#39;s reliance on political factors and subsidies for success, as well as its dependence on the Chinese market.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-024-44785-3">Why flying insects gather at artificial lights: Study reveals erratic flight behavior and its implications</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Flying insects do not directly steer towards artificial lights but turn their bodies towards them, resulting in erratic flight paths.</li>
<li>This behavior is believed to be a response to maintaining proper flight attitude and control under natural sky light.</li>
<li>The study provides a plausible explanation for why insects are attracted to artificial lights and aims to understand the impact of increasing light pollution on insect populations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39192807">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Flying insects are often attracted to artificial lights, and various theories are explored to explain this behavior.</li>
<li>Some theories suggest that insects mistake lights for the moon or use them as reference points for navigation.</li>
<li>Insects rely on the moon for orientation, and their behavior near artificial lights can be influenced by this reliance.</li>
<li>The importance of citizen science and personal scientific exploration is discussed in the context of studying insect behavior.</li>
<li>Optimizing outdoor light locations, bug zapper designs, and the impact of light on spider behavior are also touched upon.</li>
<li>There is a debate about the significance of a recent paper on insect navigation and the use of stars by insects for orientation.</li>
<li>The discussion provides valuable insights into the intricate behavior of insects and their interaction with light sources.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/qhamirani/2024/01/26/ceos-are-using-return-to-office-mandates-to-mask-poor-management/">Return-to-Office Mandates Mask Poor Management, University of Pittsburgh Study Finds</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A research paper from the University of Pittsburgh suggests that CEOs use return-to-office mandates to regain control and blame poor performance on employees, rather than for enhancing firm value.</li>
<li>Contrary to popular belief, returning to the office does not boost company value and has no significant impact on profitability or stock returns.</li>
<li>There is a decrease in employee job satisfaction due to return-to-work mandates, raising questions about the interests of the workforce vs. business bottom lines.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39191696">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores various aspects of remote work, management practices, and the pandemic&#39;s effect on work arrangements.</li>
<li>Topics debated include remote management effectiveness, the pros and cons of communication tools, challenges with onboarding new hires remotely, and controversies surrounding Amazon&#39;s work culture.</li>
<li>Other issues addressed include work-life balance, commuting, and the use of timesheets, providing multiple perspectives and opinions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ai-domains">Tiny Anguilla profits from .ai website boom</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The popularity of .ai website registrations is benefiting the Caribbean island of Anguilla financially, due to the increased demand driven by the artificial intelligence boom.</li>
<li>Vince Cate has played a key role in handling the influx of interest in these domains for Anguilla.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39194477">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on country code top-level domains (ccTLDs) like .tv, .ai, .tk, .cx, .io, and .je.</li>
<li>Participants discuss the revenue, risks, and limitations associated with these domains.</li>
<li>Topics include domain squatting, political conflicts, domain ownership, the importance of selecting top-level domains for business websites, control and decentralization of TLDs, DNS hierarchy, and the history and cost of domain registration.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://danrodricks.com/2024/01/29/tear-up-unused-parking-lots-plant-trees/">Transforming Unused Parking Lots: Embracing Green Spaces for a Sustainable Future</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author proposes the conversion of unused parking lots in urban and suburban areas into green spaces or for alternative purposes.</li>
<li>They argue that there is an excessive number of parking spaces in the US, and changes in our lifestyle have reduced the demand for asphalt.</li>
<li>The author emphasizes the detrimental effects of parking lots on human health and the environment.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39194297">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores various aspects of urban planning, transportation, parking, and livability in cities in the US.</li>
<li>Efforts to prioritize people over cars are highlighted, including the removal of parking requirements and dismantling highways to create pedestrian and bike-friendly spaces.</li>
<li>The impact of highways on traffic congestion is debated, with some advocating for their removal and others proposing alternative transportation options to address the issue. The conversation also touches on commuting challenges, housing affordability, noise pollution, and the future of transportation. Ultimately, the importance of sustainable and accessible urban environments that prioritize pedestrians and offer alternatives to car-dependency is emphasized.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.seroundtable.com/google-search-drops-cache-link-from-search-results-36787.html">Google removes cache link from search results, prompts discussions on Mastodon</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google has removed the cache link from its search results page after conducting testing for several months.</li>
<li>Users can still access the cache feature by searching &quot;[cache:domain.com]&quot;.</li>
<li>The removal of the cache link has sparked discussions among users on platforms such as Mastodon, but it does not represent the views of RustyBrick, Inc., the company that owns Search Engine Roundtable.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39198329">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google has removed the cache link from search results, leading to frustration among users who found it helpful.</li>
<li>Speculation suggests that this decision may be driven by a focus on increasing ad revenue or cost-cutting.</li>
<li>Users are concerned about the implications for AI, copyright issues, and the decline of the &quot;cache&quot; qualifier. They discuss alternative search engines like Kagi and express disappointment with the decline in search result quality, mentioning an abundance of ads and deterioration of Google&#39;s indexing capabilities. Some recommend using Archive.org or Bing Cache as alternatives.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.vpnmentor.com/news/report-coronalab-breach/">Covid Test Provider&#39;s Data Breach Exposes 1.3M Patient Records, Including PII</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A cybersecurity researcher discovered a database with 1.3 million patient records, including COVID-19 testing information and personal data, like names and dates of birth.</li>
<li>The exposed database belonged to a commercial test provider in the Netherlands and contained certificates, appointments, testing samples, and internal files.</li>
<li>The data was left unprotected for almost three weeks, posing risks to personal and medical privacy and highlighting the importance of data security and compliance with GDPR regulations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39191260">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation covers topics such as data breaches, security of personal information, COVID-19 testing and vaccinations, quarantine measures, and vendor choices.</li>
<li>Users express concerns about the vulnerability of patient records and the need for better security measures.</li>
<li>Other discussions include frustrations with companies demanding personal identification documents and skepticism about the pandemic response.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/sand-mafias-are-plundering-the-earth/">Crime Rings Trafficking Sand: A Global Threat to the Environment and Security</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Illegal sand mining and trafficking is a global problem that is causing environmental damage and security concerns.</li>
<li>The demand for sand in the construction industry is leading to unsustainable extraction rates and could result in shortages by 2050.</li>
<li>The illegal sand trade is a lucrative business protected by powerful individuals and organizations, causing destruction of habitats, flooding, and disruption of marine life. Stricter regulations and international pressure are necessary to combat this issue.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39190345">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The illegal sand trade is a lucrative industry worth billions of dollars and causes significant environmental harm.</li>
<li>Solutions to this problem include exploring alternative materials like crushed rock or desert sand, but further research is necessary.</li>
<li>Other aspects discussed include the importance of aggregate shape in concrete, the feasibility and consequences of different approaches, sand quality for construction, replenishing beaches, and the cost-effectiveness of manufacturing synthetic sand.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Making Emacs Look Nice: Using 24-bit Color in Terminals" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Making%20Emacs%20Look%20Nice%3A%20Using%2024-bit%20Color%20in%20Terminals&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20January%2031%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/31</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-31T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-30]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/30&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-30</h1>
<h2><a href="https://everything.curl.dev/libcurl/libcurl">Creating a C Program using libcurl with --libcurl Option</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The --libcurl command-line option in curl allows users to create a C program that utilizes libcurl for performing transfers.</li>
<li>The generated program serves as a reference for utilizing libcurl options and adding additional arguments.</li>
<li>While the program code includes various curl_easy_setopt options, some options may require manual implementation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39175873">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the advantages of using the curl command compared to raw HTTP and alternatives to online services.</li>
<li>Participants talk about the &quot;Copy as cURL&quot; feature and tools for converting cURL commands, as well as viewing and modifying code.</li>
<li>The conversation also covers the use of Invoke-WebRequest in PowerShell, limitations of the UNIX/POSIX model, libcurl capabilities, and the preference for deterministic tools over AI.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/AIatMeta/status/1752013879532782075">Meta AI Unveils Code Llama 70B: A More Efficient Code Generator</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The company has launched Code Llama 70B, an improved version of their code generator.</li>
<li>The new models are offered under the same licensing terms as previous versions.</li>
<li>The release aims to enhance the efficiency of the code generation process.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39178886">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers various topics related to AI models, hardware requirements, open source licensing, and Meta&#39;s strategies.</li>
<li>It explores the use of Ollama as an autocomplete provider, the availability of local models, hardware choices for running large models, and the benefits of quantization in improving efficiency.</li>
<li>Discussions also touch on Meta&#39;s decision to open source models, its impact on competition, and the potential motives behind it, as well as the broader implications of AI models, market value of companies, and concerns about data privacy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.boardzilla.io/">Introducing Boardzilla: A Framework for Web-Based Board Games</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Boardzilla is a new framework designed for developing web-based board games, created out of dissatisfaction with existing tools.</li>
<li>The framework simplifies the development process by allowing developers to use the same code for both the client and server, removing concerns about state management, persistence, and networking.</li>
<li>Although still a work in progress, Boardzilla has released developer documentation and sample games on Github, actively adding features and games, and welcomes feedback from users.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39180953">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Boardzilla is a web-based framework that streamlines the creation of board games, and user feedback is being used to make improvements.</li>
<li>User suggestions include prioritizing examples and documentation on the landing page and providing a step-by-step tutorial.</li>
<li>Discussions also cover topics such as incorporating Python on the server side, utilizing Lua in game development, and concerns regarding using React for game development. Additionally, trademark conflicts, bug reports, and alternative game development platforms are being discussed.</li>
<li>Developers are considering implementing security measures against cheating and rage quitting, adding support for AI bots, and exploring self-hosting options.</li>
<li>There is also a conversation about selecting the appropriate software license, particularly the AGPLv3 and Commons Clause licenses.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://abcnews.go.com/GMA/Family/florida-house-representatives-approves-bill-ban-social-media/story?id=106672586">Florida House approves bill banning social media for kids &lt;16</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Florida House of Representatives has passed a bill that would prohibit children under 16 from using most social media platforms, irrespective of parental consent.</li>
<li>Advocates argue that social media is detrimental to children, while opponents claim it violates both First Amendment rights and parental autonomy.</li>
<li>This development arises amidst ongoing discussions among social media companies, parents, lawmakers, and healthcare providers on how to address the effects of social media on children&#39;s mental well-being.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39175883">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation delves into the regulation of social media, age verification systems, privacy concerns, government control, and the impact of internet usage on children.</li>
<li>Alternative solutions like zero-knowledge proofs and reputation systems are discussed, alongside debates on the pros and cons of government intervention.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the difficulties of striking a balance between freedom of speech, protecting minors, and safeguarding privacy in the digital era. It also touches on the detrimental effects of social media on mental health and the possible necessity of better education on responsible online conduct.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/01/29/first-transmitted-alzheimers-disease-cases-growth-hormone-cadavers/">New cases of Alzheimer&#39;s linked to outdated medical procedure</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Scientists have discovered the first cases of transmitted Alzheimer&#39;s disease, linked to a past medical procedure involving cadaver-derived growth hormone.</li>
<li>Patients who received the hormone as children developed signs of Alzheimer&#39;s disease decades later.</li>
<li>The hormone transplant introduced the beta-amyloid protein into the patients&#39; brains, causing disease-causing plaques and suggesting a prion-like transmission mechanism.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39183063">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions delve into various topics such as disease transmission during medical procedures, concerns about blood transfusions, and the use of biological materials from other individuals.</li>
<li>There is an exploration of the connection between prion diseases and neurodegenerative disorders like Alzheimer&#39;s and Parkinson&#39;s.</li>
<li>The discussions also analyze the causes and transmission of Alzheimer&#39;s disease, emphasizing the need for additional research to comprehensively address the risks associated with certain medical practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/oxidecomputer/helios">Building and Installing Oxide Helios: A High-Performing Distribution of Illumos</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The text provides instructions for building and installing the Oxide Helios operating system, as well as modifying and updating its packages.</li>
<li>It mentions the use of diagnostic ROM files.</li>
<li>All components of Oxide Helios are licensed under the Mozilla Public License Version 2.0.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39178521">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion on Hacker News revolves around Oxide, an Illumos distribution and hardware company, and its release of Helios, which is compared to SmartOS.</li>
<li>Users express enthusiasm for Oxide&#39;s customized hardware and infrastructure solutions for on-premise servers, but raise concerns about pricing and the need for a comprehensive on-premises cloud experience.</li>
<li>The conversation expands to topics such as the challenges in attracting developers to Illumos, sustaining maintenance, the advantages of using SmartOS, vendor integration and certification, virtual machines and containers, compatibility with different hardware platforms, and the importance of open-source firmware. Collaboration with Project X developers and the desire for an open-source hardware platform are also mentioned.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/researchers-approach-new-speed-limit-for-seminal-problem-20240129/">New Algorithm for Faster Integer Linear Programming</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have created a groundbreaking algorithm that can solve integer linear programming problems much faster than previous methods.</li>
<li>The algorithm is a significant improvement and brings the runtime close to the theoretical ideal, but it is not yet practical to use in existing programs due to their complexity.</li>
<li>This development is a major advancement in the field and has the potential for future improvements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39185198">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have developed a faster approach for performing integer linear programming, but its real-world application and impact are uncertain due to other factors like heuristics and strategies that also influence solver performance.</li>
<li>The discussion revolves around the challenges and potential advantages of integrating new techniques into existing algorithms, including the usage of lattice-based algorithms, branch-and-bound methods, and linear programming to solve complex problems.</li>
<li>The primary focus is on optimization and linear programming techniques, their limitations, and their potential for practical applications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/01/29/amazon-terminates-irobot-deal-vacuum-maker-to-lay-off-31percent-of-staff.html">Amazon and iRobot&#39;s $1.7 billion acquisition deal canceled due to regulatory issues</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The planned acquisition deal between Amazon and iRobot has been cancelled due to a lack of regulatory approval.</li>
<li>iRobot will lay off around 350 employees, which accounts for 31% of its staff, and its CEO will step down.</li>
<li>The European Commission expressed concerns about the acquisition potentially impacting competition in the robot vacuum cleaner market.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39176297">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion delves into a range of topics including the aborted acquisition of iRobot by Amazon and the implications of saving failing companies.</li>
<li>The conversation also addresses the reputation of Chinese manufacturers, challenges in the tech industry, and the effects of acquisitions.</li>
<li>Additionally, the discussion highlights concerns related to trust in corporations and government agencies, integration issues between tech companies, the consequences of company consolidation, and the potential risks of monopolistic practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/collabora/WhisperFusion">WhisperFusion: Enhanced Low-Latency Conversations with AI</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>WhisperFusion is a platform that enhances the capabilities of WhisperLive and WhisperSpeech.</li>
<li>It enables seamless interaction with an AI chatbot.</li>
<li>WhisperFusion improves the user experience by combining the functionalities of the existing Whisper applications.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39176570">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The WhisperFusion AI chatbot is discussed, highlighting its low latency and interruptibility.</li>
<li>Speculations about the technology behind the chatbot include Google&#39;s speech recognition or Web Speech API.</li>
<li>Smarterchild, a similar chatbot, is praised for its fast latency but limited interruptibility. Suggestions are made to improve AI interaction by implementing features like cues and interruption.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.fosskers.ca/en/blog/rounds-of-lisp">A Tour of Lisp: Embracing Different Dialects and Pioneering Projects in 2023</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author shares their experience exploring different Lisp dialects such as Guile, Common Lisp, Fennel, Clojure, and Emacs Lisp in 2023.</li>
<li>They discuss the strengths and drawbacks of each dialect and praise Clojure for its tooling and community support.</li>
<li>The author expresses their preference for a Lisp language that combines features from Clojure and Common Lisp and encourages newcomers to embrace Lisp, seek help from online communities, and build real projects.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39182721">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The summaries cover discussions on various programming languages within the Lisp family, including Guile, Gauche, Common Lisp, Scheme, Clojure, Elisp, Hy, Fennel, Janet, and Racket.</li>
<li>Users share their experiences, opinions, and concerns about these languages, focusing on documentation, performance, compatibility, and job opportunities.</li>
<li>The advantages and challenges of using Lisp languages are explored, alongside the popularity and limitations of programming languages like Python and Java. Other topics covered include immutability, debugging, syntax, and the application of Lisp in different contexts.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/sonar-image-pilot-amelia-earhart-plane-found-pacific-ocean-2024">Former Air Force Officer Discovers Possible Amelia Earhart Plane</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Former US Air Force officer, Tony Romeo, claims to have found what may be Amelia Earhart&#39;s missing plane using sonar technology on an unmanned submersible.</li>
<li>The aircraft-shaped object was detected on the floor of the Pacific Ocean, about 100 miles from where Earhart&#39;s plane is believed to have crashed.</li>
<li>Further investigations and clearer images are required for concrete confirmation, but if confirmed, this discovery could potentially solve the long-standing mystery of Earhart&#39;s disappearance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39179031">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>There is ongoing discussion about the possible discovery of Amelia Earhart&#39;s missing plane.</li>
<li>There is debate about whether to salvage the plane or leave it as a historical artifact.</li>
<li>The financial benefits of a military career are being discussed.</li>
<li>Various theories and opinions on historical mysteries are being shared.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.freightwaves.com/news/how-walmart-uses-trucking-to-dominate-american-retail">Why Walmart Pays Truck Drivers Six Figures</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Walmart pays its truck drivers significantly higher salaries compared to the national average, with salaries in the six-figure range.</li>
<li>The company relies heavily on its trucking workforce to maintain a robust supply chain and ensure timely delivery of products to its stores.</li>
<li>Walmart has recently implemented changes in its hiring policies, allowing associates to join a training program to become fleet drivers, aiming to retain talent and maintain control over driver training and culture.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39176877">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores wages, compensation disparities, job satisfaction, and challenges across various industries, with a focus on truck drivers and Walmart.</li>
<li>Key points include the perception of low wages at Walmart and the hierarchical pay structure in European tech companies.</li>
<li>The challenges faced by truck drivers, the impact on their health, and concerns about automation and remote piloting in the trucking industry are also discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://xuanwo.io/2024/02-what-i-talk-about-when-i-talk-about-query-optimizer-part-1/">Design Patterns and Considerations of Query Optimizers: Exploring Intermediate Representation (Part 1)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>This article delves into query optimizers and the design patterns and considerations of intermediate representation (IR) in relational databases.</li>
<li>It explains how query optimizers translate SQL statements into execution plans and introduces an example of building a SQL IR using Rust programming language.</li>
<li>The article explores the importance of property derivation for analyzing and optimizing the IR, the use of SQL for calculating properties, and the modifications required for relational algebra. It also discusses the benefits of using global identifiers in the IR and emphasizes the significance of sharing experiences in database development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39176797">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The thread revolves around query optimizers and the design of the intermediate representation (IR).</li>
<li>The Query Graph Model (QGM) is critiqued, and alternative projects like Substrait, lingo-db.com, and Datafusion are suggested.</li>
<li>The discussion touches on the optimizer in MySQL 8.0 and its reliance on relational algebra, and recommendations are shared for online database courses, a YouTube playlist, and a book on databases. The importance of citing references, including the inspiration from Haruki Murakami, is also highlighted, and the author agrees to update the post accordingly.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://stratechery.com/2024/the-apple-vision-pros-missing-apps/">Apple&#39;s Vision Pro AR Headset Faces Missing Apps Challenge</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple has introduced the Vision Pro AR headset, which has the potential to replace traditional home theaters.</li>
<li>The article discusses Apple&#39;s business strategy, tracing the evolution from the iPod to the iTunes Music Store and the App Store.</li>
<li>Apple is facing an antitrust lawsuit with Epic Games, concerning its control over App Store revenue.</li>
<li>Notably, popular streaming services like Netflix and YouTube have chosen not to develop native apps for the Vision Pro, which is seen as a setback.</li>
<li>There is speculation that Apple may partner with Disney to strengthen their streaming services and compete with Netflix.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39176899">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article and discussion cover various topics related to Apple&#39;s VR headset, the potential of VR and AR technology, and the limitations and challenges of VR devices.</li>
<li>The conversation includes discussions on the lack of third-party apps and features on the Apple Vision Pro and the drawbacks of Windows Mobile compared to the iPhone.</li>
<li>There is mention of the potential use of VR in platforms like Netflix, concerns about the high cost and practicality of VR headsets, and the potential impact of VR on shared viewing experiences.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://svelte-native.technology/">Build Native iOS and Android Apps with Svelte Native</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Svelte Native is a mobile application framework powered by Svelte, enabling developers to create native iOS and Android apps without web views.</li>
<li>It offers a comprehensive development experience, leveraging the capabilities of Svelte such as transitions, stores, and reactivity.</li>
<li>Svelte Native optimizes the mobile device&#39;s performance by compiling the app and efficiently updating the native view widgets. It also provides sample projects and repositories for grocery management, real-world applications, and a Hacker News reader.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39175393">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation centers around different mobile app development frameworks, including Svelte Native, React Native, Ionic/Capacitor, and NativeScript.</li>
<li>Participants share their positive experiences and discuss concerns, limitations, and alternative options of these frameworks.</li>
<li>Topics discussed include ease of use, compatibility, native development, third-party services, web-based apps, and performance.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Creating a C Program using libcurl with --libcurl Option" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Creating%20a%20C%20Program%20using%20libcurl%20with%20--libcurl%20Option&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20January%2030%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/30</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-29]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/29&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-29</h1>
<h2><a href="https://nishtahir.com/i-looked-through-attacks-in-my-access-logs-heres-what-i-found/">Unveiling the Dangers of Self-Hosting: Analyzing Security Vulnerabilities and Targeted Attacks</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39165711">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation covers various cybersecurity measures to protect servers and prevent attacks, such as monitoring Certificate Transparency logs and securing SSH ports.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the importance of staying updated on vulnerabilities, following best practices, and implementing multi-layered security.</li>
<li>The effectiveness of IP blocking, the pros and cons of using Cloudflare, and the risks of running vulnerable servers are also discussed. Overall, the discussion highlights the need for proactive and comprehensive security measures.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://visualstudiomagazine.com/articles/2024/01/25/copilot-research.aspx">AI-powered GitHub Copilot linked to decline in code quality, raises concerns over long-term impact</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Research from GitClear reveals concerning trends in software development related to the use of AI-powered GitHub Copilot.</li>
<li>The study found that relying on Copilot is associated with an increase in &quot;mistake code&quot; and a decrease in code refactoring and reuse, raising concerns about code maintainability.</li>
<li>The research also highlights the prevalence of copy/pasted code, which can lead to future maintenance issues.</li>
<li>These findings contradict previous studies that have shown increased productivity and developer satisfaction with Copilot.</li>
<li>The report raises questions about the long-term impact of AI on code quality and who should take responsibility for addressing these issues.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39168105">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The use of AI tools like GitHub Copilot and ChatGPT in programming is generating discussion.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised regarding the impact on code quality, especially for non-trivial and SQL-related tasks.</li>
<li>The debate includes polarized views on AI, resistance to nuanced discussions about its abilities, and reliance on AI for coding.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.vitling.xyz/i-need-to-grow-away-from-these-roots/">&quot;I Need To Grow Away From These Roots&quot;: Custom Music and Light Effects with Raspberry Pi and Arduino</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;I Need To Grow Away From These Roots&quot; is a project by vitling and David Whiting that focuses on creating custom programs for Raspberry Pi and Arduino boards.</li>
<li>The project involves generating and controlling music and light effects using the custom programs.</li>
<li>The program generates chords, selects random notes to play, and illuminates LED strips with corresponding colors. The project also includes a wooden housing with wiring and audio connections.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39168986">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion touches on a range of music and programming topics, such as the vitling.xyz website, using a 303 synthesizer, autoplaying videos, learning music theory, coding music with Sonic Pi, and a project involving chords and inversions.</li>
<li>There is also mention of a video installation, comparisons to Plastikman&#39;s music, server challenges, and the cost of building and programming an LED strip with Arduino.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.rwkv.com/p/eagle-7b-soaring-past-transformers">Eagle 7B: Open-source AI Model Outperforms Transformers in Multi-lingual Benchmarks</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The RWKV open-source architecture has unveiled a new model named Eagle 7B, boasting an impressive 7.52B parameters and built on the RWKV-v5 architecture.</li>
<li>Trained on a vast amount of data, consisting of 1.1 trillion tokens in over 100 languages, Eagle 7B surpasses all other 7B class models in multi-lingual benchmarks.</li>
<li>Under the Apache 2.0 license, this model can be freely utilized for personal or commercial purposes without any limitations. The RWKV team aims to democratize AI, ensuring accessibility for people worldwide, and plans to extend language support in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39172837">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the progress and limitations of alternative LLM architectures, with a focus on the importance of context size and the suggestion to explore a larger size of ~1M tokens.</li>
<li>The capabilities and limitations of the RWKV model, a linear attention architecture, are discussed, highlighting its perfect token recall but restricted ability to remember past tokens.</li>
<li>The importance of language data in AI development and its role in human intelligence is emphasized, along with discussions on the RWKV-v5 Eagle 7B model, potential MoE models, tokenization speed, and concerns about potential censorship of models.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://www.bartkira.com">Bartkira: The Epic Fusion of The Simpsons and Akira</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bartkira.com is a website featuring the art project &quot;BARTKIRA,&quot; a fusion of The Simpsons and Akira.</li>
<li>The project includes six volumes of artwork created by over 500 international artists.</li>
<li>Users can read each volume on the website and find additional information in the FAQ section, as well as links to their Tumblr and Twitter accounts.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39165080">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Bartkira: The Simpsons and Akira&quot; is a fan project that combines elements from both &quot;The Simpsons&quot; and &quot;Akira&quot; into a reimagined story.</li>
<li>Various artists contribute to the project, depicting scenes and characters in their own art styles.</li>
<li>The project has handled copyright challenges by donating profits to charity and has not faced any cease and desist orders so far, showcasing the creativity and passion of fan artists despite the potential risks involved.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://cpldcpu.wordpress.com/2024/01/14/revisiting-candle-flicker-leds-now-with-integrated-timer/">Candle-flicker LEDs with built-in MCUs mimic real flames, helping to conserve power</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author explores a candle-flicker LED with an integrated timer, finding a microcontroller inside that resembles a PIC derivative.</li>
<li>The LED operates in PWM mode at a frequency of 125Hz, driven by the microcontroller at 1MHz.</li>
<li>The author suggests that using a microcontroller with sleep mode could reduce the LED&#39;s current consumption and increase battery life, highlighting the growing use of inexpensive microcontrollers in low-cost electronics like candle-flame LEDs.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39169048">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers a wide range of topics including creating realistic candle flickering effects with LEDs, the development and limitations of microcomputers, and the tools and equipment necessary for working with microcontrollers.</li>
<li>Other topics include the need for standardized modular gadgets, the environmental impact of lithium batteries, and the use and disposal of vapes and EV batteries.</li>
<li>Software and programming topics, such as the difference between microprocessors and microcontrollers, are also discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.agenciasinc.es/en/News/Antarctic-fungi-survive-Martian-conditions-on-the-International-Space-Station">Antarctic fungi thrive in Martian conditions, promising for future missions.</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fungi from Antarctica&#39;s McMurdo Dry Valleys have demonstrated the ability to survive in conditions resembling those on Mars.</li>
<li>The fungi maintained stable DNA and preserved over 60% of their cells after being sent to the International Space Station for 18 months.</li>
<li>This research offers essential insights for future Mars missions focused on finding signs of life, and lichens from Spain and Austria also exhibited heightened metabolic activity under Martian conditions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39168900">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Fungi from Antarctica have been found to survive in conditions that mimic those on Mars, raising questions about the potential for life on other planets.</li>
<li>This research leads to discussions about seeding other planets with Earth life forms, known as panspermia, and the adaptability of life in space.</li>
<li>The study has implications for planetary protection and our understanding of the possibility of life on other planets.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/sudo-project/sudo/commit/7873f8334c8d31031f8cfa83bd97ac6029309e4f">Sudo project strengthens security against Rowhammer attacks with code modifications</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The sudo project has implemented updates to improve security against ROWHAMMER attacks.</li>
<li>These changes involve modifying variables and adding tests for expected values.</li>
<li>The updates were prompted by a report from researchers at Worcester Polytechnic Institute and primarily impact files related to authentication, session management, and conditional statements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39165342">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers a range of topics related to computer vulnerabilities and programming optimizations.</li>
<li>Some of the topics discussed include the vulnerability of the sudo program to Rowhammer attacks and the optimizations of binary codes.</li>
<li>Other topics include the use of Minecraft and Source Engine game server hosts, mitigations of Rowhammer attacks in DRAM chips, the importance of ECC memory, alternatives to sudo like doas, the use and security implications of enum values in programming languages, and the occurrence of bit flips in data decompression.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://djanes.xyz/spam-on-github-is-getting-crazy-these-days/">GitHub Faces Surge in Spam; Users Call for Improved Reporting and Content Moderation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>GitHub is facing a surge in spam activity, as scammers post fraudulent content, tag multiple users, and quickly delete the posts.</li>
<li>The spam comments often involve cryptocurrency-related scams and have become more widespread in recent months.</li>
<li>Users are struggling to report the spam messages since they are already removed, making it challenging to address the issue effectively.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39170622">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users discuss fraudulent practices, spam, and content moderation issues on popular online platforms like eBay, Amazon, GitHub, and Twitter.</li>
<li>Negative experiences with unethical sellers, counterfeit goods, and return/refund difficulties are shared.</li>
<li>Suggestions for stricter regulations, improved buyer protection, reputation systems, filtering methods, and language analysis models are proposed. Concerns are raised about Twitter&#39;s failure to address spam effectively due to inadequate staff.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.gtk.org/2024/01/28/new-renderers-for-gtk/">GTK Introduces New Renderers &quot;ngl&quot; and &quot;vulkan&quot; for Improved Features and Correctness</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>GTK has introduced two new renderers, &quot;ngl&quot; and &quot;vulkan,&quot; with the same source code for GL and Vulkan support, making maintenance and updates easier.</li>
<li>The new renderers come with advanced features like antialiasing, fractional scaling, gradients, and dmabufs support.</li>
<li>Although the new renderers are not currently faster than the old GL renderer, they offer improved features and correctness, laying the foundation for future plans such as better color handling, GPU path rendering, and off-the-main-thread rendering. Users are encouraged to try them out and provide feedback.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39172377">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the development of new renderers for GTK, with a focus on the Broadway HTML renderer.</li>
<li>The Broadway renderer enables GTK apps to be shown in a browser using HTML and CSS, garnering praise for its craftsmanship.</li>
<li>Commenters discuss the limitations of the Broadway backend and make comparisons to other technologies like QML and Electron. The article also mentions potential improvements to GTK, such as an ANSI text renderer and pixel-perfect fractional scaling.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Unveiling the Dangers of Self-Hosting: Analyzing Security Vulnerabilities and Targeted Attacks" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Unveiling%20the%20Dangers%20of%20Self-Hosting%3A%20Analyzing%20Security%20Vulnerabilities%20and%20Targeted%20Attacks&subheading=Monday%2C%20January%2029%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/29</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-29T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-28]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/28&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-28</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/disney-unveils-the-holotile-floor-inching-us-closer-to-a-real-life-holodeck">Disney Unleashes HoloTile Floor for Seamless Shared VR Experience</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Disney has developed a technology called the HoloTile floor, which is a multi-person, omni-directional treadmill floor for enhancing the VR experience.</li>
<li>The HoloTile floor allows multiple people to have a shared VR experience and walk in any direction without colliding.</li>
<li>This technology has potential applications beyond VR, including theatrical stages, and offers a glimpse into the future of immersive entertainment.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39156444">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Disney has introduced the HoloTile floor, a novel technology that employs ultrasonic tiles to regulate friction and movement.</li>
<li>The HoloTile floor enables controlled direction of movement, although there are reservations about its safety and durability.</li>
<li>Speculation arises among viewers that the tiles may spin rather than rotate, raising questions about the reliability of the technology.</li>
<li>While the HoloTile floor presents an innovative approach to friction control, there are ongoing discussions regarding its practicality, effectiveness, and potential limitations in virtual reality applications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/rasbt/LLMs-from-scratch">Creating Your Own ChatGPT-like Language Model: A Step-by-Step Guide</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Build a Large Language Model (From Scratch)&quot; is a book that provides a step-by-step guide for creating your own language model.</li>
<li>The book includes clear explanations, diagrams, and examples to help readers understand each stage of the process.</li>
<li>It follows a similar approach to building models like ChatGPT.</li>
<li>The accompanying code and supplementary materials can be accessed on the GitHub repository.</li>
<li>Topics covered in the book include understanding large language models, working with text data, coding attention mechanisms, implementing a GPT model, pretraining on unlabeled data, finetuning for text classification, finetuning with human feedback, using large language models in practice, and an introduction to PyTorch.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39156778">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author is writing a comprehensive guide and book on building a ChatGPT-like Language Model (LLM) from scratch, aiming to educate and demystify LLMs while providing practical assistance to implement customized models.</li>
<li>While training an LLM from scratch may not be financially feasible for most, the author recommends using frameworks like HF transformers or axolotl. However, a well-funded company has demonstrated that training from scratch is possible.</li>
<li>The book covers pretraining, finetuning, and loading pretrained weights, and readers are interested in reinforcement learning advice. The discussion also includes recommendations for RL, neural networks, and transformers resources.</li>
<li>The author defends the cost of the book, mentions available coupons, and welcomes feedback through the Manning Forum or GitHub.</li>
<li>The book is expected to be 400-500 pages long, and there is a video tutorial for a shorter introduction. The suitability of the video tutorial for beginners is debated, but the creator assures that more chapters are in progress.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://law.stackexchange.com/questions/98706/is-it-insider-trading-if-i-bought-boeing-puts-while-i-am-inside-the-wrecked-airp">Wrecked Airplane Doesn&#39;t Create Insider Trading: Law Stack Exchange Users Discuss Boeing Puts</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Users on the Law Stack Exchange platform discuss whether buying Boeing put options during a plane crash would be considered insider trading.</li>
<li>The conversation examines the definition of insider trading and the potential involvement of the SEC.</li>
<li>Ultimately, it is concluded that being inside a crashed airplane does not qualify as insider information, and therefore insider trading laws would not apply. Seeking legal advice and the educational aspect of the platform are highlighted.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39157797">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the definition and legality of insider trading, specifically regarding trading stocks using non-public information.</li>
<li>Participants debate whether certain actions, like observing product issues or experiencing software failures, should be considered insider trading.</li>
<li>The conversation also covers confidentiality obligations, fiduciary relationships, and different regulations across countries, highlighting the complexity and subjective nature of defining insider trading.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tonsky.me/blog/checkbox/">The End of Square Checkboxes: Evolution and Future of User Controls</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Checkboxes in different operating systems have traditionally been square, while radio buttons have been round.</li>
<li>With the web and CSS, there has been a trend of reinventing and redesigning these controls, leading to the use of round checkboxes and checkboxes with checkmarks.</li>
<li>Apple has recently introduced round checkboxes in their new visionOS, deviating from the traditional square convention. The author speculates that square checkboxes may be replaced by toggles in 2024.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39161339">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores multiple aspects of user interface design, such as the use of round checkboxes and the confusion caused by unclear toggle buttons.</li>
<li>It highlights the influence of Apple&#39;s design choices and the challenges faced by older individuals in navigating modern UI designs.</li>
<li>The debate between radio buttons and checkboxes is discussed, along with the potential for innovation in UI design while still adhering to established conventions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://sxmo.org/">Sxmo: The Minimalist Linux Environment for Mobile Devices with Touch and SSH Support</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Sxmo is a minimalist environment for Linux mobile devices with a user-friendly menu-driven interface and support for touch and gesture controls.</li>
<li>Users can SSH into their phone and use it like any other Alpine Linux machine, making it convenient for remote use.</li>
<li>The platform is highly customizable and scriptable, allowing users to launch scripts for various actions and bind them to gestures or physical buttons. It runs on traditional Linux distributions and supports FOSS apps.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39155103">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The SXMO operating system is being discussed, focusing on its design, functionality, and compatibility with the PinePhone.</li>
<li>Users have shared their experiences and opinions, expressing both positive and negative views on SXMO.</li>
<li>Discussions cover topics such as design flaws, bugs, features, customization options, alternative ROMs, banking app workarounds, the usefulness of a tiling window manager on a phone, upcoming events, Python and Qt development, and the absence of a pin/password option for unlocking the device.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.scmagazine.com/news/gitlab-password-reset-bug-leaves-more-than-5-3k-servers-up-for-grabs">Vulnerable GitLab Instances Expose 5.3K Servers to Account Takeover</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Over 5,300 servers have not applied a crucial patch in GitLab, leaving developers&#39; accounts vulnerable to remote takeover.</li>
<li>A bug in GitLab allows attackers to reset passwords and receive the reset link on their own email without user interaction.</li>
<li>Security updates have been released, but a significant number of GitLab instances are still susceptible to this vulnerability. Users are advised to check for signs of exploitation in their logs and enable two-factor authentication.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39159002">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A password reset bug in GitLab has left over 5.3K servers vulnerable, raising concerns about account security and unauthorized access</li>
<li>The choice of programming languages and best practices are being discussed to minimize bugs and vulnerabilities in future projects</li>
<li>Criticisms are raised regarding the security team and handling of account security features, as well as discussions about engineering culture and the use of strong parameters in Ruby on Rails</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/01/in-major-gaffe-hacked-microsoft-test-account-was-assigned-admin-privileges/">Hackers breach Microsoft network using test account with admin privileges</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Hackers infiltrated Microsoft&#39;s network and accessed the email accounts of top executives by exploiting an old test account with admin privileges.</li>
<li>The attackers utilized a technique called password spraying to take advantage of a weak credential for logging into the test account.</li>
<li>They further manipulated the OAuth authorization protocol to create a malicious app and grant it access to all email addresses on Microsoft&#39;s Office 365 email service, exposing a significant configuration mistake.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39157888">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The articles and discussions highlight the security risks and concerns associated with access privileges and permissions in Microsoft&#39;s test and production environments.</li>
<li>Better isolation, access control measures, security audits, and employee training are recommended to prevent unauthorized access and potential security breaches.</li>
<li>Emphasis is placed on the importance of implementing robust security measures to protect sensitive data.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://kottke.org/21/03/the-invention-of-a-new-pasta-shape">The Sporkful&#39;s Dan Pashman Invents Cascatelli Pasta for Optimal Sauce Adherence and Forkability</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Dan Pashman, host of The Sporkful podcast, has developed a new pasta shape called cascatelli, designed to enhance sauce adhesion and eating experience.</li>
<li>The shape is now available for purchase from Sfoglini.</li>
<li>The pasta has gained popularity and is currently sold out, only leaving 5-lb bulk bags in stock.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39159263">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new pasta shape has been invented in 2021, but it has received mixed reviews.</li>
<li>Critics say the pasta takes too long to cook, has undercooked sections, and breaks off at the joints.</li>
<li>There are suspicions that positive reviews on the inventor&#39;s website may be cherry-picked or forged.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.hottakes.space/p/remote-work-won-dont-let-anyone-gaslight">Remote Work Prevails: Don&#39;t Be Gaslighted</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Remote work has become the new norm and will continue to be prevalent, despite some individuals resisting the change.</li>
<li>Data shows that a significant number of employees in the US currently work remotely and prefer to continue doing so.</li>
<li>Companies and managers who enforce return-to-office mandates are criticized for impeding employee satisfaction and productivity.</li>
<li>Arguments made by commercial real estate owners against remote work are dismissed, as the author believes the pandemic has accelerated the inevitable future of remote work.</li>
<li>The author warns of potential layoffs disguised as return-to-office initiatives and advises caution for investors, employees, and customers.</li>
<li>Remote work is asserted as the victorious model, and readers are encouraged to be aware of gaslighting attempts to convince them otherwise.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39156987">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation highlights the advantages of remote work, such as time-saving and flexibility, but also acknowledges its challenges, including isolation and limited growth opportunities.</li>
<li>The impact of remote work on social interactions, relationships with colleagues, and company culture is discussed, raising questions about the long-term effects on the class of 2020-2022 and the future of commercial real estate.</li>
<li>The conversation explores both the benefits and drawbacks of remote work for businesses and touches on concerns about bias in media discussions and the impact of remote work on productivity and employee performance. Opinions on the effectiveness and future of remote work vary.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/researchers-demonstrate-rapid-3d-printing-liquid-metal-0125">MIT researchers develop rapid liquid metal printing for large-scale aluminum parts</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>MIT researchers have developed liquid metal printing (LMP), a technique that enables rapid production of large-scale aluminum parts, including furniture.</li>
<li>LMP involves depositing molten aluminum onto a bed of small glass beads, resulting in quick hardening into a 3D structure. It is at least 10 times faster than other metal additive manufacturing processes.</li>
<li>LMP prioritizes speed and scale over resolution. The technique has potential applications in architecture, construction, industrial design, rapid prototyping with recycled metal, and can be combined with other high-resolution processes and materials to create functional furniture.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39156463">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>MIT researchers have shown that liquid metal can be 3D printed at a fast pace, providing potential applications in prototyping and non-structural designs.</li>
<li>While parts made using this method may still need milling and machining, the ability to print with liquid metal opens up possibilities for faster and more efficient fabrication facilities.</li>
<li>The process involves printing molten metal inside glass beads to achieve the desired shape, showcasing advancements in 3D printing technology.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/jan/27/sean-kirkpatrick-pentagon-ufo-conspiracy-theory-myths">Pentagon Ex-UFO Chief: Government Conspiracy Theorists Drive Wasteful Spending</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Former Pentagon chief investigator Sean Kirkpatrick accuses conspiracy theorists within the US government of spreading myths about UFOs and wasting resources on investigations.</li>
<li>Kirkpatrick claims that a group of government workers are promoting unsubstantiated stories and influencing lawmakers to support secret UFO research programs.</li>
<li>He expresses concern about lawmakers making decisions based on conspiracy-driven thinking and sensationalism, stating that many UFO sightings have logical explanations but some people refuse to accept scientific explanations due to their belief in aliens.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39156388">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The summary covers a range of topics including UFOs, alien encounters, conspiracy theories, and government involvement.</li>
<li>It mentions the influence of conspiracy theorists within the government on spending related to UFO investigations.</li>
<li>Discussions explore the human-scale nature of UFO mythology, the potential inspiration for sightings from experimental aircraft, and the possibility of advanced hominids on Earth pretending to be extraterrestrial beings.</li>
<li>The feasibility of sending robotic probes to explore space is also discussed.</li>
<li>Skepticism and debate surround the existence of aliens, the credibility of witnesses, and the lack of concrete evidence.</li>
<li>Government secrecy, transparency, and the role of organizations like AATIP in shaping the narrative about UFOs and extraterrestrial existence are also examined.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.e-basteln.de/computing/65f02/65f02/">Re-Implementation of 65C02 CPU in FPGA: 100MHz 65F02 Project on Hold</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The 65F02 is a re-implementation of the 65C02 CPU developed by the author and implemented in an FPGA.</li>
<li>The FPGA board can be plugged into the CPU socket of 6502 and 65C02-based computers, providing a clock rate of 100 MHz and storing up to 16 different memory maps.</li>
<li>The 65F02 has been successfully tested in Mephisto chess computers, Apple II, and Commodore PET/CBM computers, but the project is currently on hold due to global electronics supply bottlenecks.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39160291">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the challenges and opportunities of adding cache to a system, exploring different types of memory banks.</li>
<li>It explores the potential of creating a computer system that mimics an 80-column display by utilizing higher memory configurations.</li>
<li>The benefits of using 8-bit microprocessors for real-time tasks and the potential for optimizing computer operations are discussed, along with techniques to reduce power consumption. The article also touches on nostalgia for older computers and the excitement of faster processors. Additionally, performance improvement techniques for specific systems, like Applesoft and the Quad Core demo, are mentioned.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Disney Unleashes HoloTile Floor for Seamless Shared VR Experience" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Disney%20Unleashes%20HoloTile%20Floor%20for%20Seamless%20Shared%20VR%20Experience&subheading=Sunday%2C%20January%2028%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/28</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-28T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-27]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/27&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-27</h1>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/oasislinux/oasis">Oasis: A Statically-Linked Linux System Emphasizing Simplicity and Customization</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Oasis is a Linux-based operating system that resembles BSD and emphasizes simplicity and customization.</li>
<li>It uses completely statically linked software, fast and reproducible builds, and minimal bootstrap dependencies.</li>
<li>Oasis does not have a package manager but is compatible with pkgsrc and nix, and it uses BearSSL as its TLS and crypto library.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39142748">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers topics related to Linux systems, including the use of Oasis for creating immutable OS images and the benefits of static and dynamic linking in software development.</li>
<li>Users explore dependency management, distributed compilation, and the challenges of GPU support.</li>
<li>Different libraries, compilers, and alternative solutions like Docker and Nix are discussed, with varying opinions and suggestions on optimizing libraries and binaries, managing dependencies, and improving system stability.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-gaza-genocide-court-south-africa-27cf84e16082cde798395a95e9143c06">ICJ Orders Israel to Prevent Genocide in Gaza, Fails to Order Ceasefire</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The United Nations&#39; top court has ruled that Israel has a legal obligation to prevent death, destruction, and genocide in Gaza, but did not explicitly order an end to the ongoing military offensive.</li>
<li>The court&#39;s ruling is seen as a criticism of Israel&#39;s conduct during the conflict and has intensified international pressure to stop the offensive.</li>
<li>Israel&#39;s Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has rejected the ruling and pledged to continue the war, raising uncertainty about whether Israel will comply with the legally binding decision.</li>
<li>The court also called on Hamas to release hostages and urged the international community to ensure Israel&#39;s compliance with the ruling.</li>
<li>This ruling coincides with International Holocaust Remembrance Day.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39143043">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The summary covers various discussions related to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, including civilian casualties, the actions of the Israeli military, and the role of the ICJ.</li>
<li>Different perspectives are presented, including debates on casualty figures and the influence of external factors.</li>
<li>The summary also explores the challenges in finding a resolution, the role of Hamas, and the potential for future attacks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://skii.dev/rook-to-xss/">Exploiting a Security Vulnerability: Hacking Chess.com with XSS</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author recounts their experience of discovering and exploiting a security vulnerability on Chess.com.</li>
<li>The vulnerability allowed the author to automatically add themselves as a friend by accessing a specific URL.</li>
<li>The author used the image upload function of a rich text editor to inject raw HTML code into their profile description and execute malicious JavaScript.</li>
<li>They discuss the potential impact of a cross-site scripting attack and the challenges they faced with an OSRF exploit.</li>
<li>The author provides suggestions on how to prevent similar vulnerabilities in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39144906">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A 17-year-old UK student successfully hacked into chess.com, sparking discussions on career opportunities and degree apprenticeships at Facebook.</li>
<li>The incident raises concerns about HTML parsing challenges and potential XSS attacks on websites.</li>
<li>The conversation also highlights the rivalry between chess.com and lichess.org and mixed opinions on the user experience across different platforms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://rclone.org/">Rclone: A Versatile Tool for Managing Files on Cloud Storage</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Rclone is a command-line program for managing files on cloud storage with support for over 70 providers.</li>
<li>It offers features like encryption, compression, and hashing, making it suitable for backup, data restoration, migration, and file syncing.</li>
<li>Rclone preserves timestamps, verifies checksums, and can be used as a disk to access cloud storage, serving files over different protocols. It is open-source and has a helpful community.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39151937">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users discuss the benefits and limitations of using Rclone, a cloud storage syncing tool, for file backup.</li>
<li>Alternative syncing tools and encryption options for cloud storage are mentioned.</li>
<li>The conversation also covers the limitations of the Google API, using Rclone with other backup tools, and the cost and trade-offs of different backup options like Amazon S3 Glacier and Backblaze.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://rmi.org/the-rise-of-batteries-in-six-charts-and-not-too-many-numbers/">The Explosive Growth of Batteries: Unlocking a Sustainable Future</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The demand for batteries is rapidly increasing, leading to a potential reduction in global fossil fuel demand by half.</li>
<li>Battery sales have been doubling every two to three years, driven by the growth of electric cars.</li>
<li>Improved battery quality and decreasing costs are enabling new applications across various sectors, including transportation and energy storage. Analysts have consistently underestimated the growth of batteries.</li>
<li>Falling costs and increasing policy support are expected to further drive the adoption of batteries.</li>
<li>Rapid deployment of batteries can facilitate the phaseout of fossil fuels in road transport, shipping, aviation, and the electricity sector, leading to significant carbon emission reductions.</li>
<li>More efforts are needed to accelerate the transition to batteries for a faster and more sustainable future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39144978">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers various topics related to energy generation, storage, and consumption, focusing on electric vehicles (EVs) and renewable energy sources.</li>
<li>The conversation explores using batteries to address the timing disparity between peak demand and solar power generation and discusses the decline in rooftop solar applications in California.</li>
<li>There is a debate on residential generation and storage of electricity, the need for improved EV charging infrastructure, and the challenges of implementing EVs in rural areas. The conversation also discusses the efficiency of EVs compared to petrol vehicles and the potential for hydrogen storage and electric-powered flights.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://untranslatable.co/">Untranslatable: Embracing the World&#39;s Linguistic Diversity</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Untranslatable is a multilingual online dictionary that allows users to contribute words and expressions from different languages and cultures.</li>
<li>The project aims to provide more than just translations, offering insights into context and cultural significance.</li>
<li>It welcomes entries in any language or dialect and is supported by moderators and user voting to maintain quality and accuracy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39144710">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://blog.awais.io/o1-visa/">Software Engineer&#39;s Journey to O-1 Visa: Quick Approval and Expert Tips</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author, a software engineer turned CTO/co-founder, shares their experience obtaining an O-1 visa as a startup founder.</li>
<li>They obtained their visa in just one week with premium processing and met four out of eight extraordinary ability criteria.</li>
<li>The author advises consulting with an immigration lawyer before applying and provides recommendations for lawyers and resources for O-1 applicants.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39143958">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the US immigration system and the difficulties faced by individuals applying for visas and green cards.</li>
<li>There is debate surrounding visa requirements, the flaws in the immigration system, and the treatment of undocumented immigrants.</li>
<li>The conversation also discusses the O-1 visa for individuals with extraordinary ability, work limitations, and the significance of highlighting achievements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.danieljanus.pl/2024/01/26/lossy-css-compression/">Introducing cssfact: A Lossy CSS Compressor for Reducing Redundancy in Code</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The blog post introduces a CSS compressor called cssfact that reduces CSS code by using binary matrix factorization.</li>
<li>The technique of reducing CSS matrices helps in identifying redundancy in CSS codebases.</li>
<li>cssfact aims to output a compressed version of CSS code with fewer rules.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39143768">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The blog post introduces the concept of lossy compression for CSS and its potential advantages in reducing file size.</li>
<li>The author proposes considering the frequency of rule usage to enhance the compression process.</li>
<li>Commenters share additional tools and ideas related to CSS compression, and there are differing opinions on the practicality and usefulness of the concept. The post includes live examples and code for further experimentation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.platoedu.org">Tool Generates Quiz Questions and Flashcards from Educational YouTube Videos</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The individual has developed a tool that generates quiz questions or flashcards from educational YouTube videos.</li>
<li>The tool incorporates spaced repetition technique to enhance memory retention.</li>
<li>The individual is seeking feedback on the tool and willing to provide additional information upon request.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39148336">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author has developed an app that generates quiz questions from educational YouTube videos and uses spaced repetition.</li>
<li>Users find the app helpful and suggest adding features like community discussion and personal note-taking.</li>
<li>There is a debate regarding the value of educational entertainment videos and a desire for more control over YouTube recommendations to prioritize actual education.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.tinysa.org/wiki/">tinySA Wiki Updated with Info on tinySA Ultra: Small Spectrum Analyzer and Signal Generator</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The tinySA Wiki has been updated to include information about the tinySA Ultra, which is a small spectrum analyzer and signal generator.</li>
<li>The tinySA Ultra and tinySA4 are the same device, with the Ultra featuring a larger 4-inch screen and operating within broader frequency ranges.</li>
<li>The tinySA Basic has a 2.8-inch screen and operates within specific frequency ranges, while the Ultra has additional features like a built-in LNA and microSD card slot.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39142560">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Ukrainian army is using the TinySA, a compact spectrum analyzer and signal generator, to detect Russian drones effectively.</li>
<li>The conversation delves into spread spectrum technology and alternative approaches for detecting and intercepting drones.</li>
<li>Various spectrum monitoring and analysis tools, such as the NanoVNA and TinySA, are discussed, along with suggestions for buying affordable oscilloscopes and measuring low frequencies and identifying radio frequency interference sources.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://yaky.dev/2024-01-25-pinephone-post-daily-driver-review/">PinePhone: A Mixed Bag of Performance and Phone Issues, According to Review</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The PinePhone is a mobile Linux device with good performance but has issues with phone capabilities.</li>
<li>It has standard features and a decent display, but is difficult to see in bright light and has average battery life.</li>
<li>The Phosh and SXMO desktop environments are discussed, each with their own strengths and weaknesses.</li>
<li>There are limitations with editing YAML files and using wvkbd for terminal use.</li>
<li>Users have reported issues with the modem, especially with VoLTE, resulting in crashes and difficulties with calls.</li>
<li>Different firmware and operating system versions have been tried, but problems persist.</li>
<li>The camera works but has slow post-processing and limited video shooting capabilities.</li>
<li>Offline navigation apps are also limited.</li>
<li>There are challenges with Spotify playback on mobile Linux clients and the recommended usage of Firefox ESR as the default browser.</li>
<li>Overall, the PinePhone is practical for daily tasks but has limitations as a phone.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39145701">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users discuss their experiences with mobile devices running on Linux, including the PinePhone, Librem 5, and Ubuntu Touch, focusing on areas like software performance, hardware limitations, and user interfaces.</li>
<li>The challenges of creating affordable and fully open-source devices are highlighted, as well as concerns about their reliability and mainstream adoption.</li>
<li>Discussions also cover topics such as file sharing, photo syncing, root access on Android devices, and the cost and availability of SMS services.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.techradar.com/pro/google-is-rapidly-turning-into-a-formidable-opponent-to-bff-nvidia-the-tpu-v5p-ai-chip-powering-its-hypercomputer-is-faster-and-has-more-memory-and-bandwidth-than-ever-before-beating-even-the-mighty-h100">Google TPU v5p Outperforms Nvidia H100 for AI Workloads</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google has released the TPU v5p, an upgraded version of its tensor processing unit AI chip, with enhanced speed, memory, and bandwidth compared to its predecessor.</li>
<li>The TPU v5p is being utilized in Google&#39;s AI Hypercomputer and boasts up to 2.8 times faster training for large language models.</li>
<li>Google&#39;s custom TPUs are employed internally, and the new TPU v5p is considered a strong competitor to Nvidia&#39;s H100 GPU for AI tasks, although further benchmarking is necessary to establish a precise performance comparison.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39148544">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers Google&#39;s TPU hardware and Nvidia&#39;s GPUs, highlighting their significance in AI.</li>
<li>The competition between frameworks like PyTorch and CUDA is explored, emphasizing the importance of hardware.</li>
<li>The potential of TPUs in machine learning and the challenges and limitations of using specialized hardware for AI tasks are discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/google/google-pixel-phones-unusable-after-january-2024-system-update/">Pixel Owners Experience Issues After January 2024 Google Play Update</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google Pixel smartphone owners have been encountering various issues after a system update in January 2024, including problems with accessing internal storage, using the camera, taking screenshots, and opening apps.</li>
<li>Some users have attempted to resolve the issues by factory resetting their devices, but this has led to data loss.</li>
<li>Google is aware of the problem and is currently investigating, raising concerns about the company&#39;s quality assurance and testing protocols. The information provided in the article includes rules from online forums, details from websites, and JavaScript code related to a website called BleepingComputer.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39144740">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Pixel phone users have encountered problems after installing the January 2024 Google Play update, specifically storage issues.</li>
<li>Speculation suggests that hardware, rather than the update, may be the cause of these problems.</li>
<li>Dissatisfaction with Google and Apple is expressed, with some users considering switching brands. There are also reports of pairing issues between Garmin watches and Pixel phones, leading to suspicions of intentional problems caused by Google.</li>
<li>The discussion also touches on the balance between convenience and security in technology and concerns about software quality assurance.</li>
<li>The overall theme of the conversation is frustration with tech companies and their software updates.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-teams-outage-causes-connection-issues-message-delays/">Microsoft Teams outage causing connection issues, login problems, and message delays</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft is investigating a widespread outage impacting users of its Teams communication platform, causing connectivity issues, login difficulties, and message delays.</li>
<li>The company is actively working to fix the problem and has observed signs of improvement after implementing a failover in the EMEA region.</li>
<li>The post also includes code snippets demonstrating JavaScript functions and event handlers for controlling webpage behavior, such as printing, scrolling, dropdown menus, and popups.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39146385">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users are frustrated with Microsoft Teams due to connection problems, message delays, and glitches.</li>
<li>Complaints include slow loading times, crashes, and lack of features compared to alternatives like Slack.</li>
<li>Some users have become accustomed to the poor performance of Teams despite ongoing issues and outages.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Oasis: A Statically-Linked Linux System Emphasizing Simplicity and Customization" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Oasis%3A%20A%20Statically-Linked%20Linux%20System%20Emphasizing%20Simplicity%20and%20Customization&subheading=Saturday%2C%20January%2027%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/27</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-27T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-26]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/26&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-26</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/01/apple-announces-changes-to-ios-safari-and-the-app-store-in-the-european-union/">Apple Introduces Changes to iOS, Safari, and App Store in EU to Comply with Digital Markets Act</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple has revealed updates to its iOS, Safari, and App Store to align with the Digital Markets Act in the EU.</li>
<li>The updates involve enhanced app distribution and payment processing options for developers and improved controls and disclosures for users.</li>
<li>The changes will roll out to EU users from March 2024, and developers can explore and test the new features in the iOS 17.4 beta. Apple will offer resources to assist EU users in understanding and adapting to the modifications.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39132453">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around Apple potentially violating anti-circumvention provisions in the EU&#39;s Digital Markets Act with changes to its iOS, Safari, and App Store.</li>
<li>There is debate about whether Apple is using fear tactics to maintain its App Store monopoly or if there are legitimate security concerns.</li>
<li>The discussion explores criticism of Apple&#39;s actions, including photo scanning and its response to EU regulations, and concerns about limitations and restrictions in the Apple app store.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/graycrawford/status/1750225562281632048">Chess Pieces Redesigned as Geometric Attack Directions</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A Twitter user has found a way to redesign chess pieces using geometric shapes to represent attack directions.</li>
<li>This discovery offers a fresh and creative take on the traditional design of chess pieces.</li>
<li>By using purely geometric shapes, the new chess pieces provide a visually interesting and intuitive way to understand attack directions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39128902">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions focus on various aspects of chess, such as alternative designs for chess pieces, different movements for the knight, the influence of visual aids on learning the game, the significance of different pieces, and the possibility of creating new chess variants.</li>
<li>Participants express their opinions, propose enhancements, and analyze the pros and cons of different concepts.</li>
<li>This is an engaging and collaborative forum for chess enthusiasts to explore and exchange ideas for enhancing the game.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/after-three-years-on-mars-nasas-ingenuity-helicopter-mission-ends/">Ingenuity Mars helicopter&#39;s mission ends due to blade damage</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NASA&#39;s Ingenuity Mars Helicopter has successfully concluded its mission after surpassing its original goal of five flights in 30 days by completing 72 flights over nearly three years.</li>
<li>The helicopter sustained damage to its rotor blades during its last landing and is no longer capable of flying.</li>
<li>Ingenuity served as a technology demonstration and an aerial scout for NASA&#39;s Perseverance rover, showing that powered and controlled flight on Mars is possible despite challenges like power issues during the Martian winter. The Ingenuity team will now conduct final tests and download remaining data to officially conclude the mission.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39134349">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Mars helicopter Ingenuity has sustained damage to its rotor blades and will not be able to fly again, marking the end of its three-year project after over 70 flights.</li>
<li>Despite this setback, Ingenuity has paved the way for future Mars rotorcraft missions and has been praised for its innovation and the valuable data it has provided.</li>
<li>Discussions revolve around various topics related to space exploration, such as the accuracy of dust storms on Mars, the durability of sample tubes collected on Mars, NASA&#39;s use of advanced technology, and the ownership of lunar territory. There are also debates about the ethical considerations of establishing a human colony on Mars and the potential for a service or repair station on the planet.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://wedistribute.org/2023/11/introducing-faircamp/">Faircamp: A Free and Customizable Alternative Platform for Musicians After Bandcamp&#39;s Sale</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Faircamp is a free alternative platform for musicians following the acquisition of Bandcamp by Songtradr.</li>
<li>It is a static site generator that musicians can self-host, providing customization and payment options for albums and tracks.</li>
<li>Faircamp has received positive feedback from the music community, with some artists using RadioFreeFedi&#39;s infrastructure to host their own Faircamp sites, making it a promising alternative for supporting musicians in the Fediverse.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39129155">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around several aspects of Bandcamp, such as its strengths, community features, and cultural impact.</li>
<li>Users express their opinions on the platform&#39;s acquisition by Epic Games, the importance of supporting artists, and alternative platforms for hosting and selling music.</li>
<li>Topics like payment systems, content restrictions, discoverability, ownership, reliability, and the influence of corporations on online platforms are also covered, emphasizing the significance of community, curation, and supporting independent musicians.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/25/24049050/microsoft-activision-blizzard-layoffs">Microsoft Cuts 1,900 Employees at Activision Blizzard and Xbox</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft is cutting 1,900 jobs, around 8% of its gaming division, including employees at Activision Blizzard and Xbox, following its recent acquisition of Activision Blizzard.</li>
<li>The layoffs will impact Xbox and ZeniMax employees, and Blizzard president Mike Ybarra will be leaving the company.</li>
<li>The cancellation of projects, including Blizzard&#39;s survival game, is also part of the restructuring. Other gaming companies are also making similar cutbacks.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39129949">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion touches on various topics like job layoffs, unemployment challenges, starting a business, and the effects of acquisitions on companies and employees.</li>
<li>They also talk about the gaming industry, the decline of certain companies, and the role of AI in creative works.</li>
<li>There are discussions regarding specific games, quality concerns, profit-driven practices in the gaming industry, and the potential uses and implications of AI technology.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/rhboot/shim/commit/0226b56513b2b8bd5fd281bce77c40c9bf07c66d">Out-of-Bounds Write Vulnerability Fixed in rhboot / shim Software</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The summary addresses a code issue in the software project rhboot / shim.</li>
<li>The issue arises from incorrect trust in HTTP headers during file retrieval, resulting in an out-of-bounds write vulnerability.</li>
<li>A patch has been implemented to prevent the buffer from exceeding the allocated size, resolving the vulnerability.</li>
<li>The issue was discovered by Bill Demirkapi from the Microsoft Security Response Center.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39132300">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A critical vulnerability (CVE-2023-40547) has been discovered in the shim EFI bootloader used by Linux distros for Secure Boot.</li>
<li>Attackers can exploit the bug locally, from an adjacent network, or remotely via HTTP boot to bypass Secure Boot and gain unauthorized access.</li>
<li>This vulnerability has sparked discussions about the limitations of Secure Boot, Microsoft&#39;s implementation of it, the compatibility of the GPLv3 license, the use of encryption and signatures, and the potential risks associated with HTTP boot. The bug exposes security vulnerabilities and raises concerns about the effectiveness of Secure Boot.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://willcrichton.net/notes/portable-epubs/#epub-content%2FEPUB%2Findex.xhtml$">Easily Accessible Electronic Publications for Any Device</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Portable EPUBs are electronic publications that are designed to be easily accessible and portable across different devices.</li>
<li>EPUBs are a commonly used format for digital books and written content due to their compatibility with various devices.</li>
<li>EPUBs offer features like reflowable text and adjustable font sizes, enhancing the reading experience for users.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39138042">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the challenges and limitations of EPUB and PDF formats and suggests potential improvements and alternatives.</li>
<li>Ideas for enhancing EPUB&#39;s layout and rendering include improving typography tools and pre-calculating line breaks.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about EPUB readers&#39; lack of support for certain features and reliance on JavaScript, while PDF is preferred for technical documentation despite its drawbacks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://openai.com/blog/new-embedding-models-and-api-updates">OpenAI Introduces New Embedding Models and API Updates</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>OpenAI has launched new embedding models, including smaller and larger versions, and made updates to the GPT-4 Turbo and GPT-3.5 Turbo models.</li>
<li>The new models offer improved performance and reduced pricing.</li>
<li>OpenAI has introduced enhanced API key management and usage understanding, allowing developers to assign permissions and track usage on a key level. They have also released an updated moderation model for identifying harmful text.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39132901">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenAI has released new embedding models and API updates, enabling dimensionality reduction directly from the API.</li>
<li>Users are discussing the performance of OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4 and GPT-4 Turbo models, with some concerns raised about the quality of certain text embeddings.</li>
<li>The impact of dimensionality reduction on latency and the challenges of transitioning between different embedding sets are also being discussed.</li>
<li>Workers are expressing anxiety about job displacement and its potential impact on data quality.</li>
<li>The affordability of OpenAI&#39;s new embeddings model is highlighted, along with comparisons to open-source models and discussions about competition and pricing in the AI-as-a-Service industry.</li>
<li>Suggestions are made to address the issue of &quot;laziness&quot; in the models.</li>
<li>Moderation actions are being taken against users who violate guidelines on sensitive discussions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://phys.org/news/2024-01-japan-craft-successful-pin-moon.html">Japan&#39;s Precision Moon Lander Hits Target but Lands Upside-Down</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Japan&#39;s lunar mission, SLIM, successfully landed on the moon&#39;s surface but upside-down, with its solar batteries facing the wrong direction and unable to generate power.</li>
<li>There is hope that the probe can recharge once the moon enters its daytime.</li>
<li>This mission marks Japan&#39;s entrance as the fifth country to reach the moon and is considered a significant achievement for Japan&#39;s space technology.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39128977">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Japan&#39;s moon lander, the SLIM, successfully landed on the moon but seems to be upside-down, sparking concerns and discussions about the landing procedure and potential failure modes.</li>
<li>The lander released two rovers that transmitted images back to Earth, showcasing the capability for precision exploration.</li>
<li>Despite the landing mishap, the mission is considered groundbreaking and paves the way for future missions, while also prompting discussions on previous missions and challenges faced by Japan&#39;s space agency.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.trailofbits.com/2024/01/25/we-build-x-509-chains-so-you-dont-have-to/">Trail of Bits and Python Cryptographic Authority Release X.509 Path Validation Algorithm Implementation for Python Developers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Trail of Bits and the Python Cryptographic Authority have developed cryptography-x509-verification, a fast and memory-safe implementation of the X.509 path validation algorithm in Rust.</li>
<li>This implementation provides an alternative to OpenSSL&#39;s X.509 APIs for certificate verification in protocols like TLS and has been integrated into Cryptography&#39;s release series for use by Python developers.</li>
<li>Trail of Bits has also created x509-limbo, a test vector and harness suite designed to evaluate the conformance and behavior of various X.509 path validation implementations, aiming to enhance the security of the Python ecosystem and contribute to the open-source community.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39129806">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the development of X.509 chains and the importance of well-developed test suites.</li>
<li>It explores the potential benefits and challenges of using Rust in internet security, particularly in preventing denial of service attacks.</li>
<li>The implementation of interchangeable Prolog programs as policies in the pyca/cryptography library is discussed, along with the challenges and limitations of certificate revocation.</li>
<li>Mozilla&#39;s CRLite solution and the use of short-lived certificates are mentioned as potential alternatives to revocation.</li>
<li>The conversation covers various topics including the implementation of dynamic constraints, the &#39;webpki&#39; crate, alternatives to X.509 certificates, and the interoperability of the Python ecosystem with C.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/01/25/hpv-vaccine-prevent-cervical-cancer-cervarix-gardasil-study/">HPV Vaccine Study Finds Zero Cases of Cervical Cancer in Fully Vaccinated Women Under 14</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A recent study conducted in Scotland has shown that women born between 1988-1996 and fully vaccinated against HPV at ages 12-13 had zero cases of cervical cancer.</li>
<li>This is the first national study to track a group of women over a long period and find no instances of cervical cancer, demonstrating the effectiveness of the HPV vaccine.</li>
<li>The study highlights the importance of timely vaccination and suggests that even receiving the vaccine between ages 14-22 still significantly reduces the risk of cervical cancer. However, it&#39;s important to note that other HPV strains not covered by the vaccine can still cause cervical cancer. Continued screening for early detection is crucial.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39133086">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The HPV vaccine is effective in preventing cervical cancer and other HPV-related diseases.</li>
<li>There are issues regarding the cost and lack of insurance coverage for the vaccine.</li>
<li>There is a debate over the efficacy of the vaccine for individuals above the age of 45.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2024/01/proposed-windows-nt-sync-driver-brings-big-wine-proton-performance-improvements/">Windows NT Sync Driver Proposed for Major Performance Improvements in Linux Gaming</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Zeb Figura from CodeWeavers has suggested a Windows NT synchronization primitive driver to enhance the performance of running Windows apps and games on Linux using Wine/Proton.</li>
<li>The proposed driver would directly implement the NT synchronization primitives in the Linux kernel, eliminating the need for RPC and boosting performance.</li>
<li>Initial tests have shown promising performance improvements in various games, although the specific gains may vary depending on the hardware and software setup.</li>
<li>If the driver is approved and implemented, it could significantly enhance gaming performance on Linux, including on the upcoming Steam Deck with Wine and Proton.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39130711">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores ways to enhance gaming performance on Linux, such as proposed Windows NT sync drivers, integrating OpenVZ into the Linux kernel, and implementing syscalls for improved compatibility with Windows software.</li>
<li>Various GPU options are discussed, along with frustrations regarding proprietary drivers and experiences with AMD GPUs on Linux.</li>
<li>The comment section addresses the potential for resolving issues with running Windows software on Linux platforms and raises concerns about security and anti-cheat systems in gaming.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://interjectedfuture.com/crdts-turned-inside-out/">Exploring the Variations of Merkle CRDTs: DAGs and Search Trees</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article explores two types of Merkle Conflict-free Replicated Data Types (CRDTs): Merkle-DAG CRDTs and Merkle Search Tree CRDTs.</li>
<li>Merkle-DAG CRDTs use a directed acyclic graph to store concurrent updates and minimize syncing bandwidth between replicas.</li>
<li>Merkle Search Tree CRDTs maintain an ordered set of keys in a self-balancing and unique tree structure. The article also discusses the similarities between Merkle CRDTs and Git and the potential for implementing composable CRDTs.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39130945">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Conflict-Free Replicated Data Types (CRDTs) are being used and implemented in decentralized social networks and collaborative applications.</li>
<li>The Merkle Search Tree (MST) design is gaining recognition and adoption, with independent implementations in Go and Rust.</li>
<li>The article discusses the self-balancing feature of MSTs, their use in AT Protocol&#39;s data repository structures, and the optimization of the Merkle DAG data structure in Dolt.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2024/01/eff-and-more-100-ngos-set-non-negotiable-redlines-ahead-un-cybercrime-treaty">EFF and 110 NGOs Warn UN Cybercrime Treaty Threatens Human Rights and Privacy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) has partnered with 110 NGOs to voice their concerns about the UN Cybercrime Treaty draft.</li>
<li>They believe that the current version of the treaty lacks sufficient protection for human rights and has transformed into a tool for surveillance.</li>
<li>The EFF is calling on states to reject the treaty unless significant changes are made and will be present at the concluding session from January 29 to February 10.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39129274">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed UN cybercrime treaty is seen as inadequate in addressing cybercrime due to jurisdictional constraints and lack of access to criminals.</li>
<li>Imposing fines and sanctions on countries responsible for cybercrime is suggested but may face geopolitical challenges and public disapproval.</li>
<li>Stopping cybercrime in third world countries is difficult due to financial motives and the complexity of tracking money and data packets.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Apple Introduces Changes to iOS, Safari, and App Store in EU to Comply with Digital Markets Act" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Apple%20Introduces%20Changes%20to%20iOS%2C%20Safari%2C%20and%20App%20Store%20in%20EU%20to%20Comply%20with%20Digital%20Markets%20Act&subheading=Friday%2C%20January%2026%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/26</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-26T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-25]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/25&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-25</h1>
<h2><a href="https://zed.dev/blog/zed-is-now-open-source">Zed Code Editor Goes Open Source, Emphasizes Collaboration</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Zed, a code editor, has transitioned into an open-source project to enhance the product and engage with the programming community.</li>
<li>Zed is now available on GitHub under copyleft and Apache 2 licenses, allowing developers to access and modify the code.</li>
<li>The company plans to introduce Fireside Hacks, a real-time collaborative coding feature, while still maintaining a sustainable business model by offering integrated services and charging for private use of specific features. They encourage community contributions and provide a guide for getting involved.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39119835">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers various code editors, including Zed, Visual Studio Code (VSC), Emacs, and other alternatives.</li>
<li>Users share experiences and suggestions on improving performance, collaboration, self-hosting chat servers, startup time, and package management.</li>
<li>The conversation touches on licensing, compatibility with different operating systems, availability of collaborative editing options, and highlights the importance of real-time collaboration and efficiency for pair programming.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/openai-scrapped-promise-disclose-key-documents/">OpenAI Backtracks on Promise to Disclose Key Documents, Raises Concerns</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>OpenAI, a nonprofit AI research lab, has broken its promise to disclose key documents to the public, raising concerns about its transparency.</li>
<li>The company was founded with the aim of involving society in AI development, but when requested for governing documents and financial statements, OpenAI refused to provide them.</li>
<li>Critics argue that increased disclosure could enhance customer loyalty and regulatory trust, and access to these documents could provide insights into OpenAI&#39;s vulnerabilities, its relationship with stakeholders like Microsoft, and any revisions made to stabilize its corporate structure.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39121521">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenAI is facing criticism for its lack of transparency and shift towards profitability, raising concerns about its commitment to benefiting humanity.</li>
<li>Participants express disappointment and skepticism towards OpenAI&#39;s actions, questioning its integrity.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the implications of artificial general intelligence (AGI) development, the profit-driven focus of the tech industry, and the need for regulation and open discussions about AI.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.fundingsimulator.com/">Understanding Modern Fundraising: Introducing an Open-Source Startup Funding Simulator</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author developed an open-source tool to help founders gain a better understanding of modern fundraising and the potential dilution they may experience.</li>
<li>The tool simplifies the process of understanding startup funding by allowing users to add post-money safes, priced rounds, and employee options to see the impact on ownership.</li>
<li>The author recognizes the complexities involved in startup funding, including different types of safes, options allocation, pro-rata rights, and MFN provisions, and welcomes feedback from users of the tool.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39120647">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Discussions revolve around Fundingsimulator.com, a tool that assists founders in understanding fundraising complexities and potential dilution.</li>
<li>Users provide feedback on the tool&#39;s features and suggest improvements.</li>
<li>Other discussions include the challenges and benefits of startup funding, the relevance of VC funding at different stages of business growth, and the importance of skills and learning from successful founders. The ownership and financial complexities of startups and the potential advantages of having co-founders are also explored.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/business-news/alaska-airlines-found-more-loose-bolts-boeing-737-max-9-ceo-says-rcna135316">Alaska Airlines CEO: Loose bolts found on 737 Max planes</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Loose bolts were discovered on Alaska Airlines&#39; Boeing 737 Max 9 planes during in-house inspections following a recent near-disaster incident.</li>
<li>The Federal Aviation Administration has grounded all Boeing Max 9 planes and initiated a safety investigation, leading to flight cancellations and rearrangements for Alaska Airlines.</li>
<li>Alaska Airlines CEO Ben Minicucci holds Boeing responsible for improving its quality control systems, and the company is sending its audit staff to inspect planes on the production line.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39115878">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Alaska Airlines CEO has sent an audit team to investigate concerns about the quality control of Boeing&#39;s Max planes.</li>
<li>The FAA is inspecting Boeing&#39;s quality process, with a specific focus on the door and bolts, as well as other potential issues in the quality system.</li>
<li>There are debates about the FAA&#39;s deferential approach towards Boeing, the possibility of government acquisition of the company, the importance of independent audits and quality control, the suitability of an engineer as CEO, the role of unions in safety, and the trust placed in the FAA by Alaska Airlines and other airlines.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ctrl-alt-test.fr/2024/how-we-made-an-animated-movie-in-8kb">Creating an 8kB Animated Movie: Combining Storytelling and Animation with Technical Constraints</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A team successfully created a real-time animation within the strict size constraints of 8kB.</li>
<li>They utilized GLSL shaders, raymarching, and C++ coding to generate visuals, music, and animation.</li>
<li>The project focused on conveying emotions and storytelling through small details, camera work, editing, and synchronization.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39121101">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on creating an animated movie using Creative Commons licenses and an 8kB limit.</li>
<li>The conversation includes debates on the authenticity of a coding system and references a previous movie for inspiration.</li>
<li>Topics such as time travel, AI, and challenges in compressing and animating 2D and 3D visuals are also discussed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.kagi.com/celebrating-20k">Kagi Community Reaches 20k Paying Members, Plans Merchandise Store Launch</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Kagi community has reached a significant milestone of 20,000 paying members, with 1,500 families from around the world.</li>
<li>To show gratitude, Kagi plans to launch a merchandise store and will offer a free Kagi T-shirt and sticker pack to their first 20,000 members.</li>
<li>The t-shirts were carefully produced for quality and manufactured by a print shop in Serbia. Kagi sees this as an investment in their early adopters and a commitment to supporting their member community in the long run.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39124497">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The focus of the discussion is on the search engine Kagi and its various features, advantages, and potential vulnerabilities to SEO manipulation.</li>
<li>Users express satisfaction with prioritized search results and customization options provided by Kagi.</li>
<li>Debate arises regarding the effectiveness of giving away t-shirts to paying members as a form of advertising, with differing opinions on its impact.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ollama.ai/blog/python-javascript-libraries">Ollama Releases Python and JavaScript Libraries for Seamless Integration</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Ollama Python and JavaScript libraries have been released, enabling seamless integration with new and existing applications.</li>
<li>These libraries provide access to various features of the Ollama REST API, such as streaming, multi-modal capabilities, text completion, creating custom models, and utilizing a custom client.</li>
<li>The libraries can be found on GitHub under the organization &quot;ollama,&quot; with special recognition given to community members who have contributed libraries for different programming languages.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39125477">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ollama, a developer platform, has released libraries for Python and JavaScript.</li>
<li>Users are discussing their experiences with Ollama, including customization options and the compatibility and performance of different models.</li>
<li>Ollama is a local LLM server written in Go, designed for desktop use but not recommended for multiuser scenarios.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://unethical.info/2024/01/24/hacking-my-air-purifier/">Hacking Xiaomi Air Purifier: Reset Filter Warning with RFID Chip Hack</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author recounts their experience with a Xiaomi air purifier that had an unremovable replace filter warning.</li>
<li>They discovered a method to hack the RFID chip on the filter and reset it using a password generated from the tag&#39;s UID.</li>
<li>Instructions are provided on how to reset the filter using an NFC-enabled mobile phone, along with a list of compatible devices and comments from successful readers who have tried it.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39115837">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users discuss frustrations with DRM (Digital Rights Management) in air purifiers and share experiences of hacking devices to bypass restrictions.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about the potential increase in counterfeit filters if this hack becomes popular.</li>
<li>Alternative solutions, like using a differential pressure sensor instead of DRM, are suggested, and a plea is made for the repeal of the DMCA (Digital Millennium Copyright Act) and the right to repair for consumers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.blog/2024-01-23-good-devex-increases-productivity/">The Power of Flow State in Coding</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Flow state is a mental state of complete focus and immersion in a task, such as coding.</li>
<li>Being in a flow state can enhance productivity, creativity, and overall enjoyment of coding.</li>
<li>The article provides three practical tips for entering and maintaining a flow state during coding sessions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39119141">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversations emphasize the significance of developer experience (DevEx) in improving productivity.</li>
<li>The challenges in measuring and enhancing DevEx are discussed, including the impact of ineffective DX on productivity and frustrations with tools and processes.</li>
<li>Creating a cohesive and efficient working environment for developers is highlighted as essential for DevEx, along with the need for objective measures.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-free-file-is-now-available-for-the-2024-filing-season">IRS Free File: File Your Taxes for Free with Trusted Partners</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The IRS Free File program offers eligible taxpayers the opportunity to file their federal tax returns for free using software provided by trusted IRS partners.</li>
<li>Eligibility for the program is determined by age, income, and state residency, with most taxpayers having an adjusted gross income limit of $79,000.</li>
<li>Taxpayers with a higher income limit can also file for free using Fillable Forms, an option available through the program.</li>
<li>The program ensures the security of taxpayer information, with partner companies prohibited from using it for any purposes other than tax preparation.</li>
<li>Mobile access is available, enabling taxpayers to file their taxes using smartphones or tablets.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39119668">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores different aspects of tax filing, such as available options, government software, and online filing.</li>
<li>It also touches on the role of tax preparation companies, deductions for landlords and software engineers, tax-exempt and tax-deferred accounts, and the complexity of the tax code.</li>
<li>The conversation emphasizes the need for education, compares tax systems in other countries, and advocates for a simpler and more efficient tax filing system.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://gabrielgambetta.com/zx-raytracer.html">Reviving the ZX Spectrum: A Retro Raytracer with GO TO Statements</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author was inspired by an article and developed a raytracer for the ZX Spectrum, an old computer from the 80s.</li>
<li>The code contains GO TO statements, which might be concerning for certain readers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39118349">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation revolves around the limitations and capabilities of ZX Spectrum and Amstrad computers, including processors, programming languages, color palettes, and graphics loading processes.</li>
<li>Users share their experiences and tips for optimizing code and rendering times.</li>
<li>Alternative programming languages and compilers are discussed, along with the potential for improving performance by redoing exercises in assembly language.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/23/magazine/train-robbery-amazon-packages.html">Rise in Freight Train Robberies Targeting Amazon Packages Raises Concerns</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The rise of e-commerce has resulted in an increase in cargo theft from freight trains in the Los Angeles basin.</li>
<li>Reported incidents of cargo theft have nearly doubled since 2019, targeting specific cars and coordinated for quick unloading of stolen goods.</li>
<li>Cargo theft leads to significant annual losses estimated to be between $15 billion and $35 billion in the United States and around $50 billion globally.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39120773">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion covers a wide range of topics related to train robberies targeting Amazon packages, including the role of organized groups and opportunistic thieves.</li>
<li>It explores the legality of taking found property, the effectiveness of rewards and punishments as deterrents, and the use of guns in society.</li>
<li>It also delves into the lack of security measures in train systems, the impact of poverty and inequality on crime rates, and the correlation between homelessness and theft.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://eulerarchive.maa.org/hedi/index.html">How Euler Revolutionized Mathematics</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;How Euler Did It&quot; is an online column by Ed Sandifer, exploring the works and ideas of mathematician Leonhard Euler.</li>
<li>The articles cover various topics such as number theory, geography, and fluid mechanics.</li>
<li>The collection is hosted by the Euler Archive in partnership with the Mathematical Association of America and is available in two volumes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39118314">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation centers on the contributions and influence of mathematician Euler, including his partnerships and challenges with vision problems.</li>
<li>It compares Euler to other mathematicians and discusses the accessibility and understandability of mathematics.</li>
<li>The conversation explores the concept of exceptional individuals and the constraints of traditional education systems, along with the potential role of AI in education and the efficacy of AI tutoring.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00169-7">Progress in Autoimmune Disease Therapies Spark Hope</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Scientists are making advancements in the development of therapies for autoimmune diseases like diabetes, lupus, and multiple sclerosis.</li>
<li>Promising approaches include administering antigens to rogue cells, selectively eliminating problematic cells, and introducing engineered immune cells.</li>
<li>Nanoparticles called navacims and liver-targeted antigen therapies are showing promise in turning off autoimmune responses and reversing symptoms of multiple sclerosis, respectively. Additionally, therapies involving chimeric autoantibody receptor T cells have shown significant improvement in patients with lupus and other disorders.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39116387">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Scientists are exploring the use of antigens to train rogue cells to attack in hopes of curing autoimmune diseases, but concerns about effectiveness exist for everyone.</li>
<li>Some individuals with autoimmune diseases are hopeful for more targeted treatments.</li>
<li>Discussions surround the increased risk of infection and cancer with rheumatoid arthritis medications, preference for certain medications based on safety profiles and potential side effects, fasting as a potential treatment, other treatments for mast cell diseases and allergies, the effectiveness of current allergy treatments, and the validity of dietary interventions in treating autoimmune diseases.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Zed Code Editor Goes Open Source, Emphasizes Collaboration" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Zed%20Code%20Editor%20Goes%20Open%20Source%2C%20Emphasizes%20Collaboration&subheading=Thursday%2C%20January%2025%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/25</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-25T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-24]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/24&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-24</h1>
<h2><a href="https://viewfromthewing.com/boeing-whistleblower-production-line-has-enormous-volume-of-defects-bolts-on-max-9-werent-installed/">Whistleblower Reveals Defects in Boeing 737 MAX 9 Production Line</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The detachment of a mid-exit door plug on an Alaska Airlines Boeing 737 MAX 9 was caused by the failure to install four bolts during production, according to a Boeing employee.</li>
<li>There have been a high number of nonconforming findings on 737 mid fuselage door installations in the past year, potentially indicating production issues.</li>
<li>The problems may be linked to outsourced plane components that have defects upon arrival at the production line, suggesting a potential quality control and culture issue within certain parts of the business. The extent of the problem and whether it is isolated or systemic remains unclear.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39102021">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Discussions surrounding concerns with Boeing&#39;s manufacturing practices, engineering culture, and decisions leading to safety issues with their planes.</li>
<li>Criticism of management, outsourcing practices, and prioritization of profit over safety.</li>
<li>Whistleblower credibility, protection, and accountability, as well as discussions on regulatory agencies, sales/marketing influence, and the need for change in project management practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://leebriggs.co.uk/blog/2019/02/07/why-are-we-templating-yaml">Templating YAML vs Generating JSON: A Better Approach for Config Management</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author criticizes the practice of templating YAML and proposes using JSON instead for better configuration management.</li>
<li>They argue that YAML templating becomes challenging as configuration complexity increases, particularly with optional fields and nested structures.</li>
<li>The author introduces Jsonnet as a solution, emphasizing its capability to generate JSON config effortlessly and handle optional fields and nested structures more effectively.</li>
<li>They also mention the use of Jsonnet in their tool kr8 for simplified configuration management in Kubernetes clusters.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39101828">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text discusses various configuration languages and tools, such as YAML, JSON, TOML, AWS CDK, Terraform, Ansible, Chef, HCL, LOGO, Nix, Helm, Dhall, CDK8s, and more.</li>
<li>Participants engage in conversations and debates regarding the pros and cons of different languages, expressing frustrations and proposing alternatives.</li>
<li>Programming languages with a strong standard library are preferred, emphasizing the importance of simplicity, ease of use, and maintainability in configuration files. Some users suggest the use of DSLs or embedded languages for enhanced functionality and flexibility.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/framework-laptop-16">The Framework Laptop 16: Great Linux Support and Customizability Receive Positive Reviews</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Framework Laptop 16 is receiving positive reviews for its strong support of Linux, high performance, and customizable options.</li>
<li>It features the AMD Ryzen 7040HS processor for improved performance and offers various upgrade options.</li>
<li>The laptop&#39;s design files are open-source, and it is compatible with modern Linux distributions. However, it is slightly heavier and some I/O ports may impact its sleek design. The pricing starts at $1399 for the DIY model and $1699 for the pre-built version. Overall, the laptop is praised for its features and display quality.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39104363">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Framework Laptop is discussed, covering topics such as CMOS draining, supported Linux distros, battery life, availability, keyboard preferences, hardware upgrades, and comparisons with other laptops.</li>
<li>Users appreciate the company&#39;s commitment to upgradeability and customization.</li>
<li>Some concerns and suggestions are raised, specifically regarding battery life and power optimization.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.rawrlab.com/godot_nintendo_switch_free_port.html">Godot Engine Offers Free Nintendo Switch Port</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Godot Engine has released a free port of their engine specifically for Nintendo Switch developers.</li>
<li>The port is compatible with certain versions of Godot Engine and offers basic functionality, although it does not support C# or GDNative/GDExtension.</li>
<li>While the port may not be highly optimized, it is suitable for small to mid-sized game projects. Interested developers can request access through the Nintendo Developer Portal and are encouraged to seek support from the community.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39102002">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation covers multiple aspects of game development, such as homebrew games, piracy, and challenges faced in developing for consoles like the Nintendo Switch.</li>
<li>The limitations of developing and distributing games on different platforms are discussed, as well as the use of popular game development engines like Godot, Unity, and Unreal.</li>
<li>The importance of licensing and contracts in the gaming industry is emphasized, shedding light on the complexities and restrictions faced by developers in this field.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09514">Is Life an Expected Phase Transition in the Universe?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces a new definition of life based on the concepts of Catalytic Closure, Constraint Closure, and Spatial Closure.</li>
<li>The authors combine mathematical theories to argue that life is expected as a phase transition in the evolving universe.</li>
<li>The paper suggests new approaches to studying the phylogeny of metabolisms, searching for life on exoplanets, and experimentally exploring the emergence of rudimentary life.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39103419">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The concept of life as a phase transition in the evolving universe is explored in this article and discussion.</li>
<li>The interdisciplinary nature of studying life and the contributions of the Santa Fe Institute are emphasized.</li>
<li>The connection between entropy and life, mathematical/physics-based definition of life, and the relationship between the universe&#39;s tendency towards generating entropy and the efficiency of life are examined.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/4-reasons-to-try-mozillas-new-firefox-linux-package-for-ubuntu-and-debian-derivatives/">Mozilla&#39;s New Firefox Linux Package for Ubuntu and Debian-based Distributions</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Mozilla has launched a new Firefox package designed specifically for Linux, including Ubuntu, Debian, and other Debian-based distributions.</li>
<li>The package is built and supported by Mozilla, ensuring better performance and faster updates.</li>
<li>Users can download the package directly from the Mozilla website, offering adaptability and seamless integration with the Firefox release process.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39105114">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Mozilla has released a Firefox Linux package for Ubuntu and Debian derivatives, providing users with direct updates from the Firefox release process.</li>
<li>The package&#39;s effectiveness in resolving the need for browser restarts after updates is uncertain.</li>
<li>Users have varying preferences for installing and updating Firefox on Linux systems, with discussions around uninterrupted browsing, inconveniences of restarts, update interruptions, login and crash issues.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/23/health/deaf-gene-therapy.html">Gene therapy enables 11-year-old boy to hear, opening doors for treatment of congenital deafness</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>An 11-year-old boy named Aissam Dam has become the first person in the United States to receive gene therapy for congenital deafness.</li>
<li>The gene therapy specifically targets a mutation in the otoferlin gene, which affects approximately 200,000 people globally.</li>
<li>Aissam&#39;s treatment was successful, granting him the ability to hear for the first time.</li>
<li>This study has the potential to pave the way for gene therapies for other forms of congenital deafness.</li>
<li>Researchers presented their data on this groundbreaking trial on February 3rd.</li>
<li>The therapy involves injecting new otoferlin genes into the delicate cochlea, which has proven to be a challenging process.</li>
<li>While cochlear implants have been the standard intervention for otoferlin deafness, they do not offer the same quality of sound as gene therapy.</li>
<li>The success of Aissam&#39;s treatment has allowed the study to expand to younger children.</li>
<li>If proven effective and safe, gene therapies for other genetic causes of deafness may gain increased interest.</li>
<li>However, finding suitable candidates for the therapy has been difficult due to skepticism within the Deaf community.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39106464">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions revolve around language learning, cochlear implants, vision, deafness, gene therapy, and tinnitus treatments.</li>
<li>Participants debate topics such as the critical period for language acquisition, the effects of cochlear implants on language skills, and the ability to learn multiple languages.</li>
<li>The discussions also cover issues such as the importance of accents in language learning, advancements in technology for cochlear implants and vision correction, and ethical concerns regarding gene therapy for deafness.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://reason.com/2024/01/23/appeals-court-fbis-safe-deposit-box-seizures-violated-fourth-amendment/">FBI&#39;s Safe-Deposit Box Seizures Ruled Unconstitutional by Appeals Court</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A federal appeals court has found that the FBI violated the Fourth Amendment by searching and seizing the contents of more than 700 safe-deposit boxes without following proper protocol.</li>
<li>The court determined that the FBI exceeded the scope of its warrant by conducting a &quot;criminal search or seizure&quot; and using the obtained information to obtain additional warrants.</li>
<li>The ruling underscores the necessity for reforming federal forfeiture laws and emphasizes the significance of the Fourth Amendment in safeguarding individuals&#39; rights.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39111539">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A recent court ruling concluded that the FBI&#39;s seizure of safe-deposit boxes violated the Fourth Amendment, which protects against unreasonable searches and seizures.</li>
<li>The mishandling of the seized items by the FBI resulted in the loss of traceability and potential return to the owners.</li>
<li>The raid on the lockbox company was initiated under suspicions of money laundering, but the court ruled that the contents of the boxes could not be used to prosecute unknown crimes. Concerns exist that the seizure was part of civil asset forfeiture with intentions to charge individuals with crimes related to their deposit boxes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://waterwaymap.org">Explore Waterway Connections with WaterwayMap.org</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>WaterwayMap.org is a website that shows the interconnectedness of waterways in OpenStreetMap.</li>
<li>Users have the ability to filter the map by length and make edits using JOSM or iD.</li>
<li>The map data is obtained from OpenStreetMap contributors and users can report any issues they come across.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39110434">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores various subjects such as canals, waterways, and boating across different regions.</li>
<li>Topics include the English and Welsh canal system, the lifestyle of narrowboat owners, and the accuracy of waterway mapping on OpenStreetMap.</li>
<li>It also delves into the presence of cenotes in the Yucatan peninsula, the navigability of waterways in California and the Bay Area, and the Intracoastal Waterway along the US Eastern Seaboard.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/01/higher-vehicle-hoods-significantly-increase-pedestrian-deaths-study-finds/">Study: Higher vehicle hoods in trucks and SUVs increase pedestrian deaths</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A recent study reveals that the height of vehicle hoods in American trucks and SUVs is linked to a rise in pedestrian fatalities.</li>
<li>Analysis of crash data from 2016-2021 demonstrates that pickups and SUVs have substantially taller hoods than standard cars, making them more hazardous to pedestrians.</li>
<li>The study also indicates that pedestrians are more likely to be killed in accidents involving pickups and SUVs compared to vans and cars, highlighting the impact of larger vehicles on the increasing pedestrian death rates in the United States.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39106916">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Taller vehicle hoods, larger SUVs, and trucks contribute to increased pedestrian fatalities by limiting visibility for drivers and cyclists.</li>
<li>Safety regulations aimed at protecting occupants have inadvertently compromised driver visibility, leading to debates about prioritizing safety over appearance in car design.</li>
<li>Concerns include reduced visibility caused by wider pillars, headlight brightness regulations, passing on the right, vehicle size, electric vehicle weight, and the popularity of SUVs and trucks. Discussions focus on improving road safety and addressing concerns related to larger vehicles.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://crowsonkb.github.io/hourglass-diffusion-transformers/">Hourglass Diffusion Transformer: High-resolution Image Generation at Scale</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Hourglass Diffusion Transformer (HDiT) is a new image generative model that can train at high resolutions directly in pixel-space.</li>
<li>HDiT combines the efficiency of convolutional U-Nets with the scalability of Transformers, resulting in impressive performance on ImageNet and setting a new state-of-the-art for diffusion models on FFHQ at high resolution.</li>
<li>The model showcases efficient scaling in terms of computational cost when compared to other models, and the authors provide generated samples for evaluation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39107620">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces a high-resolution image generation model that avoids using convolutions to reduce potential artifacts.</li>
<li>The model incorporates patching and neighborhood attention, showing potential efficiency and scalability.</li>
<li>The paper explores the integration of the model into existing SD infrastructure and addresses concerns about compatibility. It also discusses the possibility of using transformer techniques.</li>
<li>The article mentions the use of ML-focused discord servers, cross-attention, text-to-image generation, and Stability AI&#39;s large text-to-image models.</li>
<li>Diffusion U-Nets, class-conditioned image generation, and budgeting for bank accounts are other topics briefly mentioned in the article.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ai.stanford.edu/~zayd/why-is-machine-learning-hard.html">Why is Machine Learning Challenging?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Machine learning is a challenging field because it involves implementing complex algorithms and models and debugging them.</li>
<li>Debugging machine learning algorithms is more difficult than traditional software engineering because it involves dealing with bugs in the model and data.</li>
<li>Debugging cycles in machine learning can take longer, leading to delays in getting feedback on fixes. Developing an intuition for identifying and fixing issues is crucial in this field.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39109481">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Hacker News discussion focuses on the challenges and complexities of machine learning (ML), emphasizing the need for a strong background in computer science, algorithms, and mathematics.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the uncertainties in ML projects, the difficulties of debugging ML models compared to traditional software engineering, and the challenges of training models with limited data.</li>
<li>The importance of selecting the appropriate tool for the task and the financial incentive of addressing these challenges are also mentioned in the discussion.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.404media.co/these-are-the-notorious-nsa-furby-documents-showing-spy-agency-freaking-out-about-childrens-toy/">NSA&#39;s Secret Ban on Furby Revealed: Concerns Over Spy Device Capabilities</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The NSA has recently disclosed documents regarding its ban on the Furby toy in the late 1990s, suspecting it could be exploited as a surveillance tool.</li>
<li>The released documents, obtained through a Freedom of Information Act request, comprise internal conversations, a memo outlining the ban, and a list of media sources that reported on the incident.</li>
<li>The documents are now publicly accessible and can be found online, though paid members have unrestricted access, while free members receive a weekly summary of news stories.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39106355">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion delves into security concerns surrounding devices like Furbys and voice assistants with recording capabilities.</li>
<li>The NSA&#39;s classification as a military agency and experiences with filing FOIA requests are also discussed.</li>
<li>The conversation explores the potential risks of compromised toys and electronic devices, as well as the importance of government security protocols and procedures.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Whistleblower Reveals Defects in Boeing 737 MAX 9 Production Line" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Whistleblower%20Reveals%20Defects%20in%20Boeing%20737%20MAX%209%20Production%20Line&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20January%2024%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/24</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-24T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-23]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/23&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-23</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/01/22/business/ftc-turbotax-free-services/index.html">FTC bans TurboTax from &#39;free&#39; advertising</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The given texts contain a wide range of data, including CSS code snippets, configuration settings, advertising information, regulatory actions, JavaScript code snippets, and news reports about TurboTax and the Federal Trade Commission.</li>
<li>Each piece of information serves a specific purpose and has its own functionality based on its context.</li>
<li>The texts provide diverse and relevant information related to TurboTax and the Federal Trade Commission.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39097356">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has banned TurboTax from advertising their &quot;free&quot; services, raising concerns about the company&#39;s marketing practices.</li>
<li>The discussion also explores the challenges people face with fractions in math and the importance of understanding this concept.</li>
<li>The topic of budgeting for low-income individuals is addressed, highlighting the financial difficulties faced by many and the need for effective budgeting strategies.</li>
<li>Different tax filing options are discussed, including the role of Intuit in the tax filing industry and their lobbying efforts.</li>
<li>The debate on the access and influence of corporations in political representation is examined, highlighting the potential implications for democracy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/01/modder-recreates-game-boy-advance-games-using-the-audio-from-crash-sounds/">Modder recreates Game Boy Advance games using crash sounds</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A modder has found a technique to develop functional Game Boy Advance games by capturing crash sounds from the original games and analyzing the audio waveforms.</li>
<li>The modder faced challenges during the process but eventually managed to recreate the game data, resulting in a perfectly accurate ROM.</li>
<li>The created ROM can be played on physical Game Boy Advance hardware, providing an exciting way to relive classic gaming experiences.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39092505">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users are discussing the idea of using audio to recover game state when Game Boy Advance (GBA) games crash.</li>
<li>The conversation explores the architecture of the GBA and the possibility of the audio hardware accessing the game&#39;s ROM.</li>
<li>Various topics are discussed, including clock recovery, coding systems, digital signal processing, GPS technology, median filters for noise removal in photos, the limitations of 8-bit resolution, and the use of emulators to detect errors in reconstructed GBA ROMs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.neowin.net/news/meta-now-lets-eu-users-unlink-their-facebook-messenger-and-instagram-accounts/">Instagram Introduces &quot;Notes Prompts&quot; to Encourage User Engagement</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Instagram has launched a new feature called &quot;Notes Prompts&quot; that enables users to send reminders or prompts to their friends.</li>
<li>This feature aims to encourage friends to respond to messages or posts.</li>
<li>Users can utilize &quot;Notes Prompts&quot; to ensure that their messages or posts receive attention and engagement from their friends.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39090879">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>European Union (EU) regulations are a hot topic, especially surrounding data privacy and technology companies.</li>
<li>Users in the EU have the ability to unlink their Facebook, Messenger, and Instagram accounts, which raises challenges and implications.</li>
<li>GDPR regulations have had an impact on user privacy, but there are limitations and criticisms of EU regulations.</li>
<li>Cookie pop-ups and the potential influence of Big Tech on legislation are also discussed.</li>
<li>Starting and growing software businesses in Europe can be difficult.</li>
<li>Differing opinions exist on the effectiveness and implementation of regulations, as well as the role of politicians and citizens in shaping them.</li>
<li>The discussions also touch on Google&#39;s services, the interconnectedness of platforms, and potential bans on YouTube or Gmail.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39099065">Hacker News Now Supports IPv6 Connection</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The user&#39;s browser is now connecting to Hacker News over IPv6, as indicated by the presence of both IPv4 and IPv6 addresses belonging to the same ASN (M5 Computer Security).</li>
<li>The user is happy about being redirected to Hacker News and hopes that it does not suffer the same fate as Reddit, which was turned off previously.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39099065">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>This summary provides an overview of IPv6 implementation, challenges, benefits, and concerns.</li>
<li>It covers topics like browser extensions, address allocation, latency issues, gaming performance, network capacity, TLS support, and CGNAT usage.</li>
<li>The discussions emphasize the complexities and potential advantages of IPv6 adoption, as well as the hesitations and difficulties encountered by users and ISPs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lightning.ai/lightning-ai/studios/code-lora-from-scratch?view=public&section=all">Unlocking Free Access: Get Started with Login</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The phrase &quot;Login Start free&quot; suggests the existence of a free login option.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39091777">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate is centered around the implementation and optimization of LoRA in machine learning models, with differing opinions on whether it should be applied to all layers or just the last layer.</li>
<li>There is confusion regarding the acronym LoRA, as it can be mistaken for the LoRa radio protocol.</li>
<li>The discussion also explores the distinction between engineering and discovery in AI, the lack of theoretical foundations for intelligence, and the challenges of establishing generalizable principles.</li>
<li>Various use cases for fine-tuning in machine learning are examined and compared to retrieval-augmented generation.</li>
<li>The conversation concludes with a lighthearted comment about potentially naming a project &quot;Lehsun.&quot;</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://konecipv4.cz/en/">Czech Republic Sets June 6, 2032 as End Date for IPv4 Services</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Government of the Czech Republic has approved a plan to adopt DNSSEC and IPv6 technologies in the state administration.</li>
<li>Starting from June 6, 2032, the country will no longer provide services over IPv4.</li>
<li>This transition is necessary due to the increasing number of devices and services, as IPv4 addresses have become insufficient, while IPv6 offers an almost limitless number of addresses.</li>
<li>The countdown to the end of IPv4 has been set at 3056 days, 13 hours, 57 minutes, and 16 seconds.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39097314">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores the challenges and benefits of transitioning from IPv4 to IPv6.</li>
<li>Implications for tracking individuals, use of unique local addresses, limitations, and security concerns of both IPv4 and IPv6 are discussed.</li>
<li>The conversation emphasizes the importance of hardware and software support, the need for initiatives to drive adoption, and the complexities of upgrading infrastructure.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://winlator.org/">Winlator: Run Windows Apps on Android with Wine and Box86/Box64</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Winlator is an Android app that lets users run Windows applications using Wine and Box86/Box64.</li>
<li>The project has been developed with the assistance of ptitSeb and the Wine developers.</li>
<li>The latest version of Winlator can be downloaded from the official website, which is copyrighted by BrunoSX.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39095337">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around running Windows apps on different platforms like Android and Linux, with users sharing their experiences and recommendations.</li>
<li>Specific topics include running games, Microsoft Office applications, and music production software.</li>
<li>There is a particular emphasis on using Wine, a compatibility layer, to run various programs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39088551">Diversion: A Next-Gen Cloud-Native Alternative to Git</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Diversion is a cloud-native version control system designed to solve scalability and complexity problems in Git.</li>
<li>It aims to maintain Git&#39;s branching and merging capabilities while offering real-time collaboration and compatibility with Git repositories.</li>
<li>Diversion is currently in open beta and will be released as open source in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39088551">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions revolve around the limitations and complexities of Git, a popular version control system, and the need for alternative solutions.</li>
<li>Diversion, a cloud-native alternative to Git, is presented as a potential solution for game developers.</li>
<li>Other topics include the use of Abstract Syntax Trees (AST) in version control, scalability challenges with monorepos in Git, and the debate over the complexity and effectiveness of Git as a version control system.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/01/solving-a-nasa-mystery-why-did-space-shuttle-commanders-lock-the-hatch/">Astronaut&#39;s Desperation in Orbit: Threatens to Stay in Space</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Taylor Wang, the first Chinese-born person to fly into space, encountered a significant setback when his experiment failed to work while on the Space Shuttle.</li>
<li>He was initially denied the chance to troubleshoot and repair the experiment, prompting him to threaten not to return to Earth.</li>
<li>This incident sheds light on the difficulties faced by non-NASA astronauts and payload specialists conducting scientific experiments in microgravity, and it remains relevant today as commercial spaceflight opens pathways for more individuals to explore space.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39088991">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation revolves around an article about an astronaut&#39;s mental health issues and the use of storytelling techniques in reporting.</li>
<li>The importance of concise journalism and the ongoing debate over article length and relevance are discussed.</li>
<li>Other topics include the justification for human spaceflight, the role of robots in space exploration, and the potential risks and safety measures in space missions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/stas00/ml-engineering">Machine Learning Engineering Open Book: A Comprehensive Resource for Training Language and Multi-Modal Models</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Machine Learning Engineering Open Book is a comprehensive collection of methodologies and resources for training large language models and multi-modal models.</li>
<li>It provides technical material, including scripts and commands, specifically aimed at training engineers and operators working with LLM/VLM models.</li>
<li>The book shares the author&#39;s experiences training open-source models, covering hardware components, performance optimization, operating SLURM, development debugging, and other miscellaneous resources.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39097502">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The ML Engineering Online Book is a beneficial resource for individuals involved in machine learning, offering insights into optimization, performance, and lower-level engineering aspects.</li>
<li>The book suggests using profilers and other tools to better understand and enhance model performance.</li>
<li>Slurm, a workload manager, is widely utilized in the high-performance computing (HPC) community, primarily in academia and research computing centers. However, outside of academia and HPC contexts, alternatives such as AWS and Snowflake are more commonly employed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/oA23zoEjPnzqfHiCt/there-is-way-too-much-serendipity">Serendipitous Discoveries: Artificial Sweeteners and the Quest for New Ones</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the accidental discoveries of artificial sweeteners and raises questions about the process of creating new ones.</li>
<li>It examines the reasons behind our preference for sweet flavors and suggests that low-calorie sweeteners may not exist naturally.</li>
<li>The discussion also highlights the potential risks of chemists tasting substances and the limitations of drug discovery methods.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39092278">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The conversation covers a wide range of scientific topics, such as migraines, triggers, and the role of quantum mechanics in chemistry.</li>
<li>It includes discussions on mathematical concepts like the square root of 2 being an irrational number.</li>
<li>The conversation also touches on topics like compounds and their effects on organisms, scientific advancements, taste and evolution, and accidental discoveries of sweeteners, including a fake sugar.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/22/science/space/arno-a-penzias-dead.html">Nobel Physicist Arno A. Penzias, 90, Confirmed Big Bang Theory</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Arno A. Penzias, a Nobel Prize-winning physicist, has passed away at the age of 90.</li>
<li>He confirmed the Big Bang theory with his discovery of cosmic microwave background radiation in 1964.</li>
<li>Penzias&#39; unexpected discovery marked a pivotal moment in cosmology, transitioning it from a philosophical field to one driven by observational research.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39098603">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Arno A. Penzias, a Nobel Prize-winning physicist, has passed away at the age of 90.</li>
<li>Penzias and his colleague Robert Wilson discovered the cosmic microwave background radiation, supporting the Big Bang theory.</li>
<li>Their significant findings were initially not fully recognized, but they were awarded the Nobel Prize in physics in 1978 for their contribution to cosmology.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tuananh.net/2024/01/21/cloud-cost-optimization-at-scale-part-1/">Automating Cloud Cost Optimization Saves $150k/year</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author emphasizes the significance of cloud cost optimization and presents a solution utilizing Lambda, Step Functions, and EventBridge.</li>
<li>The system automates tasks such as shutting down resources when not in use, implementing security policies, and auto-shutdown of resources.</li>
<li>The solution claims to have achieved a 70% decrease in non-production costs, with projected savings of $150k USD annually. Future plans include addressing more complex workloads like Kubernetes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39091416">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on cost management in cloud infrastructure, software development, and engineering.</li>
<li>Participants share their experiences and insights into reducing costs and navigating billing transparency challenges.</li>
<li>Recommendations are made for different strategies, tools, and approaches to effectively manage expenses in cloud services.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://forbetterscience.com/2024/01/02/dana-farberications-at-harvard-university/">Allegations of Fraud and Data Manipulation Rock Harvard&#39;s Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Allegations of data manipulation and misconduct have surfaced in cancer research at Harvard University&#39;s Dana-Farber Cancer Institute.</li>
<li>Specific instances of data forgery and fraudulent practices have been identified.</li>
<li>The credibility and competence of certain researchers are being questioned, and numerous retractions and corrections have been made as a result of these allegations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39098780">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article and comment section discuss allegations of falsified research at the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute.</li>
<li>Topics of conversation include challenges and biases in scientific research, university ranking systems, and declining teaching standards at Harvard.</li>
<li>Additional topics touched on in the comments include racial disparities in academic performance, grade inflation, lack of concern for correcting fraudulent papers, body positivity, networking focus at Harvard, value of education institutions, climate science, and supporting social dynamics despite personal religious beliefs.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="FTC bans TurboTax from 'free' advertising" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=FTC%20bans%20TurboTax%20from%20'free'%20advertising&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20January%2023%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-23T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-01-22]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/01/22&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-01-22</h1>
<h2><a href="https://flipperzero.one">Flipper Zero: A Versatile Multi-Tool for Hackers and Geeks</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Flipper Zero is a portable multi-tool device designed for pentesters and geeks, offering customization and open-source capabilities for hacking digital systems such as radio protocols, access control systems, and hardware.</li>
<li>It features a 1.4&quot; monochrome LCD display, a 5-button directional pad, and various connectivity options like Bluetooth, NFC, and infrared.</li>
<li>The device can read and emulate RFID cards, has a microSD card slot for storage, and can be controlled autonomously or connected to a computer or smartphone for advanced features, making hardware exploration and development more enjoyable and convenient.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39084137">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Flipper Zero is a versatile multi-tool device with various functions, including acting as an IR remote.</li>
<li>It has sparked discussions about its affordability compared to other alternatives and Chinese brands with IR blasters on their phones.</li>
<li>The device has faced controversy and limitations, including crashing iPhones, being banned by Amazon, and concerns about data exchange capabilities and privacy implications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://phys.org/news/2024-01-nasa-regains-contact-mini-helicopter.amp">NASA Reconnects with Mars Mini-Helicopter amidst Communication Outage</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NASA has successfully regained contact with its mini-helicopter on Mars following a communication disruption.</li>
<li>The provided CSS code is used to style various elements on a website, such as features, breadcrumbs, fact-checking messages, and a slide-in menu.</li>
<li>The code ensures a consistent visual appearance of webpages and includes media queries for responsive design.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078669">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>NASA has successfully reestablished communication with its Linux-powered mini-helicopter, Ingenuity, on Mars.</li>
<li>The discussion revolves around software development for the mission, including the use of Python scripts and the potential for cost reduction in the aerospace industry.</li>
<li>SpaceX&#39;s strategies for cost-cutting and in-house component production are highlighted, along with the importance of rad-hardening in critical applications. The potential use of helicopters on Mars and the challenges of designing aircraft systems for Mars exploration are also explored.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://id.uni-lj.si/DigitalnaIdentiteta/PonastavitevGesla?culture=en-GB">Restrictions on Password: Avoid Select, Insert, Update, Delete, Drop</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>This page is used for resetting the password of a digital identity.</li>
<li>Users are required to provide their personal information and username to reset their password.</li>
<li>The password must be strong and meet specific criteria.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078372">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussions cover a range of topics related to password security, web application firewalls, encryption, data mishandling, and best practices in database management.</li>
<li>Participants explore the vulnerabilities associated with passwords, SQL injection attacks, plaintext storage, and improper handling of user input.</li>
<li>Recommendations include proper password storage, input sanitization, parameterized SQL, and the use of encryption layers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://iter.ca/post/gpt-crash/">GPT-3.5 Vulnerability: Misspelled Phrase Causes Error Message and Raises Concerns of Data Poisoning</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Adding a specific phrase at the top of the response to ChatGPT 3.5 consistently triggers an error message.</li>
<li>This error does not occur with GPT-4 or when using the GPT-3.5 API.</li>
<li>The error is likely caused by the tokenization process used in OpenAI&#39;s GPT models.</li>
<li>The specific phrase is a misspelled option name found in XML configuration files for Katalon Studio software.</li>
<li>The dataset used to train GPT-3.5 may have excluded XML files, leading the model to be unaware of the misspelled token and producing invalid responses.</li>
<li>This discovery raises concerns about potential data poisoning and undermining the summarization capabilities of GPT-3.5.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39086106">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on AI language models, especially glitches with specific tokens, token generation, and their impact on text conversion.</li>
<li>The conversation includes topics such as training sets, tokenizers, and the appearance and functionality of GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 models.</li>
<li>Users have mixed opinions on visual issues, the speed, and usefulness of GPT-4 with the API, as well as skepticism towards OpenAI&#39;s approach and the ability to prove thinking.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nj.com/essex/2024/01/remembering-bell-labs-as-legendary-idea-factory-prepares-to-leave-nj-home.html">Legendary Bell Labs Prepares to Leave N.J. Home, Sparks Nostalgic Memories</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nokia Bell Labs, known for its groundbreaking inventions, is relocating its headquarters from Murray Hill to a new tech hub in New Brunswick, sparking nostalgia among current and former employees.</li>
<li>The move to the HELIX innovation center in New Brunswick, set to begin in 2025, aims to create a state-of-the-art research and development facility that meets the needs of Bell Labs researchers.</li>
<li>Despite the move, Bell Labs does not anticipate reducing its staff and remains committed to innovation and creating transformative technologies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39077867">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nokia Bell Labs is moving from New Jersey to New Brunswick, prompting discussions on the historical importance of the Murray Hill campus and the new HELIX innovation center.</li>
<li>The conversation explores various topics such as notable buildings, personal experiences, and book recommendations.</li>
<li>There is a admiration for research-focused companies like Bell Labs and a call for more concentrated research and development centers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://phys.org/news/2024-01-scientists-chaotic-protein-fueling-cancers.html">Scientists Develop Peptide Compound to Target Protein Fueling Cancer</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers at the University of California - Riverside have created a peptide compound that targets the protein MYC, commonly found in cancer cells.</li>
<li>By modifying the structure of the peptide, the researchers enhanced its ability to interact with MYC, allowing it to bind strongly to the protein.</li>
<li>This development shows promise in the development of new cancer treatments, and the researchers are focused on improving the peptide&#39;s ability to enter cells.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39084146">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Scientists have identified a molecule that can block the activity of the MYC protein, which is responsible for fueling 75% of cancers.</li>
<li>This discovery offers a potential treatment option for cancer, but its effectiveness, delivery methods, and potential side effects are still unknown.</li>
<li>While this is a promising development, it is important to note that it is still in the early stages and has not been tested on humans. Cancer research is a complex field, and success is not guaranteed, but it plays a vital role in advancing cancer care.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.abplive.com/technology/google-incognito-new-disclaimer-canary-version-you-are-being-tracked-even-in-google-incognito-mode-new-disclaimer-is-up-privacy-lawsuit-1658159">Google admits tracking users in Incognito mode, despite privacy claims</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google has updated its disclaimer for Incognito mode to make it clear that user data is still collected, despite claims of privacy.</li>
<li>The updated disclaimer states that while others using the same device won&#39;t see the user&#39;s activity, data will still be collected by the websites visited and the services used, including Google itself.</li>
<li>This confirms suspicions that Google tracks user activities even when they are in Incognito mode, so users are advised to be cautious when using it.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078417">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>There is ongoing debate about Google&#39;s tracking practices in incognito mode and the potential impact on user privacy.</li>
<li>Some users claim that Google still tracks their activity even in incognito mode, while others question the extent of the tracking and its connection to non-incognito sessions.</li>
<li>Suggestions for maintaining privacy include using alternative browsers or privacy-oriented tools, and there is a call for clearer communication from Google regarding the limitations of incognito mode.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/premium/article/buffalofish-oldest-hundred-years-mystery">Buffalofish Defy Aging: Some Live Past 100 and Stay Healthy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A recent study conducted at Apache Lake in Arizona has discovered that buffalofish, a type of freshwater fish, can live for over 100 years and have strong immune systems and stress responses as they age.</li>
<li>Previously, it was believed that buffalofish only lived until their mid-20s.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that further research on buffalofish longevity could provide insights into extending the lifespan of vertebrates, including humans. Additionally, the study highlights the need for conservation efforts as buffalofish populations are declining and there are currently no regulations on their harvest.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078061">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion thread covers various topics, such as the lifespan of fish species, the impact of immortality on society, advancements in life extension technologies, and overpopulation concerns.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the significance of adaptability, societal fairness, and the potential need for government intervention.</li>
<li>The conversation includes humorous and sarcastic comments alongside the serious discussions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lemire.me/blog/2024/01/21/c23-a-slightly-better-c/">C23 Standard Introduces New Features to C Programming Language</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The code demonstrates various features introduced in the C23 standard, such as preprocessor directives and function attributes.</li>
<li>It also covers binary literals, typeof operator, digit separators in numeric literals, constexpr keyword, static_assert keyword, and boolean arrays.</li>
<li>The author shares their insights on the new features, discussing their potential advantages and influence on code development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39081948">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article highlights improvements in the C23 programming language, including new features and compatibility issues with different compilers.</li>
<li>Topics such as design patterns, trigraphs, and the search for a programming language that offers memory safety and interfaces well with C libraries are discussed.</li>
<li>Potential alternative languages mentioned include Go, Rust, Zig, D, Nim, and Swift. The article also covers the differences between C and C++ and provides opinions on their strengths and drawbacks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.learndatalogtoday.org/">Learn Datalog: Interactive Tutorial for Database Query Language</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Learn Datalog Today&quot; is an interactive tutorial that teaches the Datomic dialect of Datalog, a declarative database query language.</li>
<li>The tutorial covers topics like querying, data patterns, transformation functions, and more.</li>
<li>It was written for the Lisp In Summer Projects 2013 and is open for improvement suggestions on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39080003">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion thread delves into the distinctions between Datalog and traditional datalog, highlighting its limitations and advantages.</li>
<li>Implementations and applications of Datalog in various databases and query languages are covered, demonstrating its versatility.</li>
<li>Alternative tools and languages for recursive reasoning and deductive queries are discussed, providing additional options for exploring these concepts.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nps.gov/subjects/digital/nps-data-api.htm">Access National Park Service Data with the NPS Data API</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The National Park Service (NPS) Data API is available for developers to use NPS data in their projects such as apps, maps, and websites.</li>
<li>The API offers various information on alerts, articles, campgrounds, events, lesson plans, news releases, parks, and visitor centers.</li>
<li>Developers can access the API resources and register for an API key on the NPS Data API website, while the NPS API roadmap outlines future updates and enhancements to the API.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39085830">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. National Park Service API is facing issues due to being understaffed and underfunded, leading to concerns among users.</li>
<li>Users have found alternative methods to access the data, but debates arise regarding the cost and reliance on third-party vendors.</li>
<li>Discussions cover topics such as paying for public data, access limitations, and the use of API keys for authentication and DDoS protection, along with the effectiveness and necessity of rate limiting and alternative authentication methods. Security concerns related to API keys are also mentioned.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nplusonemag.com/issue-44/the-intellectual-situation/why-is-everything-so-ugly/">Why Ugly Aesthetics are Trending in Fashion and Design</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article examines the growing trend of &quot;ugly aesthetics&quot; in fashion and design.</li>
<li>It explores the possible reasons behind the popularity of this trend.</li>
<li>The article raises questions about societal values and aesthetic preferences in contemporary culture.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39077622">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article examines the effects of LED lights on the nighttime ambiance of cities and the importance of preserving historical aesthetics.</li>
<li>It explores trends and preferences in design and aesthetics, as well as the challenges in constructing unique and beautiful structures.</li>
<li>Participants discuss various factors, such as the impact of lighting on sleep, personal aesthetics, economic considerations in construction, and the subjective nature of beauty.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Flipper Zero: A Versatile Multi-Tool for Hackers and Geeks" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Flipper%20Zero%3A%20A%20Versatile%20Multi-Tool%20for%20Hackers%20and%20Geeks&subheading=Monday%2C%20January%2022%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/01/22</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-22T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>