<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 19:13:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-18]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/18&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-18</h1>
<h2><a href="https://threema.ch/en/blog/posts/stop-chat-control">Chat Control Must Be Stopped – Now</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The EU Commission&#39;s &quot;Chat Control&quot; proposal aims to implement mass surveillance, potentially compromising citizens&#39; privacy and data security.</li>
<li>If passed, it would require service providers to scan messages for child sexual abuse material (CSAM), but critics argue it is ineffective against criminals and harmful to democracy.</li>
<li>Threema, a secure communication service, opposes the proposal and may leave the EU to avoid compliance, highlighting the potential misuse and opposition from privacy advocates.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40715449">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Implementing a global system to regulate internet privacy would face substantial resistance from privacy advocates and tech companies.</li>
<li>Enforcing such a system globally is nearly impossible due to varying levels of commitment to privacy and internet freedom across different countries.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://freiheitsrechte.org/en/themen/digitale-grundrechte/chatkontrolle">Chat Control: Incompatible with Fundamental Rights (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The EU Commission&#39;s draft Chat Control Regulation aims to combat child sexual violence but raises significant concerns about fundamental rights.</li>
<li>Key issues highlighted include privacy violations, chilling effects on free expression, error-prone filtering obligations, website blocking, and mandatory age verification.</li>
<li>The GFF argues that these measures violate the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights and calls for a reconsideration of the draft regulation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40715695">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The European Parliament is debating a &quot;Chat Control&quot; legislation that could infringe on fundamental rights, requiring users to opt-in to send images and videos.</li>
<li>Critics argue the proposal contradicts the EU&#39;s GDPR principles and could lead to coerced consent, raising concerns about privacy and government overreach.</li>
<li>The legislation might soon be passed by the European Council, sparking fears of mass surveillance and questioning the EU&#39;s commitment to protecting individual rights.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.patrick-breyer.de/en/council-to-greenlight-chat-control-take-action-now/">EU to greenlight Chat Control tomorrow</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The EU Council is set to vote on Chat Control, which involves bulk searches of private communications, on 20 June 2024.</li>
<li>The timing of the vote, shortly after the European Elections, is seen as an attempt to avoid public scrutiny.</li>
<li>Civil society is urged to act immediately by contacting their governments, raising awareness online, and organizing protests, as the current draft is considered unacceptable.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40710993">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The EU is poised to approve &quot;Chat Control,&quot; a regulation requiring the scanning of all direct messages on platforms like Reddit, Twitter, Discord, and Steam for CSAM (child sexual abuse material).</li>
<li>Critics argue the measure is unprecedented and likely ineffective, as offenders might migrate to private services, and it raises significant privacy and overreach concerns.</li>
<li>Signal Foundation has announced it would exit the EU if the regulation is enforced, highlighting the contentious nature of the proposal.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://htmx.org/posts/2024-06-17-htmx-2-0-0-is-released/">Htmx 2.0.0 has been released</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>htmx 2.0.0 has been released, ending support for Internet Explorer and tightening some defaults without altering core functionality or the API.</li>
<li>Major changes include moving extensions to a new repository, removing deprecated attributes, and modifying HTTP DELETE request handling.</li>
<li>The release will not be marked as the latest in NPM until January 1, 2025, to avoid forcing upgrades; version 1.x will remain the latest until then.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40709769">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Htmx 2.0.0 has been released, featuring cleanups and dropping support for Internet Explorer (IE), rather than major new features.</li>
<li>Developers are praising htmx for simplifying web development, with one user replacing 500 lines of JavaScript (JS) with a few htmx attributes, enhancing efficiency and enjoyment.</li>
<li>The release has sparked discussions on potential improvements and comparisons with other tools, highlighting htmx&#39;s role in reducing reliance on complex JS frameworks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cyberscarecrow.com/">Cyber Scarecrow</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Scarecrow is a cybersecurity tool currently in its alpha phase, designed to run in the background of your computer to deter viruses and malware.</li>
<li>It is available for download on Windows 10 and 11.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40715250">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Cyber Scarecrow is a tool that creates fake processes and registry entries to deceive malware into thinking it&#39;s under analysis, thereby stopping it from executing.</li>
<li>Users have expressed concerns about the tool&#39;s transparency, including the absence of an &quot;about us&quot; page, a GitHub link, and a code signing certificate.</li>
<li>The author has acknowledged these issues, citing the high cost of certificates, and there are suggestions to make the tool open source to build trust and validate its effectiveness through real-world testing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://j3s.sh/thought/stop-using-fandom.html">“Attention assault” on Fandom</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fandom, a popular wiki website, is criticized for intrusive ads, including auto-playing videos and constant interruptions, prioritizing profit over user experience.</li>
<li>In 2023, Fandom controversially replaced user content with McDonald&#39;s Grimace Shake ads, leading to a mass migration of wikis to independent domains like Runescape, Minecraft, and Hollow Knight.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to support independent wikis by using tools like Indie Wiki Buddy, employing ad blockers, and migrating their wikis off Fandom.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40711086">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Communities are migrating their wikis from Fandom to self-hosted or alternative platforms due to intrusive ads and outdated content.</li>
<li>Notable examples include the Runescape and Minecraft wikis, which have successfully transitioned away from Fandom.</li>
<li>Tools like Indie Wiki Buddy and LibRedirect assist users in avoiding Fandom by redirecting them to more user-friendly sources, underscoring the adverse effects of venture capital on user-driven content platforms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://redwoodresearch.substack.com/p/getting-50-sota-on-arc-agi-with-gpt">Getting 50% (SoTA) on Arc-AGI with GPT-4o</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40711484">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ryan&#39;s work on GPT-4o achieving 50% on the Arc-AGI public evaluation set is considered novel and interesting in the field of &quot;LLM reasoning&quot; research.</li>
<li>The approach involves generating around 8,000 Python programs to implement transformations, selecting the correct one, and applying it to test inputs, showcasing a hybrid of deep learning (DL) and program synthesis.</li>
<li>While the result is promising, it is based on the public evaluation set, and similar results on the private set have not yet been validated, indicating the need for further scrutiny and verification.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://frame.work/blog/introducing-a-new-risc-v-mainboard-from-deepcomputing">A new RISC-V Mainboard from DeepComputing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>DeepComputing has introduced a new RISC-V Mainboard for the Framework Laptop 13, featuring a JH7110 processor from StarFive with four U74 RISC-V cores from SiFive.</li>
<li>This development enhances the Framework ecosystem by allowing users to select different processor architectures, promoting flexibility and personalization.</li>
<li>The Mainboard, aimed at developers and hobbyists, will be demoed at the RISC-V Summit Europe and is supported by collaborations with Canonical and Red Hat for robust Linux compatibility.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40718124">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>DeepComputing has launched a new RISC-V Mainboard for Framework laptops, featuring the JH7110 processor and microSD storage, resembling a RISC-V Single Board Computer (SBC) in a Framework form-factor.</li>
<li>The mainboard targets developers and tinkerers, offering modularity and the potential to swap between x86 and RISC-V boards, though it comes with a notable performance drop compared to x86.</li>
<li>This collaboration between Framework and DeepComputing is viewed as a move to diversify and expand Framework&#39;s ecosystem, increasing visibility for RISC-V technology.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/sanfrancisco/inno/stories/news/2024/04/15/sam-altman-y-combinator-board-chair.html">Sam Altman is not on YC&#39;s board. So why claim to be its chair?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Sam Altman, former president and CEO of Y Combinator, claims to be its board chair in SPAC (Special Purpose Acquisition Company) filings.</li>
<li>Y Combinator denies Altman&#39;s claim, stating he was never on its board despite his significant role in the company.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40710417">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Sam Altman, former CEO and President of Y Combinator (YC), has been inaccurately listed as the chairman of YC in multiple official documents, including SEC filings and a SPAC website.</li>
<li>The misstatement has sparked debate, with some arguing it is a minor clerical error while others emphasize the legal implications of inaccuracies in SEC filings.</li>
<li>Critics highlight that such errors, if intentional, could be seen as misleading and undermine trust, though proving intent and material harm is complex.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.asu.edu/20240617-science-and-technology-asu-study-points-origin-cumulative-culture-human-evolution">Humans began to rapidly accumulate technological knowledge 600k years ago</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers from Arizona State University suggest that humans began rapidly accumulating technological knowledge through social learning around 600,000 years ago, marking the origin of cumulative culture.</li>
<li>The study, published in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, analyzed stone tool manufacturing techniques over 3.3 million years, noting a significant increase in complexity around 600,000 years ago.</li>
<li>This period, likely in the Middle Pleistocene epoch, also saw advancements like controlled use of fire and construction of wooden structures, indicating cumulative culture predates the divergence of Neanderthals and modern humans.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40711284">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Humans started gathering technological knowledge around 600,000 years ago, with multiple Homo species possibly sharing and exchanging technology.</li>
<li>The term &quot;human&quot; can refer to both modern humans and the entire genus Homo, but &quot;hominin&quot; is more precise; debates exist on whether Neanderthals and Denisovans are considered human.</li>
<li>The rapid accumulation of knowledge is linked to advancements in communication, potentially including early forms of language, highlighting the role of language in technological transfer.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/AgentOps-AI/tokencost">Token price calculator for 400+ LLMs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Tokencost is a utility library designed to estimate costs associated with Large Language Models (LLMs) by counting tokens in prompts and completions and applying model-specific pricing.</li>
<li>It addresses the challenge of tracking costs across various models and pricing schemes, helping users avoid unexpected bills by providing real-time cost estimates.</li>
<li>Developed by AgentOps, Tokencost is now open source, allowing developers to integrate it into their projects for better cost management.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40710154">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Tokencost is a utility library designed to estimate costs for over 400 Large Language Models (LLMs) by counting tokens in prompts and completions and multiplying by model costs.</li>
<li>Developed by AgentOps and open-sourced, it helps developers track spending and avoid unexpected bills, using a simple cost dictionary and utility functions.</li>
<li>Users have suggested improvements such as adding support for Rust, normalizing costs, and including image and function call costs, though there are concerns about accuracy for models without public tokenizers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://usmannkhan.com/bug%20reports/2024/06/17/sei-bug-report.html">Sei pays out $2M bug bounty</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In April 2024, two critical bugs were reported in Sei Network&#39;s layer-1 blockchain, affecting chain availability and integrity.</li>
<li>The Sei Foundation awarded $75,000 and $2,000,000 for the respective bug reports, which were identified and fixed before production release, ensuring no funds were at risk.</li>
<li>The proactive measures and quick response by the Sei Foundation prevented potential jeopardy to the Sei token market cap, demonstrating a strong commitment to user protection.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40710201">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Sei Network has paid out a $2 million bug bounty, highlighting the significant financial incentives in the cryptocurrency sector for identifying security vulnerabilities.</li>
<li>The bug bounty was processed through Immunefi, a platform specializing in crypto bug bounties, which often sees payouts exceeding $1 million.</li>
<li>This payout underscores the critical importance of security in the crypto industry, where the cost of potential breaches can be astronomical compared to traditional finance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-06-17/google-deepmind-shifts-from-research-lab-to-ai-product-factory">Google DeepMind shifts from research lab to AI product factory</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40711600">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google DeepMind is shifting from a research lab to an AI product factory, raising debates about the challenges and potential pitfalls of this transition.</li>
<li>Critics suggest that integrating experienced product teams from Google with DeepMind&#39;s research might be more effective than converting the research organization into a product-focused entity.</li>
<li>Concerns include the impact on fundamental research and the risk of producing rushed, underdeveloped products, though some believe this shift could lead to significant advancements in AI products.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/structured-output-from-llms">Every Way to Get Structured Output from LLMs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post addresses the challenge of obtaining structured output, such as JSON, from Large Language Models (LLMs), which typically return responses in natural language.</li>
<li>It provides a detailed comparison of various frameworks designed to convert LLM outputs into structured formats, evaluating them based on criteria like language support, JSON handling, prompt control, and supported model providers.</li>
<li>The frameworks compared include BAML, Instructor, TypeChat, Marvin, Outlines, Guidance, LMQL, JSONformer, Firebase Genkit, SGLang, and lm-format-enforcer, each with unique features and capabilities for handling structured data extraction.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40713952">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>BAML&#39;s article explores methods for obtaining structured output from Large Language Models (LLMs), emphasizing BAML&#39;s unique parsing approach for handling malformed JSON.</li>
<li>BAML offers both open-source and paid features, with paid options focusing on monitoring and enhancing AI pipelines.</li>
<li>The article compares various frameworks and discusses the challenges and trade-offs in enforcing structured output, noting some users prefer simpler methods like Pydantic for JSON validation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://olano.dev/blog/a-note-on-essential-complexity">A Note on Essential Complexity</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Software engineers have multiple overlapping and sometimes conflicting goals, such as writing code, managing complexity, and satisfying customer needs.</li>
<li>Essential complexity is inherent to the problem, while accidental complexity arises from performance issues or suboptimal tools; reducing both is crucial.</li>
<li>Senior engineers can redefine problems by challenging assumptions and negotiating with stakeholders, potentially simplifying requirements and minimizing complexity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40711661">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Software engineers sometimes embrace complexity to justify their roles, as seen in communities like Enterprise Java, .NET, and JavaScript (JS).</li>
<li>The article humorously references the Stroustrup C++ satire to highlight intentional complexity in programming languages.</li>
<li>It argues that minimizing complexity is crucial for good engineering, balancing short-term and long-term decisions, and ensuring consistency to avoid unnecessary complications.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Chat Control Must Be Stopped – Now" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Chat%20Control%20Must%20Be%20Stopped%20%E2%80%93%20Now&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20June%2018%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/18</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-18T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-17]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/17&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-17</h1>
<h2><a href="https://axio.ms/projects/2024/06/16/MicroMac.html">MicroMac, a Macintosh for under £5</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A project named Pico-mac uses a Raspberry Pi RP2040 microcontroller to emulate a Macintosh 128K, enabling it to run old Macintosh software.</li>
<li>The RP2040’s 264KB of RAM and 2MB of flash memory are sufficient to house the Mac’s 128KB memory, the emulator, and a disc image with the OS and software.</li>
<li>The project involved building a Mac 128K emulator, creating a circuit for VGA video output, and optimizing performance through overclocking and interpreter enhancements, achieving about 1.4 MIPS.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40699684">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>MicroMac, a Macintosh for under £5, has garnered significant attention, highlighting a low-cost, DIY approach to retro computing.</li>
<li>The project involves using the RP2040 microcontroller to emulate a 68k Macintosh, offering a more authentic experience than simply running an emulator on Linux.</li>
<li>The discussion also touches on the challenges and creative solutions in sourcing old tech components, emphasizing the community&#39;s resourcefulness and interest in retro computing projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2024/06/ftc-takes-action-against-adobe-executives-hiding-fees-preventing-consumers-easily-cancelling">FTC sues Adobe for hiding fees and inhibiting cancellations</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40707558">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The FTC has filed a lawsuit against Adobe for hiding fees and making cancellations difficult, addressing deceptive practices in their subscription model.</li>
<li>Adobe&#39;s shift from pay-once software to a subscription model has led to increased costs and driven users to seek alternatives like Procreate, DaVinci, and Affinity.</li>
<li>The lawsuit seeks to stop Adobe&#39;s aggressive tactics and provide refunds to affected consumers, highlighting broader issues with SaaS (Software as a Service) models.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.simonrumble.com/how-to-get-your-stuff-repaired-when-the-retailer-and-manufacturer-dont-wanna-take-em-to-court">How to get stuff repaired when the manufacturer don&#39;t wanna: take &#39;em to court</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author faced a malfunction with their Electrolux oven and was charged $160 for a diagnosis, despite Australian Consumer Law providing an automatic warranty for a reasonable product lifespan.</li>
<li>After unsuccessful negotiations with both the manufacturer and retailer, the author filed a complaint with the NSW Civil and Administrative Tribunal (NCAT), leading the retailer to cover the repair costs to avoid tribunal expenses.</li>
<li>The author encourages others to assert their consumer rights and not settle for minimal warranty periods, highlighting the importance of legal avenues like NCAT for resolving such disputes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40702782">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>In Australia, the NSW Civil and Administrative Tribunal (NCAT) offers a low-cost and straightforward way to handle consumer claims, often without needing a lawyer.</li>
<li>Similar systems exist in other regions, such as the UK&#39;s small claims courts and the EU&#39;s two-year product warranty mandate.</li>
<li>In the US, small claims court or filing a complaint with the state&#39;s Attorney General&#39;s office can be effective for consumer disputes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.deepsouthventures.com/on-being-laid-off-unplanned-entrepreneurship/">Being laid off and unplanned entrepreneurship</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Peter Askew&#39;s journey into entrepreneurship began after multiple layoffs, pushing him to find alternative revenue streams.</li>
<li>Leveraging his background in web analytics and paid search, he initially succeeded by using ad networks on high-traffic websites, eventually learning coding and acquiring premium domains like DudeRanch.com.</li>
<li>Emphasizing independence, Peter funds his projects solo, avoiding external control, and finds contentment in his self-driven entrepreneurial path.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40704428">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author started a new business after a failed startup, focusing on prototyping independently, implementing lean principles, and generating revenue from the start.</li>
<li>Despite not being an engineer, the author successfully built and marketed the product, leading to a sustainable business that funds their children&#39;s education.</li>
<li>The author highlights the U.S. healthcare system as a significant barrier to entrepreneurship, suggesting that universal healthcare could promote small business growth.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://numpy.org/devdocs/release/2.0.0-notes.html">NumPy 2.0</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NumPy 2.0.0 is the first major release since 2006, developed over 11 months by 212 contributors, featuring significant new features, performance improvements, and breaking changes to both Python and C APIs.</li>
<li>Key updates include a new variable-length string dtype, accelerated sorting functions, and a clear split between public and private APIs, along with new public C APIs for creating custom dtypes.</li>
<li>Users should be aware of breaking changes and backwards compatibility issues, with migration guides provided to assist in updating code.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40699470">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>NumPy 2.0 has been released, introducing significant changes, including deprecations of certain public APIs and new support for string routines.</li>
<li>The release aims to address historical weaknesses in string operations within NumPy, potentially benefiting NLP (Natural Language Processing) and LLM (Large Language Model) use cases.</li>
<li>Compatibility with NumPy 1.x is mostly maintained, except for the &quot;byte_bounds&quot; function, and users are advised to pin dependencies to avoid issues during the transition.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bouba/kiki_effect">Bouba/kiki effect</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Bouba/Kiki effect is a mental association where &quot;bouba&quot; is linked to rounded shapes and &quot;kiki&quot; to spiky shapes, observed globally.</li>
<li>This phenomenon, first noted in the 1920s, is evident in infants and young children, indicating its potential role in language learning.</li>
<li>fMRI studies show brain activation patterns related to this sound-shape matching, offering insights into language evolution and sound symbolism, though the effect can vary by culture and language.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40699583">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Reggio Emilia teaching methods, similar to Montessori, emphasize cross-modal forms of expression, such as translating auditory experiences into visual ones.</li>
<li>The Bouba-Kiki effect, where children naturally bridge sensory modalities, is highlighted, noting that this ability often diminishes in adults.</li>
<li>The discussion includes whether this diminishment is due to inhibition or brain development, and how language and cultural factors influence perception and naming conventions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://duckrabbit.tech/articles/learning-haskell.html">I learned Haskell in just 15 years</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40702146">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post humorously discusses the long learning curve of Haskell, a functional programming language, while emphasizing the benefits of functional programming.</li>
<li>It highlights that functional programming, though challenging, offers valuable lessons in software design that can be applied to other programming paradigms.</li>
<li>The discussion suggests F# as a more approachable alternative for beginners, as it supports both functional and object-oriented programming, easing the learning curve.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://howtoware.co/wyldcard">Trading cards with e-ink displays (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Wyldcards are plastic E-Ink trading cards that feature changeable images and memory chips to store game stats, offering new game mechanics while maintaining a physical feel.</li>
<li>The project was inspired by fictional games like Yu-Gi-Oh and Card Captors, and the creator&#39;s background in software development and IoT 3D printing facilitated its development.</li>
<li>After a viral post on Hacker News, a crowdfunding campaign on CrowdSupply raised $7277, leading to the production of 25 DevKits and plans for future game development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40705222">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Trading cards with e-ink displays are being developed, offering a new twist on traditional card games by allowing dynamic content and data storage.</li>
<li>The creator, Jonahss, mentions that these cards can store game data, making each card unique based on its usage, akin to a legacy-style game rather than a traditional trading card game.</li>
<li>The project is still in its early stages, with the focus currently on delivering crowdfunded development kits and exploring potential game designs and applications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dronedj.com/2024/06/14/dji-ban-passes-the-house-and-moves-on-to-the-senate/">DJI ban passes the House and moves on to the Senate</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. House of Representatives has passed a ban on DJI, a leading drone manufacturer, and the bill is now moving to the Senate for consideration.</li>
<li>This legislative action could significantly impact the drone industry, given DJI&#39;s prominent market position.</li>
<li>The ban is part of broader concerns over national security and data privacy related to Chinese technology companies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40705196">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The US House has passed a ban on DJI drones, now awaiting Senate approval, igniting debates on data privacy and the use of Chinese products in the US.</li>
<li>Critics argue that Congress should also scrutinize non-Chinese products, while some users distrust DJI over privacy and app issues, despite its superior technology.</li>
<li>The ban is viewed as protectionism, potentially benefiting US companies like Skydio, and has significant implications for sectors like law enforcement and public safety that rely on DJI drones.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.starlinkhardware.com/first-look-at-the-upcoming-starlink-mini/">First look at the upcoming Starlink Mini</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Starlink has received FCC approval for the new Starlink Mini dish&#39;s Wifi router, indicating an imminent launch.</li>
<li>The Starlink Mini, designed for portability, is ideal for camping, RVs, and hiking, featuring a built-in Wifi router and mesh compatibility for extended coverage.</li>
<li>The updated Starlink app now includes details about the Mini, a new shop page, and developer mode pages, suggesting the launch is just weeks away.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40699504">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The upcoming Starlink Mini is significantly smaller than the current Starlink Standard, with dimensions of 29cm x 25cm compared to 59.5cm x 38cm.</li>
<li>Discussions highlight the potential for the Starlink Mini to be more portable and viable for activities like backpacking, especially if features like the heating element can be disabled to save power.</li>
<li>The Starlink Mini could serve as a more practical backup internet solution in rural areas, with flexible subscription options allowing users to activate service only when needed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/17/24180196/adobe-us-ftc-doj-sues-subscriptions-cancel">US sues Adobe for &#39;deceiving&#39; subscriptions that are too hard to cancel</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The US government is suing Adobe for allegedly concealing fees and complicating the subscription cancellation process.</li>
<li>The Department of Justice claims Adobe enrolled consumers in high-cost plans without clear disclosure of terms, including early termination fees, and made the cancellation process cumbersome.</li>
<li>The lawsuit targets Adobe executives Maninder Sawhney and David Wadhwani, and follows Adobe&#39;s shift to a subscription model in 2012 and recent backlash over its AI training terms.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40707037">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The US government is suing Adobe, alleging that the company made it difficult for customers to cancel subscriptions.</li>
<li>The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) claims Adobe used hidden fees to trap customers, prompting legal action.</li>
<li>Comparisons are being made to Apple&#39;s more straightforward subscription cancellation process, highlighting the issue&#39;s significance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ounapuu.ee/posts/2024/06/05/usb-c-cables/">They make USB-C cables with displays now</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>USB-C cables with built-in displays are now available, showing power consumption to help monitor charging speeds.</li>
<li>These cables support USB 4, which may make them slightly stiff, but they work well with high-resolution displays and docks.</li>
<li>Users should be cautious of potential hidden malicious chips in these cables.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40701310">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>USB-C cables with displays are now available, allowing users to see power consumption directly on the cable.</li>
<li>Comparatively, the O.MG Cable, known for its advanced security testing capabilities, has been in the market for some time.</li>
<li>Discussions highlight concerns about potential malicious chips in such cables and experiences with issues like smoking and device damage, emphasizing the importance of reliable cables and trusted brands like Anker.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://allthatsinteresting.com/marion-stokes">Marion Stokes, the Woman Who Spent over 30 Years Recording Every Minute of US TV</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Marion Stokes, a former librarian and civil rights activist, recorded television broadcasts 24/7 from 1979 to 2012, amassing 71,000 tapes to preserve historical news details.</li>
<li>After her death, the Internet Archive began digitizing her extensive collection in 2013, ensuring the preservation of this unique media archive.</li>
<li>Stokes&#39; efforts, highlighted in the 2019 documentary &quot;Recorder: The Marion Stokes Project,&quot; underscore the importance of media preservation in the digital age.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40702546">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Marion Stokes recorded over 30 years of US TV, creating a significant archive that includes ads and local news often lost to time.</li>
<li>The Internet Archive is currently processing her collection, highlighting the archival value of old VHS tapes.</li>
<li>Discussions on Hacker News touched on the practicality of using apartments for storage and compared Stokes&#39; efforts to other archives like the Museum of Broadcast Communications and the Paley Center for Media.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/frectonz/sqlite-studio">SQLite Database Explorer</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40700343">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SQLite Database Explorer, a CLI tool that starts a local web server, received significant attention and praise for its clean UI built with shadcn/ui.</li>
<li>Users suggested improvements such as adding screenshots to the README and making comparisons to other tools like DB Browser for SQLite.</li>
<li>There were concerns about potential trademark issues with the name &quot;SQLite Studio,&quot; prompting the creator to plan a rename, and some users reported false positives from Windows Defender.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://cohost.org/bekoha/post/2859948-quake-1-potential-or">Quake 1 potential original font</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Quake 1 font appears to be derived from an older font named &quot;Visa,&quot; designed by Raphael Boguslav in 1966.</li>
<li>&quot;Visa&quot; was featured in Dan X. Solo&#39;s &quot;The Solotype Catalog of 4,147 Display Typefaces&quot; (1992) and &quot;Stencil Alphabets: 100 Complete Fonts&quot; (1988).</li>
<li>The discovery highlights the historical roots of the Quake font, linking it to a prize-winning design from the 1966 VGC National Type Face Design Competition.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40699459">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate on cohost.org centers around whether Quake 1&#39;s font is hand-crafted or derived from existing fonts, with significant differences noted in specific letters.</li>
<li>Some users speculate the font might be inspired by stencil designs or new typefaces like Democratica, while others suggest consulting original designers for clarity.</li>
<li>The discussion also explores the evolution of fonts and the creative processes involved, with some skepticism about the font&#39;s usage permissions.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="MicroMac, a Macintosh for under £5" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=MicroMac%2C%20a%20Macintosh%20for%20under%20%C2%A35&subheading=Monday%2C%20June%2017%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/17</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-17T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-16]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/16&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-16</h1>
<h2><a href="https://docs.murexrobotics.com/elec/boards/networking/switch">We Made The World&#39;s Smallest and Cheapest Network Switch</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>MUREX Robotics, a high school team from Exeter, NH, has released an open-source technology available for $6.9 from JLCPCB.</li>
<li>They are selling a limited run of under 25 units for $10 plus shipping, with board files accessible on GitHub.</li>
<li>For inquiries, contact Byran at <a href="mailto:byran@mrx.ee">byran@mrx.ee</a> or Max at <a href="mailto:max@mrx.ee">max@mrx.ee</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40694254">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>MUREX Robotics, a high school team from Exeter, NH, has developed the world&#39;s smallest and cheapest network switch, priced at $6.9.</li>
<li>The switch is open-source and designed to be cost-effective and accessible, targeting applications where size and cost are critical.</li>
<li>The team plans to sell a small batch of these boards soon, emphasizing their mission to democratize technology through open-source electronics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.sofiane.cc/ssh_honeypot/">What You Get After Running an SSH Honeypot for 30 Days</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40694768">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A user running an SSH honeypot for 30 days noted significant illegitimate traffic, primarily from &quot;internet security companies&quot; scanning the IPv4 space.</li>
<li>Blocking these networks reduced unwanted traffic by over 50%, but the discussion underscores the limitations of IP blocking due to CGNAT (Carrier-Grade Network Address Translation).</li>
<li>Emphasis is placed on using security tools like fail2ban, VPNs, and public key authentication to protect servers, with users sharing experiences of self-hosting and the challenges of constant attacks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.jorgegalindo.me/en/blog/posts/do-not-be-the-smartest-in-the-room-try-to-be-the-kindest">Do not try to be the smartest in the room; try to be the kindest</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40695997">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Emphasizing kindness over intelligence can improve team dynamics and productivity through listening, respect, empathy, and problem-solving.</li>
<li>Kindness creates a lasting impact and fosters a positive work environment, which is crucial for long-term success.</li>
<li>While intelligence is important, the benefits of kindness in a professional setting should not be underestimated.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nlrbedge.com/p/in-first-case-of-its-kind-nlrb-judge">NLRB judge declares non-compete clause is an unfair labor practice</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NLRB Judge Sarah Karpinen ruled that non-compete and coworker non-solicitation clauses are unfair labor practices, marking a landmark decision.</li>
<li>The case involved J.O. Mory, Inc., where a union organizer was fired for &quot;salting&quot; (organizing coworkers), and the judge ordered the organizer&#39;s reinstatement with backpay.</li>
<li>This is the first time an Administrative Law Judge (ALJ) has ruled these clauses as unfair labor practices, emphasizing the NLRB&#39;s stance against such clauses for non-supervisory workers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40696992">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An NLRB judge has ruled that non-compete clauses are an unfair labor practice, igniting discussions on other restrictive employment practices.</li>
<li>The ruling has led to debates on non-solicitation clauses and company policies that restrict managers from giving references, which some argue hinder job mobility.</li>
<li>This decision is part of a larger conversation about balancing power between employers and employees, with calls for increased worker protections to ensure fair treatment and job market mobility.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/google-cloudflare-cisco-will-poison-dns-to-stop-piracy-block-circumvention-240613/">French court orders Google, Cloudflare, Cisco to poison DNS to stop piracy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A French court has mandated Google, Cloudflare, and Cisco to block access to approximately 117 pirate sports streaming domains via their DNS resolvers, intensifying anti-piracy efforts for broadcaster Canal+.</li>
<li>Canal+ has also been granted permission to remove these sites from search results, leveraging existing site-blocking laws in France to combat piracy.</li>
<li>Despite arguments about the minimal impact on piracy rates, the court upheld Canal+&#39;s rights, and Google has confirmed it will comply with the order, raising questions about future anti-piracy strategies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40693451">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A French court has mandated Google, Cloudflare, and Cisco to alter their DNS resolvers to block access to approximately 117 pirate sports streaming domains.</li>
<li>This ruling contrasts with previous resistance from tech companies against similar U.S. legislation, highlighting a shift in their stance to maintain control and avoid legal issues.</li>
<li>Critics propose using personal DNS resolvers to circumvent these blocks, sparking ongoing debates about the balance between anti-piracy measures and internet freedom.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://louwrentius.com/the-raspberry-pi-5-is-no-match-for-a-tini-mini-micro-pc.html">The Raspberry Pi 5 Is No Match for a Tini-Mini-Micro PC</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Raspberry Pi 5, released in fall 2023, offers improved performance but is still limited by SD card storage and higher costs compared to previous models.</li>
<li>Second-hand 1L mini PCs from brands like Dell, Lenovo, and HP outperform the Pi 5 in terms of processing power, RAM capacity, and storage options (SATA and NVME SSDs).</li>
<li>While the Raspberry Pi 5 is energy-efficient, second-hand mini PCs are better suited for home server applications due to their superior performance and built-in SSD/NVME support.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40697831">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Raspberry Pi 5 has lost its affordability due to the end of a special deal with Broadcom, making it less competitive in the current market.</li>
<li>Users are finding better value in second-hand mini PCs, which offer more power and features for a similar price.</li>
<li>While the Pi 5 remains strong in educational and GPIO (General-Purpose Input/Output) applications, alternatives like used Intel NUCs or new N100 mini PCs are more attractive for general computing tasks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://micropolisweb.com/">SimCity in the web browser using WebAssembly and OpenGL</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Micropolis in WebAssembly is a port of the original SimCity Classic by Maxis, designed by Will Wright and ported by Don Hopkins.</li>
<li>The project is evolving, with ongoing development supported on Patreon and available on GitHub.</li>
<li>Users can interact with the game using various controls, such as mouse and keyboard shortcuts, with more features and easter eggs promised in future updates.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40693944">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SimCity has been ported to the web browser using WebAssembly and OpenGL, making it accessible without needing to install software.</li>
<li>This project is based on the original SimCity Classic code and aims to bring the game to modern platforms with improved performance and accessibility.</li>
<li>The port is still a work in progress, with ongoing efforts to enhance the user interface, add mobile support, and optimize performance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://anthonynsimon.com/blog/one-man-saas-architecture/">The Architecture Behind a One-Person Tech Startup (2021)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post outlines the infrastructure setup for running a one-person SaaS (Software as a Service) using Kubernetes on AWS, highlighting its low-stress, self-funded nature.</li>
<li>Key components include traffic management with Cloudflare and AWS, deployment automation via GitHub Actions and Flux, and reliability through Kubernetes&#39; autoscaling and liveliness probes.</li>
<li>Additional features cover caching with Redis, rate-limiting with Django Ratelimit, scheduled tasks with Celery, and monitoring with New Relic and Sentry, providing a comprehensive overview of managing a solo tech startup.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40694103">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The best tech stack for a startup is one that the team is already familiar with, as learning new technologies can add unnecessary complexity.</li>
<li>Prioritize quick deployment and consider refactoring later; users care more about a functional product than the underlying technology.</li>
<li>While some new technologies like Kubernetes might be overkill, simpler solutions such as Docker Swarm or managed services can be more appropriate for balancing simplicity and scalability.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://erikbern.com/2023/12/13/simple-sabotage-for-software.html">Simple sabotage for software (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The CIA&#39;s &quot;Simple Sabotage&quot; book from World War 2 provides timeless advice on disrupting productivity, now humorously adapted for modern tech environments.</li>
<li>Suggested sabotage techniques for a CTO include requiring lengthy rewrites, encouraging diverse languages, and splitting systems to increase complexity.</li>
<li>Other methods include dismissing useful metrics, linking compensation to title and team size, and creating a subjective hiring process, all aimed at subtly slowing down productivity through plausible actions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40695839">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A discussion on simple sabotage in software, referencing a 2023 article by Erik Bernhardsson, questions the effectiveness of original CIA sabotage tactics.</li>
<li>Commenters debate the practicality and impact of these strategies, noting that bad management and misguided profit optimization can naturally cripple organizations.</li>
<li>The conversation includes historical context, the role of incompetence, and modern practices like complex self-service systems and mandatory return-to-office policies that may inadvertently align with sabotage principles.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://european-alternatives.eu">European Alternatives</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post highlights European alternatives for various digital services and products, emphasizing support for local businesses and adherence to GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation).</li>
<li>It lists categories of services with the number of alternatives available, such as web analytics, cloud computing, and email providers, among others.</li>
<li>The post underscores the benefits of choosing European providers, including VAT refunds, common European payment methods, and easier enforcement of rights within the EU due to unified laws.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40695754">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>European Alternatives lists products and services from companies based in EU, EEA, EFTA, or DCFTA member countries, excluding non-EU/EFTA sub-hosting providers.</li>
<li>The site covers categories such as identity and access management, VPS providers, and search engines, with discussions on post-Brexit UK exclusion and EU regulation compliance.</li>
<li>Users also debate the quality of services like Hetzner and Tuta, and the geopolitical implications of data privacy and competition in the European tech landscape.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/9780262547482/building-simcity/">Building SimCity: How to put the world in a machine</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Building SimCity&quot; by Chaim Gingold explores the history and development of the influential simulation game SimCity, created by Will Wright.</li>
<li>The book covers the impact of SimCity on computer simulation and the history of Maxis, the company behind the game, with visual materials like diagrams and photographs.</li>
<li>Published by The MIT Press, it will be available in both paperback and eBook formats starting June 2024.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40698442">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Chaim Gingold, author and designer on Spore, is available for a Q&amp;A session, with Will Wright interviewing him on July 19th at 2 PM ET on Twitch, hosted by ROMchip.</li>
<li>Stewart Brand praised Gingold&#39;s book as one of the best origin stories and accounts of innovation in computing.</li>
<li>Gingold recommends City Skylines, Minecraft, and Tiny Glade as modern successors to SimCity, highlighting the influence of generative AI on game development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://sqlite.org/mostdeployed.html">SQLite is likely used more than all other database engines combined</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>SQLite is the most widely deployed and used database engine, present in billions of devices and applications, including Android, iOS, Mac, Windows 10, major web browsers, and various popular applications.</li>
<li>With over 4 billion smartphones each containing hundreds of SQLite databases, there are likely over one trillion active SQLite databases globally.</li>
<li>SQLite is one of the top five most deployed software modules, potentially the second most widely deployed software library after zlib, and possibly the most widely deployed software component due to its multiple instances per device.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40693500">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SQLite is extensively used, likely more than all other database engines combined, due to its ease of use, reliability, and offline functionality.</li>
<li>Users are transitioning from json+zip to gzipped SQLite for better schema enforcement when downloading data for backups or sharing.</li>
<li>Despite its popularity, SQLite is not open for contributions, but its file format is well-documented and stable, making it ideal for many applications, including iOS and Android.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://fs.blog/experts-vs-imitators/">Experts vs. Imitators</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40699079">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion contrasts experts with imitators, emphasizing that true expertise involves deep understanding and effective communication.</li>
<li>Experts argue that the ability to explain complex topics in simple terms is crucial, highlighting the importance of good communication skills alongside technical knowledge.</li>
<li>The conversation touches on the challenges experts face in conveying intricate concepts to laymen, using examples like programming languages Rust and Python to illustrate these difficulties.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://popovicu.com/posts/making-my-first-embedded-linux-system/">Making my first embedded Linux system</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post details the author&#39;s journey of building a Linux system from scratch, starting with no prior PCB (Printed Circuit Board) experience.</li>
<li>Key steps include programming microcontrollers like the Atmel ATtiny, designing a custom PCB, and creating an embedded Linux board using the F1C100s SoC (System on Chip).</li>
<li>The project involved using tools like avrdude for programming, a 4-layer PCB for complex routing, and adapting a Lichee Pi software image for the custom board.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40695165">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A user shared their experience creating their first embedded Linux system, sparking a discussion on technical details and improvements.</li>
<li>Key points include the use of a 16 Mbit flash, differential routing, and the potential benefits of adding an SD card connector.</li>
<li>The project utilized the Allwinner F1C100S, a 533MHz single-core ARMv7 with 32MB of onboard DRAM, prompting comparisons with other similar processors.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ooh.directory/">A collection of 2,299 blogs about every topic</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40693787">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new collection of 2,299 blogs on various topics has been launched on ooh.directory, reminiscent of early web directories like Yahoo&#39;s categorized link directory.</li>
<li>Users appreciate the curated nature of the directory, which improves discoverability compared to ad-filled search engines.</li>
<li>The directory is seen as a valuable resource for finding new blogs and interviewees, especially in an era where AI-generated content is prevalent.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="We Made The World's Smallest and Cheapest Network Switch" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=We%20Made%20The%20World's%20Smallest%20and%20Cheapest%20Network%20Switch&subheading=Sunday%2C%20June%2016%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/16</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-16T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-15]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/15&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-15</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.space.com/voyager-1-fully-operational">Voyager 1 is back online! NASA spacecraft returns data from all 4 instruments</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NASA&#39;s Voyager 1 spacecraft, after experiencing technical issues since November 2023, is now fully operational with all four science instruments returning usable data.</li>
<li>The issue was traced to a chip in the flight data subsystem and resolved by relocating the code, showcasing the resilience of the 46-year-old spacecraft.</li>
<li>Despite being 15 billion miles from Earth, Voyager 1 continues to provide valuable data from interstellar space, with efforts ongoing to maintain its functionality and extend its mission.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40687660">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Voyager 1 is back online and transmitting data from all four instruments, serving as a tribute to Ed Stone, a core project scientist for Voyager who recently passed away.</li>
<li>Discussions are sparked about generation ships and the potential for faster future spacecraft to reach destinations first, with concepts like time dilation and relativistic travel being explored.</li>
<li>Breakthrough Starshot proposes laser sail acceleration of gram-scale probes, which could potentially overtake Voyager 1 within a decade, highlighting advancements in space travel technology.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://rknight.me/blog/perplexity-ai-is-lying-about-its-user-agent/">Perplexity AI Is Lying about Their User Agent</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author discusses challenges in blocking AI bots, specifically Perplexity, on their server and MacStories, despite implementing blocks.</li>
<li>Perplexity AI appears to bypass robots.txt restrictions and does not use the correct user agent string, making it difficult to block their access.</li>
<li>The author is exploring further actions, including joining Perplexity&#39;s Discord for more information, filing a bug report, and considering a GDPR request.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40690898">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text discusses Perplexity AI&#39;s use of data, focusing on user control over data usage for AI training and the ethical implications of querying websites to present data in a user-requested format.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about the negative impact of aggregator services like Perplexity on content creators, as these services can decrease direct traffic to original content sources, leading to potential loss of insights and revenue.</li>
<li>The text also touches on broader issues of copyright, legality, and ethics in AI training and data scraping, comparing practices to historical cases and discussing the potential need for new regulations and analytics features.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://thenumb.at/Exponential-Rotations/">Exponentially Better Rotations (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>3D programming involves various techniques for 3D rotations, including rotation matrices, Euler angles, and quaternions, each with its own advantages and limitations.</li>
<li>Euler angles can cause issues like gimbal lock and inconsistent angular velocity, making them less suitable for interpolation in applications like robotics.</li>
<li>Quaternions and axis/angle rotations are highlighted as more effective for composing and interpolating rotations, with quaternions offering a robust method for 3D point rotations and easy computation of the exponential map.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40684901">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text explains the Lie group/Lie algebra correspondence, a mathematical concept useful for 3D rotations, allowing for smooth transitions and compositions using exponential and logarithmic maps.</li>
<li>Quaternions are highlighted for their efficiency in computer graphics, particularly in animation, due to their compact representation and computational advantages over 3x3 matrices.</li>
<li>The discussion includes the use of Kalman filters for estimating rotations, the complexities of averaging rotations, and the application of various metrics in fields like robotics and video game development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tomverbeure.github.io/2024/05/20/Tesla-FSD-First-and-Last-Impressions.html">Tesla&#39;s FSD – A Useless Technology Demo</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Tesla is offering a free trial of their Full Self-Driving (FSD) system, but users report it still makes significant errors, requiring driver intervention.</li>
<li>In multiple tests, FSD made mistakes such as incorrect lane changes, nervous corrections, and even running a red light, leading to concerns about its reliability.</li>
<li>The author concludes that while FSD shows potential, it currently lacks practical value and prefers the more reliable autopilot features like adaptive cruise control and lane centering.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40688001">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Tesla&#39;s Full Self-Driving (FSD) technology is criticized for being more of a stock price booster than a viable product, with doubts about its technological superiority over competitors.</li>
<li>Reports indicate Tesla&#39;s weak driver engagement system is inappropriate for Autopilot&#39;s capabilities, leading to misuse, crashes, and at least 13 fatal incidents.</li>
<li>The debate includes skepticism about Tesla&#39;s promises, the complexity of achieving full autonomy, and the need for more sensors to improve driving, highlighting the gap between user expectations and actual capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/Snowden/status/1801610725229498403">Snowden: &quot;They&#39;ve gone full mask-off: do not ever trust OpenAI or its products&quot;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Edward Snowden has publicly criticized OpenAI for appointing an NSA Director to their board, suggesting it is a betrayal of global rights.</li>
<li>Snowden&#39;s warning implies concerns about privacy and surveillance with OpenAI&#39;s products, including ChatGPT.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40685644">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Edward Snowden warns against trusting OpenAI, suggesting a rush to bypass intellectual property rights and exploit works without proper attribution or payment.</li>
<li>The text discusses the appointment of board members in companies like OpenAI, questioning the authenticity and potential for rubber-stamping decisions for financial gain.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about AI&#39;s impact on privacy, copyright infringement, and the potential collaboration between OpenAI and the government, leading some users to cancel their accounts and delete their data.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://syzygyfpga.io/">Syzygy: An open standard for low cost, compact and high-performance peripherals</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>SYZYGY is an open standard designed for high-performance peripheral connectivity, offering cost-effective and compact connectors and cables.</li>
<li>It bridges the gap between low-speed Digilent PMOD devices and high-performance VITA 57.1 FMC peripherals, making it ideal for prototypes, system integration, testing, and evaluation systems.</li>
<li>SYZYGY provides two types of connectors: a 40-pin standard peripheral connector and a 60-pin transceiver peripheral connector, both supporting fixed and programmable voltages and single-ended signals.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40686787">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text discusses the potential benefits of integrating hard PCIe (Peripheral Component Interconnect Express) endpoints into MCUs (Microcontroller Units) and MPUs (Microprocessor Units) for high-speed, low-latency communication.</li>
<li>Current limitations include the need for expensive FPGAs (Field-Programmable Gate Arrays) or a limited selection of MCUs/MPUs to utilize PCIe, and the lack of fast data transfer options in RISC-V MCUs.</li>
<li>The text highlights the development of the Syzygy standard by Opal Kelly, which uses innovative methods like analog voltage for peripheral addressing and has seen gradual adoption, though its popularity remains unclear compared to other standards like FMC (FPGA Mezzanine Card).</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/meliharvey/threescaper">Threescaper: A website for loading Townscaper models into Three.js</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40689296">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Threescaper is a website that allows users to load Townscaper models into Three.js, enhancing the interactive 3D experience.</li>
<li>Tiny Glade, an upcoming game written in Rust using Bevy, is noted for its intuitive building UI/UX, with suggestions to incorporate similar concepts into Unreal Editor.</li>
<li>The author discusses an interactive 3D project with features like teleportation and double jumps, and mentions performance issues and nostalgic elements reminiscent of Battlefield Heroes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://chrislakin.blog/p/spaced-repetition-for-teaching-two">Spaced repetition for teaching two-year olds how to read</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A father, known as CoffeePie, used Anki, a spaced repetition tool, to teach his children to read years earlier than average, starting at ages 2 and 1 year 9 months.</li>
<li>By age 5, his daughter was reading in English, Hebrew, and Spanish at a level comparable to a fifth or eighth grader, while his son knew multiplication tables and advanced math concepts.</li>
<li>The father observed that while Anki was effective for early reading and math, it had limitations as his children&#39;s skills advanced, necessitating more complex problem-solving tools.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40685254">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate centers on whether teaching two-year-olds to read is beneficial or potentially harmful, with arguments on both sides regarding social and cognitive impacts.</li>
<li>A developmental researcher argues that child development milestones vary and that pushing children too hard can be counterproductive, emphasizing the importance of following a child&#39;s curiosity and interest.</li>
<li>The text discusses various methods and tools for teaching reading, such as flashcards, interactive curriculums, and spaced repetition, highlighting the need for engaging and age-appropriate content.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://johnthenerd.com/blog/faster-local-llm-assistant/">Making my local LLM voice assistant faster and more scalable with RAG</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author is working on optimizing a local LLM (Large Language Model) voice assistant for smart home control, focusing on reducing latency during the &quot;prefill&quot; phase of inference.</li>
<li>They implemented a RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation) method to split large prompts into smaller sections, which helps in reducing context length and improving speed.</li>
<li>The author created a RAG API, added features like weather forecasts and calendar events, and updated their system to use this new API, aiming to make the voice assistant more efficient and responsive.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40686396">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users discuss precomputing embeddings for common services to enhance the speed of LLM (Large Language Model) voice assistants, with some suggesting recommendation algorithms as a viable solution.</li>
<li>There is a debate about the model <code>casperhansen/llama-3-70b-instruct-awq</code>, its basis on Llama 2, and its performance, with some users finding the lag between query and response problematic.</li>
<li>Opinions vary on whether AI should mimic human behavior or simply perform tasks, with some users amused by the model&#39;s sarcastic tone and others finding the introduction inhuman.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.pecar.me/sqlite-django-config">Django SQLite Production Config</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The default SQLite configuration in Django is not suitable for production due to its low-concurrency optimization, which contrasts with Django&#39;s needs.</li>
<li>For Django versions 5.0, 4.2, or older, enabling WAL (Write-Ahead Logging) journal mode can improve concurrency by preventing write requests from blocking reads.</li>
<li>Django 5.1, expected in August 2024, will allow these SQLite optimizations to be configured directly in settings.py, simplifying the process for developers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40688336">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Django SQLite Production Config has a significant issue with SQLite in WAL (Write-Ahead Logging) mode, where the WAL file can grow excessively under high load, potentially causing system failure.</li>
<li>A workaround involves running a separate thread to monitor the WAL size and slow down reads and writes if it exceeds 8 MB, but this suggests SQLite in WAL mode may not be suitable for production environments.</li>
<li>PostgreSQL is recommended for most small to medium projects due to its better handling of high-volume transactions and fewer limitations compared to SQLite.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Voyager 1 is back online! NASA spacecraft returns data from all 4 instruments" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Voyager%201%20is%20back%20online!%20NASA%20spacecraft%20returns%20data%20from%20all%204%20instruments&subheading=Saturday%2C%20June%2015%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/15</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-15T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-14]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/14&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-14</h1>
<h2><a href="https://progressandpoverty.substack.com/p/land-value-tax-in-online-games-and">Land value tax in online games and virtual worlds (2022)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40676408">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text discusses the pros and cons of implementing a Land Value Tax (LVT) in online games and virtual worlds, suggesting it could lower land values but also benefit landowners if removed.</li>
<li>It highlights the potential for LVT to shift taxes from land to labor, enterprise, and commerce, while warning of resistance from wealthy landowners and the difficulty of maintaining LVT progress.</li>
<li>The text also touches on the broader implications of LVT, including its potential to replace all other taxes, the feasibility of such a system, and the importance of public awareness and strong policies to support its implementation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/us-saudi-petrodollar-pact-ends-after-50-years">U.S.-Saudi petrodollar pact ends after 50 years</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40673567">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The U.S.-Saudi petrodollar pact has ended after 50 years, but immediate changes in the oil business are not expected.</li>
<li>The end of the pact may lead to a gradual shift towards de-dollarization, but this process will take time.</li>
<li>The U.S. remains the world&#39;s largest energy producer, which could impact the geopolitical landscape and the relevance of the petrodollar.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://martincmartin.com/2024/06/14/how-i-found-a-55-year-old-bug-in-the-first-lunar-lander-game/">I found a 55 year old bug in the first Lunar Lander game</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 1969, high school student Jim Storer created the first Lunar Landing game, which involved piloting a moon lander and managing fuel burn every 10 simulated seconds.</li>
<li>A bug in the game, unnoticed for 55 years, involved a missing &quot;divide by two&quot; that caused incorrect landing detection; fixing this improves landing accuracy.</li>
<li>The game used advanced numerical methods for its time, such as the Tsiolkovsky rocket equation and Taylor series expansion, making it a notable achievement in early game design.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40680218">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A 55-year-old bug was discovered in the first Lunar Lander game, originally written by Jim Storer in high school during the 1960s.</li>
<li>The game, written in the FOCAL programming language, required an impressive understanding of physics and numerical techniques, especially for a high school student at that time.</li>
<li>The discovery highlights the historical significance and technical challenges of early computer games, as well as the evolution of coding practices and quality assurance over the decades.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nioz.nl/en/news/fungus-breaks-down-ocean-plastic">Fungus breaks down ocean plastic</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers from NIOZ and other institutions have discovered that the marine fungus Parengyodontium album can break down polyethylene plastic when exposed to UV sunlight.</li>
<li>The fungus degrades polyethylene at a rate of about 0.05% per day, converting it into carbon dioxide, but only for plastic floating near the ocean&#39;s surface.</li>
<li>This discovery, published in the journal Science of the Total Environment, highlights the potential for biological solutions to address plastic pollution, especially as plastic production is expected to triple by 2060.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40676239">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A fungus (Parengyodontium album) has been isolated and sequenced for its ability to break down ocean plastic, raising concerns about its ecological impact if it proliferates.</li>
<li>The potential health risks of microplastics and natural biopolymers accumulating in the body are discussed, with comparisons to the harmful effects of asbestos fibers.</li>
<li>The conversation includes speculative ideas about enhancing macrophages to break down microplastics and using fungi that can coexist with human cells, though these require further research.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://fortune.com/europe/2024/06/11/ikeas-boss-solved-swedish-retailers-global-unhappy-worker-crisis-raising-salaries-introducing-flexible-working-subsidized-childcare/">IKEA&#39;s retailer&#39;s solved global &#39;unhappy worker&#39; crisis by raising salaries</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ikea addressed high employee turnover by raising wages, offering flexible work schedules, and subsidizing childcare, significantly reducing voluntary turnover rates globally.</li>
<li>CEO Jon Abrahamsson Ring implemented strategies to improve frontline employee conditions and streamline operations with technology, leading to a drop in the global quit rate from 22.4% in August 2022 to 17.5% in April 2023.</li>
<li>Despite improvements, Ikea continues to face challenges, including mental health support, managing a global workforce, and accusations of suppressing union efforts, particularly in the US.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40674135">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>IKEA has addressed its global &#39;unhappy worker&#39; crisis by increasing wages, introducing flexible work hours, and subsidizing childcare, highlighting that worker satisfaction involves more than just higher pay.</li>
<li>The discussion includes the pros and cons of company benefits versus direct monetary compensation, with some arguing that benefits can be more cost-effective and contribute to a better work environment.</li>
<li>The text also touches on broader societal implications, such as the impact of dual-income households on real estate prices and the importance of child-rearing, suggesting that professional childcare can benefit children, parents, and society.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/NVIDIA/warp">Nvidia Warp: A Python framework for high performance GPU simulation and graphics</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NVIDIA Warp is a Python framework designed for high-performance simulation and graphics code, compiling Python functions into efficient kernel code for CPU or GPU.</li>
<li>It supports spatial computing, physics simulation, perception, robotics, and geometry processing, and integrates with machine-learning pipelines using PyTorch and JAX.</li>
<li>Installation is via PyPI, with additional dependencies available, and it requires a CUDA-capable NVIDIA GPU for GPU support. The framework is compatible with x86-64 and ARMv8 CPUs on Windows, Linux, and macOS.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40680737">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia Warp is a new Python framework designed for high-performance GPU simulation and graphics, adding to the growing list of Python-to-GPU code projects like Taichi Lang and Numba.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the proprietary nature of Nvidia&#39;s open-source software, with concerns about restrictive licensing that prohibits using the software to develop competing products.</li>
<li>Users express mixed experiences with Taichi, noting its ease of use and support for data classes, but also mentioning bugs and development issues, leading some to consider switching to Nvidia Warp.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tidyfirst.substack.com/p/start-presentations-on-the-second">Start presentations on the second slide</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40680648">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text emphasizes the importance of storytelling in presentations, suggesting that they should provoke thought and engage the audience from the start.</li>
<li>It highlights the difference between oral presentations and slide decks in large corporations, noting that the latter are often text-heavy and self-explanatory for senior management.</li>
<li>The text advises using a narrative structure in technical presentations, starting with a problem, building tension, and then providing a resolution, to make the content more engaging and memorable.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.interconnects.ai/p/apple-intelligence">A look at Apple&#39;s technical approach to AI including core model performance etc.</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple has introduced a multi-model AI system called Apple Intelligence, integrating AI into various aspects of digital life to enhance user engagement.</li>
<li>Unlike competitors focusing on AI superiority, Apple emphasizes practical applications, planning to launch new AI features across all devices this fall.</li>
<li>Apple&#39;s AI strategy includes core model performance, on-device strategy, and alignment strategies, with models comparable to GPT-4 and significant privacy features.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40677810">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s AI technical approach includes using Private Cloud Compute for tasks requiring more computational capacity, ensuring data sent to the cloud is not stored or accessible to Apple.</li>
<li>The system involves partial client-side execution of models, with the main model execution in the cloud, and predicts the use of Local LoRAs (Low-Rank Adaptations) for dynamic machine learning and WebGPU for web-based model unlocking.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights Apple&#39;s vertical integration strength, potential long-term edge device AI race, and the impact of AI on iPhone sales, contrasting with Nvidia&#39;s market position and hardware sales strategy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/article/2024/jun/13/kids-no-iphone-screen-time">Taking away iPhone made daughter a better person</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author banned their daughter from using her iPhone due to its negative impact on her mental health, academic performance, and behavior.</li>
<li>The daughter was diagnosed with depression and anxiety, with a significant portion of her attention focused on social media and gaining peer approval.</li>
<li>The author highlights the broader issue of phone addiction among children and the need for both individual and systemic changes to manage phone use effectively.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40674073">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the harmful effects of social media and phone addiction, suggesting these are used as avoidance behaviors to escape difficult thoughts and emotions.</li>
<li>It argues that the solution is not to remove these coping mechanisms but to help individuals improve their mental health.</li>
<li>The text also touches on the impact of COVID lockdowns, the shift to Linux due to privacy concerns, and the potential benefits of community-based social media networks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.fr.de/politik/warnungen-milliarden-an-konzerne-gezahlt-betrugsverdacht-beim-klimaschutz-trotz-zr-93122965.html">40 out of 60 German climate greening endavours fraudulent</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The German Federal Environment Ministry is accused of negligently supporting Chinese climate protection projects, with millions of funds from the THG quota.</li>
<li>Significant fraud allegations have emerged against 40 out of 60 climate protection projects in China since August 2023, leading to the discontinuation of funding by the end of 2024.</li>
<li>The German government, alongside France and the Netherlands, is urging the EU Commission to address issues in the THG bonus system, which affects electric vehicle owners&#39; incentives and lacks robust control mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40677926">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Fraud was detected in 40 out of 60 German climate greening projects in China, with altered documents reported by a Chinese company, suggesting potential fraud by multinational oil companies.</li>
<li>German authorities accepted unverifiable claims of CO2 savings due to China&#39;s restrictions on foreign checks, despite warnings from Chinese subsidiaries about the fraud.</li>
<li>The text criticizes the current carbon credit system for being easily exploitable and suggests billing for actual emissions, while acknowledging the need for a gradual transition to avoid economic disruption.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2024/06/07/update-on-the-recall-preview-feature-for-copilot-pcs/">Microsoft&#39;s Recall AI feature is now indefinitely delayed</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>On June 7, 2024, an update was announced for the Recall preview feature on Copilot+ PCs, shifting its availability to the Windows Insider Program (WIP) starting June 18, 2024, based on community feedback to ensure quality and security.</li>
<li>Recall creates a visual timeline of PC activity by taking encrypted snapshots, which are stored locally and can be controlled, paused, or deleted by users; it requires Windows Hello Enhanced Sign-in Security for access.</li>
<li>Copilot+ PCs, launched on May 20, 2024, are advanced Windows PCs with improved performance and AI experiences, featuring enhanced security measures like the Microsoft Pluton security processor and Secured-core PC technology.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40683210">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft&#39;s Recall AI feature is delayed indefinitely due to unspecified security concerns, sparking speculation about strategic motives and potential misuse for surveillance.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about the potential for Recall AI to record and leak sensitive information, such as banking credentials and personal activities, leading to privacy issues.</li>
<li>The delay and concerns echo past criticisms of Microsoft&#39;s anti-consumer practices, with comparisons to the backlash faced during the Xbox One launch and Adobe&#39;s recent EULA update.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.lytix.co/posts/self-hosting-llama-3">Cost of self hosting Llama-3 8B-Instruct</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Self-hosting a Llama-3 8B-Instruct model is significantly more expensive than using ChatGPT, costing around $17 per 1M tokens compared to ChatGPT&#39;s $1 per 1M tokens.</li>
<li>The initial high cost of self-hosting includes hardware expenses and energy costs, making it less economical despite potential long-term savings.</li>
<li>Managing and scaling self-hosted hardware presents additional challenges and assumes unrealistic 100% utilization, making it less practical for most users.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40681784">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Self-hosting hardware can significantly reduce costs compared to using AWS, with a setup involving 4x NVidia Tesla T4s costing around $3,800.</li>
<li>The text discusses the pros and cons of self-hosting, emphasizing the need for a business case to justify it due to potential downtime and maintenance costs.</li>
<li>Groq offers cost-effective pricing for Llama 3 models, and the text suggests using quantized models and alternative services like together.ai for better efficiency.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10555529">POSIX.1-2024 is published</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40679809">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>POSIX.1-2024 has been published and will soon be available on the Open Group website, providing updated standards for shell scripting and other functionalities.</li>
<li>New features in POSIX.1-2024 include sed -E for extended regular expressions, find -print0, xargs -0, read -d for secure file processing, and support for C17, strlcpy, strlcat, and more.</li>
<li>The update emphasizes the importance of writing POSIX-compliant scripts for better compatibility across different systems, such as AIX, Debian, macOS, and various Linux distributions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.lamini.ai/blog/lamini-memory-tuning">Lamini Memory Tuning: 10x Fewer Hallucinations</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Lamini Memory Tuning is a new method to embed facts into Large Language Models (LLMs), significantly improving factual accuracy and reducing hallucinations.</li>
<li>It achieved 95% accuracy for a Fortune 500 customer, compared to 50% with other methods, and reduced hallucinations from 50% to 5%.</li>
<li>The method involves tuning millions of expert adapters with precise facts on top of any open-source LLM, optimizing for zero error on specific facts while maintaining general performance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40675577">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Lamini Memory Tuning is a method that trains numerous fact-based Low-Rank Adaptations (LoRAs) to zero loss and uses Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) to select the appropriate LoRAs for a query.</li>
<li>The method involves an expert router layer to decide which LoRAs to integrate at inference time, but the training process for the router is unclear.</li>
<li>The model combines concepts from Mixture of Experts (MoE) and cross-attention, keeping pre-trained Large Language Model (LLM) weights constant while training on the cross-attention layer to ensure factual accuracy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://yobibyte.github.io/notebooks.html">Notebooks Are McDonalds of Code</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Notebooks can lead to confusion with state and versioning, and promote bad habits like not testing or linting.</li>
<li>They often have different setups and dependencies, which can cause code crashes and frustration.</li>
<li>Notebooks are useful for testing ideas but transferring code to modules can be challenging and time-consuming.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40675397">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Notebooks are primarily for conducting experiments and recording results, not for software development.</li>
<li>Jupyter notebooks are useful for replicating course projects, inline plotting, and caching code chunks, but can be inefficient for large codebases.</li>
<li>Notebooks are beneficial for rapid experimentation, teaching, and documentation, but not ideal for production code due to potential issues with maintainability and interactivity.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Land value tax in online games and virtual worlds (2022)" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Land%20value%20tax%20in%20online%20games%20and%20virtual%20worlds%20(2022)&subheading=Friday%2C%20June%2014%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/14</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-13]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/13&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-13</h1>
<h2><a href="https://english.kyodonews.net/news/2024/06/bc2d7f45d456-japan-enacts-law-to-curb-apple-googles-app-dominance.html#google_vignette">Japan enacts law to promote competition in smartphone app stores</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Japan has enacted a new law aimed at improving child care to address the country&#39;s declining birthrate, effective June 5, 2024.</li>
<li>The legislation is part of broader efforts to create a more supportive environment for families and encourage higher birth rates.</li>
<li>This move highlights Japan&#39;s proactive approach to tackling demographic challenges and ensuring sustainable population growth.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40662176">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Japan has enacted a law to promote competition in smartphone app stores, preventing companies like Apple and Google from blocking the sale of competing apps and services.</li>
<li>The law could require Apple to allow third-party app stores and direct payment methods, raising questions about compliance with Apple&#39;s terms of service.</li>
<li>This legislation aims to challenge the dominance of IT giants and foster a more competitive market, potentially benefiting both consumers and developers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://huggingface.co/blog/mlabonne/abliteration">Uncensor any LLM with abliteration</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces &quot;abliteration,&quot; a technique to uncensor Llama models without retraining by removing their refusal mechanism.</li>
<li>Abliteration identifies and removes the &quot;refusal direction&quot; in the model&#39;s residual stream, allowing it to respond to all prompts.</li>
<li>The technique was applied to the Daredevil-8B model, resulting in the NeuralDaredevil-8B, an uncensored LLM with top performance in the 8B category, though it required further training to recover performance drops.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40665721">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text discusses the user&#39;s experience with a new AI model that provides speculative answers rather than outright refusals, which the user finds refreshing and enjoyable.</li>
<li>The debate centers around the ethics and safety measures of AI models, with arguments for and against censorship, and the potential misuse of uncensored models for harmful activities.</li>
<li>The text highlights the challenges of balancing AI safety with freedom of information, emphasizing the need for ethical guidelines and the potential legal implications of AI-generated content.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://engineering.fb.com/2024/06/12/data-infrastructure/training-large-language-models-at-scale-meta/">How Meta trains large language models at scale</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Meta is focusing on AI research to address the large-scale computation needed for training large language models (LLMs), requiring a rethinking of software, hardware, and network infrastructure.</li>
<li>They adapted existing hardware, including modifying the Grand Teton platform with NVIDIA H100 GPUs, and optimized their data center layout to maximize compute capability while maintaining an air-cooled environment.</li>
<li>Meta built two 24k GPU clusters using RoCE and InfiniBand fabrics to train Llama 3, optimizing network communication and load balancing to ensure high performance and efficient data transfer.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40664339">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta had to adapt its mechanical and thermal designs to remain in an air-cooled environment due to time constraints, leading to a validation cycle for large-scale deployment.</li>
<li>Questions remain about how Meta collects and prepares data for training, particularly concerning Personally Identifiable Information (PII), which is inaccessible by default and requires special access.</li>
<li>The text discusses the competition between tech companies like Google, Microsoft, and Meta in developing their own chips, highlighting the performance and cost-efficiency of Nvidia&#39;s GPUs versus Google&#39;s TPUs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/microsoft-solarwinds-golden-saml-data-breach-russian-hackers">Microsoft Chose Profit over Security, Whistleblower Says</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A whistleblower, Andrew Harris, claims Microsoft ignored warnings about a critical security flaw to avoid losing government business, which was later exploited by Russian hackers in the SolarWinds attack.</li>
<li>Harris, a cybersecurity expert, discovered a vulnerability in Microsoft&#39;s cloud-based program that could allow undetected access to sensitive information, but his warnings were dismissed due to potential financial implications.</li>
<li>Despite Harris&#39;s efforts and subsequent breaches, Microsoft maintained that no product or service was exploited, leading to criticism of the company&#39;s prioritization of profits over customer security.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40667976">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Whistleblower Andrew Harris, a former Microsoft cybersecurity specialist, revealed that Microsoft delayed addressing a serious flaw in Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS) to secure a lucrative government deal, leading to the SolarWinds cyberattack.</li>
<li>ProPublica’s investigation highlights a culture within Microsoft that prioritizes business growth over immediate security concerns, reflecting broader tech industry issues of balancing profit with customer security.</li>
<li>The text discusses the challenges faced by whistleblowers and cybersecurity professionals in advocating for swift action on security issues within profit-driven corporations, emphasizing the need for a cultural shift to prioritize security.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.chromium.org/2024/06/building-faster-smarter-chromebook.html">ChromeOS will soon be developed on large portions of the Android stack</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>On June 12, 2024, Chromium Blog announced that ChromeOS will integrate large portions of the Android stack to expedite the delivery of Google AI features and innovations.</li>
<li>This integration will include components like the Android Linux kernel and Android frameworks, aiming to accelerate AI innovation, simplify engineering, and enhance device compatibility.</li>
<li>Despite these changes, ChromeOS will maintain its security, consistency, and management capabilities, with regular updates and new innovations continuing in the interim.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40661703">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>ChromeOS will soon be developed using large parts of the Android stack, leveraging Android&#39;s architecture to reduce OS fragmentation and improve update consistency.</li>
<li>Chromebooks have longer support lifecycles compared to Android devices, and ChromeOS handles fragmentation better, despite not being suitable for smartphones.</li>
<li>The integration of ChromeOS and Android could lead to a more unified platform, potentially enhancing the desktop experience on mobile devices and addressing current performance issues.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2MYzvQ1v8Ww">Gerald Sussman: Programming is (should be) fun (2022) [video]</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author has extensive experience in programming, starting in 1962, and has worked with various early computers like the IBM 790, 650, and 1620.</li>
<li>The text emphasizes the creative and abstract nature of programming, comparing it to art forms like poetry, architecture, and music, and highlights the importance of understanding and managing complexity.</li>
<li>The author discusses significant concepts in programming and computer science, such as the eval and apply process in Lisp, debugging, and the philosophical aspects of identity and mutation in data structures.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40663704">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Gerald Sussman emphasizes programming as a means of storing and understanding knowledge in fields like math, physics, and biology, highlighting its deeper educational value.</li>
<li>The text underscores the importance of maintaining fun in computer science, as advocated by Alan J. Perlis, and warns against becoming gatekeepers of computing knowledge.</li>
<li>The discussion includes the shift from teaching Lisp to Python in universities, noting that while Python is commercially popular, the primary goal of education should be to develop abstract thinking rather than focus solely on commercially relevant languages.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/3d-printed-rocket">Indian startup 3D prints rocket engine in 72 hours</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Indian startup Agnikul successfully 3D printed a rocket engine in 72 hours, showcasing advancements in rapid manufacturing for space technology.</li>
<li>The team achieved their first successful launch at the Satish Dhawan Space Center, indicating progress towards &quot;on-demand&quot; rocket launches.</li>
<li>This milestone highlights the potential for more flexible and cost-effective space missions in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40668088">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An Indian startup has successfully 3D printed a rocket engine in 72 hours, significantly reducing production time.</li>
<li>The machine used for printing automatically generates a report detailing any deviations, potentially eliminating the need for post-production checks, though some experts dispute this claim.</li>
<li>The development highlights India&#39;s growing tech scene and the potential for 3D printing in complex manufacturing, despite ongoing debates about quality assurance and the necessity of post-production testing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.blog.tensorwave.com/amds-mi300x-outperforms-nvidias-h100-for-llm-inference/">AMD&#39;s MI300X Outperforms Nvidia&#39;s H100 for LLM Inference</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>AMD&#39;s MI300X accelerator outperforms NVIDIA’s H100 SXM in real-world AI workloads, achieving 33% higher throughput in a chat use case.</li>
<li>Despite NVIDIA’s mature software ecosystem, AMD&#39;s MI300X is a strong competitor, offering better performance, cost efficiency, and availability for large-scale cloud inference.</li>
<li>Benchmarks show the MI300X excels in both offline and online inference tasks, making it ideal for scaling AI inference capabilities with higher throughput and faster response times.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40667102">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>AMD&#39;s MI300X outperforms Nvidia&#39;s H100 in LLM (Large Language Model) inference, according to TensorWave, a cloud provider specializing in AI workloads.</li>
<li>The report&#39;s validity is questioned due to AMD&#39;s chip having double the transistors and memory but only performing 33% better, and the AMD setup being significantly cheaper.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights Nvidia&#39;s dominance in AI workloads, their market position, and the potential competition from AMD, emphasizing the importance of microarchitecture design skills and software in driving hardware performance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://avherald.com/h?article=519ce679">Southwest Airlines Boeing 737-8 Max Experienced Dutch Roll</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>On May 25th, 2024, a Southwest Airlines Boeing 737-8 MAX experienced a Dutch Roll mid-flight, leading to substantial structural damage, though the crew landed safely in Oakland, CA.</li>
<li>The FAA classified the event as an accident, and the aircraft was moved to Everett, WA, for further repairs after a temporary fix in Oakland.</li>
<li>Discussions among users highlight technical aspects, potential passenger alarm, and suggestions for Boeing to add a second independent Yaw Damper system for enhanced safety.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40668504">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Southwest Airlines Boeing 737-8 Max experienced a Dutch Roll, a phenomenon involving oscillations due to coupling between roll and yaw dynamic modes.</li>
<li>Dutch Roll incidents have historical precedence, with notable cases involving different aircraft models, including a fatal crash of a Japan Airlines Boeing 747SR in 1985.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights concerns about Boeing&#39;s engineering standards, the impact of management decisions, and the safety of commercial aviation, despite recent issues with the 737 Max.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://engineering.fb.com/2024/06/13/web/mlow-metas-low-bitrate-audio-codec/">MLow: Meta&#39;s low bitrate audio codec</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Meta has developed the Meta Low Bitrate (MLow) codec to improve audio quality for users with slow connections and lower-end devices, offering twice the quality of the Opus codec while using 10% less computational power.</li>
<li>MLow has been launched on Instagram and Messenger calls, with a rollout on WhatsApp, enhancing user engagement and audio quality, especially in low-bitrate conditions.</li>
<li>MLow, a CELP codec, supports SuperWideBand audio and better Forward Error Correction, improving audio quality even in packet loss scenarios, and aims to enhance audio recovery in future updates.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40670612">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta has introduced a new low-bitrate audio codec, which may not be ideal for real-time communications due to high packet rates and overhead but can be beneficial in circuit-switched or VoIP systems using header compression.</li>
<li>The codec is designed to reduce bandwidth consumption while maintaining or improving reliability and perceived audio quality, making it suitable for platforms like Facebook, Instagram, and WhatsApp.</li>
<li>The codec&#39;s performance in real-world applications depends on its ability to handle bit errors and reduced channel capacity, with Forward Error Correction (FEC) playing a crucial role in maintaining call quality.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/arm-says-it-wants-all-snapdragon-x-elite-laptops-destroyed/">Arm says it wants all Snapdragon X Elite laptops destroyed</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Arm is attempting to remove Qualcomm from the Windows market to introduce its own Cortex design, leading to a legal dispute over licensing rights for custom Arm chips.</li>
<li>Rumors suggest Nvidia, MediaTek, and AMD may enter the Windows ecosystem with Arm chips, potentially by CES 2025, with MediaTek possibly using Arm&#39;s Cortex cores.</li>
<li>Arm claims Qualcomm&#39;s use of Nuvia designs violates contractual obligations, seeking to halt shipments and destroy Snapdragon X series chips, though such disputes typically end in financial settlements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40667606">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Arm is demanding the destruction of all Snapdragon X Elite laptops due to a licensing dispute with Qualcomm over the use of Nuvia&#39;s server cores in the Snapdragon X Elite SoC.</li>
<li>The core issue is whether Qualcomm&#39;s acquisition of Nuvia invalidated Nuvia&#39;s specific license with Arm, which was originally for server/datacenter usage only.</li>
<li>The outcome of this legal battle could significantly impact future licensing deals and the broader tech industry, with potential implications for how intellectual property (IP) is transferred and used post-acquisition.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/shell-pool/shpool">Shpool, a Lightweight Tmux Alternative</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google has open-sourced Shpool, a tool initially developed for maintaining persistent terminal sessions in remote workflows.</li>
<li>Shpool aims to enhance remote work efficiency by allowing continuous terminal sessions without interruptions.</li>
<li>This release is significant as it provides developers with a robust solution for managing remote terminal sessions, potentially improving productivity in distributed teams.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40669337">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Shpool, a terminal session persistence tool developed by Google, has been open-sourced as a lightweight alternative to Tmux.</li>
<li>Shpool is designed for managing persistent sessions without extra features, making it suitable for long-running processes and system services.</li>
<li>The tool emulates a console to view state and re-render on attach, but currently does not support multiple terminal emulators or heavy use of terminal escape codes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://annas-archive.org/torrents">You can help Anna&#39;s Archive by seeding torrents</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Anna’s Archive, Library Genesis, and Sci-Hub have created a unified torrent list to preserve a vast amount of human knowledge, totaling 521.1TB, with 60% already copied in at least four locations.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to seed torrents, especially those with low seeders, to help reach 100% preservation. Large contributors (50TB or more) can contact the team for updates on deprecated torrents.</li>
<li>The list is divided into three parts: managed by Anna’s Archive, managed by others like Library Genesis and Sci-Hub, and miscellaneous torrents. Some torrents may be temporarily embargoed.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40672215">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Anna&#39;s Archive, a mirror of Library Genesis and Sci-Hub, seeks help seeding over 500 TB of books and papers for preservation, with 40% currently seeded by fewer than 4 nodes.</li>
<li>The project faces significant copyright infringement challenges, similar to other online libraries like LibGen, Sci-Hub, and Z-Library, which have faced legal actions and domain seizures.</li>
<li>The shift from IPFS to BitTorrent for preservation is due to BitTorrent&#39;s ease of use and lower infrastructure requirements, with the community debating the ethical and legal implications of torrent seeding for long-term data preservation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/amd-ceo-lisa-su-reminisces-on-helping-design-the-ps3s-infamous-cell-processor-at-ibm">AMD CEO Lisa Su reminisces about designing the PS3&#39;s infamous Cell processor</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Lisa Su, before becoming AMD CEO, worked at IBM and contributed to the design of the PlayStation 3&#39;s Cell processor, which was based on IBM&#39;s PowerPC and focused on parallelization.</li>
<li>Despite the PlayStation 3 being one of Sony&#39;s least successful consoles, it sold 87.4 million units by March 2017 and led to visually stunning games like Uncharted 3.</li>
<li>Under Lisa Su&#39;s leadership, AMD has provided hardware for both PlayStation and Xbox for two consecutive console generations, marking a significant achievement for the company in the gaming industry.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40670898">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>AMD CEO Lisa Su shared insights on designing the PS3&#39;s Cell processor, highlighting its advanced architecture and challenges in game development.</li>
<li>The PS3&#39;s Cell processor was powerful but difficult to program, leading to mixed success and limited market adoption compared to X86_64 and ARM CPUs.</li>
<li>The PS3&#39;s unique hardware, including the Cell processor and Nvidia GPU, made it a complex but innovative console, influencing the evolution of gaming consoles and their development environments.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://iterm2.com/downloads.html">iTerm 3.5.1 removes automatic OpenAI integration, requires opt-in</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>iTerm2 3.5.2 is the latest stable release, recommended for macOS 10.15 and newer, built on June 13, 2024.</li>
<li>The latest beta version, iTerm2 3.5.1beta4, is available for testing, built on June 3, 2024, with frequent updates but occasional instability.</li>
<li>Nightly builds are created daily if changes are committed, but they may contain serious bugs; the latest and older builds are available in the archives.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40668803">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The iTerm 3.5.1 update removes automatic OpenAI integration, now requiring users to opt-in, sparking debate among users.</li>
<li>Concerns were raised about potential data security risks in corporate environments, even with the opt-in feature, highlighting the need for strict network-level controls.</li>
<li>The backlash against the AI integration led to criticism of IT professionals for not properly vetting software updates and allowing auto-updates without sufficient oversight.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Japan enacts law to promote competition in smartphone app stores" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Japan%20enacts%20law%20to%20promote%20competition%20in%20smartphone%20app%20stores&subheading=Thursday%2C%20June%2013%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-13T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-12]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/12&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-12</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.stefantheard.com/silicon-valleys-best-kept-secret-founder-liquidity/">Founder Liquidity: The Hidden Practice Reshaping Startup Risk Dynamics</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Founder liquidity allows founders to sell shares during funding rounds, securing personal financial stability, which significantly alters the risk landscape compared to early employees.</li>
<li>The practice of founder liquidity is often kept secret to maintain the image of a fully committed founder, attracting top talent willing to work for less in exchange for equity.</li>
<li>The author advocates for transparency in founder liquidity, suggesting that every new funding round should disclose if founders took liquidity, to balance risk and compensation for early employees.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40654190">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text discusses the financial risks and potential regrets for founders and employees selling equity early in a startup, highlighting the significant difference in value if the startup succeeds later.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the importance of understanding the financial implications, including taxes and opportunity costs, of selling equity versus holding onto it, and suggests using equity as collateral for loans as an alternative.</li>
<li>The text critiques the startup ecosystem for often misleading employees about the value of equity, suggesting that early employees frequently get a worse deal compared to founders and that financial literacy is crucial for making informed decisions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://flameshot.org/">Flameshot: Versatile Open-Source Screenshot Tool with Cloud Integration and CLI Support</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Flameshot is a free, open-source screenshot software with customizable features, including editing, annotations, and cloud uploads for easy sharing.</li>
<li>It supports a command-line interface for scripting and key binds, and is available on Windows, macOS, and Linux.</li>
<li>Users can download AppImage or Nightly-builds Binaries for older releases, or install via Package Manager for various Linux distributions like Arch, Ubuntu, Debian, and Fedora.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40650844">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Flameshot, an open-source screenshot tool, is praised for its features and compatibility with Linux, but lacks screen recording capabilities.</li>
<li>Users discuss integrating Flameshot with Tesseract for OCR (Optical Character Recognition) and zbarimg for barcode decoding, enhancing its functionality.</li>
<li>Various users compare Flameshot with other tools like ShareX, Greenshot, and Ksnip, highlighting preferences based on simplicity, feature set, and platform compatibility.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://elixir-lang.org/blog/2024/06/12/elixir-v1-17-0-released/">Elixir 1.17 Released: Set-Theoretic Types, New Duration Data Type, and OTP 27 Support</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Elixir v1.17 introduces set-theoretic types, providing new warnings for common mistakes and supporting Erlang/OTP 27, while dropping support for Erlang/OTP 24.</li>
<li>The release includes a new Duration data type, Date.shift/2 function, and Kernel.to_timeout/1 function, enhancing date and time manipulation capabilities.</li>
<li>New warnings and type-checking features help developers find bugs earlier, with future releases expected to expand type analysis across function boundaries.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40656747">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Elixir 1.17 has been released, introducing set-theoretic types, durations, and OTP 27, which has garnered positive feedback from users.</li>
<li>The new <code>get_in/1</code> feature allows working with structs without raising errors when accessing <code>nil</code> values, enhancing developer productivity.</li>
<li>The release includes a gradual type system based on set-theoretic types, which improves type safety and expressivity, and is expected to significantly enhance the Elixir and Phoenix ecosystems.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.swift.org/documentation/articles/static-linux-getting-started.html">Swift&#39;s Static Linux SDK: Build Fully Statically Linked Executables for Any Linux Distribution</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Static Linux SDK allows Swift programs to be built for Linux without needing the Swift runtime and dependencies on the target system, creating fully statically linked executables.</li>
<li>It supports development on macOS with deployment to Linux, eliminating runtime overhead and versioning issues but resulting in larger executables and no code sharing.</li>
<li>The SDK uses the Musl C library for static linking, requiring adjustments for packages using the C library, and can build binaries for x86-64 and ARM64 machines.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40651054">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Swift&#39;s new static SDK supports user-definable platforms, including embedded systems and WebAssembly (WASM), showcasing its expansion beyond Apple ecosystems.</li>
<li>Swift&#39;s move to a non-Apple GitHub organization and its use in AI OS for security validation highlight its growing versatility and adoption in various tech domains.</li>
<li>The development allows running Swift binaries in Alpine containers, cross-compilation, and support for vanilla Debian, exciting developers who prefer Debian for development virtual machines (VMs).</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/06/11/elon-musk-drops-suit-against-openai-and-sam-altman.html">Elon Musk Withdraws Lawsuit Against OpenAI and Co-Founders</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Elon Musk has withdrawn his lawsuit against OpenAI and its co-founders, Sam Altman and Greg Brockman, which was scheduled for a hearing in San Francisco.</li>
<li>The lawsuit alleged that OpenAI deviated from its original mission to develop artificial general intelligence for humanity&#39;s benefit and became a for-profit entity controlled by Microsoft.</li>
<li>Musk&#39;s decision to dismiss the suit follows his public criticism of OpenAI&#39;s new partnership with Apple and comes after launching his own AI startup, xAI, which recently raised $6 billion in Series B funding.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40651203">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Elon Musk has withdrawn his lawsuit against OpenAI and Sam Altman, which some speculate was a strategic move possibly driven by jealousy over OpenAI&#39;s achievements.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights OpenAI&#39;s shift from its original non-profit mission to a for-profit model, raising questions about accountability and tax-exempt status.</li>
<li>The text also touches on Musk&#39;s controversial behavior and his significant influence on the tech industry, despite criticisms of his management style and public antics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/cpus/intel-is-trucking-a-916000-pound-super-load-across-ohio-to-its-new-fab-spawning-road-closures-over-nine-days">Intel Transports 916,000-Pound &#39;Super Load&#39; Across Ohio for New Chip Plant</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Intel is transporting a 916,000-pound &quot;cold box&quot; across Ohio to its new $28 billion Ohio One Campus, causing road closures for nine days.</li>
<li>The project involves building two chip factories on a 1,000-acre site, expected to create jobs and fund local schools and universities.</li>
<li>The Ohio Department of Transportation (ODOT) is ensuring infrastructure can handle the load, including moving power lines, with other companies also using the planned routes for their large loads.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40658095">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Intel is transporting a massive 916,000-pound &quot;Super Load&quot; across Ohio to its new semiconductor fabrication facility, highlighting the logistical challenges and planning required for such oversized equipment.</li>
<li>The &quot;Super Load&quot; is a 23-foot tall, 20-foot wide, and 280-foot long air-processor structure, too large for normal railroads and heavy-lift helicopters, necessitating a complex route and multiple support vehicles.</li>
<li>This transport underscores the importance of semiconductor fabrication facilities in the US for economic and defense reasons, aiming to reduce dependence on foreign countries like Taiwan and South Korea.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/06/t-mobile-users-thought-they-had-a-lifetime-price-lock-guess-what-happened-next/">T-Mobile Faces Backlash Over Broken Lifetime Price Lock Promise</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 2017, T-Mobile promised no price increases for users sticking to the same plan, but recently announced price hikes of up to $5 per line on older plans, surprising many customers.</li>
<li>T-Mobile&#39;s &quot;Un-contract&quot; promise included a clause that the company would pay the final month&#39;s bill if customers canceled due to a price increase, but this information is now harder to find.</li>
<li>T-Mobile is defending itself against an FCC complaint, stating that customers with the &quot;Price Lock&quot; guarantee (April 2022 - January 2024) are not affected by the recent price hikes, provided they stay on the qualifying plan.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40653785">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>T-Mobile users are frustrated by unexpected price increases despite believing they had a lifetime price lock.</li>
<li>Users suggest that telecom companies should incentivize switching to new plans with better features rather than raising prices on old plans.</li>
<li>The discussion includes various opinions on telecom mergers, regulations, and the impact of property taxes on home prices, highlighting the complexity of the telecom industry and its broader economic implications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twobithistory.org/2019/11/06/doom-bsp.html">The Genius of Binary Space Partitioning in Doom&#39;s Game Engine</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>John Carmack&#39;s implementation of Binary Space Partitioning (BSP) in Doom significantly improved the game&#39;s rendering speed, solving the visible surface determination (VSD) problem.</li>
<li>BSP trees, originally used in military research, allowed Doom to efficiently manage complex 3D scenes by splitting them into manageable parts, ensuring real-time rendering without excessive CPU usage.</li>
<li>Carmack&#39;s innovative use of BSP trees in Doom, influenced by academic research and prior works, exemplifies the application of advanced computer graphics techniques in video game development, marking a milestone in the industry.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40652917">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text highlights John Carmack&#39;s exceptional ability to read and understand research papers, especially in computer science, where historical context is often neglected.</li>
<li>It discusses the evolution of computer graphics and programming languages, emphasizing the importance of older, clearer research papers and the practical application of these techniques in game development.</li>
<li>The text also touches on the challenges of the tech industry, including the tendency to reinvent existing systems, the role of open-source volunteers, and the impact of software patents on innovation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://academic.oup.com/qje/article/134/3/1225/5435538">Global Historical Asset Returns: Housing Outperforms Equities with Lower Volatility</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper titled &quot;The Rate of Return on Everything, 1870–2015&quot; introduces a new data set covering all major asset classes, including housing, from 1870 to 2015 in 16 advanced economies.</li>
<li>The study reveals that residential real estate and equities have similar high returns, averaging about 7% a year, but housing returns are less volatile than equities.</li>
<li>The findings challenge common beliefs about risk and return, showing that housing has been the best long-term investment in modern history due to its lower volatility compared to equities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40650326">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Housing costs have steadily increased over the past century due to population growth outpacing the supply of desirable land.</li>
<li>Industrialization has reduced the proportion of income spent on food and labor required for goods, increasing overall wealth faster than the supply of desirable land.</li>
<li>The text discusses various factors affecting housing prices, including dual-income households, urbanization, and the impact of technology on distributed living.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/06/11/raspberry-pi-is-now-a-public-company-as-its-shares-pops-after-ipo-pricing/">Raspberry Pi Goes Public with $690M Valuation on London Stock Exchange</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Raspberry Pi has gone public with an IPO on the London Stock Exchange, initially priced at £2.80 per share, valuing the company at £542 million ($690 million).</li>
<li>The shares rose 32% to £3.70, potentially raising over $200 million, with retail investors able to trade shares starting Friday.</li>
<li>Raspberry Pi&#39;s single-board computers, popular among hobbyists, are increasingly used in industrial applications, which now account for 72% of its sales.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40656603">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Raspberry Pi has become a public company, raising concerns among some customers about a shift from its mission-driven approach to profit-making.</li>
<li>The company has been accused of anti-competitive practices and prioritizing bulk sales over individual customers during the COVID-19 pandemic.</li>
<li>Despite these issues, Raspberry Pi remains popular due to its strong ecosystem, documentation, and support, though some users are considering alternatives like Intel NUCs and second-hand PCs for better performance and stability.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://syntax.fm/show/779/why-sqlite-is-taking-over-with-brian-holt-and-marco-bambini">Why SQLite&#39;s Popularity is Soaring: Insights from Experts</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Brian Holt and Marco Bambini discuss the increasing popularity of SQLite, highlighting its efficiency, speed, and stability.</li>
<li>They address misconceptions about SQLite&#39;s capabilities and introduce SQLite Cloud, which adds shareability and enterprise features.</li>
<li>The episode explores why SQLite is gaining traction and its unique features.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40654734">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SQLite&#39;s popularity stems from its use as an application file format, offering advantages like handling rich data and being incrementally updatable.</li>
<li>The U.S. Library of Congress endorses SQLite as a recommended storage format, highlighting its reliability and efficiency.</li>
<li>Discussions include the potential issues with SQLite&#39;s journal/WAL files, the suitability of SQLite for various applications, and comparisons with other databases like DuckDB and PostgreSQL.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://gizmodo.com/ai-detectors-inaccurate-freelance-writers-fired-1851529820">AI Detectors&#39; Flaws Lead to Job Losses for Writers Despite Original Work</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Kimberly Gasuras, a veteran news reporter, lost her freelance job due to accusations of using AI, highlighting the growing reliance on AI detection tools like Copyleaks, GPTZero, Originality.AI, and Winston AI.</li>
<li>AI detectors, despite being advertised with high accuracy rates, are criticized for their unreliability and false positives, impacting professionals&#39; livelihoods and reputations.</li>
<li>Universities and companies are increasingly skeptical of AI detectors due to their inaccuracies, with some institutions banning their use after false accusations, while AI detection companies acknowledge the need for better solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40657238">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Mark lost his writing job despite proving he wrote an article by hand, resulting in a significant income loss.</li>
<li>The text discusses the challenges and limitations of AI detection in writing, highlighting issues like false positives and the difficulty of distinguishing AI-generated content from human-written content.</li>
<li>The increasing use of AI in content creation and its impact on jobs, quality of work, and the reliability of AI detectors are central themes, with concerns about AI&#39;s role in creative fields and the potential for misuse in surveillance and hiring practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://sph.umd.edu/news/study-shows-n95-masks-near-perfect-blocking-escape-airborne-covid-19">Duckbill N95 Masks Proven Most Effective at Blocking Airborne COVID-19 Particles</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A University of Maryland study found the &quot;duckbill&quot; N95 mask to be the most effective at preventing COVID-19 particles from escaping, blocking 98% of particles.</li>
<li>The study revealed that KN95 masks were less effective than expected due to poor fit and air leakage, while cloth masks outperformed both KN95 and surgical masks.</li>
<li>The research underscores the importance of mask-wearing, especially with highly transmissible COVID-19 variants, and recommends duckbill N95 masks for high-risk environments like nursing homes and healthcare settings.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40657307">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study confirms that N95 masks are highly effective at blocking airborne COVID-19, sparking discussions on why the US government didn&#39;t distribute them widely.</li>
<li>The text highlights the political implications of vaccine skepticism, noting how views on the COVID-19 vaccine have evolved, particularly among different political affiliations.</li>
<li>The effectiveness of various masks, including N95, surgical, and cloth masks, is discussed, with a focus on their ability to block viral particles and the challenges in proper mask usage and distribution.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://frereit.de/aes_gcm/">AES-GCM Security Risks: The Dangers of Nonce Reuse</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article emphasizes the critical importance of using unique nonces in AES-GCM encryption to prevent severe security failures.</li>
<li>It explains how reusing a nonce can allow attackers to decrypt ciphertexts and authenticate data without knowing the AES key, compromising the entire encryption scheme.</li>
<li>The post delves into the mathematical foundations of AES-GCM, including Galois field arithmetic and polynomial factorization, and demonstrates how these principles can be exploited to break encryption when nonces are reused.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40653125">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text highlights the risks of nonce reuse in AES-GCM encryption, particularly for long-term key usage scenarios like VPNs, packetized communications, and full disk encryption.</li>
<li>Nonce reuse can lead to severe security vulnerabilities, including potential attacks if an attacker knows both the plaintext and ciphertext.</li>
<li>Alternatives to AES-GCM, such as AES-GCM-SIV, XSalsa20, XChaCha20, and the AEGIS family of algorithms, are recommended for better performance and security, especially in environments where nonce reuse is a concern.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.noahpinion.blog/p/decade-of-the-battery-334">Batteries: The Defining Technology of the 2020s</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post argues that batteries, not AI, will be the defining technology of the 2020s, revolutionizing various sectors including warfare, transportation, and energy storage.</li>
<li>Significant advancements in battery technology have led to reduced costs and increased energy density, making them crucial for electric vehicles, drones, and renewable energy storage.</li>
<li>The integration of AI with battery-powered devices, such as autonomous drones and robots, is expected to transform industries and daily life, presenting lucrative opportunities for venture capitalists and tech companies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40650316">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Sodium-based batteries are now available on Alibaba and AliExpress, priced around $9 for a single cell or $100 for a 20-pack, and they require new Battery Management Systems (BMSs).</li>
<li>Sodium-ion batteries, which use sodium ions as charge carriers, are cheaper, safer, and perform better in extreme temperatures compared to lithium-ion batteries, but they are heavier and larger.</li>
<li>The text discusses the potential of sodium batteries to become a competitive alternative to lithium-ion batteries, especially for stationary and long-duration storage, due to their cost-effectiveness and safety.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Founder Liquidity: The Hidden Practice Reshaping Startup Risk Dynamics" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Founder%20Liquidity%3A%20The%20Hidden%20Practice%20Reshaping%20Startup%20Risk%20Dynamics&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20June%2012%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/12</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-12T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-11]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/11&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-11</h1>
<h2><a href="https://machinelearning.apple.com/research/introducing-apple-foundation-models">Apple Unveils Apple Intelligence with Advanced On-Device and Server AI Models</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>At the 2024 Worldwide Developers Conference, Apple introduced Apple Intelligence, a personal intelligence system integrated into iOS 18, iPadOS 18, and macOS Sequoia, featuring generative models for tasks like text refinement and image creation.</li>
<li>Apple emphasizes responsible AI development, focusing on user empowerment, privacy, and efficient model performance, using on-device processing and Private Cloud Compute to protect user data.</li>
<li>The system employs the AXLearn framework for efficient training, with models optimized for speed and efficiency, and includes specialized neural network modules called adapters for task-specific performance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40639506">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s announcement of On-Device and Server Foundation Models has received mixed reactions, with critics accusing them of repackaging existing AI techniques and supporters praising their refinement and popularization of established technologies.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights Apple&#39;s strategy of refining and popularizing existing technologies, such as with &quot;Apple Silicon&quot; and &quot;AirPort,&quot; rather than focusing on groundbreaking research.</li>
<li>Speculation suggests Apple might enter the server chip market with an AI chip, leveraging their silicon expertise, while debates continue over their high pricing, minimal RAM in base models, and tight ecosystem control.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://security.apple.com/blog/private-cloud-compute/">Apple&#39;s Private Cloud Compute Enhances AI Privacy and Security for iOS and macOS</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s Private Cloud Compute (PCC) introduces advanced generative AI models to iPhone, iPad, and Mac, with a strong focus on security and privacy.</li>
<li>PCC ensures user data remains private and inaccessible, even to Apple staff, by using end-to-end encryption, ephemeral processing, and anonymizing request metadata.</li>
<li>Apple will make PCC&#39;s production software publicly available for security research, supporting independent verification and maintaining public trust.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40639606">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate on AI data privacy in Apple&#39;s private cloud contrasts open-source, decentralized systems with Apple&#39;s robust privacy measures, including third-party audits and custom hardware.</li>
<li>Critics question Apple&#39;s transparency and potential backdoors, despite acknowledging strong internal security from competitors like Google and OpenAI, and suggest non-profit alternatives like GrapheneOS for verifiable security.</li>
<li>Concerns include Apple&#39;s data collection for ads, the need for strong encryption, minimal data logging, and the risks of government interference, highlighting the complexity of network infrastructure and the trade-offs between isolated machines and cloud-based systems.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lynn_Conway">Pioneering Computer Scientist and Transgender Activist Lynn Conway Passes Away at 85</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Lynn Conway (1938-2024) was a pioneering computer scientist and electrical engineer who significantly advanced modern processors and microchip design.</li>
<li>Despite facing discrimination and being fired by IBM in 1968 for transitioning, she had a notable career at Xerox PARC, DARPA, and the University of Michigan, and co-authored the influential textbook &quot;Introduction to VLSI Systems.&quot;</li>
<li>Conway was also a prominent transgender rights advocate, receiving numerous awards, including an apology and the IBM Lifetime Achievement Award in 2020, leaving a lasting legacy in both technology and transgender rights.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40648470">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Lynn Conway, a pioneering computer scientist and transgender activist, has passed away, leaving behind a legacy of inspiration and resilience.</li>
<li>Despite being fired by IBM for her gender transition, Conway rebuilt her career and became a significant figure in VLSI (Very Large Scale Integration) design, co-authoring the influential textbook &quot;Introduction to VLSI Systems&quot; and teaching a groundbreaking VLSI Design Course.</li>
<li>Her legacy is especially poignant during Pride Month, highlighting ongoing struggles against oppression and the lasting impact of her work and activism, despite facing transphobic backlash.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dgroshev.com/blog/rp2040/">RP2040: Raspberry Pi&#39;s Cost-Effective, Versatile Microcontroller for Engineers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The RP2040 is a versatile microcontroller by Raspberry Pi, designed for embedding in consumer electronics.</li>
<li>Unlike other manufacturers, Raspberry Pi offers just one model, simplifying development and fostering a large support community.</li>
<li>Priced at around 70 cents, it features two cores, 30 GPIO pins, ample internal RAM, and a unique PIO peripheral for efficient IO operations, making it a favorite among engineers for its balance of cost, functionality, and support.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40646061">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A user switched from the RP2040 to the ESP32-S3 microcontroller due to issues with the PlatformIO tool, simpler module format, and better GPIO pin capabilities for capacitive touch.</li>
<li>The RP2040 was praised for its affordability, excellent documentation, and unique Programmable I/O (PIO) feature, but criticized for high power consumption and lack of peripherals.</li>
<li>The ESP32 was highlighted for its integrated Bluetooth and Wi-Fi, despite having inferior ADCs and facing performance issues with large projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://www.povray.org/">POV-Ray Celebrates 30 Years with New Beta Release and Educational IDE Campaign</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Persistence of Vision Raytracer (POV-Ray) is a free, high-quality tool for creating 3D graphics, with customizable source code.</li>
<li>Notable updates include the beta release of POV-Ray v3.8.0, a Kickstarter campaign for an educational IDE by DKBTrace creator David K. Buck, and the 30th anniversary of POV-Ray.</li>
<li>The site has recovered from a server crash, restored its wiki and forums, and announced new features like POV-Ray export in the white_dune 3D editor.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40643207">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Hacker News user shared their 25-day experience learning ray tracing with POV-Ray, igniting nostalgic discussions about early computer graphics and programming on older systems like the 386 and 486 processors.</li>
<li>Users reminisced about long rendering times, hardware upgrades, and using software like POV-Ray and VistaPro, as well as programming in languages like C and Turbo Pascal.</li>
<li>The conversation also covered modern tools like Blender, the evolution of 3D rendering, and the impact of big tech and economic models on innovation and resource allocation, highlighting the enduring influence of POV-Ray and early internet communities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/books/news/noam-chomsky-health-update-tributes-b2559831.html">Noam Chomsky Unable to Communicate or Walk After Medical Event</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Noam Chomsky, a 95-year-old linguist and political activist, has suffered a severe health decline since a medical event in June last year, rendering him unable to communicate or walk.</li>
<li>His former assistant, Bev Stohl, confirmed that Chomsky has not appeared in public since the incident and is unlikely to do so again.</li>
<li>Tributes emphasize Chomsky&#39;s kindness, dedication to fighting injustice, and significant influence, with his absence notably felt in discussions about the Gaza conflict.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40641361">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Noam Chomsky, despite losing his ability to speak, remains mentally sharp and actively engages with young audiences, maintaining his influence in political and cognitive science.</li>
<li>He faces criticism for his views on geopolitical issues, including Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine and past interactions with Jeffrey Epstein, as well as his stances on American interventionism and historical events like the Cambodian genocide.</li>
<li>The text contrasts Chomsky&#39;s theories on innate grammar with the functioning of large language models (LLMs) and discusses his controversial opinions on the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, NATO, and US foreign policy, highlighting the polarized reactions he provokes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/06/11/norway-discovers-europes-largest-deposit-of-rare-earth-metals.html">Norway Unveils Europe&#39;s Largest Rare Earth Metals Deposit, Easing Reliance on China</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Norway has discovered Europe&#39;s largest deposit of rare earth metals in the Fen Carbonatite Complex, containing 8.8 million metric tons of rare earth oxides.</li>
<li>This find includes 1.5 million metric tons of magnet-related rare earths crucial for electric vehicles and wind turbines, potentially reducing Europe&#39;s reliance on China.</li>
<li>The discovery is a milestone for Rare Earths Norway and aligns with Europe&#39;s goal to meet its rare earth demand domestically by 2030, with mining expected to start by then.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40646658">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Norway has discovered Europe&#39;s largest rare earth metals deposit, leading to mixed reactions about resource distribution and management.</li>
<li>The discussion emphasizes Norway&#39;s historical and geographical context, effective resource management, and the broader implications of rare earth mining, including environmental concerns and geopolitical dynamics with China and Russia.</li>
<li>Misconceptions about rare earth elements are addressed, highlighting their abundance but the challenges associated with extraction.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/11/style/ai-search-slop.html">Slop: The Rise of Low-Quality A.I.-Generated Content and Its Impact on Online Platforms</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The term &quot;slop&quot; has emerged to describe low-quality, unwanted A.I.-generated content across various online platforms, including social media, art, books, and search results.</li>
<li>The term gained traction after Google integrated its Gemini A.I. model into U.S. search results, leading to initial user dissatisfaction and missteps.</li>
<li>Experts warn that such content discourages critical thinking by presenting information as definitive answers, and advocates believe having terms like &quot;slop&quot; is essential for societal discourse on modern A.I. usage.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40645983">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The term &quot;slop&quot; refers to low-quality, often AI-generated content, reflecting concerns about AI&#39;s impact on content quality and societal well-being.</li>
<li>Critics argue that AI exacerbates the issue by enabling mass production of low-quality content, driven by economic incentives and advertising profits.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the challenge of distinguishing between low-effort human content and AI-generated material, with concerns about the future of content creation and the potential for AI to manage both creation and summarization.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://usrtk.org/bees-neonics/entomological-society-america-corporate-partners/">Corporate Influence Raises Concerns at Entomological Society Conference</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>At the 2023 Entomological Society of America (ESA) meeting, significant corporate sponsorship, especially from agrochemical companies like Corteva Agriscience, was evident.</li>
<li>Despite discussions on critical topics like bee health and climate change, research on neonicotinoids—a pesticide linked to bee colony declines and produced by Corteva—was notably sparse, raising concerns about corporate influence on scientific discourse.</li>
<li>Critics argue that corporate involvement may compromise the integrity of the ESA, although the organization defends its inclusivity and diversity of scientific perspectives.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40638386">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A major conference experienced a decline in controversial pesticide research, igniting debates about the impact of corporate sponsorship in academia.</li>
<li>Critics argue that corporate funding skews research priorities and suppresses less profitable studies, while supporters believe it fosters beneficial collaboration.</li>
<li>The discussion underscores the tension between industry involvement and scientific integrity, advocating for increased federal science funding to mitigate corporate influence.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://maxleiter.com/blog/ship-every-day">Daily Commitments: Boosting Productivity and Team Visibility</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author recommends making daily tangible contributions at work, which don&#39;t have to be major features or bug fixes.</li>
<li>Benefits include a dopamine rush, increased visibility to your team, encouragement of incremental progress, and an impressive GitHub profile.</li>
<li>Contributions can also include documentation or triage, helping to combat isolation in remote work and providing daily satisfaction.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40640927">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The &quot;ship something every day&quot; approach in software development is critiqued for potentially lowering quality and promoting superficial productivity through rapid, unreflective iterations.</li>
<li>Critics argue that focusing on metrics like commit streaks can be misleading, induce anxiety, and negatively impact software stability, suggesting that meaningful work often requires more time.</li>
<li>The discussion advocates for a balanced approach to productivity, emphasizing quality over arbitrary metrics, consistent incremental progress, effective communication, and the value of internal documentation and creative projects for sustained motivation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://iandanielstewart.com/2024/06/09/engage-your-audience-by-getting-to-the-point-using-story-structure-and-forcing-specificity/">Mastering Clear Communication: Tips from Vicky Zhao&#39;s Effective Strategies</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article highlights communication strategies inspired by Vicky Zhao&#39;s video on clear articulation of ideas.</li>
<li>Key techniques include starting with a clear main point, using a 3-line story structure, and being specific with set phrases and the Via Negativa method.</li>
<li>These methods aim to improve writing, reading, thinking, and decision-making by ensuring communication is clear, engaging, and precise.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40639628">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion emphasizes effective audience engagement through concise communication and structured storytelling, contrasting different approaches like starting with the main point versus traditional story structures.</li>
<li>It highlights the importance of clear presentations using frameworks such as STAR (Situation, Task, Action, Result) for clarity and quick decision-making.</li>
<li>The conversation underscores the balance between brevity and clarity, the role of engaging presentation styles, and the effectiveness of storytelling techniques like the hero&#39;s journey, ultimately valuing genuine emotion and personal voice over rigid structures.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://christopher.engineering/en/blog/gleam-overview/">Why Gleam V1 is Winning Over Developers with Its Type-Safe BEAM Integration</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article highlights Chris, a software engineer, who revisited Gleam, a type-safe language on the BEAM, after the release of Gleam V1 in March 2024 and was impressed by its static typing.</li>
<li>Key features of Gleam include tagged unions, pattern matching, and a robust type system, with a compiler and CLI that simplify development, contrasting with JavaScript&#39;s complexity.</li>
<li>Gleam&#39;s integration with the BEAM ecosystem and OTP for building fault-tolerant software, along with its ability to transpile to JavaScript, makes it appealing to JavaScript developers; the article also introduces Lustre, a Gleam web framework.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40643167">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Gleam is a type-safe language designed for the BEAM virtual machine, known for its minimalistic design and productive features.</li>
<li>Unlike Elixir, Gleam re-implements key primitives to align with its static type system, offering simplicity, labeled arguments, and integrated tooling.</li>
<li>While Gleam&#39;s OTP (Open Telecom Platform) is less mature than Erlang&#39;s or Elixir&#39;s, it is evolving and appreciated for its ergonomic design and potential integration with projects like Vue.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/the-new-math-of-how-large-scale-order-emerges-20240610/">New Framework Unveils How Large-Scale Order Emerges from Microscopic Interactions</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article by Philip Ball discusses the concept of emergence, where large-scale patterns arise from numerous microscopic interactions, and the challenge of developing a unified scientific theory for it.</li>
<li>Researchers, including Fernando Rosas, have proposed a new framework using computational mechanics to identify criteria for emergent structures, suggesting that complex systems self-organize into hierarchical levels independent of lower-level details.</li>
<li>The study introduces the concept of informational closure, indicating that macro-level predictability and control are not enhanced by detailed microstate information, and explores its implications for understanding the universe&#39;s structure, causation, and the debate on free will.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40638764">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces Crutchfield&#39;s Epsilon machine formalism, a new method for modeling state transitions in systems with non-finite memory, addressing the limitations of finite state machines.</li>
<li>It recommends key resources on complex systems, including works by Melanie Mitchell, Crutchfield, and Cosma Shalizi, and books like &quot;The Nature of Computation&quot; by Stuart Kauffman and &quot;Networks&quot; by Mark Newman.</li>
<li>The discussion covers the interplay between macro and micro processes, the concept of heterarchy, and the importance of interdisciplinary study rooted in information theory, referencing theories by Gregory Chaitin and the Solomonoff–Kolmogorov–Chaitin framework.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2024/06/10/two_arrested_in_uk_over/">British Duo Arrested for SMS Phishing Using Homemade &quot;Text Message Blaster&quot;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>British police have arrested two individuals involved in an SMS-based phishing (smishing) campaign using a homemade &quot;text message blaster&quot; to send thousands of fraudulent texts.</li>
<li>The suspects impersonated banks and official organizations to deceive recipients, with one identified suspect, Huayong Xu, charged and set to appear in court.</li>
<li>The investigation, involving network operators, Ofcom, and the National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC), highlights the importance of reporting suspicious messages to 7726.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40642801">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Two British individuals were arrested for SMS phishing using a homemade cell tower built with Software-Defined Radio (SDR) and open-source software.</li>
<li>The article discusses the ease of creating such systems and anti-spam measures by phone providers, including reporting suspicious texts to numbers like 7726 (SPAM).</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the sophistication of spectrum monitoring in cities, especially in high-risk areas like central London, and the involvement of various authorities.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Apple Unveils Apple Intelligence with Advanced On-Device and Server AI Models" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Apple%20Unveils%20Apple%20Intelligence%20with%20Advanced%20On-Device%20and%20Server%20AI%20Models&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20June%2011%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/11</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-11T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-10]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/10&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-10</h1>
<h2><a href="https://marian42.de/article/orrery/">Building a Functional Lego Orrery: Challenges and Innovations</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A Lego Technic enthusiast built a functional orrery, modeling the orbits and rotations of the Earth, Moon, and Sun, inspired by a 2016 design from JK Brickworks.</li>
<li>The project involved complex mechanisms, precise gear ratios, and faced challenges like friction and weight, leading to a redesign for simplicity and stability.</li>
<li>Despite detailed digital instructions and promotional efforts, the project wasn&#39;t commercially successful, and the author later preferred a simpler orrery from CaDA, hoping for more elaborate designs in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40626807">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The blog post on marian42.de explores the intricate process of designing a Lego orrery, focusing on the challenges of modeling axial tilt and creating detailed building instructions.</li>
<li>The discussion includes reflections on the educational value of such projects, the evolution of LEGO Technic sets, and the potential for incorporating LEGO mechanics into school curriculums.</li>
<li>Participants express diverse opinions on the intellectual value of detailed Lego projects, acknowledging their role in fostering creativity and problem-solving skills.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://at.hn">Personalized Markdown Profiles for Hacker News Users with &quot;at.hn&quot;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;at.hn&quot; is a project providing Hacker News users with personalized subdomains displaying their HN bios in markdown format.</li>
<li>The site is opt-in, has limited functionality, and may soon include a user listing feature for improved profile discoverability.</li>
<li>The project is open for contributions on GitHub, inviting community involvement and enhancements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40632773">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A user named padolsey created &quot;at.hn,&quot; an open-source site allowing Hacker News (HN) users to display their profiles in markdown format on subdomains.</li>
<li>The project raises technical and ethical issues, including concerns about misuse for promotion, handling encoding problems, URL linkification, and preventing XSS vulnerabilities.</li>
<li>Discussions also cover GDPR compliance, data privacy, and technical feedback such as invalid HTML, subdomain handling, and &quot;nofollow&quot; links to prevent spam.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/haampie/libtree">Libtree: Visualize Shared Library Dependencies with Tree Format and Detailed Insights</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Libtree is a tool that converts <code>ldd</code> output into a tree format, helping users understand shared library dependencies and issues.</li>
<li>It offers various verbosity levels, path display options, and recursion depth limits to customize the output.</li>
<li>Prebuilt binaries for version 3.1.1 are available for multiple architectures, with installation instructions for several Linux distributions, and users can also compile from source if needed.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40626969">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Libtree&quot; is a tool that displays library dependencies in a tree format, providing insights into why a library is found or missing.</li>
<li>Unlike &quot;ldd,&quot; &quot;Libtree&quot; does not execute the target binary but manually parses ELF files and their dependencies, making it safer and more informative.</li>
<li>It is particularly useful for troubleshooting complex dependency issues, considering various search methods like LD_LIBRARY_PATH, RPATH, and RUNPATH, and is seen as an improvement over traditional tools like &quot;ldd&quot; or &quot;readelf.&quot;</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://social.coop/@jonny/107685726645817029">Social.coop: A Decentralized Social Network Powered by Mastodon</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Social.coop is a decentralized social network built on the Mastodon platform, allowing users to follow profiles, favorite, share, and reply to posts.</li>
<li>Users can interact across different servers, enhancing connectivity and community engagement.</li>
<li>The platform offers transparency with details on its administration, server statistics, and privacy policy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40631370">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Elsevier&#39;s use of unique hashes in PDF metadata to track downloads has drawn criticism for prioritizing profit over knowledge sharing, with high fees and restrictive practices seen as hindering societal progress.</li>
<li>Critics argue for copyright law reforms to promote fairer access to information, highlighting issues with the publication metric system and the high costs of open access mandates for authors.</li>
<li>The debate advocates for alternatives like Sci-Hub and open access platforms to promote innovation and calls for systemic change in the ethics and business practices of for-profit academic publishers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://yaledailynews.com/blog/2022/03/29/how-people-fall-apart-yale-faculty-discuss-the-impact-of-burnout-on-the-brain/">Yale Experts Reveal How Burnout Impacts Brain Function and Ways to Combat It</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Yale faculty discuss the neurobiological basis of burnout, focusing on its impact on the prefrontal cortex, which is responsible for higher cognitive functions.</li>
<li>Stress weakens the prefrontal cortex, leading to symptoms such as emotional exhaustion, cynicism, and a reduced sense of accomplishment, with uncontrollable stress shifting brain function to more primitive areas.</li>
<li>Strategies to mitigate burnout include seeking help, maintaining a balanced lifestyle, and engaging in hands-on activities, emphasizing the importance of perceived control over stressors.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40631663">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article delves into burnout through neuroscience, personal stories, and coping strategies, emphasizing personalized mental health approaches and advice from parents of autistic children and those with ADHD.</li>
<li>It discusses the psychological impact of societal pressures, the unsustainable pace of change, and the search for meaningful work, highlighting dissatisfaction in academia and industry.</li>
<li>Burnout in tech jobs is examined, with suggestions for job rotation and maintenance tasks, concluding with personal stories of severe burnout and the need for mental health services.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/revjaydub/status/1799212814646796648">Woman Showcases Washer Collection at Portland&#39;s First Friday, Gains Admirers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A woman in Portland, ME showcased her collection of washers during First Friday, providing descriptions but not selling them.</li>
<li>Jeff Woodbury highlighted this event on Twitter, expressing admiration for the woman&#39;s unique approach.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40627522">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A woman showcased her washer collection at Portland&#39;s First Friday Art Walk, igniting discussions about niche interests and specialized museums.</li>
<li>The conversation broadened to include historical tool and firearm museums, a YouTube channel on unusual guns, and personal anecdotes about various collections.</li>
<li>Debates emerged on the technical aspects of washers, the functionality of a RAM module, different locking mechanisms, and the ethics of sharing images online.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/WebKit/WebKit/commit/84ae355619354ee1bfa7daaa1fc95565a6726be3">WebKit Update Introduces Quirk to Address TextAutoSizing Bug on Hacker News</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A recent WebKit commit addresses a bug in TextAutoSizing on news.ycombinator.com, where <code>RenderBlockFlow::width</code> calculations were inconsistent.</li>
<li>The issue caused different font sizes on initial load versus refresh, with the width initially larger than <code>visibleWidth</code> but matching on refresh.</li>
<li>As a temporary solution, the commit introduces a quirk to skip TextAutoSizing for the site, with updates to <code>LocalFrameViewLayoutContext.cpp</code>, <code>Quirks.cpp</code>, and <code>Quirks.h</code> to bypass TextAutoSizing for specific URLs.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40631439">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A WebKit fix bypasses TextAutoSizing for news.ycombinator due to an unresolved bug, with a temporary workaround implemented.</li>
<li>Discussions focus on Apple&#39;s inconsistent app guidelines, the 30% &quot;Apple tax&quot; on in-app purchases, and mandatory app sign-ins, sparking debates on app store policies and hidden fees.</li>
<li>Broader frustrations with web compatibility, transparency from big tech, and controversial WebKit pull requests for site-specific behaviors are noted, alongside speculation about Google potentially bringing Blink to iOS due to the Digital Markets Act (DMA).</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://23words.com">23words.com: Daily Word Challenge Game with Timed and Marathon Modes</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40634042">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Hacker News discussion showcases various quick, low-stakes browser games that are both fun and mentally stimulating, such as Linxicon, WhenTaken, Angle, Metazooa, Tradle, and Globle.</li>
<li>Users share their own game creations, including Logiquiz, Zebra Puzzles, and Chrono, and provide feedback on game mechanics and user experiences.</li>
<li>A user compiles a comprehensive list of over 200 daily games at dles.aukspot.com, reflecting a community interest in simple, engaging games for daily play.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://9to5mac.com/2024/06/09/apple-blocks-pc-emulator-utm-app-store/">Apple Surprises Swift Student Challenge Winners with Exclusive Tim Cook Demo Session</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple hosted an exclusive demo session for winners of the Swift Student Challenge, led by CEO Tim Cook on June 9, 2024.</li>
<li>This event highlights Apple&#39;s commitment to nurturing young talent and providing unique opportunities for student developers.</li>
<li>The session likely included insights into new technologies and development practices, making it a significant experience for the participants.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40636331">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s decision to block a PC emulator from its iOS App Store and third-party app stores has raised concerns about anti-competitive behavior and potential violations of the Digital Markets Act (DMA).</li>
<li>Users are divided, with some appreciating Apple&#39;s control for security and quality, while others find the restrictions on virtualization and app control limiting, prompting considerations of switching to other hardware vendors.</li>
<li>The debate underscores the balance between a polished user experience and software freedom, touching on issues like scam app reduction, app updates, battery life, performance, and contrasting iPhone&#39;s user-friendliness and privacy with Android&#39;s flexibility.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-makes-direct-file-a-permanent-option-to-file-federal-tax-returns-expanded-access-for-more-taxpayers-planned-for-the-2025-filing-season">IRS Permanently Adopts Direct File for Federal Tax Returns Starting 2025</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The IRS will make Direct File a permanent option for filing federal tax returns starting in the 2025 tax season, following a successful pilot in 2024.</li>
<li>The agency plans to expand eligibility and partner with more states to cover a broader range of tax situations, based on positive feedback from users and stakeholders.</li>
<li>Direct File aims to simplify tax filing, save time and money for taxpayers, and support the IRS&#39;s digital transformation, while maintaining other free filing options like Free File, VITA, and TCE.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40634539">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The IRS has permanently introduced Direct File for federal tax returns, noted for its simplicity and efficiency, contrasting with deceptive &quot;free&quot; services that impose hidden fees.</li>
<li>The IRS is also working on streamlining data transfer to state tax systems, aiming to make the process more seamless.</li>
<li>The introduction of Free Fillable Forms and Direct File is expected to increase competition and reduce reliance on third-party services, despite resistance from the tax preparation industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.madinamerica.com/2024/06/988-records-shared/">988 Crisis Line Data Shared with Corporations Without Caller Consent, Sparking Outrage</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Recordings and transcripts from the 988 Suicide and Crisis Lifeline are being shared with researchers, AI developers, and corporations without caller consent, raising significant privacy concerns.</li>
<li>Investigations reveal vague, contradictory, and deceptive privacy policies, with data stored and shared across multiple platforms and call centers, some of which profit from sharing data.</li>
<li>Public outrage has led to calls for better privacy practices, with critics arguing that these practices exploit vulnerable individuals and that AI cannot replace the compassionate human connection essential in crisis support.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40628395">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The 988 Suicide &amp; Crisis Lifeline, a government-funded mental health service, faces allegations of sharing call data with corporations, potentially violating HIPAA regulations.</li>
<li>Critics argue that this potential breach of confidentiality could deter individuals in crisis from using the service, raising concerns about privacy and data protection.</li>
<li>The debate hinges on whether 988 is classified as a mental health service, which would mandate strict confidentiality under HIPAA.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.japantimes.co.jp/business/2024/06/08/evangelion-anime-production-company-bankrupt/">Anime Studio Gainax, Creator of &#39;Evangelion,&#39; Files for Bankruptcy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Gainax, the anime studio famous for &quot;Neon Genesis Evangelion,&quot; filed for bankruptcy on May 29, 2024, due to long-term business decline, mismanagement, and loss of key staff.</li>
<li>The company&#39;s representative director was arrested in 2019 for alleged sexual abuse of a minor, further impacting its reputation and operations.</li>
<li>Despite support from Khara, which owns the Evangelion rights, Gainax faced lawsuits over unpaid debts and ultimately could not sustain its operations, expressing regret and gratitude to its fans in a statement.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40634465">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Gainax, the anime studio known for &quot;Neon Genesis Evangelion,&quot; has declared bankruptcy due to financial struggles and mismanagement.</li>
<li>Key talents left Gainax for other studios like Khara and Trigger, and the studio engaged in unrelated ventures such as tomato farming.</li>
<li>Studio Khara now holds the rights to &quot;Evangelion&quot; and other Gainax properties, potentially revitalizing them, while the anime industry remains healthy with contributions from former Gainax talents.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/2138277/senior-employees-ordered-back-to-the-office-are-jumping-ship.html">Return-to-Office Mandates Drive Senior Staff to Seek Flexible Work Elsewhere</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Companies enforcing strict return-to-office (RTO) mandates are experiencing backlash, leading to increased employee attrition, particularly among senior-level staff, women, and millennials.</li>
<li>Research shows that rigid RTO policies are driving employees to seek jobs with more flexible remote work options, with the Federal Trade Commission&#39;s potential ban on non-compete agreements possibly intensifying this trend.</li>
<li>Companies like Amazon, Dell, and Google are using invasive tracking methods to monitor RTO compliance, further straining employee relations and highlighting the financial and personal costs of commuting.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40632625">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Senior employees are leaving companies enforcing return-to-office (RTO) policies, causing operational issues and staff dissatisfaction.</li>
<li>A newly independent company experienced significant departures when its CEO mandated a 4-day office week, perceived as a tactic to reduce headcount.</li>
<li>A Gartner survey revealed substantial senior-level departures due to RTO mandates, with the loss of AI talent seen as particularly detrimental.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Building a Functional Lego Orrery: Challenges and Innovations" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Building%20a%20Functional%20Lego%20Orrery%3A%20Challenges%20and%20Innovations&subheading=Monday%2C%20June%2010%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-10T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-06-09]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/06/09&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-06-09</h1>
<h2><a href="https://cosmosmagazine.com/science/biology/gene-therapy-restores-hearing-to-children-with-inherited-deafness/">Gene Therapy Restores Hearing in Children with Inherited Deafness</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A clinical trial has successfully restored hearing in five children with inherited deafness using gene therapy, specifically delivering functional copies of the OTOF gene via adeno-associated virus (AAV).</li>
<li>Significant improvements were observed in hearing, speech perception, and sound localization, with two children developing an appreciation for music.</li>
<li>Published in Nature Medicine, the study underscores the potential of this approach and advocates for larger international trials, noting the therapy&#39;s safety and effectiveness despite minor adverse events.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40620056">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Gene therapy has restored hearing in children with inherited deafness by injecting an adeno-associated virus carrying functional OTOF genes into their inner ears, ensuring long-term gene expression.</li>
<li>The discussion explores the potential of gene editing technologies like CRISPR for radical human modifications and the ethical implications of prioritizing cosmetic genetic engineering over medical applications.</li>
<li>Ethical concerns are raised about using gene therapy to eradicate hereditary deafness in children, focusing on consent and controversies within the Deaf community over cochlear implants.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/piku/piku">Piku: Simplifying Git Push Deployments for Personal Servers Across Multiple Languages</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Piku, inspired by Dokku, facilitates git push deployments to personal servers, supporting a Heroku-like workflow for various programming languages (Python, Node, Go, Java, Clojure, Ruby).</li>
<li>It can deploy, manage, and scale multiple applications on both ARM and Intel architectures, compatible with any cloud provider or bare metal setup using Python, nginx, and uwsgi.</li>
<li>Piku is stable, actively maintained, and designed for low-end devices, hobbyists, and educational use, emphasizing minimal dependencies, simplicity, and compatibility.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40622704">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion highlights Piku, a minimalist tool for Git push deployments to personal servers, comparing it to Heroku, Dokku, and Kubernetes for its simplicity and ease of use.</li>
<li>A tutorial for Piku, praised for its clarity, is now part of the official Piku GitHub organization, with plans for further enhancements.</li>
<li>Users discuss various deployment setups, including systemd nspawn for sandboxing and NixOS for stability, and address concerns about dependency management, security, and Docker&#39;s overhead, favoring lightweight, customizable PaaS solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ox.ac.uk/news/2024-06-07-sildenafil-viagra-improves-brain-blood-flow-and-could-help-prevent-dementia">Viagra Shows Promise in Improving Brain Blood Flow to Prevent Dementia</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A University of Oxford study published in Circulation Research indicates that sildenafil (Viagra) improves brain blood flow and function in patients at risk of vascular dementia.</li>
<li>The OxHARP trial, a double-blind, placebo-controlled study with 75 participants, found sildenafil enhances cerebrovascular function with fewer side effects compared to cilostazol.</li>
<li>These findings suggest sildenafil&#39;s potential in preventing vascular dementia, prompting the need for larger-scale trials.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40620739">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A recent study suggests Viagra, initially for cardiovascular issues and erectile dysfunction (ED), may improve brain blood flow and help prevent dementia.</li>
<li>Users report varied side effects like headaches, nausea, and nasal congestion, which often decrease over time, and emphasize the necessity of sexual stimulation for the drug to work.</li>
<li>The discussion covers broader health benefits, the unpredictability of drug research, and the need for rigorous studies to confirm benefits for conditions like Alzheimer&#39;s and vascular dementia.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://joshdata.me/iceberger.html">Draw Your Own Iceberg and Watch It Float with &#39;Iceberger&#39; Game</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Iceberger&quot; is a game developed by @joshdata, inspired by a tweet from @GlacialMeg, allowing users to draw an iceberg and visualize its floating orientation.</li>
<li>The game simulates the iceberg&#39;s three-dimensional mass distribution and relative density, key factors in determining its stable orientation.</li>
<li>The inspiration came from Megan Thompson-Munson&#39;s request for scientists to depict icebergs in their stable orientations, highlighted by her watercolor painting.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40620472">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A web tool on Hacker News lets users draw an iceberg and observe its floating behavior, sparking a discussion on user experiences and insights.</li>
<li>Users experiment with different shapes, such as stars and triangles, to see varied floating outcomes, sharing examples and suggestions for improvements.</li>
<li>The tool is praised for its educational value and simplicity, though some users express frustration over Twitter&#39;s restrictions on viewing threads without an account.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.thebignewsletter.com/p/economic-termites-are-everywhere">Matt Stoller Exposes Hidden Monopolies Draining the Economy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Matt Stoller&#39;s &quot;Economic Termites Are Everywhere&quot; examines the detrimental effects of small-scale monopolies on the economy, particularly in sectors like construction, software, and industrial gases.</li>
<li>Companies such as Verisign, Autodesk, and LinkedIn are cited for using their market power to inflate prices and hinder competition, highlighting the need for stronger antitrust enforcement.</li>
<li>Stoller advocates for legal and regulatory reforms to address these monopolistic practices and restore fair commerce and democracy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40623843">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article critiques traditional economic metrics for failing to reflect socioeconomic disparities and rising living costs, advocating for a re-evaluation of economic understanding.</li>
<li>It highlights issues such as rural decay, rising essential costs, economic inequality, and the disparity between public sentiment and statistical data in reflecting economic realities.</li>
<li>The discussion includes critiques of U.S. economic issues like healthcare access, food deserts, and restrictive housing policies, calling for improved transparency, regulation, and stronger antitrust policies to protect consumers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.writingruxandrabio.com/p/the-weird-nerd-comes-with-trade-offs">Ruxandra Teslo Advocates for &#39;Weird Nerds&#39; in Academia Amid Karikó Backlash</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ruxandra Teslo&#39;s Substack post critiques the backlash against Katalin Karikó, co-inventor of mRNA technology, for her criticisms of academia&#39;s political and social dynamics.</li>
<li>Teslo argues that academia undervalues intellectually creative &quot;Weird Nerds&quot; like Karikó, who often lack the interpersonal and political skills needed for academic success, suggesting the internet as a better environment for these individuals.</li>
<li>The post calls for a reevaluation of how human capital is valued in scientific and cultural fields, emphasizing the need for explicit pro-Weird Nerd norms to harness their potential and address academia&#39;s current crisis, including declining public trust.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40624924">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion examines the complexities of being a &quot;weird nerd,&quot; focusing on the trade-offs of intense interest in specific areas and the resulting deficiencies in other aspects of life.</li>
<li>It challenges stereotypes linking such behavior to autism, attributing it instead to deep passion, and critiques the medicalization of personality traits and the categorization of neurodiversity.</li>
<li>The text highlights the role of &quot;weird nerds&quot; in tech innovations, the importance of teamwork, and the evolving perception of terms like &quot;nerd&quot; and &quot;genius,&quot; while also addressing the challenges faced by neurodivergent individuals in professional settings.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.02528">Revolutionizing Language Models: MatMul-Free Approach Cuts Memory Use by Over 10x</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;Scalable MatMul-free Language Modeling&quot; by Rui-Jie Zhu et al. investigates removing matrix multiplication (MatMul) operations in large language models (LLMs) to lower computational costs.</li>
<li>The authors show that their MatMul-free models maintain strong performance at billion-parameter scales, comparable to state-of-the-art Transformers, while significantly reducing memory usage during inference and training.</li>
<li>They offer a GPU-efficient implementation that cuts memory consumption by up to 61%, an optimized kernel reducing it by over 10x, and a custom FPGA hardware solution for enhanced efficiency, achieving brain-like processing power.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40620955">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;Scalable MatMul-Free Language Modeling&quot; introduces a new approach to language models using ternary weights and quantization-aware training (QAT) to improve efficiency.</li>
<li>The method employs optimized and fused kernels with Triton, reducing overfitting and memory usage, and incorporates a linear transformer to minimize multiplications in the attention mechanism.</li>
<li>The implementation shows significant memory savings, is compatible with Huggingface transformers, and includes an FPGA core programmed with a custom assembler, indicating potential for future ASIC development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/the-censorship-circumvention-extension-has-disappeared-from-the-russian-version-of-mozilla-addons/130914">Mozilla Blocks Anti-Censorship Add-Ons in Russia Without Notification</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Censor Tracker 158 add-on, which helps bypass censorship in Russia, has become inaccessible in the country without prior notice or changes in settings.</li>
<li>Russian users attempting to access the add-on receive a message indicating that the page is not available in their region.</li>
<li>The developer is seeking clarification on whether this blockage is due to a request from Russian authorities or a decision made by Mozilla.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40621611">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Mozilla has banned two anti-censorship add-ons in Russia, sparking controversy and dividing users on issues of censorship and platform policies.</li>
<li>The developer of &quot;Runet Censorship Bypass&quot; was not notified, and users debate whether Mozilla&#39;s actions are justified or constitute censorship themselves.</li>
<li>The situation highlights broader concerns about user control, ethical practices, and geopolitical pressures, with some users exploring alternative browsers like Vivaldi and Kagi&#39;s Orion.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-38905963">Exploring the Fine Line Between Gambling and Insurance: Historical and Economic Perspectives</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article by Tim Harford examines the differences between gambling and insurance, highlighting their distinct legal and cultural perceptions despite both involving financial stakes on uncertain events.</li>
<li>Historical context includes early insurance practices in Babylon and China, the evolution of Lloyd&#39;s of London from a coffee house to a formal insurance marketplace, and mutual aid societies in the Alps.</li>
<li>The economic significance of insurance is underscored by examples like crop insurance in Ghana, and the article concludes by discussing financial derivatives and their role in the 2007 financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40620048">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article contrasts the impacts of insurance and gambling on financial security and societal well-being, emphasizing that insurance mitigates risks while gambling increases them.</li>
<li>Key points include the economic principles of utility, the diminishing marginal utility of money, and the ethical aspects of financial products.</li>
<li>The discussion also covers the complexities of the insurance industry, the necessity of regulation, and the differing societal perceptions and moral judgments between insurance and gambling.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dagen_H">Sweden&#39;s Historic Switch to Right-Side Driving: The Story of Dagen H</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Dagen H, or &quot;Högertrafikomläggningen,&quot; was the day Sweden switched from left-side to right-side driving on September 3, 1967, to reduce head-on collisions.</li>
<li>The transition required extensive public education, new road markings, and the replacement of 350,000 traffic signs, with non-essential traffic banned during the switch.</li>
<li>Although the change initially reduced accidents, rates returned to normal within two years; trams were largely replaced by buses, with only a few tram lines surviving.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40622912">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion highlights Sweden&#39;s switch to right-hand traffic in 1967, despite significant public opposition, and its eventual benefits.</li>
<li>Users compare the political courage required for such decisions in the past with the challenges of implementing unpopular policies in today&#39;s media-driven environment.</li>
<li>The conversation also explores global driving norms, the Geneva Convention on Road Traffic, and the broader implications of standardizing practices like driving on the right and adopting English as a second official language.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2024/06/fixing-a-knockoff-altera-usb-blaster-that-never-worked/">Fixing Faulty Altera USB Blaster Clones for Linux Compatibility</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Doug Brown fixed two faulty Altera USB Blaster clone devices for his Time Sleuth project, which measures HDMI input lag.</li>
<li>He resolved timing issues with the Waveshare USB Blaster V2 by adjusting the clock frequency and modified open-source firmware to make a cheaper Amazon clone functional on Linux.</li>
<li>Brown shares his modified firmware on GitHub and emphasizes the challenges and satisfaction of using open-source tools to convert nonfunctional devices into working ones.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40621534">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on troubleshooting a non-functional knockoff Altera USB Blaster, specifically issues with an FTDI chip.</li>
<li>Participants debate the merits and drawbacks of original versus cloned devices, including pricing, development costs, and the impact of cheaper clones on the market.</li>
<li>The thread also highlights alternative solutions, such as cheaper clones based on the Cypress FX2LP chip and open-source options.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://betula.mycorrhiza.wiki/">Betula: Self-Hosted Bookmarking for the Independent Web with IndieWeb and Fediverse Support</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Betula is a free, self-hosted bookmarking software designed for single users, allowing them to organize and publish bookmarks with tags, titles, and descriptions.</li>
<li>It supports public and private bookmarks, has a simple interface, and stores data in a single SQLite file, with IndieWeb microformats and Fediverse integration for social interaction.</li>
<li>Betula is easy to install and configure via a web interface, with development updates and source code available on SourceHut, Codeberg, and GitHub, and new versions released approximately every three months.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40622189">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Betula is a federated bookmarking software that enables users to manage and share bookmarks, designed specifically for the independent web.</li>
<li>It supports tagging and ActivityPub for social features, and is praised for being self-hostable without complex dependencies.</li>
<li>Users discuss challenges like forgetting bookmarks and suggest solutions such as content-centered bookmarks, self-hosted tools like Wallabag, and integration with note-taking apps.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mas-bandwidth.com/creating-a-matchmaker-for-your-multiplayer-game/">Building an Efficient Matchmaker for Multiplayer Games Using Real Player Data</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Glenn Fiedler&#39;s blog post on Más Bandwidth highlights the significance of a robust matchmaker for multiplayer games and introduces a matchmaking simulator based on real player data.</li>
<li>The simulator tests the matchmaker&#39;s efficiency in finding low-latency matches, aiming for ≤50ms latency, expanding to ≤100ms if necessary, and ultimately allowing any match if no ideal server is found.</li>
<li>The post underscores the importance of accurate latency estimation and suggests using latency maps and network accelerators, with the simulator showing promising results of matches found in an average of two seconds and 30-40ms RTT (Round-Trip Time).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40619752">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion examines the shift from community-driven servers to modern matchmaking in multiplayer games, which often disrupts long-term social interactions among players.</li>
<li>It highlights the benefits of persistent servers in games like &quot;Squad&quot; and &quot;Counter-Strike&quot; for relationship building and credits Glenn Fiedler&#39;s blog for successful netcode implementations using WebRTC and enet.</li>
<li>The post details a matchmaking technique involving server-authoritative netcode with client-side prediction and rollback, emphasizing low-latency connections, and discusses the challenges of balancing skill levels and latency. The source code is available on GitHub with an option to disable player shuffling.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.01637">LLM Agent Teams Outperform in Exploiting Zero-Day Vulnerabilities with HPTSA System</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;Teams of LLM Agents can Exploit Zero-Day Vulnerabilities&quot; by Richard Fang et al. investigates the use of large language model (LLM) agents in cybersecurity, focusing on zero-day vulnerabilities.</li>
<li>The authors introduce HPTSA, a system where a planning agent coordinates subagents to overcome the limitations of individual LLM agents in handling unknown vulnerabilities and long-term planning.</li>
<li>Benchmarking 15 real-world vulnerabilities, the study shows that the team-based approach of HPTSA significantly outperforms previous methods, enhancing performance by up to 4.5 times.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40624563">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion examines the strengths and weaknesses of Large Language Models (LLMs) like Claude-opus and ChatGPT in identifying zero-day vulnerabilities in code.</li>
<li>While LLMs can pinpoint technically correct issues, their broader relevance is debated, and specialized tools and expert knowledge are still essential for complex vulnerabilities.</li>
<li>Ethical and legal concerns, high costs, and practicality issues, especially for open-source projects, highlight skepticism about the added value of LLMs over existing techniques in cybersecurity.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Gene Therapy Restores Hearing in Children with Inherited Deafness" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Gene%20Therapy%20Restores%20Hearing%20in%20Children%20with%20Inherited%20Deafness&subheading=Sunday%2C%20June%209%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/06/09</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-06-09T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
