<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>hn.cho.sh</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/</link><description>Hacker News, AI-summarized.</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 22:43:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><origin>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26</origin><item><title>Everything you always wanted to know about mathematics (2013) [pdf]</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#everything-you-always-wanted-to-know-about-mathematics-2013-pdf</link><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 12:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Whistleblower drops 100 GB of Tesla secrets to German news site</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#whistleblower-drops-100-gb-of-tesla-secrets-to-german-news-site</link><description>- A whistleblower leaked over 23,000 internal files from Tesla to a German news outlet, revealing a pattern of dangerous Autopilot glitches allegedly ignored by the company.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 20:38:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI Canon</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#ai-canon</link><description>- The AI Canon is a collection of resources that cover the most important parts of modern AI.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 15:47:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Finetune GPT-Like Large Language Models on a Custom Dataset</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#how-to-finetune-gptlike-large-language-models-on-a-custom-dataset</link><description>- Learn how to fine-tune large language models (LLMs) on a custom dataset using Lit-Parrot, a nanoGPT based implementation of the GPT-NeoX model that supports StableLM, Pythia, and RedPajama-INCITE model weights.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 10:06:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Firefox displayed a pop-up ad for Mozilla VPN over an unrelated page</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#firefox-displayed-a-popup-ad-for-mozilla-vpn-over-an-unrelated-page</link><description>- Firefox displayed a pop-up ad for Mozilla VPN on top of an unrelated page, disabling the rest of the Firefox UI until closed.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 22:43:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>War Is a Racket (1935)</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#war-is-a-racket-1935</link><description>- 'War Is a Racket' is a famous booklet by Major General Smedley Butler, an ex-high-ranking Marine.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 19:16:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Colorado repealed law limiting municipal internet</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#colorado-repealed-law-limiting-municipal-internet</link><description>- Colorado has repealed a law that limited municipal internet and required voters' permission to build advanced broadband internet service in their communities, making it easier for local governments to explore broadband options.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 20:31:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Show HN: Visual intuitive explanations of LLM concepts (LLM University)</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#show-hn-visual-intuitive-explanations-of-llm-concepts-llm-university</link><description>- LLM University has created visual and intuitive explanations of LLM concepts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 12:50:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deno 1.34: Deno compile supports NPM packages</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#deno-134-deno-compile-supports-npm-packages</link><description>- Deno 1.34 release focuses on improving compatibility with npm and Node.js, enhancing overall quality of life and developer experience, and establishing the foundation for future performance improvements.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 10:16:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Implementing a distributed key-value store on top of implementing Raft in Go</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/26#implementing-a-distributed-keyvalue-store-on-top-of-implementing-raft-in-go</link><description>- A post explaining how to implement a distributed key-value store on top of implementing Raft in Go.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 13:26:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>