<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>hn.cho.sh</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/</link><description>Hacker News, AI-summarized.</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 22:14:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><origin>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11</origin><item><title>Microsoft fixes 5-year-old Defender bug, reducing Firefox-related CPU use by 75%</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#microsoft-fixes-5yearold-defender-bug-reducing-firefoxrelated-cpu-use-by-75</link><description>Sorry, the given text is not related to the title or topic of the article.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 12:58:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ever-expanding animation of the life of the 796th floor of a space station</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#everexpanding-animation-of-the-life-of-the-796th-floor-of-a-space-station</link><description>An ever-expanding animation showcasing the life of a space station's 796th floor has been created.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 07:48:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Night of the living brain fog dead or how I hacked myself better via open source</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#night-of-the-living-brain-fog-dead-or-how-i-hacked-myself-better-via-open-source</link><description>A blogger shares their journey of using open source software to manage severe sleep apnea after trying various sleep hygiene "hacks" and being prescribed CPAP.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:10:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RePalm</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#repalm</link><description>Dmitry.GR's rePalm project is a new emulator for PalmOS, covering topics such as virtual SD card support, ARM instruction translation, and more.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:22:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Effective Spaced Repetition</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#effective-spaced-repetition</link><description>A post on the effectiveness of spaced repetition in remembering anything emphasizes the importance of following rules for writing flashcards, including understanding first, being honest, repeating, organizing by source, writing atomic flashcards, and asking questions in multiple ways.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 12:07:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The biggest EV battery recycling plant in the US is open for business</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#the-biggest-ev-battery-recycling-plant-in-the-us-is-open-for-business</link><description>Ascend Elements has opened the largest electric-vehicle (EV) battery recycling plant in North America in Covington, Georgia, which has the capacity to process 30,000 metric tons of used lithium-ion batteries annually.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:38:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FTX stored private keys to crypto assets in plaintext, without access controls</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#ftx-stored-private-keys-to-crypto-assets-in-plaintext-without-access-controls</link><description>Crypto exchange FTX has been keeping private keys of users in plaintext, without access controls, according to a report by ZenGo.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 16:45:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>I fixed a parasitic drain on my car in 408 days</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#i-fixed-a-parasitic-drain-on-my-car-in-408-days</link><description>A car owner shares their experience of fixing a persistent parasitic battery drain on their 2013 Mazda3 hatchback, which took them 408 days to diagnose and fix.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:40:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How To Get Started In Soldering</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#how-to-get-started-in-soldering</link><description>Soldering is an affordable hobby and useful skill, with the best tip being to get the iron hot while avoiding melting components.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 12:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teaching ChatGPT to speak my son's invented language</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#teaching-chatgpt-to-speak-my-sons-invented-language</link><description>A father and son teach a computer the unique Kłeti language through chatbot technology, demonstrating technology's progress in making science fiction a reality.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 17:58:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al Jaffee, king of the Mad Magazine fold-in, has died</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#al-jaffee-king-of-the-mad-magazine-foldin-has-died</link><description>Sorry, there is no text to summarize as a reference was given instead.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 21:30:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hell Never Ends on x86: The Hyperspace Story, Continued, Sort Of</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#hell-never-ends-on-x86-the-hyperspace-story-continued-sort-of</link><description>HP replaced their instant-on Linux QuickWeb with a new version based on Hyperspace.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 04:27:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We Need To Talk About Vercel</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#we-need-to-talk-about-vercel</link><description>Recent discussion around Vercel has highlighted its heavy markup over AWS Lambda, surprise runaway costs, and technical deficiencies with its Content Delivery Network product.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:24:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dashcam footage shows driverless cars clogging San Francisco</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#dashcam-footage-shows-driverless-cars-clogging-san-francisco</link><description>Autonomous vehicle companies including Waymo and General Motors' Cruise have caused delays and potential danger for buses, trains, and passengers in San Francisco since September 2022, with 92 unplanned stops causing significant transit delays.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:11:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenBSD 7.3</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#openbsd-73</link><description>OpenBSD 7.3 release features kernel improvements, system updates, unlocked mmap, and hardware support.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Personal Concierge Using OpenAI's ChatGPT via Telegram &amp; Voice Messages</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#personal-concierge-using-openais-chatgpt-via-telegram--voice-messages</link><description>A new Telegram bot, utilizing OpenAI's ChatGPT, LangchainJS, OpenAI's Whisper API, and Play.ht, allows for personalized concierge services through both voice and chat.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 09:19:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EditAnything: Segment Anything + ControlNet + BLIP2 + Stable Diffusion</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#editanything-segment-anything--controlnet--blip2--stable-diffusion</link><description>The ongoing project, Edit Anything, utilizes Segment Anything, ControlNet, BLIP2, Stable Diffusion and more to "Edit and Generate Anything" in images, with a focus on fun contributions and suggestions.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 05:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Generative Agents: Interactive Simulacra of Human Behavior</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#generative-agents-interactive-simulacra-of-human-behavior</link><description>Researchers have introduced "generative agents," computational software agents that simulate believable human behavior using an architecture that extends large language models to store a complete record of the agent's experiences using natural language, synthesize those memories over time into higher-level reflections, and retrieve them dynamically to plan behavior.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 21:32:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dancing Plague of 1518</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#dancing-plague-of-1518</link><description>In 1518, a group of 50-400 people in Strasbourg, Alsace began dancing for weeks after one woman started dancing in the street, but the cause of the phenomenon is unknown.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 04:18:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>American IQ scores have rapidly dropped, proving the 'Reverse Flynn effect'</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#american-iq-scores-have-rapidly-dropped-proving-the-reverse-flynn-effect</link><description>New Northwestern University research suggests that American IQ scores are on the decline after decades of steady increases known as the 'Flynn effect.'</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Using RP2040 PIO to drive a poorly-designed displa</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#using-rp2040-pio-to-drive-a-poorlydesigned-displa</link><description>Dmitry.GR has developed a CPU-free driver with RP2040 PIO for a display supporting multiple modes and touch screen.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:43:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker News Ranking Algorithm</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#hacker-news-ranking-algorithm</link><description>The author proposes an alternative ranking algorithm for Hacker News (HN), where the current algorithm only considers the number of upvotes for a link, but the new algorithm also considers upvotes for comments.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 08:55:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutting down nuclear power could increase air pollution: study</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#shutting-down-nuclear-power-could-increase-air-pollution-study</link><description>Shutting down US nuclear plants may raise air pollution by over 5,000 deaths, MIT researchers warned.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 22:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple's plunge in PC shipments is steepest among major computer makers</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#apples-plunge-in-pc-shipments-is-steepest-among-major-computer-makers</link><description>Apple's PC shipments experienced a 40.5% decline, the largest since 2000, due to sluggish demand and industry-wide oversupply.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 09:40:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If you've raised venture capital, you have to pay yourself</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#if-youve-raised-venture-capital-you-have-to-pay-yourself</link><description>This is not the correct text for summarization as it is just an error message.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 13:34:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Kissimmee River has been brought back to life, &amp; wildlife is thriving</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#the-kissimmee-river-has-been-brought-back-to-life--wildlife-is-thriving</link><description>The Kissimmee River in Florida has been returned to its natural state after decades of being diverted into a straight canal, which brings with it a range of wildlife.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 02:47:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Use GitHub Actions to Make Your GitHub Profile Dynamic</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#use-github-actions-to-make-your-github-profile-dynamic</link><description>GitHub users can make their profile dynamic using GitHub Actions by creating a repository with a README.md file containing desired profile information, adding folders for dynamic content, and adding a new subfolder for the script that scrapes data from a website and modifying it in the README.md file; the content for the profile is found by going to github.com/[username] in a web browser, with the repository being the source of the profile page; the new subfolder for the workflow is installed into [workflows] within the root directory, and a schedule is set to run the script once a week; users can use different languages, including Ruby, TypeScript, JavaScript, and Python to make a dynamic profile; this technique enhances the GitHub profile of an individual, making it a more dynamic and ever-changing example.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 17:26:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What I've Learned About Formal Methods in Half a Year</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#what-ive-learned-about-formal-methods-in-half-a-year</link><description>The writer shares their experience learning about formal methods and the use of mathematical techniques to verify software properties.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ask HN: Open source LLM for commercial use?</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#ask-hn-open-source-llm-for-commercial-use</link><description>An HN user asked whether they could legally use an open-source LLM tool for commercial use.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 13:55:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zoomable, animated scatterplots in the browser that scales over a billion points</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/04/11#zoomable-animated-scatterplots-in-the-browser-that-scales-over-a-billion-points</link><description>Deep Scatterplots for the Web is an evolving library for displaying large amounts of data with high performance using the Apache Arrow `feather` format and WebGL.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:29:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>