<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>hn.cho.sh</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/</link><description>Hacker News, AI-summarized.</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 22:45:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><origin>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09</origin><item><title>Ink: React for interactive command-line apps</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#ink-react-for-interactive-commandline-apps</link><description>- Ink is a UI building tool for command-line apps that uses Yoga to create layouts with CSS-like properties.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 16:46:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FBI agents accuse CIA of 9/11 coverup</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#fbi-agents-accuse-cia-of-911-coverup</link><description>- Former FBI agents allege that the CIA has been hiding information about a failed recruitment effort involving a Saudi intelligence asset who met with two of the 9/11 hijackers in February 2000.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 15:26:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ancient Earth Globe</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#ancient-earth-globe</link><description>- The Ancient Earth Globe is an interactive website that allows users to see how Earth looked like millions of years ago, including the first coral reefs and the emergence of complex life on land during the Ordovician Period.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>You don't need Scrum, you just need to do Kanban right (2022)</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#you-dont-need-scrum-you-just-need-to-do-kanban-right-2022</link><description>- Scrum is a more prescriptive framework that can prevent teams from being as fast and dynamic as they could be, while Kanban is a pull-based system that provides sound principles, allowing managers to tailor them to their particular situation and obtain much better results.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 02:30:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Street Fighter II, paper trails (2021)</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#street-fighter-ii-paper-trails-2021</link><description>- The article discusses the use of a paper and scissors system to track ROM budget in the creation of Street Fighter II using the CPS-1 arcade platform in the late 90s.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 08:30:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>KeePassXC pull request to add basic support for WebAuthn</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#keepassxc-pull-request-to-add-basic-support-for-webauthn</link><description>- KeePassXC has added basic support for WebAuthn through a pull request.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ancient Greek terms worth reviving</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#ancient-greek-terms-worth-reviving</link><description>- This post discusses 12 ancient Greek terms that are worth reviving in modern society.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 22:45:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Please don't upload my code on GitHub</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#please-dont-upload-my-code-on-github</link><description>- A call to open source developers to not upload the work of others on GitHub due to the Copilot feature's potential violation of licenses and intellectual property rights.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 07:55:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cantonese Font with Pronunciation</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#cantonese-font-with-pronunciation</link><description>- Cantonese Font is a font that includes Jyutping romanization for traditional Chinese characters to aid in learning Cantonese.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 21:28:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1-Bit Hokusai's "The Great Wave"</title><link>https://hn.cho.sh/2023/05/09#1bit-hokusais-the-great-wave</link><description>- An artist has recreated all of Hokusai's 36 views of Mount Fuji as 1-bit pixel art using contemporary hardware and software on early black and white Macintosh computers, in a nostalgic attempt to capture the original vision and aesthetic of Hokusai and Susan Kare's 'the Japanese lady.'</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 19:56:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>