<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 10:07:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Unveils Powerful M4 Chip for New iPad Pro]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple has unveiled the M4 chip in the latest iPad Pro, boasting a 10-core CPU, 10-core GPU, and advanced Neural Engine for better performance.</li>
<li>The chip incorporates second-generation 3-nanometer tech for improved graphics and rendering, a new display engine, faster CPU and GPU, and advanced AI features.</li>
<li>This initiative aligns with Apple&#39;s 2030 carbon neutrality target, highlighting the company&#39;s commitment to innovation, environmental sustainability, and robust AI capabilities in the tech industry.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/05/apple-introduces-m4-chip/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZApple Unveils Powerful M4 Chip for New iPad Pro</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revolutionizing Cold Brew Coffee: Ultrasonic Waves Brew in 3 Minutes]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The University of New South Wales offers diverse study programs, including support for international students and Higher Degree Research, along with accommodation information, fee details, scholarships, and application procedures.</li>
<li>The university emphasizes research, industry partnerships, and various research areas, focusing on social impact, innovation, and collaboration within its community.</li>
<li>Researchers at the university have innovated an ultrasonic sound wave method to expedite cold brew coffee production from hours to minutes, maintaining taste quality, potentially transforming the coffee industry with a quicker and more effective brewing process.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.unsw.edu.au/newsroom/news/2024/05/Ultrasonic_cold_brew_coffee_ready_under_three_minutes</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZRevolutionizing Cold Brew Coffee: Ultrasonic Waves Brew in 3 Minutes</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LPCAMM2: The Future of Laptop Memory Upgrades]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>LPCAMM2 is a new memory standard designed for laptops, featuring modularity, repairability, and upgradeability, using LPDDR chips to allow seamless upgrades and repairs.</li>
<li>It aims to resolve the conflict between serviceability and battery life typically related to soldered LPDDR chips, representing a collaborative effort from tech giants like Dell, Micron, and Lenovo.</li>
<li>The release of LPCAMM2 signifies a progressive move towards sustainable and repairable devices in the tech industry.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ifixit.com/News/95078/lpcamm2-memory-is-finally-here</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZLPCAMM2: The Future of Laptop Memory Upgrades</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pyspread: Python-Powered Spreadsheet Solution]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Pyspread is a Python-based spreadsheet application enabling users to input Python expressions in cells, eliminating the need for a specific spreadsheet language.</li>
<li>It is open source, offering features like Python module access, data export, and versatile content display, targeting Python-savvy individuals like researchers and business analysts.</li>
<li>Users like Clara and Peter benefit from integrating Python code for data analysis, while those without programming experience, like Donna and Jack, or requiring cluster computing may find pyspread less suitable.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pyspread.gitlab.io/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZPyspread: Python-Powered Spreadsheet Solution</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revitalizing Downtowns: The Trend of Converting Office Towers into Apartments]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Real estate developer Nathan Berman specializes in converting Manhattan office towers into luxurious apartments to combat the city&#39;s housing shortage, maximizing residential space in outdated buildings.</li>
<li>The pandemic has accelerated the trend of converting office spaces to apartments, notably impacting downtown areas like the financial district, increasing residential occupancy.</li>
<li>Berman&#39;s cost-effective and eco-friendly approach has revitalized neighborhoods like the financial district, drawing in young professionals and families to live in his converted office buildings.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2024/05/06/can-turning-office-towers-into-apartments-save-downtowns</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZRevitalizing Downtowns: The Trend of Converting Office Towers into Apartments</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boeing Probed for Alleged 787 Inspections Issue]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Boeing is under a new US Federal Aviation Administration investigation for potential lapses in quality inspections on its 787 Dreamliner aircraft.</li>
<li>The FAA is examining if Boeing staff falsified records, with Boeing addressing the issue through corrective measures.</li>
<li>A whistleblower highlighted worries about production shortcuts and safety problems with Boeing planes, adding to the scrutiny on the company&#39;s practices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theguardian.com/business/article/2024/may/07/boeing-us-investigation-787-inspections-faa</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZBoeing Probed for Alleged 787 Inspections Issue</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hackers Crack NES Tetris, Enable Reprogramming within Game]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hackers found a way to reprogram NES Tetris from within the game, enabling players to prevent crashes and introduce new behaviors.</li>
<li>By manipulating crash and controller input mechanisms, players can influence the game code post-crash and inject instructions into the high score table.</li>
<li>This breakthrough offers the potential to eliminate crash bugs from NES Tetris, benefiting players aiming to exceed level 255 or revolutionize the game experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/05/hackers-discover-how-to-reprogram-nes-tetris-from-within-the-game/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZHackers Crack NES Tetris, Enable Reprogramming within Game</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Found Guilty of Illegal Staff Interrogation and Flyer Confiscation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The National Labor Relations Board found that Apple unlawfully questioned employees and took away union pamphlets at its World Trade Center store in NYC, as per a judge&#39;s determination.</li>
<li>Despite the violations, Apple has not been penalized for these actions, while additional cases on unionization issues involving Apple are ongoing.</li>
<li>Over recent years, several Apple stores have managed to form unions successfully.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.forbes.com/sites/antoniopequenoiv/2024/05/06/us-labor-board-rules-apple-illegally-interrogated-staff-and-confiscated-union-flyers/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZApple Found Guilty of Illegal Staff Interrogation and Flyer Confiscation</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decker: A Modern HyperCard Revival with 1-Bit Graphics]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Decker is a multimedia platform influenced by HyperCard and classic MacOS, allowing users to generate interactive documents like E-Zines, presentations, and games with a &quot;ditherpunk&quot; look.</li>
<li>Users can save their creations as standalone .html files, benefit from quality-of-life enhancements, a user-friendly scripting language called Lil, interactive widgets, and the option for custom widget development.</li>
<li>Decker is privacy-focused, open-source under the MIT license, command-line compatible, and provides resources like the Lil programming language, reference manual, and a community forum on Itch.io.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.beyondloom.com/decker/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZDecker: A Modern HyperCard Revival with 1-Bit Graphics</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zed: High-Performance App Development on Linux with GPUI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores the creation of Zed, a high-performing application, on Linux utilizing the GPUI framework to enable its functionality on the platform.</li>
<li>It delves into technical choices and obstacles faced, including selecting audio and rendering systems, particularly highlighting the employment of Blade, a Vulkan-based solution, for rendering on Linux.</li>
<li>The team is gearing up for an imminent alpha launch on Linux, enhancing features and stability, and is on the hunt for software development enthusiasts to join their workforce.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://zed.dev/blog/zed-decoded-linux-when</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZZed: High-Performance App Development on Linux with GPUI</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New SecureDrop Encryption Protocol Enhances Source Anonymity]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The blog post explores a new end-to-end encryption protocol for the upcoming SecureDrop system, enhancing source anonymity and preventing metadata correlation.</li>
<li>The protocol prioritizes deniability, secure message delivery, and user privacy, utilizing cryptographic primitives and a straightforward API.</li>
<li>Future developments include finalizing the protocol, tackling browser-side encryption, and gathering input from the security community, led by Giulio B. Davide TheZero and funded by the Freedom of the Press Foundation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://securedrop.org/news/introducing-securedrop-protocol/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZNew SecureDrop Encryption Protocol Enhances Source Anonymity</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Shuts Down Multiple Bethesda Affiliated Game Studios]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft has shuttered multiple Bethesda studios, such as Arkane Austin, Tango Gameworks, and others, leading to extensive job cuts.</li>
<li>The closures stem from Microsoft&#39;s strategic shift in projects and resources, resulting in the reassignment of some employees to different initiatives.</li>
<li>Titles like Redfall will cease to receive updates, while games like Mighty Doom and Hi-Fi Rush are set to be discontinued, alongside job reductions in Bethesda&#39;s publishing and corporate divisions, aligning with a broader pattern of layoffs in the gaming sector.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-closes-redfall-developer-arkane-austin-hifi-rush-developer-tango-gameworks-and-more-in-devastating-cuts-at-bethesda</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZMicrosoft Shuts Down Multiple Bethesda Affiliated Game Studios</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ultimate Guide to Dotfiles Management on GitHub]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The guide provides tutorials, utilities, frameworks, and tips for managing dotfiles on GitHub, enabling users to backup, restore, and sync their preferences and settings.</li>
<li>Users can learn from the community, share their knowledge, and find inspiration for organizing and customizing dotfiles on the site.</li>
<li>Additionally, users can contribute by submitting feature requests, opening issues, or submitting patches to enhance the guide further.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dotfiles.github.io/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZUltimate Guide to Dotfiles Management on GitHub</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Grateful Dead's Revolutionary Wall of Sound]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Owsley &quot;Bear&quot; Stanley, the Grateful Dead&#39;s sound engineer, developed the groundbreaking Wall of Sound in 1974, transforming live sound engineering.</li>
<li>Comprising over 600 speakers and cutting-edge sound technology, the Wall of Sound provided unparalleled audio quality and resolved common technical problems.</li>
<li>Despite facing some hurdles and needing modifications for practicality, the Wall of Sound significantly influenced live sound engineering with its avant-garde and inventive approach.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://audioacademy.in/the-grateful-deads-wall-of-sound/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-08T00:00:00.000ZThe Grateful Dead&apos;s Revolutionary Wall of Sound</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Caniemail.com: CSS Updates & Email Platform Scores]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The summary covers new CSS features like text-wrap, transition, word-spacing, shape-margin, and shape-outside.</li>
<li>It highlights updates from March, February, January, December, and April 2024 in the tech industry.</li>
<li>Additionally, it includes client scores for email platforms such as Apple Mail, Samsung Email, SFR, and WEB.DE.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.caniemail.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Caniemail.com: CSS Updates &amp; Email Platform Scores</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Organize Your Debates: Introducing CQ2]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>CQ2 is a free and open-source tool specifically developed for intricate discussions, aiming to tackle problems like impulsive responses and unstructured asynchronous conversations.</li>
<li>It offers organized threads, straightforward navigation, and the capability to effectively conclude discussions, ultimately aiming to enhance discussion quality and assist users in making better decisions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://cq2.co/blog/the-best-way-to-have-complex-discussions</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZOrganize Your Debates: Introducing CQ2</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explore 6k Plants: GetAnyPlant Site Simplifies Plant Info]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GetAnyPlant is a website developed by a data scientist to streamline plant information from different online stores, offering features like plant exploration, wishlist creation, and note-taking.</li>
<li>The platform consolidates and compares plant data from various sources, presenting comprehensive details, filters, and categories to facilitate user-friendly searches.</li>
<li>The creator seeks input on enhancing the site&#39;s growth, welcoming feedback and suggestions from users.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.getanyplant.com/plants</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZExplore 6k Plants: GetAnyPlant Site Simplifies Plant Info</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Extending Free Trial Boosts Conversions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Extending the free trial period for Keygen software led to increased conversion rates, as the 14-day trial was deemed too short for customers to fully grasp the product&#39;s value.</li>
<li>Offering an unlimited free tier was a strategic move that further boosted paid sign-ups by allowing users more time to integrate and appreciate the software.</li>
<li>Analyzing the time-to-convert metric empowered the author to enhance lead capture strategies effectively, resulting in a growth in paid subscriptions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://keygen.sh/blog/your-14-day-free-trial-aint-gonna-cut-it/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZExtending Free Trial Boosts Conversions</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decloaking Routing-Based VPNs: TunnelVision Exposes User Privacy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>TunnelVision is a new attack technique exposing VPN encryption vulnerabilities via DHCP manipulation since 2002, posing a severe threat to user privacy.</li>
<li>The article delves into decloaking behavior, low-level networking, and the role of network interfaces in computer communication, stressing the significance of non-tech individuals understanding these concepts.</li>
<li>To address VPN weaknesses, the text recommends network namespaces, discusses DHCP, routing tables, and mitigation strategies like ArcaneTrickster, underlining the need for VPN providers to boost user awareness, improve network namespace features, handle LAN security flaws, and offer guidance on countering decloaking attacks.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.leviathansecurity.com/blog/tunnelvision</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZDecloaking Routing-Based VPNs: TunnelVision Exposes User Privacy</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYU Professors Defending Vaping Failed to Disclose Juul Ties]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NYU professors David Abrams and Ray Niaura worked with Juul executives without revealing their connections, promoting vaping as a public health approach, despite its appeal to young people.</li>
<li>Abrams requested talking points from Juul and permitted them to review an academic paper without transparency about their affiliations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.statnews.com/2024/05/06/juul-vaping-advocates-nyu-professors-non-disclosed-conflict-interest/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZNYU Professors Defending Vaping Failed to Disclose Juul Ties</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rise of Cheaper GPU Access: Alternative Clouds Outpace Major Providers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Alternative cloud providers offering GPU access are growing due to cost-effective options for running generative AI workloads, raising significant funding for GPU infrastructure support.</li>
<li>These providers like CoreWeave, Lambda Labs, and Voltage Park are gaining popularity for their competitive pricing compared to giants like AWS, Google Cloud, and Microsoft Azure.</li>
<li>Challenges like competition from hyperscalers investing in custom AI hardware and the generative AI bubble&#39;s potential burst could affect their growth, but experts foresee short-term expansion, especially for customers seeking multi-cloud environments and trustworthy GPU access.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2024/05/05/coreweaves-1-1b-raise-shows-the-market-for-alternative-clouds-is-booming/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZRise of Cheaper GPU Access: Alternative Clouds Outpace Major Providers</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proton Mail Scrutinized for User Data Disclosure in Spain]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Proton Mail, a Swiss secure email service, faced criticism for disclosing user data to Spanish authorities, aiding an arrest linked to the Catalan independence movement, Democratic Tsunami.</li>
<li>This case showcases the challenge of balancing user privacy and legal obligations, stressing the importance of operational security (OPSEC) for encrypted communication users.</li>
<li>Despite providing robust encryption, services like Proton Mail have complied with numerous data requests, prompting users to enhance anonymity and avoid linking recovery information to personal details.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://restoreprivacy.com/protonmail-discloses-user-data-leading-to-arrest-in-spain/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZProton Mail Scrutinized for User Data Disclosure in Spain</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winners Revealed: Grand C++ Error Explosion Competition 2014]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Grand C++ Error Explosion Competition revealed winners in two categories: biggest error and artistic merit, showcasing various intriguing code samples.</li>
<li>Winning entries involve generating large error messages from minimal code, artistic pieces prone to overflow when displayed online, and imaginative cheat attempts.</li>
<li>Notable entries feature code triggering IDE code completion engine crashes, intentionally complex snippets, and a basic yet impressive demonstration of leveraging fundamental tools effectively.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tgceec.tumblr.com/post/74534916370/results-of-the-grand-c-error-explosion</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZWinners Revealed: Grand C++ Error Explosion Competition 2014</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concerns Rise as Private Equity Engages in Veterinary Industry]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Private equity firms are buying veterinary clinics and pet care companies, raising worries about increased costs and reduced care quality.</li>
<li>States are urged to scrutinize large acquisitions in the veterinary industry to safeguard consumers from adverse effects.</li>
<li>Some states have regulations to bar non-veterinarians from owning vet practices to maintain medical decisions free from corporate influence.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://stateline.org/2024/03/29/vets-fret-as-private-equity-snaps-up-clinics-pet-care-companies/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZConcerns Rise as Private Equity Engages in Veterinary Industry</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German Public Broadcasters Launch Open Source Streaming Code]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>German public broadcasters ARD and ZDF plan to share their streaming code as open source to develop a collaborative &quot;streaming OS&quot; for a shared technical base.</li>
<li>The initiative targets establishing a unified German streaming network and aiding competitors, educational institutions, and potentially European partners.</li>
<li>Managed jointly, the project aims to finalize the streaming OS by spring 2025.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.heise.de/en/news/ARD-und-ZDF-wollen-ihren-Streaming-Code-als-Open-Source-anbieten-9709177.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZGerman Public Broadcasters Launch Open Source Streaming Code</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Navigating Life's Volatility: The Role of Debt]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article highlights how debt affects one&#39;s resilience during uncertain events, stressing the significance of having cash and avoiding debt for flexibility.</li>
<li>It underscores that debt can limit one&#39;s ability to confront obstacles and adapt in an unpredictable environment.</li>
<li>Emphasizes the importance of financial preparedness to navigate unforeseen circumstances and maintain resilience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://collabfund.com/blog/how-i-think-about-debt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZNavigating Life&apos;s Volatility: The Role of Debt</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pifex: DIY JTAG Hacking with Raspberry Pi]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The PiFex is a new companion board for the Raspberry Pi, facilitating hardware hacking and working with embedded protocols like UART, SPI, I2C, JTAG, and SWD. It features an I2C OLED screen and will be available as an open-source project.</li>
<li>The blog post demonstrates the use of PiFex tools, UrJTAG, and OpenOCD to reverse-engineer a JTAG TAP on an SSD successfully, enabling memory reading and firmware analysis.</li>
<li>It also discusses utilizing Ghidra for code disassembly and analysis, along with announcing future releases and training opportunities for those keen on embedded device evaluations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://voidstarsec.com/blog/jtag-pifex</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZPifex: DIY JTAG Hacking with Raspberry Pi</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stack Overflow Teams up with OpenAI for Transformative API Partnership]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Stack Overflow and OpenAI have partnered to offer developers access to a powerful combination of technical content and advanced AI models through the OverflowAPI.</li>
<li>OpenAI will use Stack Overflow&#39;s API to enhance its models, while Stack Overflow will integrate OpenAI models to improve its products and community engagement.</li>
<li>The collaboration intends to revolutionize the developer experience, advance technology development, and advocate for ethical AI practices, with new features expected by the first half of 2024.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://stackoverflow.co/company/press/archive/openai-partnership/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZStack Overflow Teams up with OpenAI for Transformative API Partnership</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhance your Religious Experience with TOTP Authenticator for PalmOS]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text offers a guide on installing Palm apps on Palm OS devices and emulators, featuring specific apps like TOTP Authenticator, Rosary, Bible in a Year, and Catechism in a Year.</li>
<li>These apps aim to enrich the user&#39;s religious experience by providing daily readings, prayer guides, and other features.</li>
<li>The instructions cater to users looking to enhance their spiritual practices using technology, offering a unique blend of faith and digital tools.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nkorth.com/palm/apps/#totp-authenticator</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-07T00:00:00.000ZEnhance your Religious Experience with TOTP Authenticator for PalmOS</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Safeguarding Open Source: Defending Against Social Engineering Takeovers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The XZ Utils cyberattack attempted a backdoor takeover, raising concerns as similar incidents have been intercepted by the OpenJS Foundation and Open Source Security Foundation.</li>
<li>Social engineering tactics were employed to gain maintainer access to popular JavaScript projects, highlighting the importance of vigilance and security best practices for project maintainers.</li>
<li>Industry and government efforts are crucial in securing open source infrastructure, with the OpenJS Foundation and OpenSSF collaborating to enhance the security of the JavaScript ecosystem through project support and funding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://openssf.org/blog/2024/04/15/open-source-security-openssf-and-openjs-foundations-issue-alert-for-social-engineering-takeovers-of-open-source-projects/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZSafeguarding Open Source: Defending Against Social Engineering Takeovers</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel Shuts Down Al Jazeera Offices amid National Security Concerns]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Israel has banned Al Jazeera and halted its broadcasts, citing national security worries, despite facing backlash for stifling free speech and democratic values.</li>
<li>The closure of Al Jazeera&#39;s offices in Israel has sparked criticism globally as ceasefire talks with Hamas stall, with international bodies condemning the move.</li>
<li>The ban, permitted by a fresh law enabling the temporary shutdown of foreign media seen as a security risk, is part of Israel&#39;s controversial actions during the Israeli-Hamas conflict, including limiting Gaza access for foreign reporters.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/may/05/israel-shuts-down-local-al-jazeera-offices-in-dark-day-for-the-media</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZIsrael Shuts Down Al Jazeera Offices amid National Security Concerns</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Vital Role of Bollards in Public Safety]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article emphasizes the critical role of bollards in preventing vehicle collisions and tragic outcomes due to their absence.</li>
<li>Several incidents are cited where bollards could have averted accidents, reducing injuries and fatalities.</li>
<li>The author criticizes local transportation authorities for neglecting to install bollards and stresses the importance of their correct placement for public safety.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://josh.works/bollards</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZThe Vital Role of Bollards in Public Safety</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Traefik: Proxy Server Advantages Beyond Containers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores the use of Traefik, a widely used proxy server, beyond container environments, showcasing its ability to automatically handle TLS certificates and proxy services without relying on a container engine.</li>
<li>Traefik can be set up through configuration files, offering features like TLS Passthrough and support for the PROXY protocol, though lacking functionalities such as authentication and IP blocking.</li>
<li>The author emphasizes Traefik&#39;s strength, user-friendliness, and high-quality documentation, providing a configuration sample to demonstrate its setup process.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://j6b72.de/article/why-you-should-take-a-look-at-traefik/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZExploring Traefik: Proxy Server Advantages Beyond Containers</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Master Deep Reinforcement Learning Algorithms]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Deep Reinforcement Learning: Zero to Hero!&quot; course provides a hands-on experience with fundamental deep reinforcement learning algorithms such as DQN, SAC, and PPO.</li>
<li>Participants will be able to train an AI to play Atari games and complete tasks like landing on the Moon, with the environment setup involving tools like Miniconda, Poetry, and Visual Studio Code.</li>
<li>Support resources, including notebooks, solutions folder, and YouTube videos, are accessible to aid participants throughout the learning process.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/alessiodm/drl-zh</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZMaster Deep Reinforcement Learning Algorithms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft CTO's Insights on OpenAI: A 2019 Tweet Revived in 2024]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/techemails/status/1787176471146156193</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZMicrosoft CTO&apos;s Insights on OpenAI: A 2019 Tweet Revived in 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta Rivals Manhattan Project in GPU Spending]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta&#39;s GPU spending nearly matches the Manhattan Project&#39;s expenses in today&#39;s currency.</li>
<li>However, it falls behind the investment made in the Apollo Program.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/emollick/status/1786213463456448900</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZMeta Rivals Manhattan Project in GPU Spending</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monitoring Energy Usage with Smart Plugs: A Tech Success Story]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares their journey of monitoring energy usage using smart plugs, Prometheus, and Grafana, discussing setup, power consumption observations (e.g., water heater, home server, workstation), and charging patterns.</li>
<li>They also highlight stability issues with the plugs and propose future plans to automate device control according to electricity prices, expressing satisfaction with the setup for monitoring and enhancing the power efficiency of their devices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ounapuu.ee/posts/2024/05/02/smartplugs/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZMonitoring Energy Usage with Smart Plugs: A Tech Success Story</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Machine Unlearning in 2024: Challenges and Applications]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Machine Unlearning in 2024&quot; by Ken Liu delves into the concept of machine unlearning, which eliminates unwanted data from ML models without starting from zero.</li>
<li>The post delves into challenges, motivations, and potential uses of unlearning, like safeguarding user privacy and eliminating harmful content.</li>
<li>It explores different unlearning methods, such as exact unlearning and differential privacy, emphasizing the significance of legal and technical considerations, empirical methods, and algorithm assessments in AI safety, copyright protection, and AI model realms.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ai.stanford.edu/~kzliu/blog/unlearning</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZExploring Machine Unlearning in 2024: Challenges and Applications</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Simplicity vs. Complexity: The Value Proposition]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article delves into the preference for complexity in academic papers, promotions, and product development, while advocating for the advantages of simplicity.</li>
<li>It outlines how complexity is often seen as more prestigious but stresses the benefits of simplicity, such as better understanding, adoption, communication, and maintenance.</li>
<li>The author encourages a transition towards appreciating simplicity in problem-solving and decision-making, underscoring the significance of opting for the simplest solutions to intricate issues.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://eugeneyan.com/writing/simplicity/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZSimplicity vs. Complexity: The Value Proposition</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japan to Test Tooth Regrowth Medicine from Sept. 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Researchers in Japan will commence clinical trials for the world&#39;s inaugural &quot;tooth regrowth medicine&quot; in September 2024, aiming to deactivate a protein that impedes tooth growth.</li>
<li>The medicine targets individuals with congenital tooth issues, with the ambition of being market-ready by 2030, offering hope to those with tooth loss from different reasons.</li>
<li>The innovative approach could revolutionize dental care and bring relief to people suffering from missing teeth.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mainichi.jp/english/articles/20240503/p2a/00m/0sc/012000c</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZJapan to Test Tooth Regrowth Medicine from Sept. 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mastering Microsoft Flight Simulator with JavaScript Autopilot]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The tutorial presents a detailed walkthrough on developing JavaScript autopilot code for Microsoft Flight Simulator, enabling functions like auto-takeoff, waypoint navigation, terrain following, auto-landing, and flight plan saving/loading.</li>
<li>It introduces an upgraded version with a more sophisticated and user-centric method for piloting aircraft within the game.</li>
<li>Developers are motivated to delve into game scripting possibilities, with a quick setup option for instant flight engagement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pomax.github.io/are-we-flying/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZMastering Microsoft Flight Simulator with JavaScript Autopilot</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rescued Doves Typeface Unveiled from Thames]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Doves Type, an exclusive Arts and Crafts font from 1900, was discarded into the River Thames by its creator during a disagreement.</li>
<li>Graphic designer Robert Green salvaged some of the typeface from the riverbed in 2014, resulting in a digital version&#39;s creation.</li>
<li>Emery Walker&#39;s House hosts an exhibition showcasing the recovered Doves Type fragments and other Thames-discovered artifacts, while mudlarks persist in searching the river for historic relics, linking to London&#39;s history.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.artnet.com/art-world/doves-typeface-2454807</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZRescued Doves Typeface Unveiled from Thames</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unlocking ESP32-S3 SIMD Instructions: Challenges and Potential Benefits]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Espressif Systems introduced the ESP32-S3 SoC featuring SIMD instructions for programmers experienced in SIMD from other platforms.</li>
<li>The S3 outperforms older ESP32 CPUs but lacks detailed documentation and examples for effectively utilizing SIMD instructions, posing optimization challenges.</li>
<li>Despite limited instructions and memory alignment restrictions, programmers can enhance performance, particularly in functions like color conversion within imaging libraries with optimized code.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bitbanksoftware.blogspot.com/2024/01/surprise-esp32-s3-has-few-simd.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-06T00:00:00.000ZUnlocking ESP32-S3 SIMD Instructions: Challenges and Potential Benefits</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revived Dillo Project Releases Version 3.1.0]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Dillo project, dormant for almost 9 years, has been revived by the author who released version 3.1.0 after several months of work.</li>
<li>The revival includes creating a new mailing list, receiving donations via LiberaPay, bug fixes, and the addition of new features.</li>
<li>The author appreciates the contributions made and aims for the new version to be adopted by different distributions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dillo-browser.github.io/latest.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZRevived Dillo Project Releases Version 3.1.0</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't Make Me Fill Out Your Contact Form]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article critiques contact forms on websites for being problematic, citing issues like malfunctioning forms, poor user experience, and excessive personal data requests.</li>
<li>It recommends using email as a streamlined and user-centric option for communication and gathering feedback, emphasizing clear communication and accessibility for users.</li>
<li>Some entities deliberately complicate forms to sidestep regulations, underscoring the significance of facilitating user contact via clear communication channels like email.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://adamjones.me/blog/dont-use-contact-forms/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZDon&apos;t Make Me Fill Out Your Contact Form</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Develop a $20B Semiconductor Fab]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Semiconductor manufacturing is complex and precise, involving costly facilities, equipment, and safety measures to produce microchips.</li>
<li>Leading companies like Intel and Samsung invest heavily in modern fabs to meet the demand for advanced technology.</li>
<li>The semiconductor industry faces challenges due to the high costs of manufacturing, leading to a trend of companies adopting a fabless model by outsourcing chip production to foundries.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.construction-physics.com/p/how-to-build-a-20-billion-semiconductor</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZHow to Develop a $20B Semiconductor Fab</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Praise of Leisure: Bertrand Russell's Vision for a Balanced Society]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Bertrand Russell proposes a shift in societal values from glorifying work to valuing leisure, suggesting modern technology can maintain productivity with fewer working hours.</li>
<li>Russell criticizes the unequal distribution of wealth and power and questions the historical foundations of the obligation to work, advocating for a society where all can enjoy leisure and pursue their interests for a happier life.</li>
<li>His argument aims for a society where individuals have more leisure time, promoting a more content and tranquil way of living.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://harpers.org/archive/1932/10/in-praise-of-idleness/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZIn Praise of Leisure: Bertrand Russell&apos;s Vision for a Balanced Society</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ADA Lawsuit Raises Concerns Over Corporate Ties]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The American Diabetes Association settled a lawsuit for allegedly accepting corporate funds in return for promoting recipes that could be harmful to individuals with diabetes.</li>
<li>The ex-chief nutritionist, Elizabeth Hanna, filed the lawsuit, claiming pressure to endorse recipes with artificial sweeteners despite the associated risks.</li>
<li>The settlement enabled the ADA to sidestep additional investigation and potentially damaging disclosures, revealing insights into the organization&#39;s conduct and connections to corporate interests.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theguardian.com/global/commentisfree/2024/may/02/american-diabetes-association-lawsuit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZADA Lawsuit Raises Concerns Over Corporate Ties</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Verus: Verify Rust Code with Advanced Specifications]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Verus is a tool that verifies Rust code correctness by enabling developers to write specifications checked by solvers, supporting a subset of Rust and extending beyond the standard type system.</li>
<li>The project is actively developed, with incomplete documentation; users are advised to seek help on Zulip, aiming to verify concurrent code and welcoming contributions.</li>
<li>Users can experiment with Verus in-browser or pursue installation instructions for in-depth development, communicating and reporting issues on GitHub or Zulip.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/verus-lang/verus</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZVerus: Verify Rust Code with Advanced Specifications</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GPUDeploy.com: Revolutionizing GPU Access and Efficiency]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A startup transitioned from drone delivery to launch gpudeploy.com, a platform redirecting on-demand GPU instance traffic to available compute resources.</li>
<li>The website offers straightforward service without concealed charges, granting users access to GPUs such as H100s, RTX 4090s, and GTX 1080 Ti.</li>
<li>Seeking compute resources to link with their platform for potential return on investment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gpudeploy.com</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZGPUDeploy.com: Revolutionizing GPU Access and Efficiency</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Automated Hash Functions Outperform MurmurHash3]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text introduces the Hash Function Prospector tool, focusing on automated discovery of integer hash functions, particularly two-round permutations with low bias.</li>
<li>New hash functions like triple32, with bias measurements approaching the theoretical limit, are presented, outperforming established algorithms like MurmurHash3 on x86-64 architecture.</li>
<li>Code examples for implementing hash functions are offered, highlighting the significance of reversible operations and advising caution with C integer promotion rules.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/skeeto/hash-prospector</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZNew Automated Hash Functions Outperform MurmurHash3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vulture Decline Imperils Zoroastrian Burial Rites]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The decline of vultures in the Indian subcontinent is jeopardizing Zoroastrian burial customs, notably for the Parsi community that relies on vultures for body disposal at towers of silence.</li>
<li>Vulture population decrease is mainly attributed to poisoning from diclofenac given to cattle, prompting initiatives like banning the drug and captive vulture breeding as solutions.</li>
<li>Efforts such as prohibiting diclofenac usage and reintroducing captive-bred vultures into the wild aim to avert the extinction of vulture species.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/may/04/vulture-shortage-threatens-zoroastrian-burial-rites-india-iran-pakistan</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZVulture Decline Imperils Zoroastrian Burial Rites</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remembering Atari's Iconic Designer, Mike Jang]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mike Jang, a renowned Industrial Designer at Atari&#39;s coin-operated division, has passed away, leaving behind a legacy of iconic arcade cabinet designs like Missile Command and Star Wars.</li>
<li>Jang was known for his meticulous attention to detail, focus on refining ergonomics, and creating immersive physical interfaces for players, overseeing the production of games like Roadblasters.</li>
<li>His design heritage endures in the arcade hardware he crafted, and his work documents are archived at Stanford University for future research, marking his significant impact on the gaming sector.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arcadeblogger.com/2024/02/13/ataris-mike-jang/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZRemembering Atari&apos;s Iconic Designer, Mike Jang</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title
      ><![CDATA[Vera Rubin Observatory: Major Milestone as Mirror Receives First Reflective Coating]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Vera Rubin Observatory&#39;s primary/tertiary mirror has been coated with silver, a critical advancement in the telescope&#39;s construction.</li>
<li>The mirror&#39;s innovative design, featuring two optical surfaces with distinct curvatures, enables exceptional light collection and wide-field imaging capacity.</li>
<li>The successful 4.5-hour coating process signifies a major achievement in the observatory&#39;s journey towards achieving first light.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.universetoday.com/166842/vera-rubins-primary-mirror-gets-its-first-reflective-coating/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZVera Rubin Observatory: Major Milestone as Mirror Receives First Reflective Coating</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spotify's Backstage: Enterprise IT Tool Expansion]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Spotify has ventured into the enterprise and developer tools domain with its platform Backstage, offering customizable developer portals, initially launched as an open-source project in 2020.</li>
<li>The platform is now monetized through premium plug-ins and services, alongside the introduction of Spotify Portal, a low-/no-code internal developer portal, complemented by enterprise support and services.</li>
<li>The shift signifies Spotify&#39;s transformation into an enterprise-oriented developer tools firm, with upcoming additions of features and products to its portfolio.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2024/04/30/spotifys-getting-serious-about-its-enterprise-and-dev-tools-business-play/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZSpotify&apos;s Backstage: Enterprise IT Tool Expansion</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Budget Cuts Halt Mirror Fusion Test Facility]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Mirror Fusion Test Facility, a project focusing on nuclear fusion, was closed on its dedication day due to financial limitations, never being operational.</li>
<li>This project, using a magnetic mirror method to confine plasma for fusion reactions, was dismantled in 1998 after the Reagan administration&#39;s decision.</li>
<li>Recent advances like achieving the first net energy gain fusion reaction at the National Ignition Facility have sparked new optimism for the future of fusion research.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.beautifulpublicdata.com/the-mirror-fusion-test-facility/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZBudget Cuts Halt Mirror Fusion Test Facility</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sequoia: Accelerating LLM Serving on Consumer GPUs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Sequoia is a decoding framework designed for serving large language models (LLMs) on consumer GPUs without approximation, ensuring low latency.</li>
<li>It accelerates LLM serving by offloading tasks, offering scalability and robustness while adapting to various hardware platforms and model sizes.</li>
<li>Promising performance on current and upcoming hardware positions Sequoia as a versatile solution for hosting powerful LLMs and AI-generated content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://infini-ai-lab.github.io/Sequoia-Page/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZSequoia: Accelerating LLM Serving on Consumer GPUs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Judge Considers Sanctions in Google Monopoly Trial]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The US Department of Justice accused Google in the ongoing monopoly trial of intentionally destroying internal chats linked to antitrust violations, aiming to preserve its search monopoly.</li>
<li>Google&#39;s attorney argued that the deleted chats were insignificant for the case, while the judge raised concerns about Google&#39;s document retention practices and discussed potential sanctions against the company.</li>
<li>The DOJ requested four sanctions, including presuming the deleted chats were detrimental to Google and preventing Google from using lack of evidence as a defense in the trial, prompting debates on Google&#39;s motives for deleting chats and the implications of its chat policy on concealing antitrust violation evidence.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/05/judge-mulls-sanctions-over-googles-shocking-destruction-of-internal-chats/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-05T00:00:00.000ZJudge Considers Sanctions in Google Monopoly Trial</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DNS Leaks Exposed on Android: Serious Privacy Concerns]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Bugs in the Android OS can cause DNS leaks on devices, potentially compromising privacy when using certain apps with an active VPN.</li>
<li>DNS leaks may happen during VPN tunnel reconfigurations, or if apps lack a configured DNS server or use specific methods to resolve domain names.</li>
<li>A privacy app is developing temporary solutions to address the leaks, advising users to update the app for protection until Google resolves the underlying issues.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mullvad.net/en/blog/dns-traffic-can-leak-outside-the-vpn-tunnel-on-android</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZDNS Leaks Exposed on Android: Serious Privacy Concerns</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Natron Energy Launches Sodium Batteries in US]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Natron Energy has commenced manufacturing lithium-free sodium batteries in the US, presenting an eco-friendly and widely available substitute for lithium-ion batteries.</li>
<li>The sodium batteries boast faster charging rates, extended durability, and are crafted from easily accessible components, catering primarily to industrial backup power uses.</li>
<li>Future strategies involve broadening the battery application scope beyond industrial sectors to additional markets.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://newatlas.com/energy/natron-sodium-ion-battery-production-startt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZNatron Energy Launches Sodium Batteries in US</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Private Equity's Control Impacts Wheelchair Repair Times]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Private equity firms buying wheelchair manufacturers have caused significant delays in repairs for users like Maureen Amirault, affecting their mobility.</li>
<li>Disability advocates are advocating for better wheelchair services to address the repair time issue.</li>
<li>Acquisition by private equity firms resulted in prolonged repair times, prompting advocacy for improved wheelchair services.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.statnews.com/2024/05/01/wheelchair-repair-delay-numotion-national-seating-mobility/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZPrivate Equity&apos;s Control Impacts Wheelchair Repair Times</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BandMatch: Connecting Musicians to Form Bands]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>BandMatch is a platform facilitating musicians&#39; connections with nearby artists to create bands or work on projects collaboratively.</li>
<li>Users can discover details about upcoming concerts in their vicinity through the platform.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bandmatch.app</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZBandMatch: Connecting Musicians to Form Bands</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rare Brothers Grimm Fairy Tale Volumes Unearthed in Poland]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Researchers in Poland found 27 original volumes of Brothers Grimm fairy tales at Adam Mickiewicz University in Pozna, including rare prints with author footnotes, attracting interest from literary and folklore experts.</li>
<li>The discovery paves the way for more in-depth study on the Grimm brothers&#39; impact on global literature.</li>
<li>These books, possibly acquired after World War 2, hint at the possibility of other libraries holding works from the Grimm brothers&#39; personal collection.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://english.nv.ua/life/27-unique-volumes-of-grimm-brothers-fairy-tales-were-found-in-poland-50415035.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZRare Brothers Grimm Fairy Tale Volumes Unearthed in Poland</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oil Industry Collusion: Impact on Gas Prices]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 2021, the Federal Trade Commission uncovered an oil price-fixing scheme involving American oil firms and the Saudi government, inflating gas prices and burdening families with an average cost of $3,000.</li>
<li>American oil companies collaborated with OPEC to limit oil supply, bolstering prices and triggering financial consequences for consumers, leading to discussions on antitrust legal actions and governmental interference.</li>
<li>The FTC&#39;s investigation has initiated discussions and examinations concerning the impact of market dominance and price manipulation on inflation rates and corporate earnings.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thebignewsletter.com/p/an-oil-price-fixing-conspiracy-caused</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZOil Industry Collusion: Impact on Gas Prices</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improving Typography with CSS Text Box Trim]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The CSS Text Box Trim property eliminates leading whitespace from text, aiding in aligning text accurately with containers and elements.</li>
<li>Safari Technology Preview exclusively supports this property, beneficial for centering text in buttons, aligning icons, and maintaining design continuity.</li>
<li>Despite implementation challenges in major browsers, this feature holds potential for enhancing typographic precision and design consistency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/jantimon/text-box-trim-examples</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZImproving Typography with CSS Text Box Trim</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Mistral 7B: A Browser-Based Llama 3 Chatbot Powered by WebGPU]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author created Mistral 7B and Llama 3, web-based interfaces akin to ChatGPT, enhancing the WebLLM project&#39;s accessibility without needing installations or dependencies.</li>
<li>Mistral 7B and Llama 3 focus on therapy and coaching, prioritizing user privacy by keeping personal data stored locally on the user&#39;s computer.</li>
<li>Best suited for Chrome or Edge on Desktops, Mistral 7B and Llama 3 may expand browser support to include WebGPU, enabling quicker subsequent loads as the model is cached after the initial download.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/abi/secret-llama</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Mistral 7B: A Browser-Based Llama 3 Chatbot Powered by WebGPU</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimizing 1024-Bit Primes with Rust: A Performance Breakthrough]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author explores prime numbers by creating 1024-bit primes for the RSA Algorithm in Rust, implementing Fermat&#39;s Little Theorem, Miller-Rabin primality test, and a custom BigInt data structure.</li>
<li>By leveraging parallel processing and optimized algorithms, the author achieves finding a 1024-bit prime in about 40ms on average, demonstrating considerable performance enhancements.</li>
<li>The project, while not cryptographically secure, offers valuable insights and learning opportunities in the realm of prime number generation and algorithm optimization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://glitchcomet.com/articles/1024-bit-primes/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZOptimizing 1024-Bit Primes with Rust: A Performance Breakthrough</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discord Arbitration Opt-out: Deadline in 30 Days]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post discusses CSS code for web application styling, covering layout, color theming, and specific element adjustments.</li>
<li>It also provides details on opting out of arbitration on Discord within 30 days via email.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bsky.app/profile/silverwuffamute.bsky.social/post/3kqbd476nvk2i</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZDiscord Arbitration Opt-out: Deadline in 30 Days</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Links Executive Pay to Security Improvements]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft has been criticized for security breaches, impacting trust from various stakeholders in recent years.</li>
<li>In response, Microsoft launched the &quot;Secure Future Initiative&quot; to prioritize security by linking executive pay to meeting security goals.</li>
<li>The initiative includes plans for improved security practices like multifactor authentication, least-privilege access, and enhanced network monitoring, with CEO Satya Nadella stressing the significance of security over new features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/05/microsoft-ties-executive-pay-to-security-following-multiple-failures-and-breaches/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZMicrosoft Links Executive Pay to Security Improvements</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo targets 8k GitHub repos for Yuzu Switch emulator takedowns]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nintendo sent out more than 8,000 DMCA takedown notices to GitHub repos containing code from the Yuzu Switch emulator, accused of promoting piracy.</li>
<li>Yuzu emulator recently settled a $2.4 million lawsuit with Nintendo before the flood of takedown notices on GitHub.</li>
<li>Legal actions by Nintendo against emulators, like Yuzu, could affect endeavors aimed at preserving games.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.engadget.com/nintendo-blitzes-github-with-over-8000-emulator-related-dmca-takedowns-200021877.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZNintendo targets 8k GitHub repos for Yuzu Switch emulator takedowns</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Journey of Discovery: From Web Development to Bike Repair]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 2020, the narrator found a passion for bike repair by working on two old bicycles, learning through trial and error and online resources.</li>
<li>This hobby shifted their perspective on work, tangible objects, and fulfillment compared to their web development day job.</li>
<li>Embracing hands-on work has brought newfound satisfaction and a deeper appreciation for craftsmanship and its impact on both objects and individuals.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tegowerk.eu/posts/bicycle-repair/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-04T00:00:00.000ZA Journey of Discovery: From Web Development to Bike Repair</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creating "ShapeUp": A 3D Modeler in C]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Daniel Hooper developed a 3D modeler named &quot;ShapeUp&quot; during a week-long programming event using C and ray marched signed distance fields for feasibility.</li>
<li>He managed shapes with static memory allocation and incorporated a user interface, GLSL shader generator, mouse selection, and marching cubes export.</li>
<li>Despite challenges with the raylib library, Hooper completed the project, producing a functional 3D modeler with 2300 lines of C and 250 lines of GLSL code, available online for viewing and testing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://danielchasehooper.com/posts/shapeup/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZCreating &quot;ShapeUp&quot;: A 3D Modeler in C</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mastering Cryptography: Dive into Dan Boneh's In-Depth Course]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Stanford University offers an online cryptography course by Dan Boneh, covering stream ciphers, block ciphers, key exchange, and more.</li>
<li>The course provides video lectures, slides, and a free textbook for a comprehensive understanding of cryptography topics.</li>
<li>Students can explore topics like message integrity, digital signatures, and public-key encryption with in-depth explanations and real-world applications each week.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://crypto.stanford.edu/~dabo/courses/OnlineCrypto/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZMastering Cryptography: Dive into Dan Boneh&apos;s In-Depth Course</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cardio Fitness: Key Predictor of Health Risks]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article assesses numerous studies examining how cardiorespiratory fitness (CRF) affects mortality, chronic diseases, and overall well-being, underlining the significance of regular physical activity in maintaining good CRF.</li>
<li>It stresses the robust predictive nature of CRF for various health outcomes, suggesting the routine measurement of CRF in clinical settings for health assessment and interventions.</li>
<li>More research is necessary to address existing gaps in the literature and determine a causal link between CRF and health results.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bjsm.bmj.com/content/58/10/556</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZCardio Fitness: Key Predictor of Health Risks</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crafting an Innovative Rocket Engine: The Journey of E2 Engine Development]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The E2 Engine created by ABL is a durable rocket engine powered by Jet-A and liquid oxygen.</li>
<li>Despite lacking direct propulsion experience, Ryan Kuhn effectively led the program by prioritizing curiosity, intuition, and practical engineering solutions.</li>
<li>The article details the design process, with a focus on the gas generator engine cycle, turbopump design, challenges faced in developing engine components like combustion chambers and impellers, and the team at AFRL making notable progress in engine development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.ablspacesystems.com/p/building-e2</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZCrafting an Innovative Rocket Engine: The Journey of E2 Engine Development</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Developing "sqlite-vec": A New Vector Search Solution in SQLite]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Alex Garcia introduces sqlite-vec, a new SQLite extension for vector search, designed to replace sqlite-vss, offering custom SQL functions and virtual tables.</li>
<li>Written solely in C, sqlite-vec targets speed and embeddability, boasting cross-platform support for WebAssembly and mobile devices, along with improved memory management.</li>
<li>The extension, currently in progress, is set for an upcoming initial release; the developer is seeking sponsorship opportunities to advance the project.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://alexgarcia.xyz/blog/2024/building-new-vector-search-sqlite/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZDeveloping &quot;sqlite-vec&quot;: A New Vector Search Solution in SQLite</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft bans U.S. police from using facial recognition AI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft prohibits U.S. police from employing generative AI for facial recognition in Azure OpenAI Service to address concerns about biases and risks in law enforcement technology.</li>
<li>The ban covers real-time facial recognition on mobile cameras for U.S. police but not international law enforcement agencies.</li>
<li>This policy shift stems from criticism of utilizing AI in law enforcement and highlights Microsoft&#39;s collaboration with OpenAI across various government entities like the Department of Defense.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2024/05/02/microsoft-bans-u-s-police-departments-from-using-enterprise-ai-tool/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZMicrosoft bans U.S. police from using facial recognition AI</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Backblaze Q1 2024 Drive Stats: Reliable 16TB Models Lead the Pack]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Backblaze published their Q1 2024 drive stats report, examining 279,572 hard drives, revealing a 1.41% annualized failure rate overall.</li>
<li>The report highlights zero failures in three drive models, discusses drive sizes, manufacturers, and noteworthy findings like the reliability of 6TB Seagate drives and the transition from 4TB Toshiba to 16TB models.</li>
<li>The study indicates a shift towards older drive models failing later in their lifespan, recommending specific drive models for reliability and offering the Drive Stats dataset for free download, accompanied by insights from Andy Klein on cloud storage and computer security.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-drive-stats-for-q1-2024/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZBackblaze Q1 2024 Drive Stats: Reliable 16TB Models Lead the Pack</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RISC OS 5.30: A Different Computing Era for Raspberry Pi]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>RISC OS 5.30 is the latest version of the original Arm OS, compatible with Arm-based platforms like Raspberry Pi, featuring Wi-Fi support and various applications.</li>
<li>The OS, led by Steve Revill from RISC OS Open project, focuses on proper release execution, despite its unique GUI and limitations, offering productivity apps and development tools for modern hardware.</li>
<li>Not supporting vintage application emulation, RISC OS, providing a throwback to a different computing era, is free, open-source, and caters to Raspberry Pi models up to 4 or 400, delivering a distinct user experience from contemporary operating systems.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2024/05/02/rool_530_is_here/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZRISC OS 5.30: A Different Computing Era for Raspberry Pi</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boeing Whistleblower's Death Sparks Investigation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Whistleblower Josh Dean, known for exposing safety issues with Boeing planes, has tragically passed away from an unexpected illness, following another whistleblower&#39;s recent death.</li>
<li>Dean, a former quality auditor at Boeing supplier Spirit AeroSystems, accused senior management of overlooking manufacturing defects on the 737 MAX, with some of his claims corroborated by colleagues.</li>
<li>The deaths of both Dean and John Barnett, Boeing veteran, have sparked concerns due to their close timing and circumstances, prompting ongoing police investigations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.newshub.co.nz/home/world/2024/05/whistleblower-josh-dean-of-boeing-supplier-spirit-aerosystems-dies-of-sudden-illness.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZBoeing Whistleblower&apos;s Death Sparks Investigation</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Second Boeing Whistleblower Dies Abruptly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A second Boeing whistleblower has tragically passed away.</li>
<li>This incident was reported on May 2, 2024, with ongoing updates provided.</li>
<li><ul>
<li></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/boeing-whistleblower-joshua-dean-dies-sudden-illness-1896401</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZSecond Boeing Whistleblower Dies Abruptly</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Piccolo: Rust-Based Lua Interpreter with Unique Features]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores Piccolo, a stackless Lua interpreter developed in Rust, focusing on safe sandboxing and resiliency.</li>
<li>Unique features include symmetric coroutines and custom scheduling, with a spotlight on efficient garbage collection and interrupting running code.</li>
<li>Emphasis on integrating seamlessly with Rust ecosystem and creating unobtrusive interpreters for diverse systems, potential for Rust coroutines in Lua for streamlined asynchronous programming.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://kyju.org/blog/piccolo-a-stackless-lua-interpreter/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZPiccolo: Rust-Based Lua Interpreter with Unique Features</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Orangutan Exhibits Healing Behavior Using Plant]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Sumatran orangutan named Rakus used a plant paste to heal a wound on his cheek, marking the first observation of a wild animal using a medicinal plant for treatment.</li>
<li>The behavior suggests a possible connection to the shared evolutionary history between humans and great apes, showing similarities in medicine use.</li>
<li>Rakus&#39; wound healed in about a month after applying the plant poultice, indicating a potential learned behavior from his group members.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-68942123</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZOrangutan Exhibits Healing Behavior Using Plant</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hacker Search: Semantic Search Engine for Hacker News]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Jonathan developed Hacker Search, a semantic search engine for Hacker News, utilizing OpenAI&#39;s embedding models and traditional indexes for scraped content.</li>
<li>The search engine enables users to easily discover top links and summaries by entering keywords or descriptions, with plans to expand into recommending stories based on interests.</li>
<li>Despite competition, Hacker Search outperforms in keyword/sentence searches, offering users a superior experience when navigating Hacker News content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hackersearch.net</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZHacker Search: Semantic Search Engine for Hacker News</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Innovative CSS Art: A Single Div Showcase]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;A Single Div&quot; is a CSS drawing project by Lynn Fisher presented on GitHub between 2014-2019, showcasing diverse designs crafted using a single HTML element.</li>
<li>The project provides the opportunity to support the artist by purchasing a coffee and exploring additional single div designs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://a.singlediv.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZInnovative CSS Art: A Single Div Showcase</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Startup Accelerator Newchip Folds: Founders Lose Companies]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Newchip, a startup accelerator, declared bankruptcy, leading to the auctioning of warrants from over 1,000 startups, causing founders like Lacey Hunter of TechAid to lose their companies.</li>
<li>CEO Andrew Ryan received criticism for his management style, and missed opportunities in managing warrants, valued at potentially $500 million, worsened the company&#39;s financial situation.</li>
<li>Deal Syndicate acquired a significant number of warrants, with more expected to be sold shortly, highlighting the risks associated with accelerator programs through the experiences of founders like Garrett Temple.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2024/05/02/they-thought-they-were-joining-an-accelerator-instead-they-lost-their-startups/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-03T00:00:00.000ZStartup Accelerator Newchip Folds: Founders Lose Companies</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech Job Listings: Companies Hiring in May 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Job board for companies to post listings, specifying remote, onsite, intern, or visa requirements; no recruiting firms allowed.</li>
<li>Encourages readers to contact only if genuinely interested and redirects job seekers to other search threads.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40224213</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-02T00:00:00.000ZTech Job Listings: Companies Hiring in May 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senators request FTC probe into automakers' location data sharing]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Senators Wyden and Markey urged the Federal Trade Commission to probe leading automakers for sharing customers&#39; location data with law enforcement sans warrants.</li>
<li>Few automakers demand warrants for this data, while others release it upon receiving subpoenas, raising concerns about privacy and repercussions, particularly post the Supreme Court&#39;s Dobbs decision on reproductive rights.</li>
<li>The request highlights the senators&#39; worry over inadequate privacy safeguards in the handling of location data by automakers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.wyden.senate.gov/news/press-releases/wyden-markey-reveal-automakers-provide-detailed-location-information-to-law-enforcement-without-a-warrant-rarely-notify-car-owners-request-ftc-investigate-broken-promises-to-protect-drivers-privacy</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-02T00:00:00.000ZSenators request FTC probe into automakers&apos; location data sharing</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mRNA Vaccine Shows Promise Against Glioblastoma]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>University of Florida researchers created an mRNA cancer vaccine targeting glioblastoma by reprogramming the immune system to combat the cancer.</li>
<li>Tested on four adults and ten pet dogs with brain tumors, the vaccine demonstrated encouraging outcomes in stimulating the immune system against cancer cells.</li>
<li>Using the patient&#39;s tumor cells and lipid nanoparticles for delivery, this personalized vaccine is advancing to an extended Phase I clinical trial for brain cancer, potentially transforming cancer immunotherapy.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.insideprecisionmedicine.com/topics/oncology/mrna-cancer-vaccine-reprograms-immune-system-to-tackle-glioblastoma/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-02T00:00:00.000ZmRNA Vaccine Shows Promise Against Glioblastoma</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cognition: Redefining Metaprogramming with Antisyntax]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The document critiques Lisp&#39;s syntax limitations and introduces Cognition, a new fully postfix language utilizing antisyntax.</li>
<li>Cognition&#39;s development is discussed, emphasizing tokenization, delimiters, ignored characters, specific commands, and characters, along with customizable tokenizer delimiters and faliases.</li>
<li>It explores VMACROs, recursive word definitions, incorporating Brainfuck dialect, and Cognition&#39;s applications in string processing and Symbolic AI, highlighting its automation of syntax and philosophical elegance in programming.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ret2pop.nullring.xyz/blog/cognition.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-02T00:00:00.000ZCognition: Redefining Metaprogramming with Antisyntax</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[16-Year-Old Launches Factful: AI Startup Fighting Misinformation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Andrew, a high school student, developed Factful, an AI-driven web app to authenticate online content for accuracy and credibility beyond grammar checks.</li>
<li>Factful assesses context, factuality, coherence, and more, aiming to combat misinformation and uphold content integrity in the information age.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to test the free beta version of Factful on their website while providing feedback and support to Andrew.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://factful.io/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-02T00:00:00.000Z16-Year-Old Launches Factful: AI Startup Fighting Misinformation</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Create Sleek Startup Demos: Unveiling the Tools]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>People are making product demo videos by zooming in on the active function, sparking curiosity about the tools for creating such content.</li>
<li>The author shared a product demo video link as an example, highlighting the interest in tools that seem not readily available online for this specific video style.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40231790</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-02T00:00:00.000ZHow to Create Sleek Startup Demos: Unveiling the Tools</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beware of AWS S3 Cost Amplification Threat]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The AWS S3 Denial of Wallet amplification attack poses a risk to companies storing large data files on AWS S3, causing unexpected cost variations due to data transfer cost calculation methods.</li>
<li>This attack can lead to substantial unexpected expenses for companies, regardless of whether the data is publicly available, stemming from discrepancies between received data and billed amounts.</li>
<li>Mitigation measures involve implementing cost alerts, tracking API requests, and controlling access to S3 buckets to prevent potential financial exploitation by malicious actors.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://blog.limbus-medtec.com/the-aws-s3-denial-of-wallet-amplification-attack-bc5a97cc041d?gi=67ac052cc1ce</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-02T00:00:00.000ZBeware of AWS S3 Cost Amplification Threat</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fresh Scrutiny on Tire Emissions' Toxicity]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article highlights the potential harm of tire emissions, specifically focusing on the chemical 6PPD, which poses risks to the environment and human health.</li>
<li>Researchers have discovered a connection between 6PPD and fish fatalities, leading regulators to examine this chemical closely.</li>
<li>California has moved to regulate 6PPD in tires, prompting manufacturers to explore alternative options due to the concerning effects of tire emissions on air and water quality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-05-toxicity-fresh-scrutiny-salmon-die.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-02T00:00:00.000ZFresh Scrutiny on Tire Emissions&apos; Toxicity</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech Job Seekers Showcase for May 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Job seekers can share their details on the platform, including location, tech skills, resume, and email for job opportunities.</li>
<li>Only individuals seeking work should post, and readers are advised to contact the provided email addresses for job inquiries.</li>
<li>Agencies, recruiters, and job boards are prohibited from using this platform.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40224210</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-02T00:00:00.000ZTech Job Seekers Showcase for May 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reviving Neofetch: New Fork Ensures Community Development]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Neofetch, a command-line interface tool for showing system information, has been archived because of inactivity.</li>
<li>A fork has been established to guarantee ongoing community development, tackling the backlog of pull requests for potential improvements.</li>
<li>The fork will address and merge incomplete requests, potentially leading to overhauls of existing features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/LorenDB/neofetch</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-02T00:00:00.000ZReviving Neofetch: New Fork Ensures Community Development</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US DEA Proposes Reclassifying Marijuana]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration is considering reclassifying marijuana to a less dangerous drug, potentially reshaping drug policies in the country.</li>
<li>President Biden backs a review of federal marijuana laws and has granted clemency to individuals with possession convictions.</li>
<li>The proposed change may align federal drug policies with state legalization movements and appeal to younger voters, potentially benefiting President Biden&#39;s public image.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://apnews.com/article/marijuana-biden-dea-criminal-justice-pot-f833a8dae6ceb31a8658a5d65832a3b8</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZUS DEA Proposes Reclassifying Marijuana</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Musical Notation in CSS Grid]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Scribe prototype utilizes CSS Grid to generate a grid-like musical staff for enhanced music notation accessibility and smoothness on the web.</li>
<li>It demonstrates how to position musical symbols on a stave through CSS grid and data attributes, modify layout and spacing using CSS, and highlights the system&#39;s constraints and potential enhancements.</li>
<li>Additional features include stave splitting for drums and piano, multi-stave rendering, and offers a transposable lead sheet for a jazz standard.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://cruncher.ch/blog/printing-music-with-css-grid/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZExploring Musical Notation in CSS Grid</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Streamline Infrastructure Automation with Pyinfra]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>pyinfra is a Python tool for infrastructure automation, featuring speed, scalability, and versatility for ad-hoc commands, service deployment, and configuration management.</li>
<li>It offers fast execution, instant debugging, idempotent operations, and integration with connectors, making it a comprehensive solution for infrastructure automation.</li>
<li>Users can install pyinfra via pip, run commands over SSH, define states using operations, and deploy tasks using Python code, with the flexibility to extend it using the Python package ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pyinfra.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZStreamline Infrastructure Automation with Pyinfra</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borgo: A Statically Typed Language Compiling to Go]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Borgo is a new programming language that transpiles to Go, combining the simplicity of Go with the expressiveness of Rust.</li>
<li>It includes algebraic data types, pattern matching, error handling with the ? operator, and is compatible with existing Go packages.</li>
<li>Borgo syntax resembles Rust, with optional semi-colons, and offers features like Option for nil handling, Result for multiple return values, demonstrated through a guessing game example.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/borgo-lang/borgo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZBorgo: A Statically Typed Language Compiling to Go</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reddit Exposed: Bots Repost Thread 10 Months Later]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Reddit users Blaze and Lemmy.world found bots reposting an entire thread, comment by comment, identically, after 10 months.</li>
<li>This discovery highlights the presence of bots on Reddit, engaging in repetitive behaviors and potentially manipulating discussions.</li>
<li>The incident raises concerns about the authenticity of user interactions and content on the platform, emphasizing the importance of detecting and addressing bot activities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lemmy.blahaj.zone/post/11615413</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZReddit Exposed: Bots Repost Thread 10 Months Later</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Extension.js: Streamlined Web Extension Creation Tool]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Extension.js is a development tool for browser extensions that streamlines the process by offering built-in support for TypeScript, WebAssembly, React, and modern JavaScript.</li>
<li>It removes the requirement for complex configurations and setup instructions, enabling developers to concentrate on coding.</li>
<li>The tool can be seamlessly integrated into npm scripts, simplifying the creation of cross-browser extensions without the need for build configuration. Originally created to educate on extension development, it is now open for public use with feedback encouraged.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/cezaraugusto/extension.js</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZExtension.js: Streamlined Web Extension Creation Tool</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The File Filesystem: Manipulating Modern Data with Unix Tools]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>ffs is a file filesystem that lets users mount semi-structured data such as JSON on a Unix filesystem, allowing manipulation with standard shell tools.</li>
<li>It supports JSON, YAML, and TOML formats, enabling in-place file editing, requiring FUSE on Linux and macFUSE on macOS, and licensed under GPLv3.</li>
<li>Developed by mgree, ffs offers a different approach for command-line data processing compared to tools like jq and gron.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mgree.github.io/ffs/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZThe File Filesystem: Manipulating Modern Data with Unix Tools</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Penpot 2.0: The New Web-Based Open-Source Design Tool for Seamless Collaboration]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Penpot 2.0 is a new release of a web-based open-source design tool that promotes collaboration between designers and developers.</li>
<li>Users can self-host Penpot, benefiting from its integrations, open design approach, and supportive community, with testimonials highlighting its user-friendly controls and developer-focused functionalities.</li>
<li>The tool leverages web and development standards cleverly to enhance the design and development process, fostering a seamless workflow, as showcased in the Penpot Fest conference fostering collaboration between designers and developers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://penpot.app/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZPenpot 2.0: The New Web-Based Open-Source Design Tool for Seamless Collaboration</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Europe's Entrepreneurial Wake-Up Call]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author challenges stereotypes by showcasing the hard work and risk-taking mentality of European entrepreneurs, countering the notion of Europeans as lazy and risk-averse compared to Americans.</li>
<li>Suggestions include establishing a standardized legal entity in the EU, enhancing English education, and striving to build a unified business market to address hurdles like regulatory variations and limited early-stage support for startups.</li>
<li>These proposals aim to foster a more conducive environment for entrepreneurship in Europe and encourage policymakers to rethink strategies for boosting the continent&#39;s entrepreneurial landscape.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://klinger.io/posts/eu-acc</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZEurope&apos;s Entrepreneurial Wake-Up Call</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Neural Networks with Differentiable Programming]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Alices Adventures in a Differentiable Wonderland&quot; is a book introducing neural networks and differentiable programming, emphasizing automatic differentiation to optimize functions.</li>
<li>The book covers design techniques for sequences, graphs, texts, and audios, focusing on convolutional, attentional, and recurrent blocks, and uses PyTorch and JAX to explain advanced models like large language models and multimodal architectures.</li>
<li>Additional chapters will delve into topics like model re-use, density estimation, conditional computation, and model debugging, aiming to bridge theory and practical code implementation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sscardapane.it/alice-book</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZExploring Neural Networks with Differentiable Programming</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tesla lays off entire Supercharger team]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tesla is carrying out additional layoffs, with the entire Supercharger team being impacted by the reductions.</li>
<li>The company&#39;s decision to include the Supercharger team in the cuts has drawn attention due to the importance of the Supercharger network in Tesla&#39;s infrastructure.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://electrek.co/2024/04/29/tesla-conducting-more-layoffs-including-entire-supercharger-team/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZTesla lays off entire Supercharger team</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DEA to Reclassify Cannabis from Schedule I to III]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The DEA will reclassify cannabis from Schedule I to Schedule III based on a recommendation from the Department of Health and Human Services, recognizing its therapeutic benefits.</li>
<li>Despite the reclassification, challenges remain due to discrepancies between state and federal cannabis laws.</li>
<li>The process involves review by the White House Office of Management and Budget, public feedback, administrative hearings, and a final decision before any changes are implemented.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://norml.org/blog/2024/04/30/dea-accepts-health-agencys-recommendation-to-reclassify-cannabis/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZDEA to Reclassify Cannabis from Schedule I to III</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unlocking Creativity with StoryDiffusion]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>StoryDiffusion is a versatile tool utilizing consistent self-attention to create impressive comics, high-quality videos, and maintain character consistency.</li>
<li>It generates consistent cartoon character images, manages multiple character IDs concurrently, and can incorporate user-input images as conditions.</li>
<li>Inspired by Bulma&#39;s style, the tool employs a motion predictor to enhance its output quality and uniqueness.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://storydiffusion.github.io/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZUnlocking Creativity with StoryDiffusion</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arti: Rust Project Implementing Tor Anonymity Protocols]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Arti is a Rust project that implements Tor anonymity protocols, providing a functional Tor client with early support for onion services.</li>
<li>Development is ongoing to enhance security to match the C Tor implementation, making it currently suitable for experimental purposes only.</li>
<li>The most recent release is version 1.2.0, offering various resources like README, source repository, API documentation, contribution guidelines, FAQs, and Tor-related details.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tpo.pages.torproject.net/core/arti/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-05-01T00:00:00.000ZArti: Rust Project Implementing Tor Anonymity Protocols</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Webb Reveals Horsehead Nebula in Unprecedented Detail]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The NASA/ESA/CSA James Webb Space Telescope captured high-resolution infrared images of the Horsehead Nebula in the Orion constellation, showcasing its intricate features and composition.</li>
<li>The observations with Webb&#39;s MIRI and NIRCam instruments unveiled detailed structures and patterns in the nebula, enabling astronomers to delve into the physical and chemical processes shaping this area and its evolution.</li>
<li>Webb, a collaboration between ESA, NASA, and CSA, stands as the most massive and impactful telescope in space, providing crucial insights for future astronomical investigations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/Webb/Webb_captures_iconic_Horsehead_Nebula_in_unprecedented_detail</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZWebb Reveals Horsehead Nebula in Unprecedented Detail</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Czech Republic couple exposed as GRU spies in Europe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A husband and wife in the Czech Republic have been identified as GRU spies, participating in bombings and poisonings throughout Europe.</li>
<li>The involvement of the couple in such dangerous activities highlights the extensive reach and operations of the GRU in European regions.</li>
<li>This revelation underscores the ongoing threat posed by state-sponsored espionage and covert operations in international affairs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://theins.ru/en/politics/271205</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZCzech Republic couple exposed as GRU spies in Europe</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Privacy-Friendly Menstruation Tracking App Keeps Data Secure]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author developed a period tracking app due to privacy worries about existing apps storing data online.</li>
<li>The app has a straightforward calendar layout, and it only stores data locally on the user&#39;s device, addressing privacy concerns.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=earlyowlsoftware.justme.justme&amp;hl=en_US</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZPrivacy-Friendly Menstruation Tracking App Keeps Data Secure</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Internet Archive's Battle for Survival]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Internet Archive is entangled in the &quot;Hachette v. Internet Archive&quot; lawsuit over copyright infringement via their Controlled Digital Lending program, risking their archival work.</li>
<li>The GNOME Foundation is encountering financial struggles, depleting savings and potentially considering staff layoffs.</li>
<li>Microsoft unveiled the historic MS-DOS 4.0 source code, sparking authenticity and compilation concerns, while Red Hat is under fire for alleged ethics oversights and fostering a culture of silence.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lunduke.locals.com/post/5556650/the-internet-archives-last-ditch-effort-to-save-itself</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZInternet Archive&apos;s Battle for Survival</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Advanced GPT-4.5 Testing on LMSYS Platform]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The gpt2-chatbot is an advanced AI model accessible on chat.lmsys.org for chatting and benchmarking, exhibiting high performance akin to GPT-4 and Claude Opus.</li>
<li>Speculated as an early version of GPT-4.5, leveraging techniques like Chain-of-Thought, it raises discussions about ties to OpenAI and LMSYS, potentially for data collection.</li>
<li>Users are urged to test the model, offer feedback, note specific rate limitations, and utilize unique tokens for inference, advised to assess information with skepticism and evidence-based reasoning.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rentry.co/GPT2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZAdvanced GPT-4.5 Testing on LMSYS Platform</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Paint Splatters as Valid Perl Programs (2019)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Colin McMillen&#39;s paper presented at SIGBOVIK 2019 delves into generating paint splatters that do not form valid Perl programs.</li>
<li>Using OCR software, McMillen discovered that only 93% of paint splatters were recognized as valid Perl programs.</li>
<li>The paper showcases examples of paint splatters that failed to qualify as valid Perl code, along with supplementary materials like a gallery of paint splatters and their corresponding valid Perl counterparts for deeper analysis.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mcmillen.dev/sigbovik/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZExploring Paint Splatters as Valid Perl Programs (2019)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revamping a Consumer NAS with a Custom Backplane]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author customized their Terramaster F2-221 NAS by creating a new backplane, expanding SATA ports with an ASM1061 PCIe controller, and incorporating an NVMe SSD for enhanced performance.</li>
<li>Despite initial worries about BIOS compatibility, the author&#39;s thorough research, PCB prototype design, and design refinements led to successful outcomes.</li>
<li>The project details and outcomes are available for sharing on GitHub, showcasing a DIY approach to improving NAS functionality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://codedbearder.com/posts/f3-backplane/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZRevamping a Consumer NAS with a Custom Backplane</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why SQLite Prefers Bytecode Compilation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The draft examines the utilization of bytecode and a tree-of-objects method in SQL database engines, with a particular emphasis on SQLite. It elaborates on the benefits of bytecode compilation, including enhanced readability, easier debugging, incremental execution, reduced size, and potentially improved performance.</li>
<li>Additionally, it delves into the advantages of transforming code into a tree of objects, enabling adaptable query planning choices and facilitating the parallelization of dataflow programs.</li>
<li>The document also defines bytecode and abstract syntax trees (AST), shedding light on the development and debugging procedures within SQLite.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sqlite.org/draft/whybytecode.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZWhy SQLite Prefers Bytecode Compilation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FCC Fines Wireless Carriers $200M for Location Data Misuse]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The FCC fined AT&amp;T, Sprint, T-Mobile, and Verizon around $200 million for unlawfully sharing customers&#39; location data without consent or proper safeguards.</li>
<li>Carriers sold location information to third parties without customer consent and continued doing so despite ineffective safeguards, leading to FCC investigations.</li>
<li>The FCC underscored the importance of safeguarding personal data and ensuring affirmative customer consent, establishing the Privacy and Data Protection Task Force to tackle privacy issues in the telecom sector.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-402213A1.txt</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZFCC Fines Wireless Carriers $200M for Location Data Misuse</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot Workspace: Enhancing AI Model Relevance]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) leverages multiple data sources to supply generative AI models with up-to-date information and organizational knowledge.</li>
<li>RAG assists in ensuring that AI models remain current and pertinent by incorporating diverse data inputs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.blog/2024-04-29-github-copilot-workspace/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZGitHub Copilot Workspace: Enhancing AI Model Relevance</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple mandated to open iPadOS to sideloading within 6 months, EU ruling]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The EU has ordered Apple to permit sideloading on iPadOS and adhere to Digital Markets Act rules, like the iPhone, in six months.</li>
<li>This decision aims to enhance app flexibility and usage on Apple devices, possibly making iPads more suitable as laptop alternatives.</li>
<li>Apple might encounter additional scrutiny and necessary adjustments to meet EU standards, with recent App Store policy revisions potentially linked to compliance efforts with the DMA.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/apple/2024/04/apple-must-open-ipados-to-sideloading-within-6-months-eu-says/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZApple mandated to open iPadOS to sideloading within 6 months, EU ruling</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Accidental Registrations: Iceland's Presidential Race Blunder]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>11 individuals unintentionally became candidates for the Icelandic presidency due to a digital endorsement process flaw where users confused the &quot;Log in&quot; button for endorsing a candidate.</li>
<li>Journalists unveiling the problem prompted a redesign of the webpage to enhance clarity and avoid future accidental registrations, stressing the significance of distinct CTAs and visual hierarchy for better user experience.</li>
<li>The incident underscores the need for intuitive design elements to prevent user errors and ensure seamless navigation on digital platforms.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://uxdesign.cc/how-do-you-accidentally-run-for-president-of-iceland-0d71a4785a1e</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZAccidental Registrations: Iceland&apos;s Presidential Race Blunder</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Threlte: Declarative 3D Web Framework with Svelte and Three.js]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Threlte is a 3D web framework based on Svelte and Three.js, providing declarative component scaling and comprehensive access to Three.js functionalities.</li>
<li>It offers integrations for physics engines, animation libraries, and GLTF file conversion, along with various components and utilities that support custom props and events through plugins.</li>
<li>The framework has garnered praise from developers and creators, with accessible documentation and an inviting community on Discord for new members to delve deeper into Threlte.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://threlte.xyz/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZThrelte: Declarative 3D Web Framework with Svelte and Three.js</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Regulating AI: Balancing Innovation and Safety]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SB-1047, a bill targeting AI development safety, raises worries about stifling open-source innovation and decreasing overall safety, per AI expert Jeremy Howard.</li>
<li>Howard emphasizes that the bill&#39;s constraints might diminish transparency, collaboration, diversity, and resilience in the AI sector, proposing regulatory focus on AI usage over development to enhance transparency, collaboration, and invest in AI expertise.</li>
<li>The bill&#39;s broad definitions, hefty requirements, and penalties could impede open-source progress, drive talent away from California, centralize power in big corporations, and slow AI research, compelling policymakers to consider impacts on small businesses and innovation while addressing concerns on open-source development and entry barriers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.answer.ai/posts/2024-04-29-sb1047.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZRegulating AI: Balancing Innovation and Safety</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unraveling the Mystery: Disappearance of Revolutionary Tool FireChat]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FireChat was a groundbreaking tool enabling communication without internet access, favored by protesters worldwide for bypassing authoritarian restrictions.</li>
<li>Praised for its mesh network tech, FireChat suddenly vanished in February 2020, sparking speculation about its closure motives.</li>
<li>Many believe FireChat&#39;s disappearance was due to it posing a threat to the systems it circumvented.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fromjason.xyz/p/notebook/firechat-was-a-tool-for-revolution-then-it-disappeared/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-30T00:00:00.000ZUnraveling the Mystery: Disappearance of Revolutionary Tool FireChat</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R. Bradley Lathe: A Symbol of Human Ingenuity]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The website lathes.co.uk offers a variety of machine tools for sale, including manuals, catalogues, belts, books, and accessories.</li>
<li>A notable highlight is the R. Bradley Lathe, which was crafted in a Prisoner of War camp, demonstrating human creativity and resourcefulness.</li>
<li>For further inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:tony@lathes.co.uk">tony@lathes.co.uk</a> for more information.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://www.lathes.co.uk/bradley-pow-lathe/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZR. Bradley Lathe: A Symbol of Human Ingenuity</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reinventing Zilog's Z80 CPU: A Modern Open-Source Silicon Clone]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Zilog has declared the End-of-Life for the popular 8-bit CPU Z80, spurring the open-source community to work on a Free and Open Source Silicon alternative for it.</li>
<li>The aim is to develop a replacement compatible with 8-bit home computers like the ZX Spectrum, with the first production of FOSS Z80 expected in June 2024, utilizing OpenROAD flow and a 130 nm Skywater Process Design Kit.</li>
<li>Efforts include comprehensive testing of the Z80 instruction set, exploring various implementations, and generating gate-level designs resembling the original Z80 layout, offering additional resources and documentation for potential project contributors.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/rejunity/z80-open-silicon</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZReinventing Zilog&apos;s Z80 CPU: A Modern Open-Source Silicon Clone</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Have Modern Tools Compromised Software Efficiency?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The writer shares their struggle working on a 30 MB document in Google Docs due to performance issues, questioning if software development prioritizes modern tools over efficiency.</li>
<li>They advocate for developing more performance-oriented and efficient applications, highlighting the importance of optimizing software development practices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://rufatmammadli.medium.com/did-we-lose-our-way-in-making-efficient-software-30-mb-doc-file-vs-browser-fed12dd866a4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZHave Modern Tools Compromised Software Efficiency?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Williams-Sonoma Fined $3.18M for False 'Made in USA' Labels]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Williams-Sonoma fined $3.18 million for falsely labeling products as &#39;Made in USA&#39;, breaching a 2020 settlement order.</li>
<li>The Federal Trade Commission discovered deceptive U.S.-origin claims on items imported from China, despite the company&#39;s sales success.</li>
<li>Legal consequences follow the company&#39;s misleading labeling practices, highlighting the importance of accurate product origin claims.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.scrippsnews.com/business/company-news/williams-sonoma-fined-3-18-million-dollars-for-falsely-labeling-products-as-made-in-usa</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZWilliams-Sonoma Fined $3.18M for False &apos;Made in USA&apos; Labels</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zed Decoded: Enhancing Zed Editor with Ropes and SumTree]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Zed Decoded delves into using ropes, a data structure central to the Zed text editor, offering enhanced editing and memory management over typical strings.</li>
<li>The blog and video illustrate the drawbacks of strings and the benefits of utilizing ropes, particularly SumTree, for managing extensive text efficiently.</li>
<li>SumTree facilitates effective indexing and text manipulation in Zed, enhancing key features such as text display, inlays, and highlights, resulting in better performance and concurrency support in this high-performance code editor.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://zed.dev/blog/zed-decoded-rope-sumtree</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZZed Decoded: Enhancing Zed Editor with Ropes and SumTree</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LoRA+: Enhanced Large Model Adaptation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper presents a new algorithm, LoRA+, enhancing the Low Rank Adaptation (LoRA) method for fine-tuning models with large width in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence fields.</li>
<li>LoRA+ boosts performance and fine-tuning speed by utilizing distinct learning rates for adapter matrices A and B, showcasing up to a 2X SpeedUp in experiments.</li>
<li>The algorithm&#39;s efficacy is validated through comprehensive experiments, illustrating its advancement in optimizing model performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12354</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZLoRA+: Enhanced Large Model Adaptation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Dotenv: Simplifying File Loading with Unix-like Functionality]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author developed a utility enabling users to load dotenv files effortlessly using a prefixed command, removing the dependency on language-specific libraries.</li>
<li>This utility mimics the functionality of dotenv as a UNIX utility rather than a Node.js library, simplifying the process of loading dotenv files.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/gyf304/dotenv</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Dotenv: Simplifying File Loading with Unix-like Functionality</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uncomfortable Traditional Life Jackets Replaced with One-Use Balloons]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Traditional aircraft life jackets are now thin plastic one-use balloons, which Gene finds uncomfortable and unsuitable for daily use.</li>
<li>Gene observed three paragraphs in his post were repeated, impacting the overall quality and coherence.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fearoflanding.com/accidents/accident-reports/the-unstallable-plane-that-stalled/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZUncomfortable Traditional Life Jackets Replaced with One-Use Balloons</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exciting "Thorium Transition" in Atomic Nuclei with Lasers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Physicists have made a significant advancement by stimulating the &quot;thorium transition&quot; in atomic nuclei with lasers, offering prospects for highly accurate technologies such as nuclear clocks.</li>
<li>They identified a unique state in thorium atomic nuclei that laser beams can control, enabling precise measurements and future technological innovations.</li>
<li>This discovery may lead to the development of advanced atomic clock technology leveraging light oscillation for enhanced precision.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.tuwien.at/en/tu-wien/news/news-articles/news/lange-erhoffter-durchbruch-erstmals-atomkern-mit-laser-angeregt</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZExciting &quot;Thorium Transition&quot; in Atomic Nuclei with Lasers</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ollama 0.1.33-rc5 Introduces Llama 3, Phi 3, and Qwen 110B]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Ollama Public Notifications Fork has launched version 0.1.33-rc5, bringing in new models such as Llama 3, Phi 3 Mini, Moondream, Dolphin Llama 3, and Qwen 110B.</li>
<li>Updates include fixes addressing model termination problems and out of memory errors while introducing new concurrency capabilities for managing simultaneous requests and model loading.</li>
<li>The release also highlights the addition of several new contributors making their initial contributions to the project, fostering collaboration and growth within the community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ollama/ollama/releases/tag/v0.1.33-rc5</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZOllama 0.1.33-rc5 Introduces Llama 3, Phi 3, and Qwen 110B</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Urgent Action Needed to Stop SB 1047: Threat to Open-Source AI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SB 1047, a bill in California, poses risks to open-source AI and tech industry by establishing a Frontier Model Division staffed by Effective Altruism activists with policing powers, potentially leading to the imprisonment of model developers.</li>
<li>The bill is swiftly progressing through the state Senate and has global repercussions due to California&#39;s high concentration of cloud and AI companies, requiring prompt action such as submitting opposition letters, contributing to an analysis document, and raising awareness on social media.</li>
<li>Urgent collective efforts are crucial to halt the bill&#39;s passage, emphasizing the need for immediate engagement and involving others in the advocacy against SB 1047.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.affuture.org/post/9-context/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZUrgent Action Needed to Stop SB 1047: Threat to Open-Source AI</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reckless Policies Fueling Rise of Large Vehicles in America]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Larger vehicles are increasingly common on American roads, leading to road safety issues, higher emissions, and infrastructure strain.</li>
<li>Consumer choices and federal policies promoting SUVs and trucks are driving this trend towards larger vehicles.</li>
<li>Calls for regulations to tackle safety concerns for pedestrians and cyclists, alongside proposed regulatory changes at federal, state, and local levels, face pushback from the auto industry.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24139147/suvs-trucks-popularity-federal-policy-pollution</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZReckless Policies Fueling Rise of Large Vehicles in America</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Personal Computing's Impact on Personal Library Science]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The newsletter delves into the link between the past of Personal Computing and the future of Personal Library Science, stressing the use of technology to address personalized issues.</li>
<li>It draws comparisons between the evolution of personal computers and the possibilities of LLM (Personal Library Management) technology in shaping personal libraries.</li>
<li>The newsletter underscores the significance of distinct viewpoints and approaches in personal libraries, underscoring the need to comprehend our interaction with information, promising an upcoming analysis of the commonplace book&#39;s history and its relevance to Personal Library Science.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bramadams.dev/issue-55/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-04-29T00:00:00.000ZPersonal Computing&apos;s Impact on Personal Library Science</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
