<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 10:23:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Code Llama, a state-of-the-art large language model for coding]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Code Llama is a new large language model (LLM) specifically designed for coding tasks.</li>
<li>It is capable of generating code and natural language about code from code or natural language prompts.</li>
<li>Code Llama is available in three models: Code Llama, Codel Llama - Python, and Code Llama - Instruct.</li>
<li>It has outperformed other publicly available LLMs on coding tasks.</li>
<li>The models are built on top of Llama 2 and are free for research and commercial use.</li>
<li>Code Llama has the potential to improve developer workflows and make coding more accessible.</li>
<li>It supports popular programming languages and can be used for code completion and debugging.</li>
<li>Safe and responsible use of Code Llama is emphasized, and the models have undergone safety evaluations.</li>
<li>The release of Code Llama encourages innovation and collaboration in the AI community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ai.meta.com/blog/code-llama-large-language-model-coding/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZCode Llama, a state-of-the-art large language model for coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Code Llama, a state-of-the-art large language model for coding]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Code Llama is a cutting-edge large language model (LLM) specifically designed for coding tasks.</li>
<li>It can generate code and natural language about code based on prompts.</li>
<li>Code Llama has three models: Code Llama (the foundational code model), Code Llama - Python (specialized for Python), and Code Llama - Instruct (fine-tuned for natural language instructions).</li>
<li>In benchmark testing, Code Llama outperformed other publicly available LLMs on code tasks.</li>
<li>It supports popular programming languages and can be used for code completion and debugging.</li>
<li>Code Llama has different model sizes to cater to specific latency requirements.</li>
<li>It has the potential to improve coding workflows and make coding more accessible for beginners.</li>
<li>Code Llama is released under a community license, and users must adhere to the acceptable use policy.</li>
<li>The model has undergone safety evaluations and precautions have been taken to mitigate risks.</li>
<li>Developers are encouraged to evaluate the model using code-specific evaluation benchmarks and perform safety studies.</li>
<li>The goal is to continue developing generative AI for coding by leveraging Llama 2 and inspiring others to create innovative tools.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ai.meta.com/blog/code-llama-large-language-model-coding/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZCode Llama, a state-of-the-art large language model for coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hacker News Guidelines]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Hacker News guidelines specify the topics that would interest hackers, excluding politics, crime, sports, and celebrities.</li>
<li>Titles should not be altered, and the original source should be submitted without self-promotion.</li>
<li>In the comments section, users are expected to be polite, avoid snarkiness, and respond to arguments instead of resorting to name-calling. Using uppercase for emphasis and making astroturfing insinuations should be avoided. Complaints about inappropriate submissions should be flagged rather than discussed in comments.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZHacker News Guidelines</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hugging Face raises $235M from investors including Salesforce and Nvidia]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hugging Face, an AI startup, has secured $235 million in Series D funding, with notable investors like Salesforce and Nvidia participating.</li>
<li>The funding round has doubled Hugging Face&#39;s valuation to $4.5 billion since May 2022.</li>
<li>Hugging Face offers data science hosting and development tools, including an AI code repository hub, models, and datasets, as well as web apps for AI-powered applications.</li>
<li>The company provides libraries and paid functionalities such as AutoTrain, Inference API, and Infinity.</li>
<li>The funds raised will be used by Hugging Face to expand its support in research, enterprise, and startups.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/24/hugging-face-raises-235m-from-investors-including-salesforce-and-nvidia/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZHugging Face raises $235M from investors including Salesforce and Nvidia</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bypassing Bitlocker using a cheap logic analyzer on a Lenovo laptop]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author presents a method for bypassing the BitLocker encryption on a Lenovo laptop using a low-cost logic analyzer.</li>
<li>The architecture of BitLocker and the storage of the encryption key in the TPM are explained.</li>
<li>The process of capturing and decoding the TPM exchange to retrieve the encryption key is detailed, along with limitations of the method and recommendations for improved security.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.errno.fr/BypassingBitlocker.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZBypassing Bitlocker using a cheap logic analyzer on a Lenovo laptop</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The human Y chromosome has been completely sequenced]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Telomere-to-Telomere consortium has successfully sequenced and assembled the complete sequence of a human Y chromosome, adding new sequence and correcting errors.</li>
<li>This achievement provides a comprehensive reference sequence for all 24 human chromosomes, aiding in genomic research and insights into human genetic variation and evolution.</li>
<li>The study highlights the importance of accurate representation of the sex chromosome complement in reference genomes and reveals genomic differences and variations between individuals, contributing to our understanding of the human Y chromosome and genetic diversity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06457-y</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZThe human Y chromosome has been completely sequenced</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-source obsidian.md sync server]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A high school graduate has developed a sync service for Obsidian.md, providing an alternative to the official paid service.</li>
<li>While the service is still in development and lacks some features, it offers basic sync functionality.</li>
<li>The creator is aware of potential violations of the terms of service and is willing to remove the repository if necessary. The service is not aimed at competing with the official offering.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37247767</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZOpen-source obsidian.md sync server</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FreeBSD on Firecracker]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author recounts their experience of successfully porting FreeBSD to run on the Firecracker Virtual Machine Monitor.</li>
<li>Despite facing challenges, they managed to overcome them and make significant progress in optimizing FreeBSD to improve its boot time on Firecracker.</li>
<li>The author also mentions future plans, including separating Xen support and potentially porting Firecracker to run on FreeBSD.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.usenix.org/publications/loginonline/freebsd-firecracker</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZFreeBSD on Firecracker</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jacobin: A more than minimal JVM written in Go]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Jacobin is a Go-based JVM implementation that can execute Java 17 classes, offering a more comprehensive JVM implementation with clear and cohesive code.</li>
<li>Unlike other JVM implementations, Jacobin leverages Go&#39;s built-in memory management and does not include garbage collection code.</li>
<li>The project is extensively tested, and the development team aims to run OpenJDK test suites in the future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jacobin.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZJacobin: A more than minimal JVM written in Go</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proof-of-Work Defense for Onion Services]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tor has implemented a proof-of-work (PoW) defense for onion services to prevent denial of service (DoS) attacks.</li>
<li>Incoming client connections are required to solve a puzzle, proving their authenticity and discouraging attackers.</li>
<li>The PoW mechanism prioritizes genuine traffic and makes large-scale attacks impractical, enhancing the security and reliability of the Tor network.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.torproject.org/introducing-proof-of-work-defense-for-onion-services/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZProof-of-Work Defense for Onion Services</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI real-time human full-body photo generator]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Human Generator is an API tool that utilizes advanced AI algorithms to generate hyperrealistic full-body photos of people in real-time.</li>
<li>The tool offers maximum diversity in terms of ethnicity, age, and body type, and supports different poses and clothing options.</li>
<li>It is free for non-commercial use and provides additional features such as generating variations and animations.</li>
<li>Human Generator is part of a suite of products that includes Face Generator, Face Gallery, Anonymizer, and Datasets.</li>
<li>Users can contact the company to address any questions or concerns regarding the usage, safety, and storage of the generated content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://generated.photos/human-generator/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZAI real-time human full-body photo generator</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Common mistakes in salary negotiation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article offers advice on salary negotiation, highlighting the significance of withholding excessive information during the early stages of the job search.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the importance of proper preparation and control in negotiations, and warns against sharing salary details too early.</li>
<li>The article suggests using email as a communication tool for negotiating, as it allows for more thoughtful and strategic responses.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://interviewing.io/blog/sabotage-salary-negotiation-before-even-start</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZCommon mistakes in salary negotiation</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An excruciatingly detailed guide to SSH (but only the things I find useful)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This blog post offers a thorough guide to SSH, explaining different aspects like port forwarding, agent forwarding, and proxying.</li>
<li>It explores SSH features like TTY command allocation and the SSH config file, while also discussing security risks.</li>
<li>The guide includes practical examples, commands, and suggestions for setting up SSH tunnels and accessing servers, along with additional references for further information.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://grahamhelton.com/blog/ssh-cheatsheet/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZAn excruciatingly detailed guide to SSH (but only the things I find useful)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cash payments above €3000 to be outlawed in Netherlands]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>There is currently no maximum limit for cash payments in the Netherlands.</li>
<li>Sellers must conduct a client investigation for cash purchases above €10,000.</li>
<li>The government is working on a proposal to prohibit cash payments above €3,000 to prevent money laundering and terrorism financing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.rijksoverheid.nl/onderwerpen/geldzaken/vraag-en-antwoord/grote-aankopen-met-contant-geld</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZCash payments above €3000 to be outlawed in Netherlands</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia announces financial results for second quarter fiscal 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NVIDIA has achieved record-breaking revenue in the second quarter of fiscal 2024, with a 101% increase from the previous year.</li>
<li>The company&#39;s Data Center revenue also soared by 171%.</li>
<li>NVIDIA&#39;s CEO highlighted the shift towards accelerated computing and generative AI and announced plans for share repurchases and a cash dividend.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-announces-financial-results-for-second-quarter-fiscal-2024</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZNvidia announces financial results for second quarter fiscal 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bun v0.8]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Bun v0.8.0 brings new features, bug fixes, and improvements to compatibility and stability.</li>
<li>Bun 1.0 is set for release on September 7th, promising additional enhancements and bug fixes.</li>
<li>For more detailed information on the updates, refer to the provided link.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bun.sh/blog/bun-v0.8.0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZBun v0.8</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A group of Motherboard folks just spun up their own new independent outlet]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>404 Media is a new digital media company founded by former journalists from VICE&#39;s Motherboard.</li>
<li>The company focuses on producing technology journalism that has a significant societal impact and operates as a sustainable, reader-supported business.</li>
<li>They plan to report on unique stories, expose wrongdoing, and provide serious and irreverent content.</li>
<li>The site will initially offer free access to articles, but a paywall for certain content will be introduced in the future.</li>
<li>Subscribers will receive benefits such as exclusive articles, commenting privileges, and bonus podcast episodes.</li>
<li>The company&#39;s long-term goals include expanding into other media formats like books, documentaries, and films.</li>
<li>They prioritize transparency, ground-up reporting, and investigative journalism, with a focus on topics such as hacking, cybersecurity, sex, AI, consumer rights, surveillance, and privacy.</li>
<li>The founders aim to create a profitable media company by prioritizing quality journalism, making cost-effective decisions, and seeking support from their audience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.404media.co/welcome-to-404-media/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZA group of Motherboard folks just spun up their own new independent outlet</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A half-hour to learn Rust (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This article offers a comprehensive introduction to the Rust programming language, covering syntax, concepts, features, and code examples.</li>
<li>It explores important topics like pattern matching, variable bindings and references, generics, lifetimes, borrowing, and error handling.</li>
<li>The article emphasizes the usefulness of the Rust compiler and provides additional resources for further learning.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fasterthanli.me/articles/a-half-hour-to-learn-rust</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZA half-hour to learn Rust (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[So Long, Twitter and Reddit]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Software developer Andrew Kelley has left Twitter and Reddit due to the negative impact on his mental well-being.</li>
<li>Kelley believes that Twitter promotes angry and extreme content, contributing to a negative worldview.</li>
<li>He also criticizes Reddit for its profit-driven approach and quality decline, closing the /r/zig subreddit and suggesting the Ziggit alternative.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://andrewkelley.me/post/goodbye-twitter-reddit.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZSo Long, Twitter and Reddit</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coffee grounds make concrete 30% stronger]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Engineers in Australia have discovered a method to enhance the strength of concrete by incorporating roasted used-coffee grounds.</li>
<li>This technique involves turning waste coffee grounds into biochar, resulting in concrete that is 30% stronger.</li>
<li>By utilizing this approach, not only does the performance of concrete improve, but it also reduces the amount of waste sent to landfills.</li>
<li>The team intends to partner with different industries and conduct field trials to implement their findings.</li>
<li>This innovation has the potential to greatly enhance the recycling of organic waste and help preserve valuable resources such as sand.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.rmit.edu.au/news/all-news/2023/aug/coffee-concrete</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZCoffee grounds make concrete 30% stronger</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The first conformant M1 GPU driver]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Asahi Linux has released conformant OpenGL ES 3.1 drivers for M1 and M2 family GPUs, allowing compatibility with any OpenGL ES 3.1 application on Linux.</li>
<li>These drivers have been recognized by the standards body, Khronos, after passing industry-standard tests.</li>
<li>Asahi Linux&#39;s implementation includes support for compute shaders and atomics on images, despite the lack of hardware instructions for image atomics on the M1 GPU.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rosenzweig.io/blog/first-conformant-m1-gpu-driver.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZThe first conformant M1 GPU driver</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft is bringing Python to Excel]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft is integrating Python into Excel to improve data analysis and visualization capabilities.</li>
<li>Users can now manipulate and analyze Python data directly in Excel using formulas, charts, and PivotTables.</li>
<li>The integration is available in the Microsoft 365 Insiders Beta Channel and will be rolled out to other platforms in the future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/22/23841167/microsoft-excel-python-integration-support</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZMicrosoft is bringing Python to Excel</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hackers can use credit bureaus to dox nearly anyone in America]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hackers are infiltrating credit bureaus and selling personal information, including addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, and Social Security numbers.</li>
<li>The tool used to access this data is available for as little as $15 in Bitcoin, making it accessible to criminals.</li>
<li>The stolen data can be used for various crimes, such as swatting, SIM swapping, and physical violence.</li>
<li>Credit bureaus and data brokers like TLOxp, Data-Trac, SearchBug, and USinfoSearch have come under scrutiny for their involvement in selling personal data.</li>
<li>Lawmakers are urging action to prevent this practice, and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau has proposed new rules to regulate the trade of credit header data.</li>
<li>The effectiveness of these changes in addressing the problem remains uncertain.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.404media.co/the-secret-weapon-hackers-can-use-to-dox-nearly-anyone-in-america-for-15-tlo-usinfosearch-transunion/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZHackers can use credit bureaus to dox nearly anyone in America</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A good measurement culture where numbers don’t replace common sense]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>KPI (key performance indicator) psychosis is a prevalent issue in technology companies, where decisions are solely based on data and disconnect from reality.</li>
<li>Companies heavily rely on data to overcome human biases, but using KPIs as the sole basis for decision-making has its limitations.</li>
<li>The article suggests a solution that combines intuition and data, continuously reflects on the reliability of KPIs, and focuses on the actual objective rather than just the KPI itself.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.promaton.com/how-to-avoid-kpi-psychosis-in-your-organization-5ffc83967f2b</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZA good measurement culture where numbers don’t replace common sense</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GPT-3.5 Turbo fine-tuning and API updates]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenAI has introduced a new feature called fine-tuning for their GPT-3.5 Turbo model, allowing developers to customize it for specific use cases.</li>
<li>Early tests have shown that a fine-tuned version of GPT-3.5 Turbo can outperform the base GPT-4 model in certain tasks, indicating improved performance.</li>
<li>Fine-tuning offers benefits such as increased steerability, reliable output formatting, and the ability to customize the tone. The updated model also supports handling 4k tokens and offers cost savings through prompt size reduction.</li>
<li>OpenAI has released pricing details for fine-tuning and announced the availability of updated GPT-3 models.</li>
<li>OpenAI has implemented moderation systems to ensure the safe deployment of fine-tuned models and plans to launch a fine-tuning user interface soon.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openai.com/blog/gpt-3-5-turbo-fine-tuning-and-api-updates</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZGPT-3.5 Turbo fine-tuning and API updates</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I only lost 10 minutes of data, thanks to ZFS]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares their experience with a SSD failure on their laptop and how they successfully recovered their data using ZFS incremental replication.</li>
<li>The post discusses the repairability and power efficiency of AMD CPUs, along with different storage expansion and backup strategies.</li>
<li>The conversation explores the benefits and challenges of replicating drives and troubleshooting hardware issues, while also mentioning alternative tools and concerns about other file systems like btrfs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mastodon.social/@chromakode/110936177254839251</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZI only lost 10 minutes of data, thanks to ZFS</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The feds asked TikTok for lots of domestic spying features]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The US government sought an agreement with TikTok that would have granted them significant control and access to the app&#39;s operations, according to a leaked draft agreement obtained by Forbes.</li>
<li>The agreement would have given US agencies extensive powers, such as the ability to examine TikTok&#39;s records and servers, veto executive appointments, and demand changes to the app&#39;s terms of service.</li>
<li>The government&#39;s demands drew criticism as they resembled surveillance tactics commonly associated with China. TikTok and the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) declined to comment on the draft agreement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gizmodo.com/tiktok-cfius-draft-agreement-shows-spying-requests-1850759715</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZThe feds asked TikTok for lots of domestic spying features</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prettymapp – Create maps from OpenStreetMap data in a Streamlit webapp]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Prettymapp is a web app and Python package that generates stunning maps using OpenStreetMap data.</li>
<li>It is a faster and more user-friendly version of the prettymaps project.</li>
<li>The package can be integrated into Python applications for personalized customization and development purposes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/chrieke/prettymapp</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZPrettymapp – Create maps from OpenStreetMap data in a Streamlit webapp</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experian fined $650K by the FTC and DOJ for spam emails with no opt out]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Experian, a credit reporting agency, has been fined $650,000 by the US government for violating spam laws and not providing an opt-out option for marketing emails.</li>
<li>The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) discovered that Experian sent deceptive marketing emails to customers with free credit monitoring memberships, lacking clear notice and an opt-out mechanism.</li>
<li>As a result, the Department of Justice (DOJ) obtained a permanent injunction against Experian, prohibiting certain types of messages and requiring explicit opt-out options in marketing emails.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/22/23841646/experian-fined-spam-emails-ftc-doj</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZExperian fined $650K by the FTC and DOJ for spam emails with no opt out</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Structured logging with slog]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The new log/slog package in Go 1.21 introduces structured logging to the standard library.</li>
<li>Structured logs utilize key-value pairs for easy parsing, filtering, searching, and analysis.</li>
<li>The package aims to create a standardized framework for structured logging in the Go ecosystem, with different log levels and customizable output format options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://go.dev/blog/slog</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-23T00:00:00.000ZStructured logging with slog</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[uBlock Origin Lite now available on Firefox]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>uBlock Origin Lite is a content blocker extension for Firefox that blocks ads, trackers, and miners.</li>
<li>The extension uses a declarative approach for efficient filtering and does not require broad permissions at installation.</li>
<li>Users have the option to grant extended permissions on specific sites for more precise filtering.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/ublock-origin-lite/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-22T00:00:00.000ZuBlock Origin Lite now available on Firefox</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GNU Parallel, where have you been all my life?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The blog post discusses the author&#39;s experience using GNU Parallel for gathering statistics on end-to-end test pass/fail rates.</li>
<li>Parallel execution using GNU Parallel improved performance and offered additional functionality.</li>
<li>The post emphasizes features of GNU Parallel, such as concurrency control, output capture, and advanced capabilities described in the author&#39;s book.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://alexplescan.com/posts/2023/08/20/gnu-parallel/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-22T00:00:00.000ZGNU Parallel, where have you been all my life?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't fire your illustrator]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author explores the use of AI image generators and how they can impact various groups, including physical media artists and commercial illustrators.</li>
<li>The concept of stable diffusion is explained, along with the challenges of using text to direct image generation.</li>
<li>AI is predicted to replace certain types of illustration and writing tasks, but achieving specific results can be challenging, and the use of image constraints is suggested. The author emphasizes the importance of AI products that seamlessly integrate into an illustrator&#39;s workflow and expresses hope for future AI products catering to commercial illustration.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sambleckley.com/writing/dont-fire-your-illustrator.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-22T00:00:00.000ZDon&apos;t fire your illustrator</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saving Lives (2004)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Steve Jobs motivated the engineers working on the Macintosh computer to improve the boot time by telling them that every 10 seconds saved would save a dozen lives.</li>
<li>The engineers succeeded in reducing the boot time by more than 10 seconds in the subsequent months.</li>
<li>This story highlights Steve Jobs&#39; leadership style and the dedication of the engineers in meeting his expectations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.folklore.org/StoryView.py?story=Saving_Lives.txt</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-22T00:00:00.000ZSaving Lives (2004)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Made Stable Diffusion XL Smarter by Finetuning It on Bad AI-Generated Images]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Max Woolf&#39;s blog post introduces Stable Diffusion XL 1.0 (SDXL), an open-source model for generating high-resolution images.</li>
<li>The author shares his process of using a cloud virtual machine with a midrange L4 GPU and highlights new features in the diffusers Python library.</li>
<li>The post explores the use of LoRAs for finetuning SDXL, showcases image generation examples with and without LoRAs, and discusses the &quot;wrong prompt&quot; technique to improve AI-generated images.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://minimaxir.com/2023/08/stable-diffusion-xl-wrong/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-22T00:00:00.000ZI Made Stable Diffusion XL Smarter by Finetuning It on Bad AI-Generated Images</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 years ago Valve released Proton]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Valve&#39;s release of Proton, a modified version of Wine, transformed Linux gaming five years ago by enabling popular games to run on the platform.</li>
<li>This sparked a surge in Linux gaming and contributed to the creation of the Steam Deck.</li>
<li>Proton&#39;s ongoing enhancements have improved compatibility and performance, granting Linux gamers access to a diverse selection of games, leading to enthusiastic user feedback.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2023/08/5-years-ago-valve-released-proton-forever-changing-linux-gaming/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-22T00:00:00.000Z5 years ago Valve released Proton</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The ideal viewport doesn't exist]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article discusses the fragmentation of screen sizes and browser viewports and the importance of considering this in design decisions.</li>
<li>The authors conducted an experiment with over 120,000 data points and found that the top viewport sizes were primarily small, potentially mobile devices.</li>
<li>The article advises against using specific breakpoints and hard values, instead advocating for flexibility and allowing the browser to determine the best outcome based on conditions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://viewports.fyi/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-22T00:00:00.000ZThe ideal viewport doesn&apos;t exist</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Growing share of Americans favor more nuclear power]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A recent survey by Pew Research Center shows that 57% of Americans now support expanding nuclear power in the United States, up from 43% in 2020.</li>
<li>However, solar power (82%) and wind power (75%) remain more favored by Americans compared to nuclear power.</li>
<li>Support for nuclear power has increased among both Democrats and Republicans, with men and Republicans being more likely to support it and believe the government should encourage its production. The United States currently has 93 nuclear power reactors, mainly located in the South, but the number has declined since its peak in 1990, potentially due to concerns over accidents and international tensions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2023/08/18/growing-share-of-americans-favor-more-nuclear-power/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-22T00:00:00.000ZGrowing share of Americans favor more nuclear power</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Podman Desktop celebrates 500k downloads]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Podman Desktop, an open-source container project, has achieved a significant milestone with over 500,000 downloads.</li>
<li>The Podman team expresses gratitude for user contributions and feedback and is committed to enhancing the tool&#39;s functionality for Kubernetes usage.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to participate in discussions centered around improving Kubernetes support, streamlining feature installation and configuration, and expanding documentation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://blog.podman.io/2023/08/celebrating-500k-downloads-the-podman-desktop-journey-%f0%9f%8e%89/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-22T00:00:00.000ZPodman Desktop celebrates 500k downloads</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upcoming .com and .xyz domain price increase]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Namecheap, a domain registrar, is notifying customers about upcoming price increases for .COM and .XYZ domains in September.</li>
<li>.COM domain renewals will experience a 9% increase across all registrars, including Namecheap.</li>
<li>Customers are encouraged to renew their .COM domains before September to secure the current rates or explore alternatives to .COM domains.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.namecheap.com/blog/upcoming-com-and-xyz-domain-price-increase/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-22T00:00:00.000ZUpcoming .com and .xyz domain price increase</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kris Nóva has died]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Kris Nóva, the influential leader and mentor of Nivenly, has sadly passed away, leaving behind a legacy of professionalism and vision.</li>
<li>The Nivenly community is mourning the loss of Kris Nóva and grappling with the next steps for the future.</li>
<li>It is unclear at this time how the Nivenly community will navigate the path forward without Kris Nóva&#39;s guidance and expertise.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nivenly.org/blog/2023/08/19/an-announcement-regarding-kris-n%C3%B3va/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZKris Nóva has died</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shouldn't distant objects appear magnified?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Astronomy Stack Exchange is a platform for astronomers and astrophysicists to engage in Q&amp;A.</li>
<li>A user raises a question about why very distant objects don&#39;t appear magnified.</li>
<li>Another user clarifies that the expansion of space does cause magnification, although it becomes noticeable at a specific distance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://astronomy.stackexchange.com/questions/54499/shouldnt-very-very-distant-objects-appear-magnified</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZShouldn&apos;t distant objects appear magnified?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[So you want to learn physics (2021)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Susan Rigetti has released a second edition of her guide to learning physics on your own, incorporating reader feedback and making improvements.</li>
<li>The guide recommends studying various subjects in physics, starting with calculus and progressing to specialized fields.</li>
<li>It also suggests popular physics books for broader perspectives, including textbooks on undergraduate and graduate-level physics, as well as advanced topics like general relativity and quantum field theory.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.susanrigetti.com/physics</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZSo you want to learn physics (2021)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jazz² Resurrection: Open-source Jazz Jackrabbit 2 reimplementation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Jazz² Resurrection is an open-source reimplementation of the game Jazz Jackrabbit 2, allowing players to experience the classic game on modern platforms.</li>
<li>The game can be downloaded and played on various platforms, including Windows, Linux, macOS, Android, Nintendo Switch, and web browsers.</li>
<li>The project is licensed under the GNU General Public License v3.0 and utilizes the modified nCine game engine, providing a versatile and customizable gaming experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://deat.tk/jazz2/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZJazz² Resurrection: Open-source Jazz Jackrabbit 2 reimplementation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We’re All Just Temporarily Abled]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author injures their knee during their vacation and contemplates the fleeting nature of physical ability.</li>
<li>They express appreciation for accessibility aids that assist them during their recovery.</li>
<li>The author acknowledges their privilege in having a job that permits them to take the necessary time off for healing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2023/temporarily-abled/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZWe’re All Just Temporarily Abled</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Electricity Maps]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The list ranks countries and regions based on the carbon intensity of their electricity consumption, indicating the environmental impact of their energy usage.</li>
<li>The data used for the ranking is sourced from Electricity Maps, an open-source platform that visualizes the climate impact of electricity.</li>
<li>The app not only provides information but also allows users to contribute by adding their own regions or countries to the list. Additionally, it offers historical data and enables users to view carbon intensity levels over different time periods.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://app.electricitymaps.com</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZElectricity Maps</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FreeBSD replaces bubblesort with mergesort on SYSINTs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FreeBSD (HEAD) has implemented mergesort algorithm to replace the bubblesort algorithm in its SYSINITs.</li>
<li>This change has resulted in a notable improvement in speed.</li>
<li>The adoption of mergesort algorithm signifies the commitment of FreeBSD to enhance performance and efficiency in its systems.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/cperciva/status/1693127769901969772</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZFreeBSD replaces bubblesort with mergesort on SYSINTs</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Without belief in a god, but never without belief in a devil]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores Eric Hoffer&#39;s book &quot;The True Believer&quot; and its relevance in understanding the motivations behind mass movements.</li>
<li>Hoffer argues that frustration plays a crucial role in driving mass movements, which intentionally exploit this frustration among their members.</li>
<li>The article highlights how polarized politics and the quest for equality contribute to frustration and the emergence of social movements.</li>
<li>Hoffer also suggests that mass movements offer dissatisfied individuals a sense of purpose and identity.</li>
<li>The article further mentions Hoffer&#39;s observation that hatred is often used as a unifying force in mass movements.</li>
<li>Overall, the article underscores the dangers of mass movements and their ability to manipulate and take advantage of individual frustrations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.robkhenderson.com/p/without-belief-in-a-god-but-never</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZWithout belief in a god, but never without belief in a devil</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anxious brains redirect emotion regulation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Anxious individuals show overexcitability in the frontopolar cortex (FPl) and rely on other frontal cortex regions for emotion control.</li>
<li>Stronger connections between the amygdala and FPl are found in anxious individuals.</li>
<li>The study also reveals a higher ratio of GABA to glutamate in the FPl of anxious individuals, suggesting potential interventions for anxiety disorders.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-40666-3</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZAnxious brains redirect emotion regulation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An abandoned cabinet full of Kodachrome slides in San Francisco]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A cabinet of Kodachrome slides containing captivating photos of San Francisco in the 1960s was discovered on a sidewalk.</li>
<li>The slides showcase the construction of the Bay Area Rapid Transit system and everyday life in the city.</li>
<li>The photographer, James Martin, was a schoolteacher who had a passion for San Francisco.</li>
<li>Two additional cabinets of slides are currently unaccounted for.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://petapixel.com/2023/08/16/the-mystery-of-an-abandoned-cabinet-full-of-kodachrome-slides-in-san-francisco/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-21T00:00:00.000ZAn abandoned cabinet full of Kodachrome slides in San Francisco</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amsterdam to use “noise cameras” against too loud cars]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Amsterdam has implemented &quot;noise cameras&quot; to address the issue of noisy vehicles in the city.</li>
<li>Electric road signs have been placed to alert drivers if their vehicles are too loud, and these signs will later be replaced by noise cameras that will automatically issue fines to offending drivers.</li>
<li>Noise signs will be tested in two locations initially, with plans to install more sound meters and signs throughout the month. This initiative aims to minimize noise disturbances in the city. Rotterdam is also partnering with Amsterdam on a similar experiment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nltimes.nl/2023/08/11/amsterdam-use-noise-cameras-loud-cars</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZAmsterdam to use “noise cameras” against too loud cars</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How do we pay for parking?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares a frustrating experience assisting an elderly woman with parking apps and highlights the challenges and limitations of the system.</li>
<li>Users in a conversation express concerns about the complexity of parking apps, reliance on smartphones, and potential financial implications.</li>
<li>Suggestions are made for a unified app or eliminating the need for parking apps altogether, and privatization and revenue issues in cities are mentioned. The author advocates for analog options for parking payment, particularly for older individuals, and expresses frustration with complex digital systems and a lack of improvement in daily lives despite technological advancements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://cohost.org/cathoderaydude/post/2521077-hahaha-we-live-in-he</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZHow do we pay for parking?</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Windy.com: global weather website with live filters]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text mentions multiple cities and locations in the United States, Canada, Mexico, and Cuba.</li>
<li>It also highlights Hurricane Hilary approaching the West Coast.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.windy.com</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZWindy.com: global weather website with live filters</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aviation navigation log on $20 receipt printer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Carlos shares his flight training experiences and highlights the difficulties of managing information in a small cockpit.</li>
<li>He developed a project using a receipt printer to create a navigation log that improves his flight experience.</li>
<li>Carlos expresses his enthusiasm for technology and his intention to continue developing the project in the future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://carloslagoa.com/blog/flipreps/flipreps.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZAviation navigation log on $20 receipt printer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why do old books smell so good?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Scientists are studying the distinct smell of old books and using the volatile organic compounds (VOCs) released to determine their age, condition, and history.</li>
<li>The smell of old books is caused by the breakdown of paper and other organic compounds, releasing specific compounds like benzaldehyde, vanillin, ethylbenzene, and 2-ethyl hexanol.</li>
<li>VOC analysis can help librarians and historians identify preservation needs and match orphaned books with their original libraries.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://scienceswitch.com/2023/08/19/why-do-old-books-smell-so-good/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZWhy do old books smell so good?</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stable Diffusion in C/C++]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This repository contains a C/C++ implementation of Stable Diffusion, a technique for generating images.</li>
<li>It offers support for different precisions, quantizations, and platforms.</li>
<li>The repository includes instructions for downloading weights, building and running the code, as well as information about memory and disk requirements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/leejet/stable-diffusion.cpp</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZStable Diffusion in C/C++</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rivet – Open-source game server management with Nomad and Rust]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Rivet is an open-source game server management tool designed to simplify the deployment of dedicated servers for game developers without infrastructure experience.</li>
<li>It is built primarily using Rust and Lua, with integration of other tools and libraries.</li>
<li>Rivet supports various features such as edge proxies, caching, analytics, overlay networks, and Redis Lua scripts.</li>
<li>It is licensed under Apache 2.0 and aims to be an accessible and comprehensive game server manager.</li>
<li>Rivet does not handle networking logic but works in conjunction with existing tools.</li>
<li>It has been in closed beta since January 2022 and supports millions of monthly active users across multiple titles.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/rivet-gg/rivet</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZRivet – Open-source game server management with Nomad and Rust</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clone-a-Lisa]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Clone-a Lisa is a game where players race against the clock to paint a replica of the Mona Lisa in just 60 seconds.</li>
<li>The game can be accessed on the website VOLE.wtf and includes sound effects for added immersion.</li>
<li>It offers a fun and challenging experience that puts players&#39; painting skills to the test in a limited timeframe.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://vole.wtf/clone-a-lisa/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZClone-a-Lisa</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cellebrite asks cops to keep its technology secret]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Phone hacking technology company Cellebrite is asking law enforcement agencies to keep their technology usage secret, raising concerns about transparency and defendants&#39; rights.</li>
<li>Critics argue that disclosure is important for evaluating evidence and protecting privacy.</li>
<li>Government contractor Harris Corporation has made similar requests for secrecy regarding their cellphone surveillance tool.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/19/cellebrite-asks-cops-to-keep-its-phone-hacking-tech-hush-hush/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZCellebrite asks cops to keep its technology secret</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WD refused to answer our questions about its self-wiping SanDisk SSDs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Western Digital&#39;s SanDisk SSDs are reportedly causing data loss, and the company has been unresponsive to inquiries about the issue.</li>
<li>Multiple reports of data loss have emerged, including from employees at The Verge and Ars Technica.</li>
<li>Western Digital continues to sell the SSDs despite being aware of the problem, and the company&#39;s head of PR has refused to address the issue.</li>
<li>Allegations have been made that Western Digital is using fake Amazon reviews and manipulating search results to downplay the failures.</li>
<li>The company is now facing multiple class-action lawsuits over the SanDisk SSD failures.</li>
<li>Western Digital has also been accused of deceptive practices, such as attempting to include subpar drives in its product lineup and triggering unnecessary warnings on its NAS disks.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/23837513/western-digital-sandisk-ssd-corrupted-deleted-questions</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-20T00:00:00.000ZWD refused to answer our questions about its self-wiping SanDisk SSDs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ask vs. Guess Culture]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores the concept of ask culture vs guess culture and how it impacts relationships and interactions.</li>
<li>Ask culture involves directly asking for what you want, while guess culture relies on reading indirect cues and only asking if confident of a positive response.</li>
<li>The article provides examples of clashes between these cultural norms and offers strategies for navigating a guess culture in a primarily ask culture work environment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jeanhsu.substack.com/p/ask-vs-guess-culture</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZAsk vs. Guess Culture</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mister Rogers had a point – routinely greeting six neighbors maximizes wellbeing]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Saying hello to multiple neighbors is associated with higher wellbeing in adults in the US, according to a study by Gallup.</li>
<li>Americans&#39; wellbeing score increases as the number of neighbors greeted increases, up to a maximum of six neighbors.</li>
<li>Greeting neighbors is more common among older adults and those with higher incomes, and it is linked to improvements in social, community, career, physical, and financial wellbeing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.gallup.com/poll/509543/saying-hello-linked-higher-wellbeing-limits.aspx</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZMister Rogers had a point – routinely greeting six neighbors maximizes wellbeing</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The FBI proves again it can’t be trusted with Section 702]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The FBI has been found accessing private communications of a state senator and a U.S. senator without following proper rules and limitations.</li>
<li>The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (FISC) revealed this information in a declassified opinion, emphasizing the FBI&#39;s disregard for privacy and civil liberties.</li>
<li>There is bipartisan support for significant changes or termination of Section 702, which authorizes the collection of overseas communications. The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) is advocating for the closure of warrantless access to U.S. communications and increased transparency in any renewal of Section 702.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2023/07/deja-vu-fbi-proves-again-it-cant-be-trusted-section-702</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZThe FBI proves again it can’t be trusted with Section 702</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Windows 11 will happily execute a binary compiled 30 years ago]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Windows 11 showcases impressive backwards compatibility as it can run a binary compiled 30 years ago, specifically from August 18, 1993.</li>
<li>This highlights Microsoft&#39;s commitment to ensuring compatibility with legacy software.</li>
<li>It signifies that users can still access and run older applications on the latest version of Windows without any issues.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/mikko/status/1692503249595584526</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZWindows 11 will happily execute a binary compiled 30 years ago</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Textual: Rapid Application Development framework for Python]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Textualize is a Rapid Application Development framework for Python that enables developers to create advanced user interfaces in the terminal and, in the future, in web browsers.</li>
<li>It offers various features like mouse support, 16.7 million colors, and smooth animations.</li>
<li>Textualize is compatible with Linux, macOS, and Windows and requires Python 3.7 or above. It can be easily installed via pip and provides documentation, examples, and a Discord community for support.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Textualize/textual</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZTextual: Rapid Application Development framework for Python</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[C and C++ prioritize performance over correctness]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Prioritizing performance over correctness in C and C++ programming languages can result in broken programs.</li>
<li>Issues with uninitialized variables, null pointers, and undefined behavior are common in C and C++ due to this prioritization.</li>
<li>The Go programming language is presented as an alternative with a different philosophy that prioritizes safety and security.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://research.swtch.com/ub</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZC and C++ prioritize performance over correctness</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Broadband monopolies push bill that would crush the ability to stand up to them]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Telecom giants are seeking to limit local government&#39;s authority over telecom infrastructure through proposed legislation, leading to consumer frustration.</li>
<li>Local governments are expressing a growing interest in establishing their own fiber networks, contributing to the push for increased control.</li>
<li>The conversation also encompasses various issues such as the removal of headphone jacks on phones, ongoing investigations involving Trump, and difficulties associated with online anonymity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.techdirt.com/2023/08/18/with-hr-3557-broadband-monopolies-are-pushing-a-bill-that-would-crush-your-towns-ability-to-stand-up-to-them/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZBroadband monopolies push bill that would crush the ability to stand up to them</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Learning async Rust with entirely too many web servers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article focuses on learning asynchronous programming in Rust by building multiple web servers.</li>
<li>It covers various topics including concurrent programming with threads, non-blocking I/O, efficient event handling with epoll, implementing a reactor and scheduler, creating futures and using closures, handling TCP connections, and graceful shutdown.</li>
<li>The article provides code snippets and detailed explanations to demonstrate the concepts and techniques involved in building efficient and responsive servers using asynchronous programming in Rust.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ibraheem.ca/posts/too-many-web-servers/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZLearning async Rust with entirely too many web servers</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Police are getting DNA data from people who think they opted out]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Forensic genetic genealogists are using a loophole in the GEDmatch DNA database to access DNA data from individuals who have opted out of sharing with law enforcement.</li>
<li>This technique has helped solve cold cases, but it raises concerns about privacy and the lack of regulation.</li>
<li>Ancestry and 23andMe do not allow law enforcement access, but MyHeritage and GEDmatch do with user consent, and GEDmatch has a loophole for protected profiles.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://theintercept.com/2023/08/18/gedmatch-dna-police-forensic-genetic-genealogy/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZPolice are getting DNA data from people who think they opted out</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Worldcoin ignored initial order to stop iris scans in Kenya, records show]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Crypto startup Worldcoin defied an order from the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner (ODPC) in Kenya to halt the collection of personal data, including iris scans.</li>
<li>The ODPC had previously directed Worldcoin to stop collecting data in May, but the company persisted until it was suspended by the Ministry of Interior and Administration in August.</li>
<li>The ODPC has taken legal action to preserve the data collected by Worldcoin while investigations into security, privacy, and legality issues are underway.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/worldcoin-in-kenya/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-19T00:00:00.000ZWorldcoin ignored initial order to stop iris scans in Kenya, records show</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to communicate when trust is low without digging yourself into a deeper hole]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Effective communication is essential for rebuilding trust in relationships.</li>
<li>The author provides various tips for effective communication, including acknowledging the difficulty of the conversation, checking in afterwards, and speaking tentatively.</li>
<li>Other tips include using techniques like &quot;the story in my head,&quot; engineering positive interactions, and valuing effort in communication.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://charity.wtf/2023/08/17/how-to-communicate-when-trust-is-low-without-digging-yourself-into-a-deeper-hole/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-18T00:00:00.000ZHow to communicate when trust is low without digging yourself into a deeper hole</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[StarLite 12.5-inch Linux tablet]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Star Labs offers the StarLite laptop, a compact and powerful device designed for portability.</li>
<li>The laptop features an Intel Alder Lake N200 processor, 16GB memory, and a 12.5-inch 3k touch display.</li>
<li>It is powered by open-source firmware, offering secure boot flow and firmware customization. The laptop also includes features like a backlit keyboard, crystal-clear touch display, a small charger with a large battery, and easy firmware updates.</li>
<li>The laptop is highly customizable and comes with various distribution options.</li>
<li>The starting price is $498, and payment options are available.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://us.starlabs.systems/pages/starlite</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-18T00:00:00.000ZStarLite 12.5-inch Linux tablet</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Job Corps: free, residential training and education for low-income young adults]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Job Corps is a free program that offers training and education in over 100 areas across 10 industries for low-income young adults.</li>
<li>It provides free housing, meals, medical care, and a living allowance.</li>
<li>The program has helped many individuals succeed in fields like advanced manufacturing, information technology, healthcare, construction, and hospitality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jobcorps.gov/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-18T00:00:00.000ZJob Corps: free, residential training and education for low-income young adults</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1.56M dehumidifiers recalled due to fire and burn hazards]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The US Consumer Product Safety Commission has issued multiple recalls for dehumidifiers sold under various brand names like Frigidaire, GE, and Kenmore.</li>
<li>These dehumidifiers have been linked to fatal fires, prompting urgent action from consumers.</li>
<li>Consumers are advised to check the provided images and if they have a matching dehumidifier, they should request a refund and remove it from their homes promptly.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/16/23835116/have-you-seen-these-dehumidifiers-stop-using-them-or-you-might-die</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-18T00:00:00.000Z1.56M dehumidifiers recalled due to fire and burn hazards</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China’s property giant Evergrande files for bankruptcy protection in Manhattan]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Evergrande Group, a major Chinese property company, has filed for Chapter 15 bankruptcy protection in a US court.</li>
<li>The company is heavily in debt and has been undergoing restructuring proceedings in Hong Kong, the Cayman Islands, and the British Virgin Islands.</li>
<li>Evergrande&#39;s shares have been suspended since March 2022, and there are concerns that the troubles in China&#39;s property sector could have broader economic repercussions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.cnbc.com/2023/08/18/china-property-developer-evergrande-files-for-bankruptcy-protection-in-us.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-18T00:00:00.000ZChina’s property giant Evergrande files for bankruptcy protection in Manhattan</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turmoil, a framework for developing and testing distributed systems]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Turmoil is a new framework designed to help developers and testers work on distributed systems.</li>
<li>The framework allows for simulating hosts, time, and the network in a single process, making it easier to test and develop distributed systems.</li>
<li>With Turmoil, developers have fine-grained control over the network, enabling them to drop, hold, or delay messages between hosts.</li>
<li>The blog post provides instructions on how to use Turmoil and encourages users to provide feedback for future development and improvement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tokio.rs/blog/2023-01-03-announcing-turmoil</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-18T00:00:00.000ZTurmoil, a framework for developing and testing distributed systems</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SUSE to go private]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>EQT Private Equity, the majority shareholder of SUSE Linux Enterprise, plans to take the company private by delisting it from the Frankfurt Stock Exchange.</li>
<li>EQT will make a voluntary public purchase offer to buy the shares of other SUSE shareholders before the delisting, offering EUR 16.00 per share, which is a 67 percent premium on the XETRA closing share price.</li>
<li>SUSE&#39;s Management Board and Supervisory Board support the delisting, as it will allow the company to focus on its operational priorities and long-term strategy. The offer document will be published soon, with settlement expected in October 2023.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.suse.com/news/EQT-announces-voluntary-public-purchase-offer-and-intention-to-delist-SUSE/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-18T00:00:00.000ZSUSE to go private</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I am afraid to inform you that you have built a compiler (2022)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author humorously describes a developer who unintentionally builds a compiler despite their initial reluctance.</li>
<li>The developer faces challenges with the abstract syntax tree (AST) library and handling different AST nodes.</li>
<li>They encounter difficulties supporting nested code structures and dealing with compatibility issues for older machines.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rachit.pl/post/you-have-built-a-compiler/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-18T00:00:00.000ZI am afraid to inform you that you have built a compiler (2022)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SUSE to Go Private]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SUSE, the European open-source software company, is set to go private as its majority owner, Marcel LUX III SARL, plans to merge the company into an unlisted Luxembourg entity.</li>
<li>EQT Private Equity, controlled by EQT VIII fund entities, will launch a public purchase offer to the remaining shareholders, offering a 67% premium on the closing share price.</li>
<li>SUSE&#39;s management and supervisory boards are in support of the delisting, as they believe it will allow the company to focus on its long-term strategy without the pressure from public markets. The offer is expected to be settled in October 2023.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://opensourcewatch.beehiiv.com/p/suse-go-private</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-18T00:00:00.000ZSUSE to Go Private</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[micro – A Modern Alternative to nano]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Micro is a user-friendly and easily installable modern text editor.</li>
<li>It offers customization options through a simple json format and Lua scripting, along with features like multiple cursors, a plugin system, and mouse support.</li>
<li>Users appreciate Micro for its simplicity and functionality, and can report bugs on GitHub or engage in informal discussions on Gitter chat.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://micro-editor.github.io/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-18T00:00:00.000Zmicro – A Modern Alternative to nano</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LK-99 isn’t a superconductor]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>LK-99, once believed to be a room-temperature superconductor, has been found to be an insulator due to impurities in the material, such as copper sulfide.</li>
<li>The discovery emphasizes the significance of using single crystals for precise examination of material properties.</li>
<li>The debunking of LK-99 as a superconductor is considered a rapid and conclusive outcome.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-02585-7</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZLK-99 isn’t a superconductor</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Htmx is part of the GitHub Accelerator]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>htmx has been selected for the inaugural class of the GitHub Open Source Accelerator.</li>
<li>This program offers htmx developers the chance to collaborate with and learn from successful open source developers.</li>
<li>With the goal of making working on htmx a full-time job, htmx plans to work on htmx 2.0 and encourages exploring other open source projects from the accelerator.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://htmx.org/posts/2023-06-06-htmx-github-accelerator/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZHtmx is part of the GitHub Accelerator</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naomi Wu and the Silence That Speaks Volumes]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Chinese tech influencer Naomi Wu, known as &quot;Sexy Cyborg,&quot; has been silenced, raising concerns about state repression and Western perception of Chinese activists.</li>
<li>The article highlights Wu&#39;s technical expertise and relatability, as well as the unfavorable treatment she has received from Western media and lack of coverage on her situation.</li>
<li>The closure of the Beijing LGBT Center and increased oppression faced by the LGBTQ community in China are discussed, along with accusations of colluding with foreign forces and cybersecurity vulnerabilities. This raises concerns about the consequences for individuals speaking out and China&#39;s surveillance and censorship tactics.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hackingbutlegal.com/naomi-wu-and-the-silence-that-speaks-volumes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZNaomi Wu and the Silence That Speaks Volumes</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brand-new Linux release, which I'm calling the Debian Linux Release (1993)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ian A. Murdock is announcing the upcoming release of Debian Linux, developed from scratch.</li>
<li>Murdock is seeking suggestions and feedback from the Linux community for specific packages and features.</li>
<li>The Debian Linux Release aims to be sleeker, up-to-date, easier to install and maintain, with a menu system, extensive documentation, and options for non-Internet users to receive upgrade packages and access additional packages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://wiki.debian.org/DebianHistory?action=AttachFile&amp;do=get&amp;target=Debian-announcement-1993.txt</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZBrand-new Linux release, which I&apos;m calling the Debian Linux Release (1993)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How They Tried to Kill Me]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Russian journalist Elena Kostyuchenko was poisoned in Munich and fled Ukraine after reporting on the kidnapping and torture of individuals by Russian soldiers.</li>
<li>Her reporting was taken down, and she received threats, leading her to move to Berlin for safety.</li>
<li>Kostyuchenko falls ill with long COVID and suspects she may have been poisoned, although the police investigation is closed due to lack of evidence.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nplusonemag.com/online-only/online-only/how-they-tried-to-kill-me/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZHow They Tried to Kill Me</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How do we save water: Stop growing alfalfa in Imperial County]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The cultivation of alfalfa in California is leading to significant water waste and exacerbating the state&#39;s water supply crisis.</li>
<li>The practice primarily benefits large agribusiness corporations and allows water to be sold at a low price.</li>
<li>The author questions the sustainability of growing alfalfa in the desert and suggests reducing cultivation to alleviate the water supply issue.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.desertsun.com/story/opinion/contributors/valley-voice/2023/02/05/growing-alfalfa-in-imperial-county-and-california-wastes-water/69860506007/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZHow do we save water: Stop growing alfalfa in Imperial County</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today I learned you can pause the Windows Task Manager moving apps around]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Holding down the CTRL key allows users to pause the Windows Task Manager, preventing apps from moving around.</li>
<li>This shortcut can be used on Windows 10, Windows 11, and potentially older versions of the operating system.</li>
<li>While Microsoft is developing a force quit option for Windows 11, the CTRL key shortcut will still be valuable for users who haven&#39;t upgraded yet.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/16/23834125/microsoft-windows-task-manager-pause-shortcut</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZToday I learned you can pause the Windows Task Manager moving apps around</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Windows feature that resets system clocks based on random data is wreaking havoc]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Windows&#39; Secure Time Seeding feature is causing significant disruptions by resetting clocks to incorrect times, impacting critical systems like routing tables for cell phone numbers.</li>
<li>The feature, intended to maintain accurate system clocks, has been identified as the root cause of the time resets that have been reported since 2016.</li>
<li>Engineers and administrators have been frustrated by the issues caused by this little-known feature, leading to inconvenience and unavailability of services.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/security/2023/08/windows-feature-that-resets-system-clocks-based-on-random-data-is-wreaking-havoc/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZWindows feature that resets system clocks based on random data is wreaking havoc</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo is trying to patent some broad Tears of the Kingdom mechanics]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nintendo is attempting to patent several components and mechanics from The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom game, such as loading screen maps and character movement physics.</li>
<li>The patents are considered broad and unreasonable, which may impede the innovation of other developers.</li>
<li>One particularly unique patent pertains to the physics of a character riding on a moving vehicle and their corresponding reactions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-is-trying-to-patent-some-really-broad-tears-of-1850730637</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZNintendo is trying to patent some broad Tears of the Kingdom mechanics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ts_zip: Text Compression Using Large Language Models]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The ts_zip utility, part of the ts_server software, enables text compression using Large Language Models, offering higher compression ratios than other tools.</li>
<li>Text files of various sizes have different compression ratios, along with details on compression speed and memory requirements for specific models.</li>
<li>Smaller RWKV models are recommended for text compression due to their RNN structure and faster performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bellard.org/ts_server/ts_zip.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-17T00:00:00.000ZTs_zip: Text Compression Using Large Language Models</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We reduced the cost of building Mastodon at Twitter-scale by 100x]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Red Planet Labs achieved a 100x reduction in cost for building a Twitter-scale Mastodon instance using the Rama platform.</li>
<li>The instance was built with only 10,000 lines of code, compared to Twitter&#39;s 1 million lines.</li>
<li>Rama offers scalability, performance, and fault tolerance, simplifying backend development. The team plans to release Rama for public download and open-source their Mastodon implementation. PState in Mastodon is used to track data and improve efficiency. Optimization techniques are discussed, and the release of Rama documentation and API is mentioned.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://blog.redplanetlabs.com/2023/08/15/how-we-reduced-the-cost-of-building-twitter-at-twitter-scale-by-100x/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZWe reduced the cost of building Mastodon at Twitter-scale by 100x</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Firefox finally outperforming Google Chrome in SunSpider]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Firefox has surpassed Google Chrome in the SunSpider JavaScript benchmark, marking a significant achievement for Mozilla developers.</li>
<li>Despite this success, Chrome continues to outperform Firefox in the more demanding JetStream 2.0 benchmark.</li>
<li>Firefox has focused on improving upload speed and introducing other enhancements to enhance its overall performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Firefox-Faster-SunSpider</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZFirefox finally outperforming Google Chrome in SunSpider</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The OpenTF Manifesto]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The OpenTF Manifesto raises concerns about a license change in Terraform, an open-source platform, and advocates for either reverting the change or establishing a foundation to maintain an open-source version.</li>
<li>Various companies and individuals actively participate in open-source community initiatives to enhance projects and foster collaboration.</li>
<li>On August 15th, 2023, a group of individuals contributed to individual development and open-source community efforts, such as testing, documentation, consultancy, and utilizing open-source tools.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://opentf.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZThe OpenTF Manifesto</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Is LLaMa.cpp Possible?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author examines the feasibility of running the LLaMa inference code in raw C++ on different hardware, including devices with limited RAM like the Raspberry Pi.</li>
<li>The significance of memory bandwidth in deep learning is discussed, along with the benefits of using lower precision models to decrease memory usage.</li>
<li>Calculations and examples are provided for running LLaMa on various hardware, with an emphasis on the importance of memory bandwidth when sampling from transformers. Additionally, the author highlights the importance of distillation and extended training for smaller models to improve efficiency. However, they acknowledge the possibility of errors in their calculations and encourage feedback.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://finbarr.ca/how-is-llama-cpp-possible/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZHow Is LLaMa.cpp Possible?</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Opendream: A layer-based UI for Stable Diffusion]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Opendream is a web UI tool that introduces features like layering, non-destructive editing, and portability to image generation and manipulation through diffusion models.</li>
<li>Users can build upon existing images, conduct multiple experiments on the same image, and save and share their workflows.</li>
<li>Opendream supports extensions and offers a user-friendly method to write and utilize new diffusion features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/varunshenoy/opendream</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZOpendream: A layer-based UI for Stable Diffusion</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISPs complain that listing every fee is too hard, urge FCC to scrap new rule]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The US broadband industry is opposing a requirement by the FCC to disclose all monthly fees, arguing that it would add complexity and burden for both consumers and providers.</li>
<li>Lobby groups suggest including an explanatory statement about fees, similar to government-imposed taxes, instead of listing all fees.</li>
<li>Consumer advocates criticize this proposal, stating that it allows ISPs to hide the true cost of service.</li>
<li>The FCC&#39;s broadband labeling rules, including pricing and additional charges, are currently being reviewed by the US Office of Management and Budget.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/08/isps-complain-that-listing-every-fee-is-too-hard-urge-fcc-to-scrap-new-rule/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZISPs complain that listing every fee is too hard, urge FCC to scrap new rule</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CSS Selectors: A Visual Guide]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This visual guide provides an explanation of various CSS selectors, including pseudo-classes and pseudo-elements, with examples of their usage.</li>
<li>The guide covers selectors for elements, classes, IDs, attributes, and different states of input elements.</li>
<li>It also mentions additional CSS pseudo-classes and pseudo-elements for targeting and styling specific elements within a webpage and provides resources such as SVG generators, tools, and design resources. Please note that it includes affiliate links for related services.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fffuel.co/css-selectors/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZCSS Selectors: A Visual Guide</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How should I read type system notation?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Programming Language Design and Implementation Stack Exchange is a platform for programming language designers and implementers to exchange questions and answers.</li>
<li>A recent question on the site sought guidance on reading type system notation.</li>
<li>The site provides an explanation of the basics, including syntax, grammars, relations, judgments, axioms, and inference rules. It also discusses the role of the context or type environment in determining variable types and other considerations in specifying type systems.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://langdev.stackexchange.com/questions/2692/how-should-i-read-type-system-notation</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZHow should I read type system notation?</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why host your own LLM?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author presents an argument in favor of self-hosting language models (LLMs) instead of relying on publicly available models like OpenAI&#39;s GPT-4.</li>
<li>Self-hosting offers greater control over model architecture and weights, customization and fine-tuning capabilities, and a long-term relationship with the AI model.</li>
<li>Self-hosting allows for more experimentation, optimization, and staying up-to-date with evolving technology, while APIs may not provide the same level of access and understanding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://marble.onl/posts/why_host_your_own_llm.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZWhy host your own LLM?</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modern CSV version 2]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The developer of Modern CSV, Evan, has released version 2 of the tabular file editor/viewer for Windows, Mac, and Linux.</li>
<li>This new version introduces several improvements including an enhanced UI/UX, improved performance, additional features, updated documentation, and native support for Apple Silicon.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to try out the new version and provide feedback to the developer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moderncsv.com/modern-csv-2-is-now-available/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-16T00:00:00.000ZModern CSV version 2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
