<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 10:19:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wavacity – a FOSS port of Audacity to the web]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Wavacity is a free, open-source online audio editor, similar to Audacity, that can be utilized directly in web browsers.</li>
<li>Despite similarities, Wavacity is neither affiliated with nor endorsed by Audacity.</li>
<li>The released Wavacity code comprises various functions and scripts essential for editor functioning and user interface.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://wavacity.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZWavacity – a FOSS port of Audacity to the web</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doug Lenat has died]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post pays homage to Doug Lenat, a renowned AI researcher known for his pioneering work on Cyc, a project designed to encode common sense knowledge for machines to understand.</li>
<li>Cyc, although not commercially profitable, is highlighted by Gary Marcus as a revolutionary experiment critical for developments towards artificial general intelligence.</li>
<li>Marcus focuses on the significance of understanding Cyc&#39;s objectives for budding AI researchers and promotes Lenat&#39;s last paper, co-authored with him, which discusses takeaways from Cyc and possibilities of merging symbolic AI methods with modern Large Language Models.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://garymarcus.substack.com/p/doug-lenat-1950-2023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZDoug Lenat has died</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[X/Twitter has updated its terms of service to let it use posts for AI training]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Twitter has amended its Terms of Service, enabling the company to utilize user posts for AI training.</li>
<li>This adjustment may lead to privacy concerns and potentially a more personalized but limiting internet experience.</li>
<li>This update appears to contradict past commentary from Elon Musk who admonished third-party firms utilizing Twitter data for AI systems.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://stackdiary.com/x-can-now-use-posts-for-ai-training-as-per-terms-of-service/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZX/Twitter has updated its terms of service to let it use posts for AI training</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who is hiring? (September 2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post is soliciting job advertisements from companies, including information about the location and the availability of remote work or visa sponsorship.</li>
<li>It also provides resources and links that job seekers can use to find more information.</li>
<li>Readers are cautioned against complaining about job postings and can reference related threads for more context.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37351667</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZWho is hiring? (September 2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Farewell EC2-Classic, it’s been swell]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>On August 15, 2023, Amazon Web Services (AWS) completely discontinued EC2-Classic, the initial variant of their cloud computing service EC2, which had been operational for close to 17 years.</li>
<li>EC2-Classic simplistically managed the infrastructure, making it easier to design and build applications, and, over time, evolved with new features such as Elastic IPs, Auto Scaling, Load Balancing, and VPC, which led to the design of individually managed cloud segments.</li>
<li>The retirement of EC2-Classic denotes a significant step in the progression of cloud computing; however, AWS remains devoted to advancing and building adaptable systems for customer use.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.allthingsdistributed.com/2023/09/farewell-ec2-classic.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZFarewell EC2-Classic, it’s been swell</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lidl Product Recall [pdf]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;&quot;</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.lidl.co.uk/static/assets/Paw_Patrol_Public_Recall_poster-500790.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZLidl Product Recall [pdf]</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wikipedia search-by-vibes through millions of pages offline]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text introduces a browser-based search engine designed for Wikipedia that enables users to find relevant results offline, enhancing the search experience through sentence transformers, product quantization, and transformers.js.</li>
<li>Featuring faceted search, the engine allows users to search within specified subcategories. It holds a compact database capable of supporting millions of embeddings, with search results updating progressively.</li>
<li>The process outlined includes embedding all of Wikipedia, compressing these embeddings, and then utilizing ONNX (Open Neural Network Exchange) models and the Arrow format for efficient data storage.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.leebutterman.com/2023/06/01/offline-realtime-embedding-search.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZWikipedia search-by-vibes through millions of pages offline</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A deep dive into Single Pair Ethernet]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author discusses the exploration of Single Pair Ethernet (SPE) and Power over Data Lines (PoDL) for high data rates, power delivery, and simplified wiring.</li>
<li>Sensor node creation and testing for wave behavior measurement is also a highlighted component of the project.</li>
<li>Several stages like waterproof housing and PCB design, firmware development using different sensors and libraries, and overcoming encountered challenges were part of the process.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://electricui.com/blog/spe-sensor-node</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZA deep dive into Single Pair Ethernet</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Police Seized Innocent Peoples Property, Kept It for Years. What Will SCOTUS Do?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Supreme Court is preparing to review a case regarding civil asset forfeiture, a method that enables law enforcement to confiscate people&#39;s assets without proving their guilt.</li>
<li>This practice is under criticism for its disregard for due process and the financial stress it imposes on innocent property owners, who may struggle to reclaim their assets.</li>
<li>It is further contended that law enforcement agencies frequently exploit this practice for monetary gain, with the government denying accountability and disregarding due process, often affecting individuals disproportionately.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://reason.com/2023/07/11/police-seized-innocent-peoples-property-and-kept-it-for-years-what-will-the-supreme-court-do/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZPolice Seized Innocent Peoples Property, Kept It for Years. What Will SCOTUS Do?</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARM wrestles assembly language guru's domains away, citing trademark issues]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Maria Markstedter, a recognized expert in assembly language and security researcher, has been served a cease-and-desist order from Arm&#39;s lawyers for using their trademark in her domain name, arm-assembly.com.</li>
<li>Despite her contributions to Arm through her extensive writing, including a book about Arm&#39;s instruction set architecture (ISA), her websites were taken down after her hosting provider received a similar cease and desist letter.</li>
<li>Amid criticism for Arm&#39;s actions, Markstedter has proposed that Arm donate her book to universities and individuals who can&#39;t afford it, although there has been no response to this suggestion thus far.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2023/08/31/a_star_star_domains/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-09-02T00:00:00.000ZARM wrestles assembly language guru&apos;s domains away, citing trademark issues</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CT scans of coffee-making equipment]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article details the history and evolution of the Moka Express and AeroPress coffee brewing methods, utilizing CT scans for in-depth construction analysis.</li>
<li>It includes useful tips for efficiently employing these brewing methods and features a brief mention of gooseneck kettles and Porlex burr grinders.</li>
<li>The importance of these accessories is emphasized in creating a superior coffee brewing experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scanofthemonth.com/scans/coffee</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZCT scans of coffee-making equipment</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When your coworker does great work, tell their manager (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author emphasizes the necessity of acknowledging and supporting colleagues from underrepresented groups at work, contributing towards a more inclusive office environment.</li>
<li>The method for this support includes telling managers about the excellent work these colleagues are doing, potentially aiding in their promotion. It also includes providing constructive feedback and public recognition.</li>
<li>The author, however, cautions about the significance of seeking permission before complimenting a colleague&#39;s work to their managers, respecting personal comfort levels and boundaries. They also provide additional resources for further reading and learning.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jvns.ca/blog/2020/07/14/when-your-coworker-does-great-work-tell-their-manager/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZWhen your coworker does great work, tell their manager (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghostfolio: Open-source wealth management software]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ghostfolio is a privacy-oriented, open-source personal finance dashboard that assists users in tracking and managing their investments in stocks, ETFs, and cryptocurrencies across multiple platforms.</li>
<li>It provides insights into portfolio composition and puts a strong emphasis on privacy and data ownership, receiving positive feedback for its user-friendly interface and useful features.</li>
<li>Ghostfolio operates on a subscription model, offering premium services to its users, and is backed by a robust community of contributors.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ghostfol.io</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZGhostfolio: Open-source wealth management software</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RFC 3339 vs. ISO 8601]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text elucidates on varied date and time formats and their compliance with different standards, illustrating with examples for enhanced understanding.</li>
<li>It delves into timestamps, the length of time or duration values, and ranges in disparate formats, broadening the scope of time-related concepts.</li>
<li>The existence of a validation service and a timezone switcher is mentioned, along with a comprehensive list of timezones across different regions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ijmacd.github.io/rfc3339-iso8601/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZRFC 3339 vs. ISO 8601</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Teaching with AI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenAI has published a guide directed at educators for utilizing their AI language model, ChatGPT, in classrooms.</li>
<li>The guide offers suggested conversation triggers, explains the workings and limitations of ChatGPT, as well as information on AI detectors and bias.</li>
<li>There are teacher testimonials detailing use case scenarios ranging from role-playing difficult discussions, making quizzes and lesson agendas, supporting non-English speakers, to teaching critical reasoning. The guide also contains sample prompts for educator usage.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openai.com/blog/teaching-with-ai</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZTeaching with AI</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Animated Knots]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Animated Knots by Grog&quot; is a comprehensive online resource providing detailed instructions and animated demonstrations for various types of knot tying, applicable to numerous activities such as boating, fishing, climbing, and household tasks.</li>
<li>The website offers in-depth sections on knot terminology, safety information, and rope properties, underlining the significance of knot tying knowledge for safety purposes.</li>
<li>It offers mobile applications oriented towards specific activities such as climbing, boating, fishing, and scouting, featuring a &quot;Knot of the Day&quot; and blog, and even details on knot tying for specific works such as arborist and horse farming.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.animatedknots.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZAnimated Knots</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[USENET rises again?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>USENET, the first text-only social network composed of newsgroups distributed across multiple servers, is revitalizing with its management committee reconvening.</li>
<li>The committee has undertaken the task to refine the list of newsgroups, renovate the website, and incorporate new features for its diverse range of client apps and operating systems.</li>
<li>Despite issues with piracy, USENET continues to maintain its popularity as a discussion platform with a dedicated user base.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2023/08/30/usenet_revival/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZUSENET rises again?</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ask Microsoft: Are you using our personal data to train AI?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mozilla Foundation is demanding clarifications from Microsoft about its intentions to use personal data, such as audio, video, chat, and attachments, for AI model training.</li>
<li>The specificity of Microsoft&#39;s usage of these personal data types remains uncertain, despite input from privacy experts and lawyers.</li>
<li>Mozilla has expressed concern over the privacy implications and urged Microsoft to elucidate its plan surrounding the use of personal data in AI training.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/campaigns/microsoft-ai/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZAsk Microsoft: Are you using our personal data to train AI?</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shell abandons its plan to offset CO2 emissions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Shell Plc has scrapped its plans to execute carbon offset projects in its bid to lower its carbon footprint.</li>
<li>The company&#39;s CEO, Wael Sawan, did not mention this pledge at a recent investor event in June, indicating a strategic change.</li>
<li>This new direction points towards cost reduction and a refocus on oil and gas development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2023-08-31/shell-silently-abandoned-its-100-million-a-year-plan-to-offset-co2-emissions</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZShell abandons its plan to offset CO2 emissions</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modern genetic data suggests pre-humans were a group of only 1,280 individuals]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A recent genetic study proposes that human ancestors nearly faced extinction around 900,000 years ago when the breeding population decreased to just 1,280 and took another 117,000 years to expand.</li>
<li>Up to two-thirds of genetic diversity was lost during this population bottleneck, which may have critically influenced the evolution of modern humans.</li>
<li>The study underscores the significance of climate change in this era but necessitates additional archaeological and fossil evidence to corroborate the findings.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-02712-4</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-09-01T00:00:00.000ZModern genetic data suggests pre-humans were a group of only 1,280 individuals</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I automated half of my typing]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The user has been utilizing a tool that analyzes their Slack messages and generates keyboard shortcuts for commonly used phrases over the past year.</li>
<li>The tool works by parsing the Slack messages to recognize frequently repeated phrases.</li>
<li>This tool provides users with efficiency and convenience by turning routine phrases into easily accessible keyboard shortcuts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/eschluntz/compress</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZI automated half of my typing</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Caste]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post&#39;s author identifies as a member of the Other Backward Classes (OBC), a socio-economically disadvantaged group in India.</li>
<li>They highlight the issue of underrepresentation in academia, specifically pointing out the scarcity of OBC faculty within top-tier Indian institutions.</li>
<li>The overall objective of the post is to raise awareness and offer encouragement for OBC individuals seeking to advance in higher education or secure faculty positions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cs.toronto.edu/~meel/opinions/caste.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZMy Caste</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A DIY ‘bionic pancreas’ is changing diabetes care]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A community of individuals managing type 1 diabetes have developed DIY open-source software to automate blood glucose level management, emphasizing the importance of personalization over commercial systems.</li>
<li>Advocates are pushing for FDA clearance for an open-source algorithm to increase the accessibility to these DIY devices, but cooperation between device manufacturers is necessary for interoperability.</li>
<li>The reported benefits of these open-source AI algorithms in managing diabetes highlight the value of user choice and the progress within the open-source community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-023-02648-9</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZA DIY ‘bionic pancreas’ is changing diabetes care</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft is using malware-like pop-ups in Win11 to get people to ditch Chrome]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft is prompting Windows 11 users with pop-up messages suggesting to switch their default search engine from Google to Bing, even when they&#39;re utilizing Chrome.</li>
<li>These tactics are causing user frustration, as they consider such pop-ups intrusive and believe they should not be subjected to advertisements within an operating system they have bought.</li>
<li>Microsoft has recognized the backlash and has temporarily halted these notifications while they attempt to resolve the issue.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/30/23851902/microsoft-bing-popups-windows-11-malware</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZMicrosoft is using malware-like pop-ups in Win11 to get people to ditch Chrome</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Windows 11 system components use the default browser to open links in Europe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft has rolled out Insider Preview Build 23531 for Windows 11 to the Dev Channel, packed with updates like fixes for safe mode, File Explorer, HDR backgrounds, and Task Manager.</li>
<li>Some known problems continue to persist with the Start menu and search functions on the taskbar. Developers are encouraged to download the latest Windows Insider SDK and NuGet packages to keep up to date.</li>
<li>After a reboot, the Dev Channel is now receiving 23000 series builds, hence the desktop watermark, a regular feature for pre-release builds.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2023/08/25/announcing-windows-11-insider-preview-build-23531-dev-channel/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZWindows 11 system components use the default browser to open links in Europe</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hundreds of thousands trafficked to work as online scammers in SE Asia, says UN]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A report from the UN Human Rights Office reveals that organized criminal gangs are forcing hundreds of thousands of Southeast Asians into online criminal activities like romance-investment scams, crypto fraud, and illicit gambling.</li>
<li>These criminal organizations subject their victims to human rights abuses such as threats, torture, sexual violence, forced labor, and arbitrary detention. The scale of this online scam trafficking is challenging to estimate due to its secretive nature.</li>
<li>The report calls on affected nations to reinforce human rights, enhance governance, enforce the rule of law, and tackle corruption as part of their response to these scams, which have escalated during the COVID-19 pandemic.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.ohchr.org/en/press-releases/2023/08/hundreds-thousands-trafficked-work-online-scammers-se-asia-says-un-report</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZHundreds of thousands trafficked to work as online scammers in SE Asia, says UN</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FCC refuses to scrap rule requiring ISPs to list every monthly fee]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) has denied appeals from Comcast and other ISPs to remove a rule obliging them to disclose all monthly fees.</li>
<li>ISPs argued that this requirement posed administrative challenges and unwarranted complexity, but the FCC stressed the need for transparency for consumers when choosing their internet service.</li>
<li>By legislation, the FCC will enforce these rules, necessitating ISPs to include all government-imposed fees on the broadband label.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/08/fcc-says-too-bad-to-isps-complaining-that-listing-every-fee-is-too-hard/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZFCC refuses to scrap rule requiring ISPs to list every monthly fee</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Long Live the 'GPU Poor' – Open-Source AI Grants]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Open source projects in AI are surging, but developers often lack resources to sustain their work long-term.</li>
<li>AH Capital Management is initiating the a16z Open Source AI Grant program to offer financial support to these developers, mitigating the pressure to generate profits.</li>
<li>The initial group of grant beneficiaries and funded projects have been disclosed.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://a16z.com/2023/08/30/supporting-the-open-source-ai-community/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZLong Live the &apos;GPU Poor&apos; – Open-Source AI Grants</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Absurd Success]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author details their recent developments in enhancing a search engine, such as reducing RAM requirements, removing the need for downtime during upgrades, and increasing document indexing capacity.</li>
<li>A plan is unveiled to improve the URL database and reverse index construction, efforts that have already resulted in reduced RAM usage, simplified backups, and expedited index construction.</li>
<li>The author&#39;s narrative expresses their satisfaction with the performed modifications and asks for donations for continuous improvement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.marginalia.nu/log/87_absurd_success/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZAbsurd Success</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hacking the LG Monitor's EDID]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article addresses a problem with an LG ULTRAGEAR monitor not functioning correctly on the Linux operating system.</li>
<li>The issue is investigated by exploring the Extended Display Identification Data (EDID) file and modifying it using a hex editor.</li>
<li>The problem seems to be linked to graphics card drivers on Linux rather than the monitor itself, suggesting a potential avenue for solving similar issues.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gist.github.com/kj800x/be3001c07c49fdb36970633b0bc6defb</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-31T00:00:00.000ZHacking the LG Monitor&apos;s EDID</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISPs should not police online speech no matter how awful it is]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) argues that Internet Service Providers (ISPs), particularly Tier 1, should not act as content regulators, warning it could lead to potential power abuse and censorship.</li>
<li>The EFF referenced Hurricane Electric, a Tier 1 ISP, which partially denied service to disrupt traffic for a controversy-ridden forum, describing it as a concerning precedent for future censorship acts that may block legal speech.</li>
<li>Instead of ISPs policing content, the EFF advocates for enforcing laws and privacy measures by law enforcement and courts, insisting that protecting human rights shouldn&#39;t depend on corporations acting as speech police.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2023/08/isps-should-not-police-online-speech-no-matter-how-awful-it</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZISPs should not police online speech no matter how awful it is</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Keystroke timing obfuscation added to ssh(1)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Damien Miller has introduced keystroke timing obfuscation to ssh(1), aiming to mask the timing between keystrokes by sending interactive traffic at regular intervals and sending false keystrokes.</li>
<li>This new feature has been incorporated through enhancements to the SSH (Secure Shell) protocol and is expected to be adopted in other systems shortly.</li>
<li>Predominantly seen as a security update, it is predicted to be included in the next OpenBSD release, a free and open-source operating system known for its focus on security features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article;sid=20230829051257</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZKeystroke timing obfuscation added to ssh(1)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why did Python win?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author started their programming journey with JavaScript in 2013, before transitioning to other languages such as Python and eventually settling on Ruby as their preferred language.</li>
<li>The author has observed a shift in language popularity, noticing that Ruby, once on par with Python, has seen a decline in use.</li>
<li>Prompting curiosity, the author is seeking reasons behind this observed trend, leading to less usage and popularity of Ruby.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37308747</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZWhy did Python win?</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Griffin – A fully-regulated, API-driven bank, with Clojure]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Griffin is a regulated banking service business providing API-based solutions and uses Clojure for their platform, citing merits such as immutability and an audit log.</li>
<li>Their platform operates on Kubernetes on AWS with FoundationDB as its database. They apply an event sourcing model and employ Netty, an asynchronous http handler, for handling payment responses.</li>
<li>The company emphasizes the recruitment of remote Clojure coders and rigorous testing of distributed systems to avert race conditions and errors. They employ a testing approach similar to generative testing for better error control.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.juxt.pro/blog/clojure-in-griffin/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZGriffin – A fully-regulated, API-driven bank, with Clojure</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel shows 8 core 528 thread processor with silicon photonics]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Intel has introduced an 8-core, 528-thread processor featuring silicon photonics at the Hot Chips 2023 event. This processor includes a direct mesh-to-mesh optical fabric and is tailored to handle hyper-sparse data workloads.</li>
<li>The processor is designed with a Reduced Instruction Set Computer (RISC) Instruction Set Architecture (ISA), optimizing its simplicity and power efficiency.</li>
<li>The product is being assembled in a multi-chip package with the Embedded Multi-die Interconnect Bridge (EMIB). It is still under development and lacks a commercial name as of now.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.servethehome.com/intel-shows-8-core-528-thread-processor-with-silicon-photonics/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZIntel shows 8 core 528 thread processor with silicon photonics</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Accessible Palette: stop using HSL for color systems (2021)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Postmark has developed a new tool, Accessible Palette, to deal with inconsistencies in lightness and contrast ratios in its prior color system.</li>
<li>The tool uses the CIELAB and LCh color spaces, which offer a more precise representation of how humans perceive color.</li>
<li>Users can utilize Accessible Palette to create color palettes with consistent lightness and predictable contrast; however, popular design tools like Figma, Sketch, and Adobe XD currently do not support these color spaces.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://wildbit.com/blog/accessible-palette-stop-using-hsl-for-color-systems</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZAccessible Palette: stop using HSL for color systems (2021)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iFixit Petitions Government for Right to Hack McDonald's Ice Cream Machine]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>iFixit and Public Knowledge are requesting the Librarian of Congress to permit hacking of McDonald&#39;s McFlurry machines for repair purposes, arguing these machines are often unreliable and allowing digital lock breaking would facilitate diagnosis and repairs.</li>
<li>Currently, Taylor holds exclusive servicing contracts with McDonald&#39;s franchises, but a proposed exemption to the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) could let the franchises undertake their own repairs.</li>
<li>This movement comes amid a lawsuit between Taylor and Kytch, a company that created a device decoding the machines&#39; error codes, and seeks expansion of the repair exemption to include commercial industrial equipment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.404media.co/activists-petition-government-for-right-to-hack-mcdonalds-mcflurry-machines-to-repair-them/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZiFixit Petitions Government for Right to Hack McDonald&apos;s Ice Cream Machine</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New study finds microplastics infiltrate all systems of body, alter behaviour]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Professor Jaime Ross from the University of Rhode Island carried out a study indicating that microplastics can penetrate all systems of the body, even the brain, leading to changes in behavior in mammals.</li>
<li>The research, with mice as test subjects, discovered that exposure to microplastics resulted in both changes in behavior and alternation in immune markers in the liver and brain tissues.</li>
<li>The study illustrates an urgent need for more investigations on health implications linked with microplastic exposure, specifically in mammals.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.sustainableplastics.com/news/microplastics-found-pass-blood-brain-barrier-even-though-ingested-drinking-water</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZNew study finds microplastics infiltrate all systems of body, alter behaviour</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grave flaws in BGP Error handling]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Border Gateway Protocol (BGP), crucial for the routing of network traffic on the internet, is found to have significant flaws in its error handling, potentially causing network disruptions and internet outages.</li>
<li>The author, a professional BGP vulnerability tester, has discovered these issues in multiple vendors&#39; BGP systems and expressed dissatisfaction with their security responses.</li>
<li>The author advocates for the need for vendors to be more accountable for resolving security issues, such as offering bug bounties, and criticizes the ineffectiveness of reporting security flaws directly to vendors, suggesting customer notification as an alternative.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.benjojo.co.uk/post/bgp-path-attributes-grave-error-handling</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZGrave flaws in BGP Error handling</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fomos: Experimental OS, built with Rust]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fomos is an experimental operating system (OS) constructed using Rust, aiming to streamline the relationship between an application and the OS. In Fomos, an app is treated as merely a function and liaises with the OS via a Context structure.</li>
<li>Fomos OS encompasses attributes like sandboxing, instrumentation, debugging, and the transparent restarting of applications. To deal with older versions of apps, the OS constructs new functions within the Context.</li>
<li>Challenges still linger, including security and the scheduling modalities. Future plans encompass extending functionalities like permanent storage, GPU support, network connectivity, and an abstract structure for application communication.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Ruddle/Fomos</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-30T00:00:00.000ZFomos: Experimental OS, built with Rust</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ChatGPT Enterprise]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenAI has launched ChatGPT Enterprise, a new platform providing enhanced security, privacy, faster processing, longer context windows, and data analysis capabilities.</li>
<li>The platform, which is favorably adopted by over 80% of Fortune 500 companies, offers full access to GPT-4 (an advanced AI model) and gives organizations the ability to deploy custom AI assistants without compromising data privacy.</li>
<li>OpenAI values data privacy, signaling that ChatGPT Enterprise is SOC 2 compliant and provides encrypted conversations, planning to introduce additional features in the future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openai.com/blog/introducing-chatgpt-enterprise</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-29T00:00:00.000ZChatGPT Enterprise</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When your classmates threaten you with felony charges]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author discovered a security flaw in a social media app, Fizz, and responsibly disclosed it, only to face a legal threat.</li>
<li>They were able to satisfactorily resolve the situation by seeking legal representation.</li>
<li>The author offers three essential lessons for comparable instances: thoroughly documenting research, remaining composed under threats, and procuring legal help when required.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://miles.land/posts/classmates-legal-threat-fizz-defcon/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-29T00:00:00.000ZWhen your classmates threaten you with felony charges</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What do I think about Community Notes?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Twitter&#39;s Community Notes feature is a fact-checking tool that attaches context notes to tweets to combat misinformation, operating via an open-source algorithm which is discussed in detail in this article.</li>
<li>The article delves into the mechanics of this algorithm, which prioritizes notes with positive ratings from diverse user perspectives, revolving around the concept of &quot;polarity&quot; values in determining note usefulness.</li>
<li>The piece also addresses concerns about centralized manipulation, emphasizes the educational value of Community Notes, and advocates for its potential growth and development, despite acknowledging its lack of full decentralization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://vitalik.ca/general/2023/08/16/communitynotes.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-29T00:00:00.000ZWhat do I think about Community Notes?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon acquires Fig]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fig, a company creating tools for developers, has been acquired by Amazon Web Services (AWS), a subsidiary of Amazon offering cloud computing services.</li>
<li>Current users of Fig will continue to receive support, and the paid team features will be available for free.</li>
<li>As an immediate effect of this acquisition, new user registrations for Fig&#39;s products are paused as the company aims to optimize its products for current clientele and carry out its integration with AWS.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fig.io/blog/post/fig-joins-aws</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-29T00:00:00.000ZAmazon acquires Fig</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenTelemetry in 2023]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenTelemetry (OTEL) was established in 2019 as a merger of two open-source tracing projects, aiming to provide top-notch telemetry for organizations.</li>
<li>OTEL, second most active in Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), has wide acceptance among observability providers and comprises specifications and implementations for metrics, logs, traces, and agent management.</li>
<li>Expansive and widely used, it offers an SDK for instrumenting code in popular languages and a collector to receive and export telemetry, with future expansion and improvement plans.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bit.kevinslin.com/p/opentelemetry-in-2023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-29T00:00:00.000ZOpenTelemetry in 2023</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New images and video confirm Austin-made Tesla model Y has cracked front casting]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>An owner of an Austin-manufactured Tesla Model Y discovered a cracked front casting issue two months after delivery, drawing attention to quality control issues.</li>
<li>The same owner also found a missing brake fluid reservoir cap on their vehicle, which can be a significant safety concern.</li>
<li>The owner, who has not received a proper response from Tesla regarding the issues, urges other Model Y owners to inspect their vehicles and requests Tesla to provide solution documentation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.autoevolution.com/news/new-images-and-video-confirm-austin-made-tesla-model-y-has-cracked-front-casting-220165.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-29T00:00:00.000ZNew images and video confirm Austin-made Tesla model Y has cracked front casting</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An unexpected find that freed 20GB of unused index space (2021)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article focuses on PostgreSQL database optimization techniques such as index deduplication, table rebuilding, using partial indexes, and preventing unnecessary index creation on foreign keys.</li>
<li>The author shares their personal experience, wherein these methods helped free up around 70GB of excess space.</li>
<li>Special focus is given to partial indexes, not only for their capability to enhance performance but also for their role in saving storage space; the implementation process using Django ORM is also covered.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hakibenita.com/postgresql-unused-index-size</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-29T00:00:00.000ZAn unexpected find that freed 20GB of unused index space (2021)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My mother is slowly losing her eyesight, how to prepare?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A user seeks user-friendly and non-technical methods to aid their elder mother, who suffers a degenerative eye condition yet remains an ardent reader, in reading more comfortably.</li>
<li>The user is interested in ways to raise the font size on her e-reader, making it easier for her to read.</li>
<li>The user also looks for ways to facilitate her continued enjoyment of online literature quizzes despite her visual impairment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37293002</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-29T00:00:00.000ZMy mother is slowly losing her eyesight, how to prepare?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Serial adapter/reboot controller for Apple M1/M2]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Central Scrutinizer is a serial adapter and reboot controller specifically designed for Apple M1/M2 machines, offering developers a low-level debugging port.</li>
<li>It also includes a USB2.0 pass-through for booting using the m1n1 bootloader and requires a soldered-on Raspberry-Pi Pico to operate.</li>
<li>The hardware and software for this device are open-source, and it can be assembled with a Pico upon request with various shipping options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tindie.com/products/aaafnraa/serial-adapter-reboot-controller-for-apple-m1m2/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-29T00:00:00.000ZSerial adapter/reboot controller for Apple M1/M2</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3M is paying $5.5B to resolve 300k lawsuits over defective combat earplugs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>3M, a renowned equipment manufacturer, will pay over $5.5 billion to resolve around 300,000 lawsuits charging it sold defective combat earplugs to the US military.</li>
<li>The lawsuits alleged 3M knew its earplugs were too short to provide adequate protection but did not inform the government or the users about it.</li>
<li>Without the settlement, 3M&#39;s potential liability could have exceeded $9.5 billion. This follows a $10.3 billion payment made by 3M in June to settle claims over &quot;forever chemicals.&quot;</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://qz.com/3m-is-paying-5-5-billion-to-resolve-300-000-lawsuits-o-1850780085</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-29T00:00:00.000Z3M is paying $5.5B to resolve 300k lawsuits over defective combat earplugs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new method to reprogram human cells to better mimic embryonic stem cells]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Australian scientists have developed a new method called TNT reprogramming to make human cells act more like embryonic stem cells.</li>
<li>The method aims to erase the cell&#39;s memory and reduce differences between induced pluripotent stem (iPS) cells and embryonic stem (ES) cells.</li>
<li>This breakthrough could advance cell therapies and biomedical research, according to the researchers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.uwa.edu.au/news/Article/2023/August/Scientists-find-way-to-wipe-a-cells-memory-to-reprogram-it-as-a-stem-cell</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-28T00:00:00.000ZA new method to reprogram human cells to better mimic embryonic stem cells</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where do fonts come from? Monotype, mostly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Monotype, a dominant player in the font industry, is posing challenges for independent font designers who struggle to compete and make a living.</li>
<li>Monotype&#39;s market dominance and acquisitions make it difficult for independent designers to thrive, as they take a significant portion of their earnings.</li>
<li>Independent designers also face issues with unauthorized use of their fonts by big corporations.</li>
<li>Monotype is planning to introduce a subscription model for its MyFonts marketplace, raising concerns that it may primarily benefit Monotype.</li>
<li>Monotype is exploring the use of AI for font discovery, but font designers argue that AI cannot replicate the human story and meaning behind fonts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thehustle.co/where-do-fonts-come-from/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-28T00:00:00.000ZWhere do fonts come from? Monotype, mostly</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[111,111.1 meters is reliably 1 degree of latitude]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Stack Exchange is a platform for cartographers, geographers, and GIS professionals to ask and answer questions.</li>
<li>A user is seeking an algorithm to offset latitude and longitude coordinates by a specific distance in meters for their work on an embedded system.</li>
<li>Vincenty&#39;s direct formula is suggested as a potentially helpful algorithm for this purpose, as it is known for its speed and accuracy.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gis.stackexchange.com/a/2964/5599</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-28T00:00:00.000Z111,111.1 meters is reliably 1 degree of latitude</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overthewire.org]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The OverTheWire community provides wargames to help individuals learn and practice security concepts.</li>
<li>These games can be accessed through SSH on various ports.</li>
<li>The community offers a chat platform for users to seek assistance, ask questions, or provide suggestions. Plus, there is a donation plea available for those interested in supporting the community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://overthewire.org/wargames/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-28T00:00:00.000ZOverthewire.org</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some of the error messages produced by Apple's MPW C compiler (2006)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The summary consists of error messages from Apple&#39;s MPW C compiler, decompiled from the String resources.</li>
<li>The error messages include humorous and sarcastic remarks about programming errors and limitations of the compiler.</li>
<li>Copyright concerns are also mentioned in the summary.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~jasonh/personal/humor/compile.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-28T00:00:00.000ZSome of the error messages produced by Apple&apos;s MPW C compiler (2006)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Can Eat Glass]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;I Can Eat Glass&quot; was a linguistic project started by Ethan Mollick in the early days of the internet.</li>
<li>The project aimed to translate the phrase into various languages, resulting in over 150 translations.</li>
<li>Although the original webpage is no longer available, the project gained popularity and became an internet meme, providing humorous translations for tourists.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_Can_Eat_Glass</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-28T00:00:00.000ZI Can Eat Glass</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WTFPython: Exploring and understanding Python through surprising snippets]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;wtfpython&quot; is a project that delves into the hidden aspects and lesser-known features of Python using intriguing code snippets.</li>
<li>It covers a wide range of topics, such as Python concepts, optimizations, unexpected behaviors, common misconceptions, and programming tips.</li>
<li>The project offers a resource called &quot;wtfpython&quot; that provides detailed explanations and examples, and encourages contributions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/satwikkansal/wtfpython</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-28T00:00:00.000ZWTFPython: Exploring and understanding Python through surprising snippets</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Python Type Hints – *args and **kwargs (2021)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The blog post explores the usage of Python&#39;s variable argument operators, *args and **kwargs, in conjunction with type hints.</li>
<li>The incorrect method of declaring types for args and kwargs is discussed, highlighting the need to define the types of the contained arguments.</li>
<li>The Python Enhancement Proposal (PEP) 484 is referenced as a basis for the correct approach, which involves specifying the types of the individual arguments.</li>
<li>The post concludes with an example that successfully passes type checks, showcasing the effectiveness of the recommended method.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://adamj.eu/tech/2021/05/11/python-type-hints-args-and-kwargs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-28T00:00:00.000ZPython Type Hints – *args and **kwargs (2021)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scrum is a cancer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author of the tweet strongly criticizes Scrum, arguing that it makes software teams ineffective.</li>
<li>Two anecdotes are provided to support the negative opinion, one about using Poker as a planning tool and another about the belief that adding process improves efficiency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/svpino/status/1695806027256475777</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-28T00:00:00.000ZScrum is a cancer</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mother is arrested in Bangladesh after son in US criticizes government online]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A mother in Bangladesh has been arrested due to her son&#39;s Facebook post criticizing the government.</li>
<li>The son, a Ph.D. student in the U.S., expressed frustration over his mother&#39;s detention, which he believes was a result of his post.</li>
<li>This incident raises concerns about censorship and persecution of people in the Bangladeshi diaspora who speak out against the government.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.nbcnews.com/news/asian-america/mother-arrested-bangladesh-son-us-criticizes-government-online-rcna101392</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-28T00:00:00.000ZMother is arrested in Bangladesh after son in US criticizes government online</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[E-ink is so Retropunk]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores the author&#39;s fascination with e-ink devices and compares them to the simplicity and magic of computers from the 80s and 90s.</li>
<li>The benefits of e-ink devices are highlighted, including their low power consumption, simple architecture, and lack of unnecessary software and features.</li>
<li>The unique software ecosystem surrounding e-ink devices is discussed, and readers are encouraged to participate in hacking and developing for these devices. Some limitations, such as the proprietary display driver of the reMarkable 2 and the lack of strong package management on the Kobo, are mentioned.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rmkit.dev/eink-is-so-retropunk/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-27T00:00:00.000ZE-ink is so Retropunk</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Block YouTube ads on AppleTV by decrypting and stripping ads from Profobuf]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author explores various methods and tools to block YouTube ads on Apple TV, including decrypting and manipulating Protocol Buffer data.</li>
<li>They discuss the importance of privacy and the negative effects of ads and tracking.</li>
<li>The author sets up a pfSense router and multiple access points, discusses network configurations, troubleshoots issues, and experiments with using a VPN to change their YouTube location and avoid ads.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ericdraken.com/pfsense-decrypt-ad-traffic/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-27T00:00:00.000ZBlock YouTube ads on AppleTV by decrypting and stripping ads from Profobuf</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slack’s migration to a cellular architecture]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Slack has transitioned from a monolithic architecture to a cell-based architecture to enhance redundancy and minimize the impact of site failures.</li>
<li>The migration was prompted by an incident where network disruption in one availability zone resulted in errors for Slack users.</li>
<li>Slack&#39;s new cellular architecture enables the isolation of failures within a single availability zone and redirects user requests to ensure continuous service availability.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://slack.engineering/slacks-migration-to-a-cellular-architecture/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-27T00:00:00.000ZSlack’s migration to a cellular architecture</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If you're interested in eye-tracking, I'm interested in funding you]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Paul Graham, a renowned investor and co-founder of Y Combinator, is actively seeking to fund a startup that focuses on enhancing eye-tracking technology for people with ALS.</li>
<li>The startup&#39;s primary goal would be to develop an improved eye-controlled keyboard, which can greatly assist individuals affected by ALS in communication and everyday tasks.</li>
<li>Graham&#39;s interest in this field showcases the potential for technological advancements to significantly improve the lives of those with ALS, offering a glimpse into the exciting possibilities of assistive technology innovation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/paulg/status/1695596853864321055</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-27T00:00:00.000ZIf you&apos;re interested in eye-tracking, I&apos;m interested in funding you</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[90% of “eco-friendly” paper straws contain traces of toxic forever chemicals]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A study from the University of Antwerp reveals that 90% of eco-friendly paper straws contain harmful &quot;forever chemicals&quot; called PFAS.</li>
<li>PFAS have been linked to various health issues such as high cholesterol, reduced immune response, thyroid disease, and increased cancer risk.</li>
<li>The study found PFAS in 69% of the 39 tested straw brands, with paper straws having the highest presence of these chemicals. The water-resistant coating on paper straws likely contributes to the use of PFAS.</li>
<li>This challenges the assumption that paper straws are automatically healthier and more sustainable than plastic alternatives, calling for further research to determine if PFAS leach out of paper straws during typical use.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://scienceswitch.com/2023/08/27/90-of-eco-friendly-paper-straws-contain-traces-of-toxic-forever-chemicals/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-27T00:00:00.000Z90% of “eco-friendly” paper straws contain traces of toxic forever chemicals</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fish – A friendly interactive shell]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fish shell is a command line shell available on GitHub for macOS, Linux, and various platforms.</li>
<li>Features of fish shell include syntax highlighting, autosuggest-as-you-type, and tab completions.</li>
<li>Installation instructions are provided for macOS, Linux, and Windows, including building from source and dependencies.</li>
<li>The summary also mentions how to contribute to the project and where to find support and resources.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/fish-shell/fish-shell</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-27T00:00:00.000ZFish – A friendly interactive shell</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thoughts about what worked in math circles]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Leading a math circle for 7-8 year olds involved experimenting with different topics to capture their attention.</li>
<li>Propositional logic puzzles and game theory games were successful, while geometry and fold-and-cut activities were not engaging for the children.</li>
<li>Storytelling played a crucial role in engaging young learners, leading them to appreciate math for its own sake, but the author acknowledges the need for more engaging stories with a new group of children.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://buttondown.email/j2kun/archive/thoughts-about-what-worked-in-math-circles/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-27T00:00:00.000ZThoughts about what worked in math circles</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A venture-backed startup has quietly bought more than 80 mom-and-pop shops]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Teamshares, a New York-based startup, specializes in acquiring small businesses that lack succession plans and offering employee ownership.</li>
<li>The company has successfully acquired 84 businesses and generates revenue by selling fintech products.</li>
<li>Teamshares has raised an impressive $245 million in venture capital and intends to replace existing vendors while expanding its product offerings.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/24/this-venture-backed-startup-has-quietly-bought-more-than-80-mom-and-pop-shops/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-27T00:00:00.000ZA venture-backed startup has quietly bought more than 80 mom-and-pop shops</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[n8n.io - A powerful workflow automation tool]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>n8n is a workflow automation tool that is designed to make it easier for technical people to create complex automations efficiently.</li>
<li>It offers a user-friendly interface and the option to customize the automation using JavaScript.</li>
<li>With over 350 native integrations and the ability to create custom scenarios, n8n can be used in various use cases such as customer integrations, CRM customization, and SaaS backend prototyping.</li>
<li>It prioritizes scalability and customizable error handling and can be self-hosted for free or used in the cloud with affordable pricing options.</li>
<li>The n8n community provides support and resources for its users, and the platform is highly praised for its capabilities and flexibility.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://n8n.io</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-27T00:00:00.000Zn8n.io - A powerful workflow automation tool</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Linux on a Commodore 64]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Semu-c64 is a project that allows running Linux on a Commodore C64 using a fork of the semu emulator.</li>
<li>It requires a RAM Expansion Unit and runs very slowly, with booting Linux on a real C64 estimated to take a week.</li>
<li>The code can be built using make and mos-c64-clang, and the emulator can be run on VICE EMU by creating a .d64 file and loading the semu executable.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/onnokort/semu-c64</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-27T00:00:00.000ZLinux on a Commodore 64</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenTF announces fork of Terraform]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenTF is a fork of Terraform created by the OpenTF initiative.</li>
<li>The initiative aims to keep Terraform open-source and has gained significant support from the community.</li>
<li>OpenTF is being developed under a well-known license, will be community-driven, impartial, layered, and modular, and will be backwards-compatible.</li>
<li>OpenTF plans to become part of the Linux Foundation and the Cloud Native Computing Foundation to ensure it remains open-source and vendor-neutral.</li>
<li>The project is nearing completion, with a repository-wide rename, selection of steering committee members, and adjustments to community documents already completed.</li>
<li>A working release of OpenTF is expected in the near future.</li>
<li>OpenTF has already received support from multiple companies and is expected to grow.</li>
<li>OpenTF will be compatible with existing Terraform providers and modules.</li>
<li>Its licensing model will be governed by the foundation and community.</li>
<li>Contributions to OpenTF can be made through resource pledges, spreading the word, and eventually code contributions.</li>
<li>The project aims to establish a public roadmap and RFC process for community input.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://opentf.org/announcement</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZOpenTF announces fork of Terraform</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Factorio: Space Age]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The game &quot;Factorio&quot; is getting a new expansion called &quot;Factorio: Space Age,&quot; which continues the player&#39;s journey after reaching space.</li>
<li>The expansion will introduce new worlds, interplanetary space platforms, and logistics, providing unique challenges and resources.</li>
<li>The release date for the expansion is planned for approximately a year from now and will include improvements to the overall game, such as better train control and blueprint building.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://factorio.com/blog/post/fff-373</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZFactorio: Space Age</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beating GPT-4 on HumanEval with a fine-tuned CodeLlama-34B]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Phind Team has trained CodeLlama models on a dataset and achieved impressive performance results on HumanEval.</li>
<li>They have released the models on Huggingface for verification and to support the open-source community.</li>
<li>The models&#39; pass@1 scores were mentioned, along with a comparison to the performance of GPT-4.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.phind.com/blog/code-llama-beats-gpt4</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZBeating GPT-4 on HumanEval with a fine-tuned CodeLlama-34B</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Web scraping for me, but not for thee]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Companies like Meta and Microsoft prohibit web scraping on their own properties while freely scraping data from other companies&#39; properties, creating a hypocritical stance.</li>
<li>Web scraping involves acquiring data from the internet, but the legal question of who can access and use that data is complex.</li>
<li>Social media companies aggressively pursue web scraping litigation to protect user-generated content, using legal theories like trespass to chattels or breach of contract, even without property rights in the data.</li>
<li>The author criticizes the legal regime that allows companies to create their own intellectual property rights through online terms of use agreements.</li>
<li>The lack of legal requirement for intellectual honesty or consistency in the breach-of-contract-as-property legal regime is highlighted.</li>
<li>The author blames the courts for enabling this hypocrisy and calls for a solution to prevent private companies from inventing intellectual property rights through online contracts.</li>
<li>The legal state of web scraping is seen as unstable and likely to face challenges in the future, specifically in generative AI cases.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://blog.ericgoldman.org/archives/2023/08/web-scraping-for-me-but-not-for-thee-guest-blog-post.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZWeb scraping for me, but not for thee</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Giving up the iPad-only travel dream]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares their experience of using an iPad as their primary travel device and the reasons behind their decision to switch back to a MacBook Air.</li>
<li>They mention the lack of flexibility and functionality compared to a MacBook Air as a key factor in their decision.</li>
<li>Specific limitations, such as the inability to use certain apps and accessories, are highlighted as frustrating aspects of using an iPad for professional work.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sixcolors.com/post/2023/08/why-i-gave-up-on-the-ipad-only-dream/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZGiving up the iPad-only travel dream</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The EU's war on behavioral advertising]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The EU has secured a victory in limiting behavioral advertising, as Meta (formerly Facebook) has agreed to end opt-in defaults for in-app behavioral advertising in the EU.</li>
<li>Changes in privacy policies and legislation, such as Apple&#39;s App Tracking Transparency and Google&#39;s phasing out of third-party cookies, have influenced this decision.</li>
<li>Privacy regulations have had a significant impact on the reach and effectiveness of behavioral advertising, leading to the rise of non-personalized product versions and a potential de-prioritization of EU markets by platforms. However, concerns remain about the potential consequences of the EU&#39;s strict regulatory approach on social media platforms&#39; ability to monetize.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thisisunpacked.substack.com/p/the-eu-war-on-behavioral-advertising</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZThe EU&apos;s war on behavioral advertising</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leaked Wipeout source code leads to near-total rewrite and remaster]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The source code for the original Wipeout game has been leaked, leading to an independent developer rewriting and remastering the game.</li>
<li>Developer Dominic Szablewski improved performance and gameplay by rewriting the rendering, physics, sound, and other elements of the game.</li>
<li>Szablewski has made the code available on GitHub, allowing for it to be compiled for multiple platforms. He hopes that Sony, the owner of the Wipeout franchise, will either allow the remaster to continue or officially release a remastered version.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/08/developer-rewrites-original-wipeout-from-abysmal-leaked-windows-source/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZLeaked Wipeout source code leads to near-total rewrite and remaster</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HelloSystem: A graphical OS built on FreeBSD]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>helloSystem is a user-friendly desktop system based on FreeBSD, with a focus on simplicity and usability for creators.</li>
<li>It is designed to be welcoming to Mac users who are looking to switch to a different operating system.</li>
<li>For more details and information about helloSystem, visit their GitHub page.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hellosystem.github.io/docs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZHelloSystem: A graphical OS built on FreeBSD</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The College Board website shares GPAs, SAT scores with TikTok and Facebook]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The College Board, which administers the SAT and Advanced Placement exams, has been found sharing student data with big tech companies like Facebook and TikTok.</li>
<li>This data sharing is facilitated through &quot;pixels,&quot; invisible tracking technology used for targeted advertising.</li>
<li>Despite claims by the College Board that personally identifiable information is not shared, tests conducted by Gizmodo showed otherwise, raising privacy concerns.</li>
<li>The mandatory nature of the College Board&#39;s services in the American education system adds to these privacy concerns.</li>
<li>The College Board has a history of privacy issues, including selling student data in the past.</li>
<li>It is unclear if the organization is still committed to student privacy as it is no longer a signatory of the Student Privacy Pledge.</li>
<li>The College Board defends its data usage, claiming it helps students access and succeed in college.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gizmodo.com/sat-college-board-tells-facebook-tiktok-your-scores-gpa-1850768077</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZThe College Board website shares GPAs, SAT scores with TikTok and Facebook</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Email Authentication: A Developer's Guide]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Email authentication is crucial for successful email delivery and to prevent emails from ending up in spam folders.</li>
<li>SPF, DKIM, DMARC, and BIMI are key authentication protocols that establish the legitimacy of email senders and enhance domain reputation.</li>
<li>Resend offers automatic handling of SPF and DKIM authentication for improved email deliverability.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://resend.com/blog/email-authentication-a-developers-guide</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-26T00:00:00.000ZEmail Authentication: A Developer&apos;s Guide</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Code Llama, a state-of-the-art large language model for coding]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Code Llama is a new large language model (LLM) specifically designed for coding tasks.</li>
<li>It is capable of generating code and natural language about code from code or natural language prompts.</li>
<li>Code Llama is available in three models: Code Llama, Codel Llama - Python, and Code Llama - Instruct.</li>
<li>It has outperformed other publicly available LLMs on coding tasks.</li>
<li>The models are built on top of Llama 2 and are free for research and commercial use.</li>
<li>Code Llama has the potential to improve developer workflows and make coding more accessible.</li>
<li>It supports popular programming languages and can be used for code completion and debugging.</li>
<li>Safe and responsible use of Code Llama is emphasized, and the models have undergone safety evaluations.</li>
<li>The release of Code Llama encourages innovation and collaboration in the AI community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ai.meta.com/blog/code-llama-large-language-model-coding/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZCode Llama, a state-of-the-art large language model for coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Code Llama, a state-of-the-art large language model for coding]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Code Llama is a cutting-edge large language model (LLM) specifically designed for coding tasks.</li>
<li>It can generate code and natural language about code based on prompts.</li>
<li>Code Llama has three models: Code Llama (the foundational code model), Code Llama - Python (specialized for Python), and Code Llama - Instruct (fine-tuned for natural language instructions).</li>
<li>In benchmark testing, Code Llama outperformed other publicly available LLMs on code tasks.</li>
<li>It supports popular programming languages and can be used for code completion and debugging.</li>
<li>Code Llama has different model sizes to cater to specific latency requirements.</li>
<li>It has the potential to improve coding workflows and make coding more accessible for beginners.</li>
<li>Code Llama is released under a community license, and users must adhere to the acceptable use policy.</li>
<li>The model has undergone safety evaluations and precautions have been taken to mitigate risks.</li>
<li>Developers are encouraged to evaluate the model using code-specific evaluation benchmarks and perform safety studies.</li>
<li>The goal is to continue developing generative AI for coding by leveraging Llama 2 and inspiring others to create innovative tools.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ai.meta.com/blog/code-llama-large-language-model-coding/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZCode Llama, a state-of-the-art large language model for coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hacker News Guidelines]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Hacker News guidelines specify the topics that would interest hackers, excluding politics, crime, sports, and celebrities.</li>
<li>Titles should not be altered, and the original source should be submitted without self-promotion.</li>
<li>In the comments section, users are expected to be polite, avoid snarkiness, and respond to arguments instead of resorting to name-calling. Using uppercase for emphasis and making astroturfing insinuations should be avoided. Complaints about inappropriate submissions should be flagged rather than discussed in comments.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZHacker News Guidelines</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hugging Face raises $235M from investors including Salesforce and Nvidia]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hugging Face, an AI startup, has secured $235 million in Series D funding, with notable investors like Salesforce and Nvidia participating.</li>
<li>The funding round has doubled Hugging Face&#39;s valuation to $4.5 billion since May 2022.</li>
<li>Hugging Face offers data science hosting and development tools, including an AI code repository hub, models, and datasets, as well as web apps for AI-powered applications.</li>
<li>The company provides libraries and paid functionalities such as AutoTrain, Inference API, and Infinity.</li>
<li>The funds raised will be used by Hugging Face to expand its support in research, enterprise, and startups.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/24/hugging-face-raises-235m-from-investors-including-salesforce-and-nvidia/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZHugging Face raises $235M from investors including Salesforce and Nvidia</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bypassing Bitlocker using a cheap logic analyzer on a Lenovo laptop]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author presents a method for bypassing the BitLocker encryption on a Lenovo laptop using a low-cost logic analyzer.</li>
<li>The architecture of BitLocker and the storage of the encryption key in the TPM are explained.</li>
<li>The process of capturing and decoding the TPM exchange to retrieve the encryption key is detailed, along with limitations of the method and recommendations for improved security.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.errno.fr/BypassingBitlocker.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZBypassing Bitlocker using a cheap logic analyzer on a Lenovo laptop</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The human Y chromosome has been completely sequenced]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Telomere-to-Telomere consortium has successfully sequenced and assembled the complete sequence of a human Y chromosome, adding new sequence and correcting errors.</li>
<li>This achievement provides a comprehensive reference sequence for all 24 human chromosomes, aiding in genomic research and insights into human genetic variation and evolution.</li>
<li>The study highlights the importance of accurate representation of the sex chromosome complement in reference genomes and reveals genomic differences and variations between individuals, contributing to our understanding of the human Y chromosome and genetic diversity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06457-y</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZThe human Y chromosome has been completely sequenced</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-source obsidian.md sync server]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A high school graduate has developed a sync service for Obsidian.md, providing an alternative to the official paid service.</li>
<li>While the service is still in development and lacks some features, it offers basic sync functionality.</li>
<li>The creator is aware of potential violations of the terms of service and is willing to remove the repository if necessary. The service is not aimed at competing with the official offering.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37247767</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZOpen-source obsidian.md sync server</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FreeBSD on Firecracker]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author recounts their experience of successfully porting FreeBSD to run on the Firecracker Virtual Machine Monitor.</li>
<li>Despite facing challenges, they managed to overcome them and make significant progress in optimizing FreeBSD to improve its boot time on Firecracker.</li>
<li>The author also mentions future plans, including separating Xen support and potentially porting Firecracker to run on FreeBSD.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.usenix.org/publications/loginonline/freebsd-firecracker</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZFreeBSD on Firecracker</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jacobin: A more than minimal JVM written in Go]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Jacobin is a Go-based JVM implementation that can execute Java 17 classes, offering a more comprehensive JVM implementation with clear and cohesive code.</li>
<li>Unlike other JVM implementations, Jacobin leverages Go&#39;s built-in memory management and does not include garbage collection code.</li>
<li>The project is extensively tested, and the development team aims to run OpenJDK test suites in the future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jacobin.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZJacobin: A more than minimal JVM written in Go</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proof-of-Work Defense for Onion Services]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tor has implemented a proof-of-work (PoW) defense for onion services to prevent denial of service (DoS) attacks.</li>
<li>Incoming client connections are required to solve a puzzle, proving their authenticity and discouraging attackers.</li>
<li>The PoW mechanism prioritizes genuine traffic and makes large-scale attacks impractical, enhancing the security and reliability of the Tor network.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.torproject.org/introducing-proof-of-work-defense-for-onion-services/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-25T00:00:00.000ZProof-of-Work Defense for Onion Services</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI real-time human full-body photo generator]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Human Generator is an API tool that utilizes advanced AI algorithms to generate hyperrealistic full-body photos of people in real-time.</li>
<li>The tool offers maximum diversity in terms of ethnicity, age, and body type, and supports different poses and clothing options.</li>
<li>It is free for non-commercial use and provides additional features such as generating variations and animations.</li>
<li>Human Generator is part of a suite of products that includes Face Generator, Face Gallery, Anonymizer, and Datasets.</li>
<li>Users can contact the company to address any questions or concerns regarding the usage, safety, and storage of the generated content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://generated.photos/human-generator/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZAI real-time human full-body photo generator</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Common mistakes in salary negotiation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article offers advice on salary negotiation, highlighting the significance of withholding excessive information during the early stages of the job search.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the importance of proper preparation and control in negotiations, and warns against sharing salary details too early.</li>
<li>The article suggests using email as a communication tool for negotiating, as it allows for more thoughtful and strategic responses.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://interviewing.io/blog/sabotage-salary-negotiation-before-even-start</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZCommon mistakes in salary negotiation</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An excruciatingly detailed guide to SSH (but only the things I find useful)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This blog post offers a thorough guide to SSH, explaining different aspects like port forwarding, agent forwarding, and proxying.</li>
<li>It explores SSH features like TTY command allocation and the SSH config file, while also discussing security risks.</li>
<li>The guide includes practical examples, commands, and suggestions for setting up SSH tunnels and accessing servers, along with additional references for further information.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://grahamhelton.com/blog/ssh-cheatsheet/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZAn excruciatingly detailed guide to SSH (but only the things I find useful)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cash payments above €3000 to be outlawed in Netherlands]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>There is currently no maximum limit for cash payments in the Netherlands.</li>
<li>Sellers must conduct a client investigation for cash purchases above €10,000.</li>
<li>The government is working on a proposal to prohibit cash payments above €3,000 to prevent money laundering and terrorism financing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.rijksoverheid.nl/onderwerpen/geldzaken/vraag-en-antwoord/grote-aankopen-met-contant-geld</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZCash payments above €3000 to be outlawed in Netherlands</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia announces financial results for second quarter fiscal 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NVIDIA has achieved record-breaking revenue in the second quarter of fiscal 2024, with a 101% increase from the previous year.</li>
<li>The company&#39;s Data Center revenue also soared by 171%.</li>
<li>NVIDIA&#39;s CEO highlighted the shift towards accelerated computing and generative AI and announced plans for share repurchases and a cash dividend.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-announces-financial-results-for-second-quarter-fiscal-2024</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZNvidia announces financial results for second quarter fiscal 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bun v0.8]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Bun v0.8.0 brings new features, bug fixes, and improvements to compatibility and stability.</li>
<li>Bun 1.0 is set for release on September 7th, promising additional enhancements and bug fixes.</li>
<li>For more detailed information on the updates, refer to the provided link.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bun.sh/blog/bun-v0.8.0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZBun v0.8</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A group of Motherboard folks just spun up their own new independent outlet]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>404 Media is a new digital media company founded by former journalists from VICE&#39;s Motherboard.</li>
<li>The company focuses on producing technology journalism that has a significant societal impact and operates as a sustainable, reader-supported business.</li>
<li>They plan to report on unique stories, expose wrongdoing, and provide serious and irreverent content.</li>
<li>The site will initially offer free access to articles, but a paywall for certain content will be introduced in the future.</li>
<li>Subscribers will receive benefits such as exclusive articles, commenting privileges, and bonus podcast episodes.</li>
<li>The company&#39;s long-term goals include expanding into other media formats like books, documentaries, and films.</li>
<li>They prioritize transparency, ground-up reporting, and investigative journalism, with a focus on topics such as hacking, cybersecurity, sex, AI, consumer rights, surveillance, and privacy.</li>
<li>The founders aim to create a profitable media company by prioritizing quality journalism, making cost-effective decisions, and seeking support from their audience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.404media.co/welcome-to-404-media/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZA group of Motherboard folks just spun up their own new independent outlet</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A half-hour to learn Rust (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This article offers a comprehensive introduction to the Rust programming language, covering syntax, concepts, features, and code examples.</li>
<li>It explores important topics like pattern matching, variable bindings and references, generics, lifetimes, borrowing, and error handling.</li>
<li>The article emphasizes the usefulness of the Rust compiler and provides additional resources for further learning.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fasterthanli.me/articles/a-half-hour-to-learn-rust</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZA half-hour to learn Rust (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[So Long, Twitter and Reddit]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Software developer Andrew Kelley has left Twitter and Reddit due to the negative impact on his mental well-being.</li>
<li>Kelley believes that Twitter promotes angry and extreme content, contributing to a negative worldview.</li>
<li>He also criticizes Reddit for its profit-driven approach and quality decline, closing the /r/zig subreddit and suggesting the Ziggit alternative.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://andrewkelley.me/post/goodbye-twitter-reddit.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZSo Long, Twitter and Reddit</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coffee grounds make concrete 30% stronger]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Engineers in Australia have discovered a method to enhance the strength of concrete by incorporating roasted used-coffee grounds.</li>
<li>This technique involves turning waste coffee grounds into biochar, resulting in concrete that is 30% stronger.</li>
<li>By utilizing this approach, not only does the performance of concrete improve, but it also reduces the amount of waste sent to landfills.</li>
<li>The team intends to partner with different industries and conduct field trials to implement their findings.</li>
<li>This innovation has the potential to greatly enhance the recycling of organic waste and help preserve valuable resources such as sand.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.rmit.edu.au/news/all-news/2023/aug/coffee-concrete</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-08-24T00:00:00.000ZCoffee grounds make concrete 30% stronger</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
