<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 10:07:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title
      ><![CDATA[Eloquent JavaScript 4th Edition: A Comprehensive Guide to JavaScript and Programming]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Eloquent JavaScript 4th edition&quot; is a book by Marijn Haverbeke covering JavaScript, programming, and digital concepts, available online or in paperback under a Creative Commons license.</li>
<li>The book delves into language, browser, Node.js, with illustrations by diverse artists, offering resources like code sandbox, exercise solutions, and multiple book versions.</li>
<li>It has been published in various editions and translated into different languages, making it a valuable resource for learners interested in JavaScript and the digital world.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://eloquentjavascript.net/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZEloquent JavaScript 4th Edition: A Comprehensive Guide to JavaScript and Programming</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sweden Joins NATO for Collective Defense]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Sweden joined NATO as the 32nd member on March 7, 2024, by submitting its instrument of accession to the United States Government.</li>
<li>Being part of NATO&#39;s collective defense, Sweden&#39;s membership will have implications on its foreign and security policies.</li>
<li>The Prime Minister&#39;s Office and the Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Sweden have issued various statements and press releases addressing Sweden&#39;s NATO membership.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.government.se/press-releases/2024/03/sweden-is-a-nato-member/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZSweden Joins NATO for Collective Defense</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bypass Copy-Paste Restrictions with Chrome Extension 2.0]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text addresses the frustration of encountering copy and paste restrictions in web applications.</li>
<li>A Google Chrome extension has been introduced to bypass copy and paste blocking, with a recent version 2 update offering enhanced control over the supported sites and increased transparency regarding data handling.</li>
<li>This release aims to empower users with more options to overcome copy and paste limitations on various websites efficiently.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/aaronraimist/DontFuckWithPaste</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZBypass Copy-Paste Restrictions with Chrome Extension 2.0</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Exponential Smoothing for Smooth UI Animations]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text delves into utilizing exponential smoothing for generating smooth animations, especially in UI elements such as toggle buttons, explaining its mathematical concept and comparing it to other easing functions.</li>
<li>It provides practical examples of implementing exponential smoothing and touches on challenges like animation jittering and floating-point precision.</li>
<li>Exponential smoothing emerges as a valuable technique for creating seamless and lifelike animations, offering a smooth user experience in UI design.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lisyarus.github.io/blog/programming/2023/02/21/exponential-smoothing.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZExploring Exponential Smoothing for Smooth UI Animations</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beware: Potential Data Exposure from Private Links]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Malware/url analysis platforms such as urlscan.io, Hybrid Analysis, and Cloudflare Radar store numerous private links submitted by users, including cloud storage files and password reset links.</li>
<li>Concerns arise as these links can be publicly accessed via search engines, potentially compromising data privacy and security.</li>
<li>Users face challenges in preventing leaks and safeguarding sensitive information, despite some platforms offering the option to flag and remove such links. Exercise caution when accessing these links to mitigate phishing and malware risks.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://vin01.github.io/piptagole/security-tools/soar/urlscan/hybrid-analysis/data-leaks/urlscan.io/cloudflare-radar%22/2024/03/07/url-database-leaks-private-urls.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZBeware: Potential Data Exposure from Private Links</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Ex-Engineer Faces Jail for AI Theft]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Former Google software engineer Linwei Ding faces charges for stealing AI trade secrets from Google while collaborating with Chinese companies, punishable by up to 10 years in prison.</li>
<li>Google detected the theft, prompting law enforcement involvement, resulting in Ding&#39;s arrest and the confiscation of electronic devices holding stolen data.</li>
<li>The Justice Department highlights worries about national security due to foreign entities potentially exploiting AI tech for nefarious activities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apnews.com/article/china-google-justice-department-63156ade1e564d15d92adbef91e9c5da</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZGoogle Ex-Engineer Faces Jail for AI Theft</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Pile: 800GB Open-Source Language Modeling Dataset (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Pile is an 800GB open-source language modeling dataset hosted by The Eye, combining 22 smaller datasets in jsonlines format, enhancing cross-domain knowledge and model generalization.</li>
<li>It serves as a benchmark for evaluating models, with good performance on Pile BPB indicating a grasp of diverse domains, leading to enhancements in language modeling benchmarks.</li>
<li>GPT-3 and GPT-2 have demonstrated strong performance on The Pile dataset, showcasing the dataset&#39;s impact on model training and evaluation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pile.eleuther.ai/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZThe Pile: 800GB Open-Source Language Modeling Dataset (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Answer.AI Launches Project to Utilize Multiple GPUs for QLoRA Training]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Answer.AI, led by Jeremy, unveils their first project post-launching their R&amp;D lab, emphasizing the utilization of multiple GPUs for QLoRA training.</li>
<li>The initiative originated from the primary request of open-source model builders, with support from Tim Dettmers to kickstart the project.</li>
<li>Jeremy encourages engagement by welcoming inquiries and feedback on the project.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.answer.ai/posts/2024-03-06-fsdp-qlora.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZAnswer.AI Launches Project to Utilize Multiple GPUs for QLoRA Training</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Futuristic visual programming: Flyde revolutionizes coding]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Flyde is an open-source visual programming language created to enhance traditional coding by enabling the execution of complex diagrams without the need for manual code translation.</li>
<li>It integrates seamlessly with TypeScript/JavaScript code, compatible with Node.js and web browsers, offering a bridge between visual and text-based coding.</li>
<li>Gabriel foresees a future where AI handles coding tasks, emphasizing orchestration and high-level issue resolution, while inviting input on Flyde&#39;s development direction.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/flydelabs/flyde</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZFuturistic visual programming: Flyde revolutionizes coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monitoring Global Energy Systems from Space]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The European Space Agency&#39;s Sentinel-1 satellite utilizes radar imagery to track shifts in the global energy sector at sea, such as changes in offshore wind farms, shipping routes, and offshore oil and gas infrastructure.</li>
<li>The article highlights how Europe&#39;s sanctions on Russian oil are reshaping global crude oil movements, alongside the impact of droughts on the Panama Canal and its repercussions on the worldwide LNG market.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.datadesk.eco/p/sky-lapse-in-two-tone</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZMonitoring Global Energy Systems from Space</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Evolution of UNIX: A Story of Berkeley Software.]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article delves into the history and progression of the UNIX operating system, emphasizing its distribution to academic institutions and research centers by AT&amp;T in the 1970s.</li>
<li>Key personalities like Bill Joy and Ken Thompson are highlighted, along with the UNIX advancements at the University of California, Berkeley, and the legal hurdles and impact BSD had on contemporary systems such as macOS and FreeBSD.</li>
<li>It references &quot;Abort Retry Fail&quot; by Bradford Morgan White as a valuable resource for documenting the computing industry&#39;s history.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.abortretry.fail/p/the-berkley-software-distribution</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZThe Evolution of UNIX: A Story of Berkeley Software.</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Computers Calculate Sine Functions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The blog post explains how calculators calculate the sine function through reduction, approximation, and reconstruction steps.</li>
<li>It contrasts the less precise Taylor series approach with the more accurate minimax approximation methods employed by Intel processors.</li>
<li>Understanding these techniques offers a glimpse into the math computations supporting computer simulations and computational tools.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://androidcalculator.com/how-do-calculators-compute-sine/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZHow Computers Calculate Sine Functions</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Area 51 (2005) Source Code Unearthed in Garage Sale]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The unofficial release of the Area 51 (2005) video game source code is aimed at preserving this nostalgic cult classic from the early 2000s.</li>
<li>The source code snapshot from March 2005 contains the Entropy engine, game logic, and cross-platform targets, seeking contributors for compiling, debugging, and potentially porting the game to current systems.</li>
<li>Those interested can participate by forking the repository and engaging with the community on platforms like Discord and GitHub Discussions to assist in the restoration project.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ProjectDreamland/area51</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-08T00:00:00.000ZArea 51 (2005) Source Code Unearthed in Garage Sale</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Ends Epic Games Developer Account Amid iOS Threat Controversy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple has terminated Epic Games&#39; developer account, citing it as a threat to the iOS ecosystem after Epic challenged Apple&#39;s dominance in the app economy.</li>
<li>Epic believes Apple is retaliating for criticizing its proposed rules and attempting to compete, while Apple states that Epic breached contractual obligations.</li>
<li>The feud highlights the power dynamics and conflicts between tech giants, shedding light on the complexities of the app store market.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2024/03/06/apple-terminates-epic-games-developer-account-calling-it-a-threat-to-the-ios-ecosystem/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZApple Ends Epic Games Developer Account Amid iOS Threat Controversy</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FDA Approves Dexcom Stelo Glucose Biosensor System for Over-the-Counter Use]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The FDA approved the first over-the-counter continuous glucose monitor, the Dexcom Stelo Glucose Biosensor System, for individuals over 18 not on insulin, enabling continuous blood glucose monitoring via a sensor and smartphone app.</li>
<li>The device is not suitable for those with low blood sugar issues, as it aims to provide health information independently of healthcare providers, helping to advance health equity by allowing healthcare at home.</li>
<li>Clinical trials showed results similar to other monitors, but reported adverse events include local infections and skin irritation, showcasing the FDA&#39;s support for innovative home healthcare solutions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-clears-first-over-counter-continuous-glucose-monitor</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZFDA Approves Dexcom Stelo Glucose Biosensor System for Over-the-Counter Use</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chrome Extension Alerts Ownership Changes]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Under New Management&quot; is a Chrome extension that notifies users about ownership changes in their installed extensions, aiming to enhance security by detecting potential risks.</li>
<li>Users can acquire the extension from the Chrome Web Store or by downloading a prebuilt release, utilizing technologies like Parcel, React, Typescript, and TailwindCSS.</li>
<li>The extension operates by leveraging an external server, the ExBoost API, to monitor modifications in the Chrome Web Store.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/classvsoftware/under-new-management</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZChrome Extension Alerts Ownership Changes</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Airtable Acquires Airplane: A Reflection on the Acquisition Process]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author&#39;s former company, Airplane, was acquired by Airtable, leading to the shutdown of their product after almost two years of work.</li>
<li>Factors like revenue growth decline, employee departures, and leadership shifts were highlighted as precursors to the acquisition.</li>
<li>The author and some coworkers turned down job offers from Airtable due to unclear communication and dissatisfaction with the acquisition process, reflecting on customer impact and proposing different potential outcomes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://yolken.net/blog/end-of-airplanedev</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZAirtable Acquires Airplane: A Reflection on the Acquisition Process</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NTSB Raises Concerns Over Boeing Withholding Details on Door Plug]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Boeing is not sharing crucial details with the National Transportation Safety Board about a door plug panel incident on a Boeing 737 Max 9 aircraft.</li>
<li>The NTSB faces challenges in identifying who handled the door plug, as Boeing has not supplied the needed documents or employee information.</li>
<li>The FAA has set a deadline until late May for Boeing to rectify broader quality-control problems, raising worries about the company&#39;s quality assurance procedures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.npr.org/2024/03/06/1236277058/boeing-737-max-9-alaska-airlines-door-plug-removed-ntsb-commerce-cantwell-cruz</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZNTSB Raises Concerns Over Boeing Withholding Details on Door Plug</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Dada: A New Programming Language]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dada-lang.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Dada: A New Programming Language</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Docker Image Compiler for Portable Executables]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Dockerc compiles Docker images into standalone binaries for running executables without using docker run or package installation commands.</li>
<li>It offers features like compiler, rootless containers, MacOS, Windows, x86_64, and arm64 support, with options to specify arguments, environment variables, and volumes.</li>
<li>Skopeo is utilized for image loading, and the tool can be constructed from source with Zig.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/NilsIrl/dockerc</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZDocker Image Compiler for Portable Executables</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leadership: Authenticity Over Corporate Jargon]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author criticizes a mandatory leadership meeting at their workplace, highlighting the lack of genuine leadership and the abundance of corporate jargon.</li>
<li>They stress the importance of authenticity and empathy over empty rhetoric in management roles.</li>
<li>The author reflects on their experiences with various leaders, questions traditional leadership roles, and explores their interest in Extreme Programming and Pivotal Software.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ludic.mataroa.blog/blog/leadership-is-a-hell-of-a-drug/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZLeadership: Authenticity Over Corporate Jargon</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hackers Earn $50,000 Bounty from Google for AI Vulnerability]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The team discovered a code injection method in SVG to evade a CSP filter, enabling email exfiltration, leading to a successful report to Google and a bounty reward.</li>
<li>Besides their findings, other participants also identified similar exploits during the event, resulting in a total earnings of $50,000 and a notable position in the competition.</li>
<li>Engaging with Google&#39;s VRP team, the team gained insights into AI hacking, fostering anticipation for future hacking opportunities with Google.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.landh.tech/blog/20240304-google-hack-50000/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZHackers Earn $50,000 Bounty from Google for AI Vulnerability</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Medellín's Cooling Success: Green Corridors Combat Climate Change]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Medellín, Colombia effectively reduced its city temperature by 2°C in three years by creating &quot;Green Corridors&quot; with tree-lined areas and green infrastructure, enhancing urban cooling, air quality, and biodiversity.</li>
<li>The initiative not only decreased CO2 levels and air pollution but also boosted cycling rates, drawing attention from other cities aiming to tackle climate change and urban heat island issues.</li>
<li>Despite facing maintenance hurdles, Medellín is dedicated to scaling up and improving its green infrastructure project for long-term sustainable benefits.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://reasonstobecheerful.world/green-corridors-medellin-colombia-urban-heat/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZMedellín&apos;s Cooling Success: Green Corridors Combat Climate Change</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unlock Savings with Bob Cassette Rewinder]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Bob Cassette Rewinder offers a budget-friendly method to bypass Bob Dishwasher&#39;s costly DRM system by Daan Tech, saving 98% on detergent costs.</li>
<li>Through analyzing cassette circuitry, the author reset the counter, gauged detergent concentration, and proposes eco-friendly refillable cartridge usage, scrutinizing Daan Tech&#39;s subscription model.</li>
<li>The article delves into sustainability concerns and cost-effective alternatives while questioning the environmental strategies of the company.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/dekuNukem/bob_cassette_rewinder</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZUnlock Savings with Bob Cassette Rewinder</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Fructose: Strongly Typed LLM Calls]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fructose is a Python package by Erik from Banana, utilizing LLMs as strongly typed functions to ensure correctly typed outputs through function type signatures.</li>
<li>It is currently a client-only library calling gpt-4 in json mode, with plans to introduce a lightweight formatting model to enhance accuracy and minimize token burn.</li>
<li>The aim of Fructose is to facilitate the creation of more intricate applications by integrating code with LLMs effectively.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/bananaml/fructose</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Fructose: Strongly Typed LLM Calls</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FDA Bans PFAS 'Forever Chemicals' from US Food Packaging]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The FDA has declared that PFAS, harmful &quot;forever chemicals,&quot; will be eliminated from new food packaging items in the U.S., including takeout containers and fast-food wraps.</li>
<li>U.S. food packaging producers have voluntarily phased out PFAS to decrease consumer exposure to these long-lasting chemicals, aiming to improve food safety.</li>
<li>This action is a positive move toward safeguarding consumers by reducing a significant source of PFAS exposure, despite other environmental outlets for these chemicals still existing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.livescience.com/health/food-diet/pfas-forever-chemicals-to-officially-be-removed-from-food-packaging-fda-says</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZFDA Bans PFAS &apos;Forever Chemicals&apos; from US Food Packaging</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhancing Tailwind CSS v4.0 with Rust Engine for Improved Performance]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tailwind CSS is launching version 4.0, featuring a revamped engine in Rust for enhanced performance and reduced size.</li>
<li>New functionalities such as improved @import management, vendor prefixing, and CSS-native elements like CSS variables are introduced.</li>
<li>The update involves eliminating obsolete classes, upcoming JavaScript configuration, and a standalone CLI under development for the next release.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tailwindcss.com/blog/tailwindcss-v4-alpha</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZEnhancing Tailwind CSS v4.0 with Rust Engine for Improved Performance</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nikon Acquires RED.com, Enhancing Cinema Camera Innovation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nikon Corporation has acquired RED.com, LLC, a distinguished US cinema camera manufacturer recognized for its cutting-edge digital cinema cameras.</li>
<li>The partnership seeks to merge Nikon&#39;s product development and image processing proficiency with RED&#39;s expertise in cinema cameras to introduce inventive products to the professional digital cinema camera sector.</li>
<li>This acquisition allows both companies to enhance their market presence and further advance the realms of film and video production, leveraging RED&#39;s esteemed reputation and commitment to excellence.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nikon.com/company/news/2024/0307_01.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-07T00:00:00.000ZNikon Acquires RED.com, Enhancing Cinema Camera Innovation</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kagi Enhances Search with Wolfram|Alpha Integration]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Kagi aims to enhance search engine results using AI instead of generating them, focusing on authentic content and collaborating with Wolfram|Alpha for improved capabilities.</li>
<li>Integration with Wolfram|Alpha offers quick access to math, time, and unit conversion, alongside knowledge graph widgets and instant summary boxes.</li>
<li>Users can give feedback on the integration and anticipate upcoming features like an enhanced calculator widget, sports scores, and a customizable search widget API.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.kagi.com/kagi-wolfram</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZKagi Enhances Search with Wolfram|Alpha Integration</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monitoring Meta's Business Product Outages]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://metastatus.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZMonitoring Meta&apos;s Business Product Outages</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI's Mission and Partnership Challenges]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenAI is dedicated to ensuring that Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) benefits humanity, facing challenges in funding and partnership with Elon Musk.</li>
<li>The summary showcases OpenAI&#39;s commitment to advancing AI technology for societal benefit, with examples of their tools being utilized across different fields.</li>
<li>Despite disagreements with Elon Musk on the path to AGI development, OpenAI remains focused on their mission, leading to their decision to part ways while continuing to make significant progress.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openai.com/blog/openai-elon-musk</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI&apos;s Mission and Partnership Challenges</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZLUDA: Run CUDA Apps on AMD GPUs with Open-Source Project]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>ZLUDA is an open-source project by Andrzej Janik, enabling CUDA applications for NVIDIA GPUs to run on AMD GPUs, specifically targeting version 3 to allow unmodified application migration to new hardware.</li>
<li>Initially intended for Intel GPUs, ZLUDA has been repurposed for AMD GPUs and tested with software like Blender, photogrammetry apps, and the Arnold renderer, offering near-native performance for CUDA apps on AMD GPUs, despite limitations like slower performance on some apps and incomplete OptiX support.</li>
<li>Janik mentioned the need for major GPU manufacturer support for further ZLUDA development, emphasizing its availability for developers despite being a non-universal solution with potentially limited success for certain CG apps.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cgchannel.com/2024/02/open-source-project-zluda-lets-cuda-apps-run-on-amd-gpus/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZZLUDA: Run CUDA Apps on AMD GPUs with Open-Source Project</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cracking Meta's Messenger Certificate Pinning on macOS]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores cracking Meta&#39;s Messenger certificate pinning on macOS to bypass network request interception.</li>
<li>Different methods like binary patching are discussed to disable certificate pinning and intercept requests successfully.</li>
<li>The approach includes modifying the binary code to deactivate certificate pinning, with the modified version shared among team members for application.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://texts.blog/2024/02/20/cracking-metas-messenger-certificate-pinning-on-macos/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZCracking Meta&apos;s Messenger Certificate Pinning on macOS</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Teen Programmer's Unique Lifestyle: Living on Trains in Germany]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>German teenager Lasse Stolley, a digital nomad, travels 600 miles daily on trains in Germany using an annual railcard, working as a programmer and sleeping on night trains.</li>
<li>Initially needing to persuade his parents, they now back his decision, as he enjoys the freedom to explore various parts of the country while living a minimalist lifestyle due to train space limitations.</li>
<li>Reflecting on his unconventional and calming lifestyle, Lasse spends approximately €10,000 (£8,500) annually to sustain his train-dwelling lifestyle.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://metro.co.uk/2024/03/03/spend-8-500-a-year-live-a-train-20388001/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZTeen Programmer&apos;s Unique Lifestyle: Living on Trains in Germany</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decoding Apple's Paper Text Editor]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article delves into the functionality of the Apple text editor, Paper, emphasizing the TextView class and its key elements: NSTextStorage, NSTextContainer, NSLayoutManager, and ScrollView.</li>
<li>It elaborates on how these components work together to deliver a smooth text editing experience across Apple devices, covering topics such as text styling, layout attributes, text selection, Uniform Type Identifiers (UTIs), text sharing on iOS, and obstacles related to inter-app data transfer.</li>
<li>Additionally, the article touches on optimizations improving typing speed, caching intricate value objects, and leveraging meta attributes for structuring and formatting text efficiently.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://papereditor.app/internals</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZDecoding Apple&apos;s Paper Text Editor</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embracing EU Realities: Key to Effective Management]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Understanding the European Single Market is vital for managers and executives to craft effective management strategies and make informed decisions within the EU.</li>
<li>Regulations like the Digital Markets Act and Digital Services Act aim to maintain the digital single market in the EU, emphasizing the importance of compliance to prevent financial repercussions for companies.</li>
<li>Proactive adaptation to EU regulations is crucial for avoiding costly errors and achieving success in the European market, which promotes peace, integration, and trade liberalization through standardization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.baldurbjarnason.com/2024/facing-reality-in-the-eu-and-tech/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZEmbracing EU Realities: Key to Effective Management</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Datalog: A Promising Solution for Graph Algorithms]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Modern programming languages lack built-in support for graphs and graph algorithms, requiring explicit graph representations, as discussed in response to Hillel Wayne&#39;s article.</li>
<li>Datalog, a declarative language grounded in relational algebra, is suggested as a proficient solution for effectively expressing and executing graph algorithms, showcasing high performance, simple representation, and compatibility with conventional languages.</li>
<li>The proposal of Datalog highlights its potential as a viable option for upcoming programming languages, emphasizing its efficiency and integration capabilities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tylerhou.com/posts/datalog-go-brrr/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZDatalog: A Promising Solution for Graph Algorithms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cloudflare Introduces AI Firewall for Enhanced Model Security]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Cloudflare has introduced Firewall for AI, a specialized security layer for Large Language Models (LLMs) to detect vulnerabilities and offer insight to model owners.</li>
<li>The kit comprises tools like Rate Limiting and Sensitive Data Detection to tackle the unique challenges faced by LLMs, addressing the top vulnerabilities identified by the OWASP foundation.</li>
<li>Emphasizing the significance of safeguarding models, data, and users, Cloudflare&#39;s Firewall for AI aims to boost AI model security, combat user input attacks like prompt injections, and prevent data exfiltration.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.cloudflare.com/firewall-for-ai</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZCloudflare Introduces AI Firewall for Enhanced Model Security</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023 Update: Progress Towards MacBook-Like Smooth Scrolling on Linux]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GitClear&#39;s blog post delves into software engineering metrics, code review, commit activity, and strategies for faster code review.</li>
<li>Emphasizes the significance of measuring and addressing tech debt, comparing various software engineering metrics, and unveiling a new &quot;Developer Analytics&quot; tool.</li>
<li>Provides insights on advancements for achieving smooth scrolling on Linux touchpad similar to a MacBook by 2023.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gitclear.com/blog/linux_touchpad_like_macbook_2023_update_smooth_scroll</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-06T00:00:00.000Z2023 Update: Progress Towards MacBook-Like Smooth Scrolling on Linux</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI uncovers 'murmurations' in elliptic curves]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mathematicians have uncovered surprising patterns, termed &quot;murmurations,&quot; in elliptic curves using artificial intelligence, with implications for number theory and cryptography.</li>
<li>Connections have been identified between elliptic curves, L-functions, and modular forms, enhancing understanding in mathematics.</li>
<li>Machine learning algorithms have shown promise in forecasting elliptic curves&#39; characteristics, potentially sparking advances in number theory.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/elliptic-curve-murmurations-found-with-ai-take-flight-20240305/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZAI uncovers &apos;murmurations&apos; in elliptic curves</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[European Court Upholds Privacy Rights with Encryption Ruling]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The European Court for Human Rights determined that Russia cannot compel Telegram to grant access to encrypted messages, highlighting the significance of robust encryption for safeguarding privacy rights.</li>
<li>This ruling might alleviate the pressure on social media companies in the U.S. to enable access to encrypted messages for law enforcement purposes.</li>
<li>The decision also impacts the UK, where forthcoming laws may have comparable expectations from technology firms, reinforcing the right to privacy and endorsing end-to-end encryption as a defense against IT-related violations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/03/05/encryption-eu-human-rights-privacy-ruling/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZEuropean Court Upholds Privacy Rights with Encryption Ruling</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Power of Shen: Revolutionizing Programming Languages]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Shen Group is dedicated to implementing Shen technology across various programming platforms to overcome language barriers, emphasizing functional programming with features like pattern matching, lambda calculus consistency, and macros.</li>
<li>They offer educational materials, publications, and tools like the THORN theorem prover and the Yggdrasil project, aiming to unify programming languages.</li>
<li>Shen Technology, developed by Mark Tarver in September 2021, promises a powerful and versatile programming experience for developers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://shenlanguage.org/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-06T00:00:00.000ZThe Power of Shen: Revolutionizing Programming Languages</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Claude 3 Model Family: Intelligent, Fast, and Versatile]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Claude 3 model family comprises three models: Haiku, Sonnet, and Opus, each escalating in intelligence and speed, excelling in analysis, forecasting, content creation, code generation, and multi-language conversations with near-instant responses.</li>
<li>Haiku is the swiftest and most economical, Sonnet strikes a balance between intelligence and speed, while Opus leads in intelligence. They provide advanced vision, refined accuracy, vast context processing, and heightened safety features for automation, data processing, sales, customer support, and content management.</li>
<li>Users can access these models on platforms such as claude.ai, Amazon Bedrock, and Google Cloud, with forthcoming updates geared towards bolstering enterprise functionalities and safety protocols.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-3-family</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZClaude 3 Model Family: Intelligent, Fast, and Versatile</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Puter: Advanced Browser-Based Desktop Environment]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Puter&quot; is a sophisticated open-source desktop environment accessible through a web browser, emphasizing being feature-rich, fast, and customizable.</li>
<li>It serves as a substitute for cloud storage platforms or acts as a remote desktop for servers, made with vanilla JavaScript and jQuery for optimal performance and stack management.</li>
<li>The project targets web development, cloud computing, and distributed systems, offering multiple applications, deployable either locally or in live environments, and fostering a welcoming community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/HeyPuter/puter</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZPuter: Advanced Browser-Based Desktop Environment</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unveiling the Graph Type Conundrum]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article delves into the absence of native graph types in popular programming languages, the intricacies of developing graph libraries, and the significance of selecting an appropriate internal graph representation.</li>
<li>It highlights the complexities of graph algorithms, the balance between performance and memory consumption, and how different representations affect graph operations.</li>
<li>Additionally, it mentions graph querying languages, mainstream languages supporting graphs, and the diverse applications of graphs, underlining the importance of optimizing graph operations and exploring specialized solutions for graph problem-solving.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/graph-types/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZUnveiling the Graph Type Conundrum</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple fined 1.8B euros by EU for antitrust in Spotify case]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The website reuters.com features an animation with a 1.5-second fade-in effect, necessitating enabled JavaScript and disabled ad blockers to view.</li>
<li>Additionally, the site incorporates a captcha delivery script for security purposes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-hit-with-over-18-bln-euro-eu-antitrust-fine-spotify-case-2024-03-04/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZApple fined 1.8B euros by EU for antitrust in Spotify case</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call for Return of Physical Controls in Cars by 2026]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Euro NCAP is advocating for car manufacturers to reintroduce physical controls for fundamental functions in vehicles by 2026 to combat distracted driving caused by touchscreen overuse.</li>
<li>The organization suggests separate physical controls for turn signals, hazard lights, windshield wipers, horn, and emergency features to enhance safety.</li>
<li>While Euro NCAP lacks the authority to enforce the use of physical controls, a five-star safety rating from them carries significant weight and could incentivize manufacturers to implement the suggested changes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/03/carmakers-must-bring-back-buttons-to-get-good-safety-scores-in-europe/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZCall for Return of Physical Controls in Cars by 2026</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Lawsuit Settled: Yuzu Emulator Developers Pay $2.4M]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Yuzu settled a lawsuit with Nintendo, agreeing to pay $2.4 million in damages, with both parties mutually accepting the agreement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/oatmealdome/status/1764704580724576465</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZNintendo Lawsuit Settled: Yuzu Emulator Developers Pay $2.4M</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Managing Type 1 Diabetes with Golang: Innovative Tools and Tips]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The blog post explores the difficulties of handling Type 1 diabetes, emphasizing the constant monitoring needed, drawing from the author&#39;s personal journey.</li>
<li>It delves into technological progress in diabetes management, drawing parallels to workplace incident management, utilizing open-source solutions for tracking glucose and incidents.</li>
<li>The author shares inventive methods for collecting glucose data and leveraging incident.io for incident workflows, showcasing how coding aids in managing their health, advocating for others to create projects for better self-care.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bytesizego.com/blog/keeping-alive-with-go</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZManaging Type 1 Diabetes with Golang: Innovative Tools and Tips</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Unveils New MacBook Air with M3 Chip]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple unveils new 13- and 15-inch MacBook Air models powered by the M3 chip, providing enhanced performance, extended battery life, and upgraded AI functions.</li>
<li>The laptops boast a sleek design, vibrant display, and are offered in four color variations, catering to users looking for style and functionality.</li>
<li>Featuring support for external monitors, Wi-Fi 6E connectivity, enhanced camera features, microphones, and speakers, the MacBook Air delivers a diverse and trustworthy option for those in need of efficiency, portability, and advanced features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/03/apple-unveils-the-new-13-and-15-inch-macbook-air-with-the-powerful-m3-chip/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZApple Unveils New MacBook Air with M3 Chip</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Opus 1.5: Machine Learning Boosts Audio Quality]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Opus 1.5 is out, bringing enhancements in audio quality, such as Deep REDundancy (DRED) for concealing packet loss using ML technology.</li>
<li>New features like DRED, LACE, and NoLACE for improved speech quality are off by default, needing manual activation.</li>
<li>The update addresses the balance between loss and latency, aims for DRED standardization, and utilizes a generative model for realistic data loss scenarios.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://opus-codec.org/demo/opus-1.5/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZOpus 1.5: Machine Learning Boosts Audio Quality</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia restricts translation layers in CUDA software beyond its chips]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nvidia updated its licensing terms to prohibit using translation layers for running CUDA-based software on non-Nvidia hardware, a response to ZLUDA and Chinese GPU makers&#39; efforts.</li>
<li>The move intends to safeguard Nvidia&#39;s leadership in accelerated computing, especially in AI applications, allowing legal recompilation of CUDA programs but encouraging porting tools from competitors like AMD and Intel.</li>
<li>This adjustment may prompt a change in Nvidia&#39;s stronghold in the GPGPU sector as rivals enhance hardware while software developers explore alternative platforms.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/gpus/nvidia-bans-using-translation-layers-for-cuda-software-to-run-on-other-chips-new-restriction-apparently-targets-zluda-and-some-chinese-gpu-makers</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZNvidia restricts translation layers in CUDA software beyond its chips</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Astro App: A Comprehensive Sky Object Planning Tool]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The speaker developed a personal tool inspired by NINA&#39;s sky atlas and Robinhood to address the lacking specific sky object planning features in Stellarium and SkySafari.</li>
<li>This newly created tool enables users to access altitude charts, compile lists of favorite objects, check annual maximum and minimum daily altitudes, and utilize real-time cloud data.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://astro.sshh.io/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Astro App: A Comprehensive Sky Object Planning Tool</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Singapore Airlines' Troubled Concorde Service: A Brief History]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Singapore Airlines ran a Concorde between Singapore and London in the late 1970s and early 1980s, dealing with overflight permissions and political issues.</li>
<li>The Concorde service faced financial losses and incidents like an onboard stabbing, leading to its short operation before being terminated.</li>
<li>The last Concorde flight jointly operated departed from Singapore in October 1980; G-BOAD, the aircraft, eventually set records and retired in 2003, now exhibited at the Intrepid Sea, Air &amp; Space Museum in New York.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mainlymiles.com/2024/03/03/singapore-airlines-concorde-full-story/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZSingapore Airlines&apos; Troubled Concorde Service: A Brief History</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Startup Acquisition: $465M Deal Leaves Founders with Nothing]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The acquisition of FanDuel by Paddy Power Betfair for $465M left founders and employees with nothing due to strong liquidation preference rights held by two lead investors.</li>
<li>Liquidation preference, dictating who gets paid first and how much in an acquisition, played a crucial role in this outcome.</li>
<li>Building a healthy, fundable startup is vital to attract investors and negotiate for more favorable terms, highlighting the significance of understanding and navigating investment agreements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fundablestartups.com/blog/half-a-billion</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZStartup Acquisition: $465M Deal Leaves Founders with Nothing</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Miles Davis Jazz Album 'Kind of Blue' Recording in 1959]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores the legendary jazz album &quot;Kind of Blue&quot; recorded in 1959 by Miles Davis, John Coltrane, and Bill Evans, with a specific focus on the track &quot;So What.&quot;</li>
<li>It delves into the cultural and social background of the time, showcasing the unique playing styles of the musicians and their innovative approach.</li>
<li>Additionally, it briefly mentions the structure of popular songs in the twentieth century and the forthcoming book by James Kaplan.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/music/a46871755/james-kaplan-miles-davis-3-shades-of-blue-excerpt/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZMiles Davis Jazz Album &apos;Kind of Blue&apos; Recording in 1959</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rust for Embedded Systems: Benefits, Challenges, Solutions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper explores using Rust programming language for developing embedded software in safety-critical systems like medical devices and autonomous vehicles.</li>
<li>It emphasizes Rust&#39;s memory safety features and its compatibility with existing C codebases, but also points out challenges like inadequate support, limitations of Static Application Security Testing tools, and difficulties in engineering interoperable code.</li>
<li>Developers encounter obstacles when utilizing Rust for embedded systems, requiring insights and recommendations outlined in the paper to address these challenges.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.05063</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-05T00:00:00.000ZRust for Embedded Systems: Benefits, Challenges, Solutions</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimizing CSS for Printing Webpages]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explains how to write CSS for printing webpages, focusing on creating print generators for forms and using @page in CSS to set printing preferences.</li>
<li>It covers setting page size, margins, media queries, box model for margins and padding, and formatting articles for print, along with generating multiple pages with custom elements using JavaScript.</li>
<li>Additionally, it discusses rendering pages on a website, manipulating page elements with JavaScript, setting print orientations, and including user interaction features like checkboxes, with a sample cheatsheet for HTML essentials and a CSS code snippet for styling webpages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://voussoir.net/writing/css_for_printing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZOptimizing CSS for Printing Webpages</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[French Court Orders Orange to Pay €650,000 for GPL Violation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Court of Appeal of Paris mandated Orange, a French telecommunications company, to compensate €500,000 for actual damages and €150,000 for moral damages for breaching the GPL by infringing Entr’Ouvert’s Lasso software copyright.</li>
<li>Orange utilized Lasso software in a government portal without adhering to the GPL licensing conditions, resulting in this legal dispute that culminated in the recent damages ruling by the Paris Court of Appeal.</li>
<li>The Court of Cassation&#39;s reversal of a prior judgment set the stage for the monetary sanctions imposed on Orange following years of litigation surrounding this case.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://heathermeeker.com/2024/02/17/french-court-issues-damages-award-for-violation-of-gpl/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZFrench Court Orders Orange to Pay €650,000 for GPL Violation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Critique of Dead Butterfly Depictions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Emily S. Damstra critiques the common misrepresentation of butterflies in art and products, emphasizing the need for accurate depictions in natural, lifelike poses over traditional pinned positions.</li>
<li>The discussion addresses the symbolism of butterflies in art, the trend towards using live butterfly-based artwork in field guides, and the ongoing debate on their portrayal across different media.</li>
<li>The article offers insights into the author&#39;s ongoing projects and encourages readers to subscribe for future updates.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.emilydamstra.com/please-enough-dead-butterflies/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZCritique of Dead Butterfly Depictions</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bug in Windows API's Reader/Writer Locks]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Users are blocked due to a network policy and are prompted to log in or create an account with a distinct User-Agent.</li>
<li>If users believe the block is a mistake, they can submit a ticket with their IP address and Reddit account details.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://old.reddit.com/r/cpp/comments/1b55686/maybe_possible_bug_in_stdshared_mutex_on_windows/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZBug in Windows API&apos;s Reader/Writer Locks</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Observable Framework 2.0 Revolutionizes Data App Development]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mike Bostock introduced Observable Framework 2.0, an open-source static site generator for developing visually appealing data apps, dashboards, and reports.</li>
<li>The framework enables JavaScript integration in Markdown, provides hot-reloading, and emphasizes reactivity, simplifying data communication and presentation.</li>
<li>Observable Framework targets developers aiming to construct impactful dashboards and reports, showcasing its potential for creating interactive dashboards and hinting at future applications.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://simonwillison.net/2024/Mar/3/interesting-ideas-in-observable-framework/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZObservable Framework 2.0 Revolutionizes Data App Development</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Strategic Insights for Effective Kubernetes Utilization]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Paul Butler discusses the benefits of using Kubernetes at Jamsocket, focusing on simplicity and utilizing a subset of its features effectively.</li>
<li>He highlights running multiple processes, redundancy, and code-based configuration as key aspects of using Kubernetes efficiently.</li>
<li>Paul mentions alternative solutions like Railway and Render, emphasizing the strategic use of Kubernetes with a clear understanding of its purpose.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://paulbutler.org/2024/the-haters-guide-to-kubernetes/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZStrategic Insights for Effective Kubernetes Utilization</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Expert Advice on Solar Energy, Rugby Rules, and Byzantine Empire]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text encompasses diverse topics such as solar panel energy, rugby rules, and The Byzantine Empire.</li>
<li>It includes guidance on organizing a closet, public speaking tips, internet slang explanations, and a code snippet for a function.</li>
<li>Messages also address regrets for missing a wedding, congratulating a professor on an award, and seeking forgiveness for event absences.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gemini.google.com/share/238032386438?hl=en</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZExpert Advice on Solar Energy, Rugby Rules, and Byzantine Empire</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improving PC Cooling with Python and Grafana]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Upgrading to a 5950X CPU led the author to address loud fan behavior by creating a Python script as a systemd service to manage fan and pump speeds based on temperature data.</li>
<li>Resolving the issue involved utilizing sysfs with the nct6775 kernel module for fan control and k10temp for CPU temperature readings, opting for a simpler solution over Liquidctl and lm-sensors.</li>
<li>The author improved their system&#39;s cooling efficiency and decreased noise levels by implementing this new control setup, alongside discussing the integration of Grafana and InfluxDB for monitoring while mentioning future enhancements and challenges.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://calbryant.uk/blog/better-pc-cooling-with-python/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZImproving PC Cooling with Python and Grafana</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supermium: Chromium-Based Browser for Legacy Windows Systems]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Supermium is a Chromium-based web browser designed for Windows XP, 2003, Vista, 7, 8.x, and newer OS versions, offering enhanced privacy and usability compared to Google Chrome.</li>
<li>Developed by Win32, this open-source browser supports Chrome extensions, custom tab features, and advanced security measures, striving to mirror Chrome&#39;s capabilities with added privacy improvements.</li>
<li>Supermium targets users looking for a privacy-focused alternative while enjoying the functionality of Chrome on various Windows operating systems.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://win32subsystem.live/supermium/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZSupermium: Chromium-Based Browser for Legacy Windows Systems</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[French artists' 1899 Predictions for Life in 2000]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>French artists in 1899 accurately predicted automated farming and robotic devices in postcards envisioning life in 2000, viewable online.</li>
<li>The article delves into future predictions, highlighting Ted Mills&#39; contributions to the arts.</li>
<li>Open Culture, providing free educational resources like courses and audiobooks, depends on reader donations and is curated by founder Dan Colman.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.openculture.com/2024/02/how-french-artists-in-1899-envisioned-what-life-would-look-like-in-the-year-2000.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZFrench artists&apos; 1899 Predictions for Life in 2000</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Motion Blur in Animation: Creating Realistic Effects]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article discusses motion blur in animation, highlighting the importance of achieving a natural look by aligning with human vision and perception.</li>
<li>It explains using a shutter function to create a smoother effect in fast-moving objects, emphasizing real-time infinite motion blur animation with a shader for objects like orbiting circles.</li>
<li>The text covers the mathematical calculations and techniques for motion-blurred rotating objects and alternative methods for motion blur in ray-traced rendering, addressing challenges with surface normals and limitations of multisampled methods at high speeds.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.osar.fr/notes/motionblur/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZMotion Blur in Animation: Creating Realistic Effects</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Woman Named "Steve": IT Pioneer, Entrepreneur, Philanthropist]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Dame Stephanie Shirley, also known as &quot;Steve,&quot; is a celebrated IT pioneer, entrepreneur, and philanthropist in Britain, renowned for founding &quot;Freelance Programmers&quot; in the 1960s.</li>
<li>Shirley&#39;s tech company focused on hiring women re-entering the job market after having children, growing to employ over 8,500 individuals and reaching a valuation of $3 billion.</li>
<li>Her contributions to software development include programming for Concorde&#39;s black box and collaborating with NATO, with a personal story of fleeing Nazi Europe and later becoming an influential figure in the IT sector, transitioning to supporting autism research in philanthropy.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.computer.org/publications/tech-news/research/dame-stephanie-steve-shirley-computer-pioneer</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZA Woman Named &quot;Steve&quot;: IT Pioneer, Entrepreneur, Philanthropist</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joplin: Your Secure and Versatile Note-Taking App]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Joplin is an open-source note-taking app enabling users to create multimedia notes, collaborate, save web pages, customize, and access notes across devices.</li>
<li>The app prioritizes privacy and security, offering end-to-end encryption and operating under strict EU privacy regulations from its base in France.</li>
<li>Positive feedback highlights Joplin&#39;s user-friendly interface and robust features, solidifying its position as a favored note-taking tool in the market.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://joplinapp.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZJoplin: Your Secure and Versatile Note-Taking App</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Master Google's SRE Principles and Best Practices]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The book offers a detailed exploration of Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) principles and practices utilized at Google, delving into areas like risk management, automation, incident management, and more.</li>
<li>It provides valuable insights on management strategies, collaboration, and cross-industry lessons learned, enriching the understanding of implementing reliable production services.</li>
<li>Appendices feature tools and templates aimed at enhancing the effective management of production services.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sre.google/sre-book/table-of-contents/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-04T00:00:00.000ZMaster Google&apos;s SRE Principles and Best Practices</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New HSR Thresholds and Fees for 2024 Announced]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>New HSR thresholds and filing fees for 2024 have been announced, emphasizing competition in the marketplace.</li>
<li>The changes will be implemented on February 5, 2024.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ftc.gov/business-guidance/blog/2024/03/price-fixing-algorithm-still-price-fixing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZNew HSR Thresholds and Fees for 2024 Announced</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SoundThinking's Surveillance Raises Civil Rights Concerns]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A leaked spreadsheet in 2024 exposed that ShotSpotter (now SoundThinking) deployed acoustic sensors in cities to detect gunfire for law enforcement, sparking criticism over secrecy and civil rights implications.</li>
<li>The concentration of sensors in Albuquerque suggests a link between income levels and surveillance, raising concerns around privacy and misuse of surveillance tech amidst ShotSpotter&#39;s evidence manipulation and lack of public accountability.</li>
<li>Despite assertions of precision, there are limited independent assessments on the system&#39;s efficacy, highlighting the need for transparency and oversight in surveillance technologies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://computer.rip/2024-03-01-listening-in-on-the-neighborhood.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZSoundThinking&apos;s Surveillance Raises Civil Rights Concerns</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wintergatan's Mesmerizing Marble Machine Music]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The video showcases a marble machine playing Wintergatan&#39;s music, combining different sounds and instruments to produce a distinctive piece.</li>
<li>It begins with the machine starting, marbles rolling, instruments playing, and the music evolving, culminating in a gradual conclusion.</li>
<li>The video ends with the marbles halting, the machine shutting down, and a moment of silence.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IvUU8joBb1Q</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZWintergatan&apos;s Mesmerizing Marble Machine Music</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimizing Code in Go for One Billion Row Challenge]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ben Hoyt optimized Go code to tackle the One Billion Row Challenge, reaching a notable processing time of 3.99 seconds for weather station data, by minimizing memory allocations and enhancing parsing techniques.</li>
<li>His approach outperformed traditional UNIX tools, showcasing the benefits of custom methods, parallelization, and selective avoidance of standard library functions for enhanced efficiency.</li>
<li>The emphasis on code optimization not only boosts user experience but also leads to cost savings in data processing workflows, as highlighted by Hoyt&#39;s experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://benhoyt.com/writings/go-1brc/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZOptimizing Code in Go for One Billion Row Challenge</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crafting a Minecraft Server in Bash: Overcoming Challenges and Creative Solutions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares their experience creating a Minecraft server in Bash, addressing challenges like binary data parsing and optimizing performance.</li>
<li>The project, Witchcraft, faces limitations with decimal numbers and multiplayer functionality, requiring the latest BusyBox version for operation.</li>
<li>The post has garnered praise for its innovative use of Bash scripting in Minecraft, sparking discussions on handling floating point numbers, NULs, and real-time server setup in various forums.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sdomi.pl/weblog/15-witchcraft-minecraft-server-in-bash/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZCrafting a Minecraft Server in Bash: Overcoming Challenges and Creative Solutions</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mathematicians Prove Pólya's Conjecture on Disk Eigenvalues]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mathematicians at the University of Montreal have resolved Pólya&#39;s conjecture for the eigenvalues of a disk, a 70-year-old math problem that was previously unsolved.</li>
<li>They utilized spectral geometry to delve into wave propagation, offering a theoretical solution with implications for computational mathematics.</li>
<li>This breakthrough underscores the importance and versatility of mathematical findings across different disciplines, emphasizing the elegance and significance of mathematics in practical applications.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-03-mathematicians-plya-conjecture-eigenvalues-disk.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZMathematicians Prove Pólya&apos;s Conjecture on Disk Eigenvalues</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introduction to Data Science: HarvardX Class Notes (2019)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Introduction to Data Science originated as class notes for the HarvardX Data Science Series, now available on GitHub under a Creative Commons license.</li>
<li>The book acknowledges the developers of R and other packages, contributors, teaching assistants, and support from NIH grant R25GM114818.</li>
<li>Appreciation is expressed to all who contributed through GitHub pull requests or suggestions, with provided links to the book, updates, and additional resources.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://rafalab.dfci.harvard.edu/dsbook-part-1/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZIntroduction to Data Science: HarvardX Class Notes (2019)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CS 6120: Advanced Compilers - Lesson 1 Overview]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cs.cornell.edu/courses/cs6120/2023fa/self-guided/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZCS 6120: Advanced Compilers - Lesson 1 Overview</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minimal Phone Embraces Simplicity with E Ink Display & QWERTY Keyboard]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Minimal phone is a minimalist handset featuring an E Ink display and physical QWERTY keyboard to minimize distractions.</li>
<li>Running on the MnmlOS platform, a modified version of Android, it will offer restricted access to third-party apps, emphasizing basic functions like calling, texting, and email for productivity and simple entertainment.</li>
<li>User privacy and security take precedence in the design, with a planned crowdfunding campaign for production, priced at $400 retail, and long-term support with updates for over five years.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://newatlas.com/mobile-technology/minimal-phone-eink-keyboard/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZMinimal Phone Embraces Simplicity with E Ink Display &amp; QWERTY Keyboard</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Audio Engineering Pioneer and Amateur Radio Icon, Bob Heil K9EID, Passes Away]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Dr. Bob Heil, K9EID, an audio engineering pioneer for live rock music and dedicated amateur radio enthusiast, passed away at 83 after battling cancer, leaving a lasting legacy in both industries.</li>
<li>Founder of Heil Sound, he was renowned for his technical expertise and mentorship in the ham radio community, generously supporting organizations like ARRL.</li>
<li>The amateur radio community is honoring Dr. Heil with heartfelt tributes, emphasizing his technical accomplishments and compassionate nature; the ARRL website showcases a photo gallery and news pieces commemorating his life.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arrl.org/news/bob-heil-k9eid-silent-key</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZAudio Engineering Pioneer and Amateur Radio Icon, Bob Heil K9EID, Passes Away</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX reaches 17Mb/s speed from satellite to Samsung phone]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SpaceX accomplished a high download speed of 17Mb/s from a satellite to an unmodified Samsung Android phone, shared by Elon Musk on March 2, 2024.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1764032892663906313</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZSpaceX reaches 17Mb/s speed from satellite to Samsung phone</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rogue Wikipedia Editors Create Roads-Exclusive Website]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The US Roads Project, a group of Wikipedia editors focusing on US roads, split from Wikipedia to AARoads due to disagreements on sourcing standards.</li>
<li>Conflict arose over defining valid sources, with some supporting stricter rules and others favoring more flexible guidelines.</li>
<li>Departure of the US Roads Project from Wikipedia resulted in the resignation of some editors; members may consider returning to Wikipedia in the future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gizmodo.com/competing-wikipedia-editors-only-about-roads-aaroads-1851298769</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZRogue Wikipedia Editors Create Roads-Exclusive Website</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Generating Transparent Images with Latent Transparency in SD WebUI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The document introduces a work-in-progress extension for SD WebUI that produces transparent images and layers with latent transparency.</li>
<li>It includes model releases for SDXL, instructions on generating transparent images using specific models, and plans to optimize and launch new models.</li>
<li>Recommendations cover modifying samplers and model settings, along with updates on the sampler adjustments for the model.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/layerdiffusion/sd-forge-layerdiffusion</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZGenerating Transparent Images with Latent Transparency in SD WebUI</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Health Payment Processor Hit by Ransomware, Prescription Market Impacted]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>AlphV, a Russian-speaking ransomware group, targeted the largest US health care payment processor, leading to a nine-day struggle for pharmacies, health care providers, and patients to access life-saving medications.</li>
<li>Operating as a ransomware-as-a-service model, AlphV has amassed over $300 million in ransom payments in the past.</li>
<li>This incident underscores the severe consequences ransomware attacks can have on critical infrastructure, following previous attacks on entities like Colonial Pipeline and hospital networks, with law enforcement facing difficulties in disrupting AlphV&#39;s operations, posing a continued threat to US organizations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/03/us-prescription-market-hamstrung-for-9-days-so-far-by-ransomware-attack/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-03T00:00:00.000ZUS Health Payment Processor Hit by Ransomware, Prescription Market Impacted</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple to Support Progressive Web Apps in EU in iOS 17.4]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple has decided to support Progressive Web Apps in the EU in iOS 17.4 following consumer feedback and the EU Digital Markets Act.</li>
<li>This change addresses security and privacy challenges with web apps and includes notarizing iOS apps, reducing fees, and enabling multiple browser engine support.</li>
<li>Companies like Spotify and Epic Games have expressed discontent with these modifications.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://appleinsider.com/articles/24/03/01/apple-reverses-course-on-death-of-progressive-web-apps-in-eu</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZApple to Support Progressive Web Apps in EU in iOS 17.4</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fugitive Wirecard COO Jan Marsalek Uncovered as Decade-Long GRU Spy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The COO of Wirecard, Jan Marsalek, was disclosed to have worked as a spy for the Russian GRU for ten years, as reported by Roman Dobrokhotov, Christo Grozev, and Michael Weiss on March 1, 2024.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://theins.ru/en/politics/269612</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZFugitive Wirecard COO Jan Marsalek Uncovered as Decade-Long GRU Spy</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK Firms Embrace 4-Day Workweek, Reporting Lasting Benefits]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Many companies have adopted a four-day workweek, leading to happier employees, reduced turnover, and improved efficiency, along with lasting benefits in health and work-life balance.</li>
<li>Success varies based on company-specific requirements and the efficiency of the implementation plan, with some firms making the policy permanent while others assess its impact.</li>
<li>Challenges include balancing client expectations, maintaining adaptability during challenging situations, and ensuring flexibility in the workforce.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.npr.org/2024/02/27/1234271434/4-day-workweek-successful-a-year-later-in-uk</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZUK Firms Embrace 4-Day Workweek, Reporting Lasting Benefits</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Gains Pegasus Spyware Code in Legal Win]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>WhatsApp has obtained access to the NSO Group&#39;s Pegasus spyware code following a legal dispute, enabling them to delve into the spyware&#39;s complete functionality.</li>
<li>The court dismissed NSO&#39;s effort to solely provide details on the installation layer, granting WhatsApp broader access to explore the spyware&#39;s capabilities.</li>
<li>NSO is not required to reveal its customers or server structure, with the trial scheduled to commence in 2025.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/03/whatsapp-finally-forces-pegasus-spyware-maker-to-share-its-secret-code/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZWhatsApp Gains Pegasus Spyware Code in Legal Win</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CSS-Tricks: The Rise, Fall, and Lost Opportunity]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author, who sold CSS-Tricks to DigitalOcean, saw the site&#39;s content and community dismantled after a hopeful beginning.</li>
<li>Despite attempting to reclaim ownership to revive the site, DigitalOcean declined the author&#39;s proposal.</li>
<li>A plan proposed by the author to relaunch the site was not followed through.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chriscoyier.net/2024/02/28/where-im-at-on-the-whole-css-tricks-thing/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZCSS-Tricks: The Rise, Fall, and Lost Opportunity</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atlanta Magnet Man: Keeping Streets Safe, One Ride at a Time]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Alex Benigno, known as the &quot;Atlanta Magnet Man,&quot; cleans Atlanta&#39;s streets using a trailer equipped with magnets, collecting over 410 pounds of metal to prevent car tire damage.</li>
<li>His initiative, recognized on social media, showcases the importance of maintaining safe public spaces, as public services fall short in this aspect.</li>
<li>Organizations like PropelATL applaud Benigno&#39;s efforts, emphasizing the necessity for cities to invest in the upkeep of public infrastructure for safety.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wabe.org/the-atlanta-magnet-man-is-saving-our-car-tires-one-bike-ride-at-a-time/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZAtlanta Magnet Man: Keeping Streets Safe, One Ride at a Time</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech Job Guidelines: Location, Remote, Intern, Visa - Hiring Companies Only.]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Guidelines for job postings on a specific platform include location details, remote options, and preferences for interns or visa candidates.</li>
<li>Only hiring companies are allowed to post job listings, with readers advised to email if interested.</li>
<li>Additional job search resources are provided for further assistance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39562986</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZTech Job Guidelines: Location, Remote, Intern, Visa - Hiring Companies Only.</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Old vs. New Growth Wood: Quality and Longevity Compared]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Old growth wood, harvested from trees aged 100 years or more, is more stable and durable due to tighter growth rings, more heartwood, and fewer knots.</li>
<li>In contrast, new growth wood from faster-growing trees is less durable, prone to warping and rotting, making old growth lumber superior in quality.</li>
<li>Historic windows made from old growth lumber can last over 100 years with proper care, highlighting the value of preserving and restoring them over replacing with new growth wood alternatives.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hullworks.com/wood/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZOld vs. New Growth Wood: Quality and Longevity Compared</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhancing cURL Security with Advanced Fuzzing Techniques]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Trail of Bits conducted a security assessment of cURL and libcurl, enhancing fuzzing techniques to boost code coverage for OSTIF. They pinpointed overlooked code areas, added new seed files, and broadened the range of fuzzed protocols.</li>
<li>Recommendations were given to augment HSTS and Alt-Svc handling coverage. Suggestions for creating dictionaries for supported protocols and implementing structure-aware fuzzing were proposed to improve bug detection efficiency.</li>
<li>Low coverage in critical security files was addressed based on coverage reports, with upcoming updates expected post a 2023 audit.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.trailofbits.com/2024/03/01/toward-more-effective-curl-fuzzing/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZEnhancing cURL Security with Advanced Fuzzing Techniques</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uncovering Noether's Principle in ML: Connection to Conservation Laws]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text delves into Noether&#39;s principle application in physics and machine learning, emphasizing conservation laws and invariances in both fields.</li>
<li>Transformations of data clusters can preserve gradients and other values, akin to conservation laws found in physics.</li>
<li>Symmetry plays a crucial role in upholding stability and optimality in systems, as highlighted in the discussion.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://cgad.ski/blog/where-is-noethers-principle-in-machine-learning.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZUncovering Noether&apos;s Principle in ML: Connection to Conservation Laws</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Accidental Deletion Reveals Lessons on Database Flaws]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author mistakenly removed a game from MAME while attempting to add a proper dump of a Taiwanese version of Martial Masters, realizing the game wasn&#39;t a distinct revision and highlighting the need for thorough data verification.</li>
<li>This incident underscored the significance of double and triple-checking data in databases to detect unnoticed corrupted information.</li>
<li>The experience served as a valuable lesson on the development and imperfections of databases.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.mistys-internet.website/blog/blog/2024/03/01/that-time-i-accidentally-deleted-a-game-from-mame/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZAccidental Deletion Reveals Lessons on Database Flaws</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing JSR: The JavaScript Registry]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>JSR is an open-source package registry tailored for modern JavaScript and TypeScript, providing API docs, .d.ts files, and transpiling for cross-runtime compatibility.</li>
<li>Compatible with Node, Deno, and Cloudflare Workers, JSR collaborates with any JavaScript package manager and enhances npm by offering strongly typed modules and editor support.</li>
<li>JSR does not substitute npm but functions as a complementary tool, ensuring developers have a seamless experience with robust typings and cross-runtime capabilities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jsr.io</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing JSR: The JavaScript Registry</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FastUI: Python-Powered Fast Web UI Building]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FastUI is an upcoming tool for constructing web app interfaces using declarative Python code, enabling developers to craft React-based web apps without JavaScript.</li>
<li>It stresses a clear separation between backend logic and front-end UI design, promoting the reuse of components and a RESTful architecture.</li>
<li>FastUI streamlines communication between backend and frontend by establishing a uniform schema, facilitating the flexibility to integrate various technologies seamlessly.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/pydantic/FastUI</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZFastUI: Python-Powered Fast Web UI Building</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Choosing Ethical FOSS Chat Tools Over Discord]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Discord is criticized for excluding specific users, restricting control over chat logs and moderation, and conflicting with FOSS values, according to the author.</li>
<li>The article promotes FOSS alternatives such as SourceHut, Matrix, and Zulip, advocating for ethical software choices to sustain the FOSS ecosystem.</li>
<li>Accessibility issues with Discord are addressed, with some advancements highlighted for visually impaired users in recent years.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://drewdevault.com/2021/12/28/Dont-use-Discord-for-FOSS.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-02T00:00:00.000ZChoosing Ethical FOSS Chat Tools Over Discord</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6: A Revamped Desktop Experience]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>KDE Plasma 6 is the latest major release of the desktop environment, emphasizing the transition to Wayland, enhancing performance, security, and compatibility with new hardware.</li>
<li>Changes in KDE Plasma 6 include adopting double-click to open files by default, updating the Breeze theme, and enhancing applications like Dolphin and Spectacle.</li>
<li>KDE Frameworks 6 have been launched, laying a robust groundwork for future development, as users eagerly anticipate the evolution of Plasma in the upcoming years.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/963851/0c64b8038c62432c/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZKDE Plasma 6: A Revamped Desktop Experience</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Billing Team Resolves Leap Year Bug Overcharging Subscribers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The billing team resolved a bug that was inaccurately billing monthly subscribers for an additional day, ensuring fair charges for all users.</li>
<li>All test suites have successfully passed, indicating the bug fix is effective, and a postmortem is planned for 2028 pending QA validation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39554539</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZBilling Team Resolves Leap Year Bug Overcharging Subscribers</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hetzner Introduces Hourly Billing for Most Products]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hetzner will switch from monthly to hourly billing for most products starting in March 2024, aiming to enhance user-friendliness.</li>
<li>Invoices during the March and April transition period may fluctuate due to the hourly billing system, reflecting the previous month&#39;s product usage.</li>
<li>Automated payments are an option, and the billing date might be adjusted to improve customer service; however, domains, SSL certificates, and licenses will maintain their annual fee structure.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://docs.hetzner.com/general/others/new-billing-model/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZHetzner Introduces Hourly Billing for Most Products</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Serving Blog Posts as Linux Manual Pages]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author transformed blog posts into Linux manual pages using content negotiation and roff syntax, updating their site to create manual pages for each post and configuring NGINX to process requests for text/roff versions.</li>
<li>Users can request manual pages using the curl command and view them using the man command, making it an engaging exploration of typesetting tech and command line interfaces.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jamesg.blog/2024/02/29/linux-manual-pages/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZServing Blog Posts as Linux Manual Pages</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modernizing a C++ Legacy Codebase: Best Practices for Security and Efficiency]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article offers a detailed guide on enhancing a legacy C++ codebase by gradually enhancing security, developer experience, correctness, and performance through steps like updating with CI tools, linters, and auto-formatting.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the significance of effective communication, collaboration, and code quality maintenance for efficient and secure software development while highlighting the complexities of dependency management in C++.</li>
<li>Recommended practices include utilizing git submodules and compiling from source for improved reliability and control in managing dependencies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gaultier.github.io/blog/you_inherited_a_legacy_cpp_codebase_now_what.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZModernizing a C++ Legacy Codebase: Best Practices for Security and Efficiency</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Row Zero: The Ultimate Spreadsheet Solution]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Row Zero is a cloud-based tool enabling business teams to analyze vast data volumes in a spreadsheet interface, connecting to diverse data sources and facilitating real-time collaboration.</li>
<li>The tool integrates with Python for in-depth analysis, enhances data processing speed, and accuracy, targeting business intelligence, finance, operations, and marketing teams for streamlined data analysis.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rowzero.io</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Row Zero: The Ultimate Spreadsheet Solution</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Distance-Based Workout Tracker: Self-Hosted Web App]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The individual experimented with different web tools for tracking workouts, particularly running, but found them unsatisfactory.</li>
<li>Subsequently, they opted to develop a personalized tool tailored for distance-based activities such as walking, running, and cycling.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/jovandeginste/workout-tracker</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZDistance-Based Workout Tracker: Self-Hosted Web App</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Struct: Feed-Centric Chat Platform]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Struct Chat, a new platform by product designer Jason, aims to tackle the issues like clutter and inefficiencies present in platforms such as Slack and Discord.</li>
<li>The platform utilizes threads, feeds, and AI to maintain focused conversations, generate titles, summaries, and offers robust search functionalities.</li>
<li>Structbot, an AI assistant powered by GPT-4, enhances user experience by answering questions, proactively responding, and smoothly integrating with Chat GPT on various operating systems and Slack.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://struct.ai/blog/introducing-the-struct-chat-platform</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Struct: Feed-Centric Chat Platform</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pioneering Neuroscientist Tackles Alzheimer's and Addiction with Ultrasound]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Dr. Ali Rai, a leading neuroscientist, created an experimental ultrasound treatment to combat beta-amyloid protein in the brain, potentially slowing Alzheimer&#39;s disease progression.</li>
<li>The innovative approach demonstrated success in decreasing plaques, enhancing brain function, and treating Parkinson&#39;s, essential tremors, and addiction.</li>
<li>Dr. Rai&#39;s research signifies a significant advancement in developing enhanced therapies for neurological disorders and addiction, fostering hope for improved treatment outcomes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7BGtVJ3lBdE</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZPioneering Neuroscientist Tackles Alzheimer&apos;s and Addiction with Ultrasound</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Preventing System Overload: Defcon's Graceful Feature Degradation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper explores Meta&#39;s Defcon system, utilizing graceful feature degradation to avert system overload and possible outages by categorizing product features based on business criticality levels.</li>
<li>Incident responders can manage capacity by deactivating features using knobs, controlling feature status on the server-side and client-side, with testing conducted to assess its effects on resource usage and user interactions.</li>
<li>Future endeavors include automating the knob upkeep process, addressing challenges outlined in the paper.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.micahlerner.com/2023/07/23/defcon-preventing-overload-with-graceful-feature-degradation.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZPreventing System Overload: Defcon&apos;s Graceful Feature Degradation</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unveiling GGUF: Program Compilation, GPU Initialization, and Hardware Details]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The message discusses compiling a program, sharing build details, and hardware information.</li>
<li>It loads a model with specific key-value pairs and tensors, initializing GPU processing.</li>
<li>Details about the GPU being utilized are also provided in the message.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://vickiboykis.com/2024/02/28/gguf-the-long-way-around/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZUnveiling GGUF: Program Compilation, GPU Initialization, and Hardware Details</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rendering Protein Structures at Atomic Level in Cells with Unreal Engine]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The preprint explores utilizing the Unreal Engine to visualize protein structures at the atomic level within cells, enabling interactive navigation inside the cell environment.</li>
<li>Cryogenic electron tomography enables the identification of macromolecules inside cells, but the visualization at the atomic level is challenging, addressed by using a video game engine.</li>
<li>Tools are presented to convert protein structures from CryoET into scenes for exploration, with the authors sharing the work under a CC-BY 4.0 International license.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2023.12.08.570879v1</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZRendering Protein Structures at Atomic Level in Cells with Unreal Engine</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Musical Legacy of 'Shave and a Haircut']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Shave and a Haircut&quot; is a famous musical call-and-response couplet used for comedic purposes in various entertainment forms.</li>
<li>The tune is recognized globally, appearing in songs, TV shows, movies, and even serving as an identity verification method for POWs in the Vietnam War.</li>
<li>This melody holds cultural significance across countries, referenced in literature, music, bluegrass genre, works of artists such as Frank Sinatra, and even in shows like Animaniacs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shave_and_a_Haircut</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZThe Musical Legacy of &apos;Shave and a Haircut&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[High-Performance Lock-Free Ring Buffer for Cross-Thread Communication]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post explores a high-performance lock-free ring buffer for seamless cross-thread communication, focusing on circular buffers, DMA, concurrency design, and implementation specifics.</li>
<li>Emphasizing contiguous data for efficient communication, it delves into DMA in embedded systems and implements non-blocking asynchronous buffers with atomic pointers for thread safety.</li>
<li>Designed for x86 and ARM platforms, this ring buffer offers user-friendly interfaces for static allocation and can divide into Producer and Consumer halves for diverse scenarios.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ferrous-systems.com/blog/lock-free-ring-buffer/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZHigh-Performance Lock-Free Ring Buffer for Cross-Thread Communication</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI and Tech Sectors on Edge: Money Bubble Warning]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article raises concerns about a possible financial bubble burst in AI and tech sectors due to overvaluation and lack of comprehension, reminiscent of the 2008 crisis.</li>
<li>It highlights the benefits of AI while cautioning against excessive investments and discusses challenges in teaching machines human language, along with worries about environmental and financial implications of generative AI.</li>
<li>Companies such as Nvidia are profiting but facing resistance, sparking concerns about job repercussions and society&#39;s heavy reliance on AI, emphasizing the need to adapt to new tech cautiously.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/202x/2024/02/25/Money-AI-Bubble</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-03-01T00:00:00.000ZAI and Tech Sectors on Edge: Money Bubble Warning</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Varda Capsule Reentry – Journey from LEO to Earth]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qw4DseiPu7E</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZVarda Capsule Reentry – Journey from LEO to Earth</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unleashing Efficiency: Geometric Algebra in 3D Graphics]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The &quot;Look, Ma, No Matrices!&quot; project on GitHub explores using Geometric Algebra and Euclidean PGA in computer graphics to create a matrix-free 3D engine, aiming for more efficient rotations, translations, and transformations.</li>
<li>The project emphasizes the importance of understanding PGA motors, normalization, and efficient implementation of PGA products like composition and sandwich operators for improved transformations, while also detailing the conversion of orthogonal matrices to PGA motors and scaling in 3D models.</li>
<li>Tangent rotors for normal mapping in tangent space and motor skinning for skeletal animation are highlighted in this project, showcasing the potential for substantial memory footprint and efficiency improvements in computer graphics through PGA.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://enkimute.github.io/LookMaNoMatrices/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZUnleashing Efficiency: Geometric Algebra in 3D Graphics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Choose Firefox: A Detailed Exploration]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author prefers Firefox due to its extensive customization options via about:config, strong data privacy, private web page translations, support for Mozilla&#39;s Gecko engine, and excellent extension support on Android.</li>
<li>Firefox offers a user-friendly picture-in-picture video player and emphasizes Mozilla&#39;s dedication to user privacy and high customization levels.</li>
<li>The article highlights the importance of selecting a browser that aligns with individual preferences and needs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://xn--ime-zza.eu/3</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZWhy Choose Firefox: A Detailed Exploration</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six-Planet Star System Investigated for Alien Tech]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Astronomers have detected a star system containing six sub-Neptune planets in perfectly aligned orbits, sparking interest in exploring possible alien technology.</li>
<li>Despite not discovering advanced extraterrestrial life in the HD 11067 system, researchers are eager to conduct further investigations due to its edge-on position, which enhances the chances of identifying signals from a civilization with advanced technology.</li>
<li>Ongoing studies focus on enhancing data about the planets in the system and how they formed, as scientists persist in their quest to uncover life beyond our solar system to address the age-old question of the existence of other civilizations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/alien-technosignatures-exoplanet-mathematically-perfect-orbits</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZSix-Planet Star System Investigated for Alien Tech</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HDMI Forum Denies AMD's Open-Source HDMI 2.1 Driver Support]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The HDMI Forum declined AMD&#39;s proposal for open-source HDMI 2.1 driver support, impacting the implementation of HDMI 2.1+ features in Linux graphics drivers.</li>
<li>After three years of collaboration, the request was rejected, potentially restricting HDMI 2.1+ functionality in open-source drivers.</li>
<li>Users are recommended to utilize DisplayPort as there might not be HDMI 2.1+ feature support in open-source drivers following the HDMI Forum&#39;s decision.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/HDMI-2.1-OSS-Rejected</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZHDMI Forum Denies AMD&apos;s Open-Source HDMI 2.1 Driver Support</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring SymPy: Python Library for Symbolic Mathematics]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SymPy is a free Python library for symbolic mathematics, lightweight, and user-friendly, suitable for tasks from tensor algebra to quantum field theory.</li>
<li>It can be embedded in different applications and expanded with custom functions, found in projects like Cadabra, ChemPy, devito, and EinsteinPy.</li>
<li>SymPy is integrated into various tools for tasks such as linear circuit analysis, mathematical optimization, and multibody dynamics, also featured in systems like SageMath and Spyder for mathematical computations and analysis.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sympy.org/en/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZExploring SymPy: Python Library for Symbolic Mathematics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MicroZig: Embedded Zig project infrastructure for multiple chip families]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>MicroZig is an embedded Zig project infrastructure offering a monorepo architecture with packages for different chip families for firmware development.</li>
<li>Users can access examples for specific chip families, build firmware files, and are encouraged to contribute, although Windows users might face challenges with the developer experience.</li>
<li>The repository contains development and deployment tools, along with guidelines for setting up a local test environment, while MicroZig versions align closely with Zig versions following a specific versioning scheme.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ZigEmbeddedGroup/microzig</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZMicroZig: Embedded Zig project infrastructure for multiple chip families</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pql: Open-source Pipelined Query Language Compiling to SQL]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The newly released pql version 0.1.0 is an open-source pipelined query language written in Go that compiles to SQL, following the Unix philosophy for efficient query development.</li>
<li>Developed to bridge the gap between proprietary query languages like Splunk and open-source databases supporting SQL, pql offers a simple interface based on Microsoft&#39;s kql syntax.</li>
<li>pql supports various tabular operators and specific functions, with unknown functions forwarded to the underlying SQL engine, and its source code is accessible on GitHub under the Apache 2.0 license.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pql.dev/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZPql: Open-source Pipelined Query Language Compiling to SQL</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Government Agencies Exploit Targeted Ads for Surveillance]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article discusses the national security concerns linked to the dating app Grindr, revealed by technologist Mike Yeagley, who tracked government workers through phone data for security reasons.</li>
<li>Companies such as PlanetRisk and UberMedia are using advertising data for intelligence, raising worries about privacy and possible misuse, notably regarding government entities like the Department of Homeland Security.</li>
<li>The text emphasizes the impact and consequences of surveillance tech in modern society, shedding light on privacy issues and the potential for data misuse.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.wired.com/story/how-pentagon-learned-targeted-ads-to-find-targets-and-vladimir-putin/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZHow Government Agencies Exploit Targeted Ads for Surveillance</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel Plans 1nm Process by 2027: $100B Investment and AI Integration]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Intel plans to roll out a 1nm process by late 2027, targeting substantial power and performance enhancements by expanding production capacity across different process nodes.</li>
<li>With a $100 billion investment worldwide, Intel aims to leverage AI in production operations to secure the position of the second-largest foundry globally by 2030, amid fierce competition like Qualcomm&#39;s X Elite laptop outperforming Intel&#39;s Core Ultra in AI benchmarks.</li>
<li>TSMC faces high demand for constructing new fabs to manufacture AI chips, signaling a surging market for cutting-edge semiconductor technology alongside recent additional developments like TSMC&#39;s 10 planned new fabs and US R&amp;D funding offers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/cpus/intel-puts-1nm-process-10a-on-the-roadmap-for-2027-aiming-for-fully-ai-automated-factories-with-cobots</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZIntel Plans 1nm Process by 2027: $100B Investment and AI Integration</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rare Stem Cell Transplant Puts Man in Dual Remission from Blood Cancer and HIV]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Paul Edmonds from California achieved remission from both blood cancer and HIV, becoming the fifth person globally to do so.</li>
<li>His treatment included a stem cell transplant from a donor with a unique genetic mutation that confers resistance to HIV, sparking hope for HIV patients.</li>
<li>The City of Hope, the institute behind his care, shared the story in the New England Journal of Medicine, highlighting the potential of personalized treatments for older HIV patients with blood cancer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/feb/28/blood-cancer-hiv-treatment</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZRare Stem Cell Transplant Puts Man in Dual Remission from Blood Cancer and HIV</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proposed VP9 Codec Library Rewrite in Rust]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Daniel Almeida suggests rewriting the VP9 codec library in Rust as a proof-of-concept, converting rkvdec and hantro to use the Rust library for potential benefits in the V4L2 project.</li>
<li>The Rust code offers a C API for C drivers and enhances memory safety for intricate algorithms, aiming to assess the advantages of Rust in codec libraries.</li>
<li>The patch serves as an initial trial for integrating Rust code in the kernel, providing testing guidelines for interested individuals while not mandating a complete switch to Rust.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/20240227215146.46487-1-daniel.almeida@collabora.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZProposed VP9 Codec Library Rewrite in Rust</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ensuring Privacy: Embed YouTube Videos Safely]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article presents a code snippet to embed YouTube videos on a website with enhanced privacy measures, focusing on minimizing tracking and enhancing security.- It suggests using &quot;<a href="http://www.youtube-nocookie.com">www.youtube-nocookie.com</a>&quot; to prevent tracking through cookies and sets a Content Security Policy (CSP) for compatibility.- The code also incorporates a &quot;loading=&#39;lazy&#39;&quot; attribute for better accessibility.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dustri.org/b/youtube-video-embedding-harm-reduction.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZEnsuring Privacy: Embed YouTube Videos Safely</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VATSIM: Revolutionizing Online Aviation With 100,000+ Members]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>VATSIM is an online aviation network with a vast community of over 100,000 virtual pilots and air traffic controllers from around the globe.</li>
<li>Users have the opportunity to engage in realistic online flying using popular flight simulators and user-friendly applications provided by the network.</li>
<li>VATSIM offers a modern audio system and various radio stations, allowing users to file flight plans, communicate with other participants, and promptly begin their online flying experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://vatsim.net/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZVATSIM: Revolutionizing Online Aviation With 100,000+ Members</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Children's Play: Embracing Risk and Excitement]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mariana Brussoni emphasizes the importance of risk and excitement in children&#39;s play, advocating for necessary rather than excessive safety measures for optimal development.</li>
<li>She criticizes the decrease in outdoor play and rise in screen time, promoting activities like climbing and exploration crucial for kids&#39; physical and cognitive growth.</li>
<li>Brussoni suggests countering intensive parenting by encouraging independent play, fostering outdoor play, creating engaging play areas, and lobbying for more school recess, while underlining the detrimental effects of excessive screen time on children&#39;s well-being.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.afterbabel.com/p/why-children-need-risk-fear-and-excitement</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-29T00:00:00.000ZChildren&apos;s Play: Embracing Risk and Excitement</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Airfoils: Key to Efficient Flight]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post explores the physics of flight, specifically airfoils&#39; significance in maintaining aircraft in the air.</li>
<li>It details airflow visualization techniques, air particle behavior, pressure distribution, viscosity, and the influence of pressure gradients on airfoil efficiency.</li>
<li>Understanding these aerodynamic principles is crucial for crafting effective airfoils, leading to the mastery of flight.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ciechanow.ski/airfoil/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZExploring Airfoils: Key to Efficient Flight</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Sues Yuzu Emulator Creators, Alleging Switch Game Piracy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nintendo has filed a copyright infringement lawsuit against the Yuzu emulator creators, accusing the tool of enabling piracy by bypassing copyright protection on Nintendo Switch games.</li>
<li>The lawsuit mentions the significant earnings of Yuzu&#39;s Patreon page, generating nearly $30,000 monthly, leading Nintendo to seek damages, a jury trial, and the closure of the emulator.</li>
<li>As a consequence, the release of the Dolphin emulator on Steam has been canceled.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://overkill.wtf/nintendo-sue-yuzu-emulator/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZNintendo Sues Yuzu Emulator Creators, Alleging Switch Game Piracy</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Open Source to Profit: Transforming Nodemailer into EmailEngine]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author transitioned their open-source project, Nodemailer, into a business named EmailEngine to address financial challenges, implementing a subscription-based model to commercialize the software successfully.</li>
<li>Initially hesitant, the author discovered selling software to be more sustainable than relying on donations, leading to a stable revenue stream.</li>
<li>Regretting not starting the software sales earlier, the author now enjoys consistent financial success with their business venture.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://docs.emailengine.app/how-i-turned-my-open-source-project-into/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZFrom Open Source to Profit: Transforming Nodemailer into EmailEngine</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. probes UnitedHealth antitrust practices]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.wsj.com/health/healthcare/u-s-launches-antitrust-investigation-of-healthcare-giant-unitedhealth-ff5a00d2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZU.S. probes UnitedHealth antitrust practices</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title
      ><![CDATA[Enhance Unit Testing with Testcontainers: Lightweight Database & Brokers in Docker]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Testcontainers offers lightweight instances of databases, message brokers, and more in Docker containers for unit testing with real dependencies, removing the need for mocks or complex setups.</li>
<li>It supports various languages and testing frameworks like Java, Go, .NET, Node.js, Python, Rust, Haskell, Ruby, Clojure, and Elixir, catering to different developers and projects.</li>
<li>Companies like Spotify and Capital One have leveraged Testcontainers; the community includes Community Champions dedicated to enhancing the framework.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://testcontainers.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZEnhance Unit Testing with Testcontainers: Lightweight Database &amp; Brokers in Docker</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[F-35C Tailhook Testing Challenges and Redesign]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Testing the F-35C tailhook for carrier landings faced challenges due to the initial design flaws, resulting in numerous failed attempts and necessitating a redesign.</li>
<li>The test team addressed issues with the pivot pin and made adjustments to enhance functionality, although a landing test incident caused damage to the landing gear, prompting a reevaluation of testing methods.</li>
<li>Despite setbacks, the post ends with the discontinuation of specific test protocols and the ongoing testing of the F-35C tailhook.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://the-engi-nerd.github.io/posts/welcome/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZF-35C Tailhook Testing Challenges and Redesign</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Green Spaces in Cities Can Lower Temperatures by 5°C]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Incorporating green spaces in urban areas, such as botanical gardens and parks, can reduce city air temperatures by up to 5 °C, aiding in fighting climate change and enhancing air quality.</li>
<li>Tailored planning solutions are crucial for each community to fully utilize the cooling advantages of green infrastructure, states a study by the University of Surrey.</li>
<li>Green spaces like street trees and wetlands play a vital role in mitigating heatwaves and creating a healthier urban environment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://newatlas.com/environment/surrey-cooling-effects-green-spaces-waterways/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZGreen Spaces in Cities Can Lower Temperatures by 5°C</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boeing Safety Culture Criticized by FAA Panel]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>An FAA panel harshly criticized Boeing&#39;s safety practices, pointing out a lack of employee awareness in reporting safety issues.</li>
<li>The article delves into various safety-related subjects within the aviation industry, offering a broader perspective on safety concerns beyond Boeing.</li>
<li><ul>
<li></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.ainonline.com/aviation-news/air-transport/2024-02-26/boeing-missing-key-elements-safety-culture-faa-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZBoeing Safety Culture Criticized by FAA Panel</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Experience Makes Time Seem to Pass Faster]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Our brains process time differently as we age; familiarity and predictability make time seem to pass quicker, while novelty and surprise create longer-lasting memories.</li>
<li>To slow down our perception of time, it is advisable to actively pursue new and unpredictable experiences rather than falling into routines.</li>
<li>Embracing change and unpredictability can enhance the quality of our lives by making time feel more extended and experiences more memorable.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://invertedpassion.com/why-time-seems-to-pass-faster-as-we-age/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZWhy Experience Makes Time Seem to Pass Faster</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing RecurseChat: macOS App for Local AI Chat]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>RecurseChat is a macOS application allowing users to chat with local AI models, emphasizing simplicity and customization for advanced users.</li>
<li>Key features include zero config setup, multi-modal chat, importing ChatGPT history, full-text search, and offline functionality.</li>
<li>The author acknowledges @ggerganov&#39;s llama.cpp contribution, enabling the app&#39;s development, and welcomes feedback for future enhancements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://recurse.chat/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing RecurseChat: macOS App for Local AI Chat</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ant Geopolitics: Ant Societal Structure and Human Challenges]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The essay delves into the global society established by ants in the last four centuries, drawing parallels to human civilizations in terms of growth and expansion.</li>
<li>It examines the distinctive societal structure of ants and the disruptive presence of species such as the Argentine ant and red fire ants, emphasizing their impact on ecosystems and the challenges they present to humans.</li>
<li>Efforts to manage invasive ants and the repercussions of human intervention on species diversity are addressed, showcasing the intricate abilities of ant colonies that set them apart from human societies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://aeon.co/essays/the-strange-and-turbulent-global-world-of-ant-geopolitics</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZAnt Geopolitics: Ant Societal Structure and Human Challenges</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Global Rainwater Unsafe to Drink Due to PFAS Chemicals]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Stockholm University study revealed that rainwater globally is unfit for drinking due to high levels of persistent toxic chemicals called PFAS, found throughout the environment.</li>
<li>PFAS, known as &quot;forever chemicals,&quot; do not break down easily and have surpassed safe drinking water limits in rainwater, posing health risks upon consumption.</li>
<li>Despite a decline in human PFAS levels over two decades, stricter guidelines are in place due to better understanding of their harmful effects, highlighting the necessity to accept PFAS contamination as an inescapable environmental issue.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2022-08-rainwater-unsafe-due-chemicals.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZGlobal Rainwater Unsafe to Drink Due to PFAS Chemicals</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SuperTux: A Super Mario-inspired Jump'n'Run Adventure]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SuperTux is a jump&#39;n&#39;run game reminiscent of Super Mario Bros, with players exploring various worlds, battling enemies, gathering power-ups, and aiming to save Penny.</li>
<li>The game is downloadable on leading platforms and provides guidance on setup and gameplay, with avenues like IRC, forums, social media, and Discord for community assistance.</li>
<li>Ongoing development for SuperTux includes upcoming enhancements and features for forthcoming versions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/SuperTux/supertux</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-02-28T00:00:00.000ZSuperTux: A Super Mario-inspired Jump&apos;n&apos;Run Adventure</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
