<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 10:08:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gooey: Transform Your Python Command Line Program into a GUI App with Ease]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Gooey is a Python library that allows developers to convert console programs into GUI applications with a single line of code.</li>
<li>It offers various features such as internationalization, customizable layouts and menus, dynamic validation of user inputs, lifecycle events, and progress tracking.</li>
<li>Gooey can be installed through pip or by cloning the project from GitHub, and it provides options for custom icons and packaging.</li>
<li>The library is designed for Python developers who want to create user-friendly GUI interfaces for their console programs.</li>
<li>Contributions in the form of code, translations, documentation, or graphics are encouraged.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/chriskiehl/Gooey</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZGooey: Transform Your Python Command Line Program into a GUI App with Ease</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[W4 Games Secures $15M to Fuel Godot Engine Video Game Development]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Irish startup W4 Games has secured $15 million in Series A funding to support video game development using the open-source Godot Engine.</li>
<li>The funding round was led by OSS Capital, with participation from prominent investors including Naval Ravikant and Justin Hoffman.</li>
<li>W4 Games plans to expand globally, introduce new offerings, and increase its workforce by over 100% within the next year and a half, leveraging the open-source model to revolutionize the gaming industry.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://w4games.com/2023/12/07/w4-games-raises-15m-to-drive-video-game-development-inflection-with-godot-engine/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZW4 Games Secures $15M to Fuel Godot Engine Video Game Development</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A380 Engine Failure: Qantas Flight 32's Miraculous Landing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Qantas Flight 32, operated by an Airbus A380, suffered a major engine failure in 2010 due to a small defect in an oil pipe.</li>
<li>The engine exploded, causing significant damage to the aircraft, but the flight crew skillfully landed the plane safely without any injuries.</li>
<li>This incident showcased the effectiveness of aviation safety measures and emphasized the overall safety of flying. Despite the incident, the A380 model remained in service until 2021, even though it was not widely favored by many airlines.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://admiralcloudberg.medium.com/a-matter-of-millimeters-the-story-of-qantas-flight-32-bdaa62dc98e7</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZA380 Engine Failure: Qantas Flight 32&apos;s Miraculous Landing</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Murder Engine: A Promising Pixel Art ECS Game Engine in C#]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Murder Engine is an in-development pixel art ECS game engine based on MonoGame.</li>
<li>The engine follows the Murder architecture and offers examples for world, entity, and component creation.</li>
<li>Murder Engine supports development on Linux, macOS, Windows, and SteamDeck, with .NET 8 SDK installed.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/isadorasophia/murder</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZMurder Engine: A Promising Pixel Art ECS Game Engine in C#</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Empowering Developers: Creating Apps for Linux to Drive Innovation and Growth]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The summary emphasizes the need for more applications on Linux and encourages developers to create new apps instead of focusing on creating more Linux distributions.</li>
<li>It highlights the benefits of app development, such as fulfilling personal needs, inspiring new developers, building communities, learning new skills, earning income, and targeting diverse Linux distributions.</li>
<li>Developers are provided with resources and platforms, such as GNOME, KDE, elementary OS, Electron, and Ubuntu Touch, to start creating Linux apps.</li>
<li>Industry professionals stress the importance of a thriving app ecosystem for Linux.</li>
<li>Various tools and platforms for publishing and distributing Linux apps, including AppCenter, AppImage, Flatpak, Open Build Service, and Snapcraft, are mentioned.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://makealinux.app</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZEmpowering Developers: Creating Apps for Linux to Drive Innovation and Growth</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mozilla's Efforts Pay Off: Firefox Speed Boosted by 50%]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mozilla has focused on improving the speed and performance of Firefox, leading to a 50% boost in performance based on the Speedometer 2.1 benchmark.</li>
<li>Users have noticed a 15% increase in the speed at which web pages load on average.</li>
<li>Mozilla will be releasing more technical information about their progress in the near future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/quick-as-a-fox-firefox-keeps-getting-faster/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZMozilla&apos;s Efforts Pay Off: Firefox Speed Boosted by 50%</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doug Engelbart's 1968 Demo: Videos, Photos, and More]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The document contains valuable information and resources about Doug Engelbart&#39;s 1968 demo, such as videos, photos, conference proceedings, and online exhibits.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the continued importance and impact of Engelbart&#39;s work, as well as the various events and recognition he has received.</li>
<li>The document also provides online resources for those interested in learning more about Engelbart&#39;s contributions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dougengelbart.org/content/view/209/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZDoug Engelbart&apos;s 1968 Demo: Videos, Photos, and More</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vulnerabilities in TETRA Radio Network Encryption Algorithms Exposed]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Researchers at Midnight Blue have discovered vulnerabilities in the authentication and encryption algorithms used in the TETRA radio network, which is widely used in critical infrastructures worldwide.</li>
<li>The vulnerabilities, including a deliberate backdoor, have been reported to the NCSC in the Netherlands and publicly disclosed to encourage patch implementation.</li>
<li>Midnight Blue has reverse-engineered and released C-source code of the encryption algorithms to shed light on the vulnerabilities, as ETSI (responsible for TETRA algorithms) does not disclose or subject them to public research.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cryptomuseum.com/radio/tetra/burst.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZVulnerabilities in TETRA Radio Network Encryption Algorithms Exposed</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Increase in Air Traffic Control Incidents Due to Shortage of Controllers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The United States is currently experiencing a nationwide shortage of air traffic controllers, leading to a fatigued and demoralized workforce.</li>
<li>Controllers are hesitant to seek help for physical and mental health issues, further exacerbating the problem.</li>
<li>The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) is facing challenges in training and hiring new controllers, resulting in understaffed control sites and increased overtime hours. This has led to safety concerns and resignations among controllers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2023/12/02/business/air-traffic-controllers-safety.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZIncrease in Air Traffic Control Incidents Due to Shortage of Controllers</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing SecureAI Tools: Open-source Chat with AI Models and PDFs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SecureAI Tools is an open-source application layer for interacting with AI language models (LLMs) and OpenAI-compatible APIs.</li>
<li>It currently offers two features: Chat-with-LLM and Chat-with-PDFs.</li>
<li>The tool is designed for self-hosting and includes basic user management features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/SecureAI-Tools/SecureAI-Tools</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing SecureAI Tools: Open-source Chat with AI Models and PDFs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon's Honesty Problem: Failed Refund on Undelivered Item Sparks Criticism, Prompts Legal Action and Credit Card Provider Change]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author recounts a negative experience with Amazon where a high-value item was not delivered and no refund was issued, raising concerns about theft within Amazon&#39;s delivery system and criticizing their handling of the situation.</li>
<li>The author expresses dissatisfaction with American Express&#39;s response to a chargeback and plans to pursue legal action.</li>
<li>The author advises against using one-time passwords for high-value items and suggests finding a new credit card provider.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bentasker.co.uk/posts/blog/opinion/amazon-parcel-contents-get-stolen-and-then-amazon-tries-to-keep-payment.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZAmazon&apos;s Honesty Problem: Failed Refund on Undelivered Item Sparks Criticism, Prompts Legal Action and Credit Card Provider Change</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fintech Startup Raises $8M to Revolutionize Charitable Giving with AI and Blockchain]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fintech startup Deadweight Loss as a Service has raised $8 million in seed funding and is launching a platform to optimize charitable giving using AI and blockchain technology.</li>
<li>The platform introduces two key features: OmniMatch™, which matches funding up to 50 cents on the dollar, and Antidollars™, which can remove or donate $1 to an organization&#39;s antithesis.</li>
<li>Users can send money or Antidollars™ to supported organizations, and the platform guarantees a minimum subsidy of 10 cents per dollar. The startup has seen promising volume in closed beta and plans to introduce Pro Mode™ in the future to enhance liquidity with AI technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://unoriginal.blog/introducing-dwlaas/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZFintech Startup Raises $8M to Revolutionize Charitable Giving with AI and Blockchain</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spotify's Enhanced Shuffling Algorithm: Fibonacci Hashing for Even Artist Distribution]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This blog post delves into Spotify&#39;s initial approach to shuffling songs in a playlist, and the problem they encountered with consecutive songs by the same artist.</li>
<li>Spotify modified their shuffling algorithm to evenly distribute artists throughout the playlist by implementing dithering algorithms.</li>
<li>The author explores a method for selecting colors using the HSV space and applies the Fibonacci hashing algorithm to evenly distribute colors.</li>
<li>The post discusses an algorithm for shuffling songs based on artists and compares it with the Fisher-Yates shuffle.</li>
<li>Fiedler&#39;s algorithm, the history of hashing, and the use of hash functions to reduce stored item information are also covered.</li>
<li>The post concludes by suggesting the conversion of a number into binary format and dividing it by a prime number to determine an address.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pncnmnp.github.io/blogs/fibonacci-hashing.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZSpotify&apos;s Enhanced Shuffling Algorithm: Fibonacci Hashing for Even Artist Distribution</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sneakers Film Promo Kit: Password-Protected Floppy for Media]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Sneakers Computer Press Kit is a promotional tool released in 1992 for the movie &quot;Sneakers&quot;.</li>
<li>It is a floppy-based &quot;computer press kit&quot; designed for press use, containing information on the cast, plot, and production.</li>
<li>The program is password-protected and DOS-based, assisting the press in quickly accessing the provided information.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.org/details/Sneakers_Film_Promotional_Floppy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZSneakers Film Promo Kit: Password-Protected Floppy for Media</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Shifts iPad Engineering to Vietnam, Reduces Dependence on China]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple is shifting its product development resources for the iPad to Vietnam to decrease reliance on China for manufacturing.</li>
<li>The company is collaborating with China&#39;s BYD, a major iPad assembler, to transfer new product introduction (NPI) resources to Vietnam, marking a significant move.</li>
<li>This highlights the growing importance of Vietnam as a production hub for Apple and reflects the trend of tech companies exploring alternative manufacturing locations beyond China.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://asia.nikkei.com/Spotlight/Supply-Chain/Apple-to-move-key-iPad-engineering-resources-to-Vietnam</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-10T00:00:00.000ZApple Shifts iPad Engineering to Vietnam, Reduces Dependence on China</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Cuts Off Beeper Mini's Access, Sparks Outage and Privacy Concerns]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Beeper, a startup that provided Android users with access to iMessage, suffered an outage after Apple blocked its access, preventing users from sending texts via the Beeper Mini app.</li>
<li>Apple managed to disable the app, according to Beeper CEO Eric Migicovsky, raising concerns about the future of Beeper Mini.</li>
<li>Migicovsky questioned Apple&#39;s motives, as the app had been seen as a way to enhance security for iPhone users, particularly in relation to unencrypted green bubble texts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/12/08/apple-cuts-off-beeper-minis-access-after-launch-of-service-that-brought-imessage-to-android/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZApple Cuts Off Beeper Mini&apos;s Access, Sparks Outage and Privacy Concerns</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Israeli WhatsApp group silencing pro-Palestinian voices]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The J-Ventures Global Kibbutz Group is an pro-Israel WhatsApp group composed of investors, tech executives, activists, and government officials that aims to shape public opinion and counter criticisms of Israel.</li>
<li>The group employs various tactics such as smearing journalists, canceling events with Palestinian voices, and attempting to send military equipment to Israel&#39;s special forces.</li>
<li>This highlights the close relationship between the tech sector, the Israeli government, and pro-Israel advocacy, which has raised concerns among civil libertarian organizations and free speech advocates.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jackpoulson.substack.com/p/inside-the-pro-israel-information</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZThe Israeli WhatsApp group silencing pro-Palestinian voices</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trains plagued by hidden mechanisms: Polish hackers uncover major issue]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Polish train manufacturer encountered a significant problem when their trains became inoperable after maintenance due to hidden mechanisms.</li>
<li>The Dragon Sector team, a group of Polish hackers, was enlisted to assist and identified the code responsible for the train malfunctions after extensive analysis and reverse engineering.</li>
<li>They developed a tool to eliminate the software locks and successfully repaired multiple trainsets, although little action has been taken by authorities to address the issue. The case has been reported to law enforcement agencies by CERT Polska.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://badcyber.com/dieselgate-but-for-trains-some-heavyweight-hardware-hacking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZTrains plagued by hidden mechanisms: Polish hackers uncover major issue</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mistral AI Unveils New Mixtral-8x7B-32kseqlen System]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mistral AI has released a new system called mixtral-8x7b-32kseqlen.</li>
<li>The release was announced through a tweet, which included a magnet link and release code.</li>
<li>The details and features of the mixtral-8x7b-32kseqlen system were not mentioned in the given text.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/MistralAI/status/1733150512395038967</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZMistral AI Unveils New Mixtral-8x7B-32kseqlen System</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FDA Approves Casgevy: CRISPR-Based Medicine for Sickle Cell Disease Treatment]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The FDA has granted approval to Casgevy, the first-ever medication based on CRISPR gene-editing technology, for sickle cell disease treatment.</li>
<li>Casgevy has the potential to alleviate the recurrent pain associated with sickle cell disease, representing a significant advancement in genetic medicine.</li>
<li>The FDA is also expected to evaluate Casgevy as a treatment for beta thalassemia, while another approved sickle cell treatment, Lyfgenia, exists.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.statnews.com/2023/12/08/fda-approves-casgevy-crispr-based-medicine-for-treatment-of-sickle-cell-disease/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZFDA Approves Casgevy: CRISPR-Based Medicine for Sickle Cell Disease Treatment</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JC Python package converts CLI tool output to JSON]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The jc Python package is designed for converting CLI tool output, file types, and strings into JSON format.</li>
<li>It can be used as a library in Python or as an Ansible filter plugin.</li>
<li>The package supports multiple commands, file types, and strings and offers options for further processing the JSON output.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/kellyjonbrazil/jc</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZJC Python package converts CLI tool output to JSON</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Verizon's Mistake: Stalker Gets Victim's Data]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Verizon Wireless mistakenly provided a stalking victim&#39;s address and phone logs to her alleged stalker, who posed as a police officer and sent a fake search warrant.</li>
<li>The incident resulted in the stalker&#39;s arrest and charges of stalking and fraud.</li>
<li>Verizon claims to process legal demands confidentially and in compliance with the law, but this incident shows a failure to protect sensitive information.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/12/verizon-fell-for-fake-search-warrant-gave-victims-phone-data-to-stalker/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZVerizon&apos;s Mistake: Stalker Gets Victim&apos;s Data</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[StripedHyena: The Future of Efficient Architecture Design]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Together Research has developed open-source models called StripedHyena as alternatives to Transformers for efficient sequence modeling.</li>
<li>StripedHyena models, such as SH 7B and SH-N 7B, combine attention and gated convolutions in novel ways to achieve improved training and inference performance.</li>
<li>They outperform Transformers on short and long-context tasks, with faster training and inference speeds and reduced memory footprint, and explore techniques like hybridization and multi-head gated convolutions for better scaling.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.together.ai/blog/stripedhyena-7b</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZStripedHyena: The Future of Efficient Architecture Design</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[American Chestnut Foundation Halts Blight-Resistant Seed Distribution]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The American Chestnut Foundation (TACF) is dedicated to restoring the American chestnut tree, which has been devastated by chestnut blight fungus.</li>
<li>TACF has used various methods, including traditional breeding and biotechnology, to develop disease-resistant and genetically diverse chestnuts.</li>
<li>Their transgenic tree Darling 58 has shown poor performance and contains a lethal gene, prompting TACF to discontinue its support and explore alternative methods for increasing blight tolerance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tacf.org/darling-58/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZAmerican Chestnut Foundation Halts Blight-Resistant Seed Distribution</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring the Limited Availability of Single-Letter Domain Names]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Most single-letter domain names, except for q.com and z.com, do not resolve on the internet.</li>
<li>The post explores single-letter domain names under .org, .net, and .co TLDs, revealing information about their owners and purposes.</li>
<li>The limited usage and availability of single-letter domains are highlighted, leading to disappointment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nerology.substack.com/p/xcom-is-twitter-but-what-are-a-zcom</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZExploring the Limited Availability of Single-Letter Domain Names</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iA Writer Launches iAノートブック: The Ultimate Distraction-Free Writing Experience]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>iA Writer, a digital writing app, is launching a physical notebook called iAノートブック to improve the writing experience.</li>
<li>The notebook is designed to minimize distractions and features fading watermark guidelines.</li>
<li>Extensive testing and collaboration with a Japanese bookbinding partner were involved in the design process.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ia.net/topics/ia-writer-in-paper</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-09T00:00:00.000ZiA Writer Launches iAノートブック: The Ultimate Distraction-Free Writing Experience</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gemini Video Demo: Not Real-Time or Voice; Still Images and Narration Used]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google recently showcased a video demo of Gemini that has garnered attention.</li>
<li>However, a PSA clears up that the demo was not done in real time or using voice.</li>
<li>Instead, it relied on still images from video footage and human prompts were added later.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/parmy/status/1732811357068615969</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZGemini Video Demo: Not Real-Time or Voice; Still Images and Narration Used</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creating Stunning Images with SVG: A Step-by-Step Tutorial]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This tutorial offers a comprehensive guide on coding and creating images using SVG (Scalable Vector Graphics).</li>
<li>It covers various topics such as drawing basic shapes, building a Christmas tree, making a gingerbread figure, using clip-path, drawing paths, stars, snowflakes, forests, and more.</li>
<li>Additionally, it explores advanced concepts like using gradients, drawing Bézier curves, adding animation, creating background patterns, and incorporating JavaScript for interaction.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://svg-tutorial.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZCreating Stunning Images with SVG: A Step-by-Step Tutorial</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creating Noisy SVGs: Exploring Texture in Web Design]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author explores the growing trend of incorporating textures in web design and expresses their fascination with it.</li>
<li>They discuss the challenges faced in replicating textures using SVGs and share their efforts in creating an SVG with a noisy, textured shadow effect.</li>
<li>The author explains the process of utilizing gradients, masks, and filters to achieve the desired effect, although the result may render differently in Safari.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://daniel.do/article/making-noisy-svgs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZCreating Noisy SVGs: Exploring Texture in Web Design</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Drive Data Loss Issue: Users Dispute Google's "Fix"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Some Google Drive users are experiencing a data loss issue, with files vanishing mysteriously.</li>
<li>Google claims to have fixed the problem, but users are reporting that the fix is ineffective.</li>
<li>The issue primarily affects files created and saved in the web interface, not the desktop app.</li>
<li>Google has not provided a clear explanation of the problem or its resolution.</li>
<li>Recovery instructions involve using a hidden UI in the desktop app or command line prompts.</li>
<li>Users are frustrated by the lack of communication and support from Google, and many are still experiencing the problem despite the supposed fix.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/12/google-calls-drive-data-loss-fixed-locks-forum-threads-saying-otherwise/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZGoogle Drive Data Loss Issue: Users Dispute Google&apos;s &quot;Fix&quot;</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fairphone 5: Repairable, Sustainable, and Impressive Camera]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Fairphone 5 is praised for its repairability and sustainability by the author.</li>
<li>The quality of the camera and OLED screen are highlighted as impressive features.</li>
<li>Fairphone&#39;s integrity is commended while criticizing Android&#39;s update policy.</li>
<li>The recommendation to use LineageOS for older devices is given.</li>
<li>Commenter mentions receiving helpful repair information from Fairphone&#39;s product management.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ifixit.com/News/87664/fairphone-5-keeping-it-10-10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZFairphone 5: Repairable, Sustainable, and Impressive Camera</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Lost Gem: Unearthing a Hidden Country Song from The X-Files]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>While watching The X-Files, the individual heard a captivating country song playing in a bar scene.</li>
<li>The individual was so intrigued by the song that they used Shazam, a music identification app, to find out its title and artist.</li>
<li>This demonstrates the power of technology in helping us discover new music and enhancing our entertainment experiences.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/laurenancona/status/1731900441800155459</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZA Lost Gem: Unearthing a Hidden Country Song from The X-Files</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta Launches Purple Llama: Open Tools for Safe Generative AI Deployment]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta has launched the Purple Llama project, which offers trust and safety tools for developers to responsibly deploy generative AI models and experiences.</li>
<li>The initial releases include CyberSec Eval, a cybersecurity safety evaluation set, and Llama Guard, an input/output filtering safety classifier.</li>
<li>Meta intends to collaborate with other tech companies to make these tools accessible to the open-source community, as part of their commitment to open and transparent science and the development of an open ecosystem for generative AI.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ai.meta.com/blog/purple-llama-open-trust-safety-generative-ai/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZMeta Launches Purple Llama: Open Tools for Safe Generative AI Deployment</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lithium Market Plunges as Demand Surges and Spot Prices Collapse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Battery-grade lithium carbonate spot prices have dropped by 77% in one year due to a shift from a lithium shortage to a surplus, caused by increased production and demand.</li>
<li>Stardust Power, a startup, intends to construct a lithium refinery in the US using funds from a merger with a Special Purpose Acquisition Company (SPAC).</li>
<li>The US plans to join the global lithium production market, alongside current dominant players such as Australia, Chile, and China, with Exxon Mobil and other companies preparing for production in the near future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://wolfstreet.com/2023/11/23/lithium-shortage-bubble-implodes-once-again-as-demand-and-production-both-surged/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZLithium Market Plunges as Demand Surges and Spot Prices Collapse</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta's 'Imagine with Meta AI' Generates Photorealistic Images using 1.1B Social Media Photos]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta has launched a new website called &quot;Imagine with Meta AI&quot; that uses AI to generate images based on written prompts.</li>
<li>The AI model was trained on a massive dataset of 1.1 billion publicly available images from Facebook and Instagram.</li>
<li>Users can generate images on the website by importing their Meta account from Facebook or Instagram, but the AI model doesn&#39;t handle text rendering or different media outputs effectively.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/12/metas-new-ai-image-generator-was-trained-on-1-1-billion-instagram-and-facebook-photos/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZMeta&apos;s &apos;Imagine with Meta AI&apos; Generates Photorealistic Images using 1.1B Social Media Photos</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Data Engineering Design Patterns: Unlock the Secrets to Efficient and Effective Data Architecture]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Data Engineering Design Patterns&quot; is a book that discusses the concept of convergent evolution in data engineering and its importance in design patterns.</li>
<li>The book offers a comprehensive understanding of data engineering, covering history, core concepts, and best practices.</li>
<li>It is targeted towards professionals and practitioners in data engineering, assuming a basic understanding of SQL, programming, and data tools.</li>
<li>The book provides practical guidance on navigating complex data architectures using open-source tools.</li>
<li>A unique feature of the book is its iterative approach, with new chapters released regularly and incorporating reader feedback.</li>
<li>By learning and applying these design patterns, data engineers can enhance the efficiency and effectiveness of their work and contribute to better decision-making and business outcomes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dedp.online/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZData Engineering Design Patterns: Unlock the Secrets to Efficient and Effective Data Architecture</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tailscale Gives Users IP Address Control for Network Security]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tailscale, a network security software company, now gives users control over the IP addresses assigned to their nodes.</li>
<li>Previously, Tailscale allocated unique IP addresses within its own universe, but due to high demand, they are now allowing the reuse of addresses from the CGNAT range.</li>
<li>Tailscale has also introduced a beta feature that allows users to define the IP pool from which their nodes are assigned addresses, and existing nodes can have their IP addresses changed.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tailscale.com/blog/choose-your-ip/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZTailscale Gives Users IP Address Control for Network Security</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beware of Fake Chips: A Tech Sector Scam]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author of the article conducted an investigation into fake chips in the tech sector, specifically chips that were disguised as more expensive models by changing their markings.</li>
<li>Through various tests, the author discovered discrepancies in power consumption, confirming that the chips were not genuine.</li>
<li>Fake chips are a prevalent issue that can cause potential damage to the devices they are used in. Additionally, the author mentioned designing a prototype board for retro machines that uses new, genuine chips.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://linuxjedi.co.uk/2023/12/01/fake-chips-i-got-stung/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZBeware of Fake Chips: A Tech Sector Scam</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tesla Shares 48V Architecture to Drive Automotive Advancements]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tesla is making its 48V architecture available to other automakers, with the goal of advancing the automotive industry.</li>
<li>The 48V architecture is a power system that allows for more efficient energy distribution in vehicles.</li>
<li>By sharing this technology, Tesla hopes to drive innovation and accelerate the adoption of electric vehicles in the market.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://electrek.co/2023/12/07/tesla-shares-48v-architecture-with-other-automakers-to-move-the-industry/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZTesla Shares 48V Architecture to Drive Automotive Advancements</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tesla strike expands as Danish and Norwegian unions unite with Swedish employees]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Employees at Tesla in Sweden have been on strike since October, and labor unions in Denmark and Norway are planning to join the boycott.</li>
<li>The Danish union 3F and Norway&#39;s Fellesforbundet will take action to disrupt Tesla&#39;s operations, demanding compliance with labor agreements in the Nordic countries.</li>
<li>If a collective agreement is not reached by mid-December, sympathy strikes will start in Denmark and Norway. The strikes are a response to allegations of Tesla&#39;s refusal to negotiate with unions and provide fair wages, pensions, and insurance for employees.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2023/12/07/swedish_tesla_strike_international/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZTesla strike expands as Danish and Norwegian unions unite with Swedish employees</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Employees Reluctant to Join Microsoft Amidst Culture Clash and Compensation Concerns]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>After the removal of CEO Sam Altman, OpenAI employees considered accepting a blanket offer from Microsoft, but most were not genuinely interested in working for Microsoft and saw it as a last resort.</li>
<li>Many employees felt pressured to sign an open letter demanding Altman&#39;s reinstatement and the resignation of the OpenAI board, driven by a clash of cultures, lack of respect for Microsoft&#39;s talent bar, and disbelief in compensation promises.</li>
<li>Money was also a motivating factor, as millions of dollars in equity were at risk if OpenAI were to collapse. However, Altman has been reinstated, and the planned tender offer for equity is proceeding, valuing OpenAI at over $80 billion. Microsoft employees were upset with the promise to match salaries for OpenAI employees, considering Microsoft&#39;s previous layoffs and salary cuts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/openai-employees-did-not-want-to-work-for-microsoft-2023-12</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-08T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI Employees Reluctant to Join Microsoft Amidst Culture Clash and Compensation Concerns</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google's Gemini AI: The Multimodal Model Redefining Performance and Transforming Input to Output]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Gemini is an AI model developed by Google that can reason across various media formats, including text, images, video, audio, and code.</li>
<li>It outperforms previous models and even human experts in language understanding tasks and excels in reading comprehension, commonsense reasoning, math problem solving, code generation, and document understanding.</li>
<li>Gemini comes in three sizes - Ultra, Pro, and Nano - catering to different tasks and needs, and has the potential to transform any type of input into any type of output.</li>
<li>Google has built Gemini with safeguards and inclusivity in mind, and integration into applications will be available on Google AI Studio and Google Cloud Vertex AI.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://deepmind.google/technologies/gemini/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZGoogle&apos;s Gemini AI: The Multimodal Model Redefining Performance and Transforming Input to Output</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Unveils Gemini: Next-Gen AI Model for Advanced Text, Coding, and Multimodal Tasks]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google has released Gemini, their most advanced AI model, which is capable of excelling in various tasks such as text analysis, coding, and multimodal tasks.</li>
<li>Gemini has surpassed previous models without the need for additional text extraction systems and has showcased impressive reasoning abilities.</li>
<li>It can comprehend complex subjects, generate high-quality code, and has been built to be reliable, scalable, and efficient. Google is prioritizing responsible AI development and has implemented safety evaluations and collaborations with experts to mitigate any potential risks.</li>
<li>Google plans to enhance Gemini&#39;s capabilities by expanding it to new languages and platforms, considering it a significant milestone in advancing AI&#39;s impact on creativity, knowledge, science, and everyday life.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.google/technology/ai/google-gemini-ai/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZGoogle Unveils Gemini: Next-Gen AI Model for Advanced Text, Coding, and Multimodal Tasks</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Plans Transparency Reporting to Address Government Surveillance]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Unidentified governments are using push notifications to monitor smartphone users&#39; data stored on Google and Apple servers, as stated by US Senator Ron Wyden.</li>
<li>Apple plans to update its transparency reporting after previously being prohibited from disclosing information on this surveillance.</li>
<li>The source of this information on government surveillance through push notifications is undisclosed, but it is believed to involve &quot;democracies allied to the United States.&quot;</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.macrumors.com/2023/12/06/apple-governments-surveil-push-notifications/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZApple Plans Transparency Reporting to Address Government Surveillance</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rethinking serverless: Introducing the FLAME pattern for granular elastic scaling]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author discusses the challenges and drawbacks of auto-scaling applications using serverless computing.</li>
<li>The proposed solution, called FLAME pattern, allows for on-demand, granular elastic scaling of specific parts of an application code without rewriting or using proprietary runtimes.</li>
<li>FLAME library, implemented in Elixir, can be used on any cloud platform with an API to run the app code, making it suitable for languages with concurrency capabilities and offering features such as pool scale-up and scale-down logic, hot vs cold startup, remote runner monitoring, and deployment freshness.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fly.io/blog/rethinking-serverless-with-flame/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZRethinking serverless: Introducing the FLAME pattern for granular elastic scaling</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation's Digital Ownership Quandary]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Sony&#39;s recent content removals and account bans on PlayStation showcase the vulnerabilities of digital ownership.</li>
<li>Users lost access to purchased Discovery content due to licensing arrangements, and some experienced unexpected bans from their PlayStation Network accounts, resulting in the loss of digitally purchased games.</li>
<li>Sony has restored account access for affected users, but no explanation or assurance against future bans has been provided. These incidents emphasize the fragility of digital ownership, leading users to consider purchasing physical copies of games and media.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/5/23989290/playstation-digital-ownership-sucks</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZPlayStation&apos;s Digital Ownership Quandary</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concerns raised by African Python community to PSF regarding grant delays for DjangoCon Africa, leading to financial strain and negative perceptions. Call for clarity, inclusivity, and review of grant allocation process.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The pan-African Python community has expressed concerns to the Python Software Foundation (PSF) regarding delays in grant approval for DjangoCon Africa.</li>
<li>The conference organizers have faced financial challenges and negative perceptions, leading to strains on their budget and decision-making.</li>
<li>There are concerns about the PSF&#39;s response, the voting system, and the organization&#39;s stance on LGBTQIA+ community safety. The article calls for clarity, inclusivity, and a review of policies and collaboration.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pythonafrica.blogspot.com/2023/12/an-open-letter-to-python-software_5.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZConcerns raised by African Python community to PSF regarding grant delays for DjangoCon Africa, leading to financial strain and negative perceptions. Call for clarity, inclusivity, and review of grant allocation process.</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quad9 Wins German Court Case Against Sony Entertainment]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The German court in Dresden has ruled in favor of Quad9, stating that Quad9 is not responsible for copyright infringement.</li>
<li>Sony Entertainment (Germany) had filed the lawsuit more than two years ago to force Quad9 to stop resolving certain domain names involved in copyright infringement.</li>
<li>Quad9 argued that they have no connection to the infringing parties and that Sony&#39;s demand for blocking was ineffective.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://quad9.net/news/blog/quad9-turns-the-sony-case-around-in-dresden/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZQuad9 Wins German Court Case Against Sony Entertainment</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wikifunctions: A New Wikimedia Project Creating a Global Library of Functions]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Wikifunctions is a new project developed by the Wikimedia Foundation with the goal of creating a library of functions that can be accessed and contributed to by users globally.</li>
<li>The project aims to simplify the work of volunteers by providing functions in any programming language and integrating them with Wikipedia and other Wikimedia projects.</li>
<li>It is supported by grants from Google.org, The Rockefeller Foundation, and the Wikimedia Endowment, and is now available for public use. The ultimate objective is to facilitate knowledge creation across different languages, enabling free sharing and improvement by editors worldwide.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://wikimediafoundation.org/news/2023/12/05/introducing-wikifunctions-first-wikimedia-project-to-launch-in-a-decade-creates-new-forms-of-knowledge/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZWikifunctions: A New Wikimedia Project Creating a Global Library of Functions</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[23andMe Faces Backlash for Requiring Binding Arbitration in TOS Update]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Genetic testing company 23andMe is changing its Terms of Service (TOS) to include binding arbitration for dispute resolution instead of focusing on strengthening its security measures.</li>
<li>This update means that users would have to bring their cases to a neutral third-party arbitrator, whose decision would be final and legally binding.</li>
<li>Users have a 30-day period to opt out of these new terms, but the change has drawn criticism as it reduces users&#39; rights and protections in the event of a security breach.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://stackdiary.com/23andme-updates-tos-to-force-binding-arbitration/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000Z23andMe Faces Backlash for Requiring Binding Arbitration in TOS Update</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unveiling the ESP32: Open-source MAC Layer Development]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The passage highlights the limitations of the closed-source Wi-Fi implementation on the ESP32 microcontroller, emphasizing the need for an open-source alternative.</li>
<li>The author explains their approach to reverse engineering the Wi-Fi hardware and the tools they employ for this purpose.</li>
<li>The passage provides an update on the development of a proof of concept for transmitting Wi-Fi packets and outlines future plans for the project, while also appealing for collaboration and financial support.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://zeus.ugent.be/blog/23-24/open-source-esp32-wifi-mac/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZUnveiling the ESP32: Open-source MAC Layer Development</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LogoFAIL attack compromises Windows/Linux firmware, remains undetectable]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The LogoFAIL attack infects and takes control of Windows and Linux device firmware during boot-up, making it hard to detect and remove.</li>
<li>The attack exploits vulnerabilities in UEFI systems of various computer models from different manufacturers, bypassing traditional endpoint security measures.</li>
<li>LogoFAIL manipulates boot logo images to execute malicious code, giving the attacker full control over the device&#39;s memory and disk. Lenovo, Dell, HP, Intel, AMD, and ARM devices are vulnerable, and security patches are being released to address the vulnerabilities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2023/12/just-about-every-windows-and-linux-device-vulnerable-to-new-logofail-firmware-attack/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-07T00:00:00.000ZLogoFAIL attack compromises Windows/Linux firmware, remains undetectable</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beeper Mini: Android Gets iMessage with End-to-End Encryption]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Beeper Mini is a third-party iMessage client for Android that enables Android users to send and receive end-to-end encrypted messages directly to Apple servers without a Mac server relay.</li>
<li>Users can join iMessage group chats, access all chat features, and register their Android phone number on iMessage using Beeper Mini.</li>
<li>The developers plan to add support for other chat networks like SMS/RCS, WhatsApp, and Signal in the future, and note that third-party iMessage clients have existed before with multi-protocol chat apps like iChat.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.beeper.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZBeeper Mini: Android Gets iMessage with End-to-End Encryption</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Declining Firefox usage threatens support from U.S. government websites]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mozilla Firefox browser may face a decline in support from U.S. government websites due to its low market share.</li>
<li>The U.S. Web Design System only supports browsers with over 2% usage, and currently, Firefox has a 2.2% share.</li>
<li>The rise of Chrome and Safari on mobile devices is contributing to the decline of Firefox&#39;s usage.</li>
<li>If Firefox falls below the 2% threshold, it may no longer be supported by government websites, potentially leading to a domino effect with corporations discontinuing support as well.</li>
<li>The author expresses concern about the future relevance of Firefox if its decline continues.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.brycewray.com/posts/2023/11/firefox-brink/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZDeclining Firefox usage threatens support from U.S. government websites</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Understanding iMessage: Inside Apple's Messaging Protocol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This blog post offers a comprehensive explanation of the internal workings of iMessage, with a particular focus on two key components: the Apple Push Notification Service (APNs) and the IDentity Services (IDS).</li>
<li>The Apple Push Notification Service (APNs) is responsible for facilitating the sending and receiving of push notifications in iMessage.</li>
<li>The IDentity Services (IDS) function as a keyserver in encrypted conversations, allowing for the exchange of public keys.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jjtech.dev/reverse-engineering/imessage-explained/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZUnderstanding iMessage: Inside Apple&apos;s Messaging Protocol</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Shazam's Algorithm Identifies Songs: A Deep Dive (2022)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article provides an explanation of how Shazam identifies songs using its algorithm.</li>
<li>It discusses the process of creating a fingerprint of the audio sample and matching it with hashes in a database.</li>
<li>The article also mentions the introduction of a new implementation called &quot;abracadabra&quot; and highlights challenges in song recognition.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cameronmacleod.com/blog/how-does-shazam-work</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZHow Shazam&apos;s Algorithm Identifies Songs: A Deep Dive (2022)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI-Powered Mass Spying: An Erosion of Privacy]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Artificial intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing surveillance and spying, allowing for the tracking of activities and the understanding of conversations at an unprecedented scale.</li>
<li>AI-powered systems can now summarize meetings and organize millions of conversations, enabling mass spying where all data is saved, searchable, and comprehensible in large quantities.</li>
<li>Mass spying can reveal intricate details about individuals, including their relationships, alliances, and conversations, and is fueled by ubiquitous microphones like Siri and Alexa.</li>
<li>Governments, corporations, and tech monopolies are already engaging in mass surveillance, and mass spying will worsen personalized advertising and erode privacy.</li>
<li>Limiting mass spying would require robust data privacy regulations, although little has been done thus far to address mass surveillance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2023/12/the-internet-enabled-mass-surveillance-ai-will-enable-mass-spying.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZAI-Powered Mass Spying: An Erosion of Privacy</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fine-tuning Mistral 7B for Magic the Gathering Drafts]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author examines the concept of fine-tuning in language models, focusing on Magic the Gathering drafts.</li>
<li>Data from 17lands is utilized to train and assess the performance of the model.</li>
<li>Fine-tuning on new data is found to be more advantageous and cost-effective compared to employing larger pre-trained models, as demonstrated by the successful performance of the draft AI in Magic the Gathering.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://generallyintelligent.substack.com/p/fine-tuning-mistral-7b-on-magic-the</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZFine-tuning Mistral 7B for Magic the Gathering Drafts</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SQLite Introduces JSONB for Faster JSON Processing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SQLite has introduced a new feature called JSONB, which is a rewrite of the SQLite JSON functions.</li>
<li>JSONB can be significantly faster than the original JSON functions, depending on usage patterns.</li>
<li>JSONB changes the internal binary representation of JSON into a contiguous byte array, making it smaller and potentially reducing database size.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sqlite.org/forum/forumpost/fa6f64e3dc1a5d97</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZSQLite Introduces JSONB for Faster JSON Processing</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Professors Under Pressure: Quality Over Quantity]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author of the tweet is concerned about the emphasis on quantity rather than quality in the work produced by professors.</li>
<li>They argue that this pressure can lead to a decrease in the overall quality of the work.</li>
<li>The author advocates for a shift in focus towards prioritizing quality over quantity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/hbouammar/status/1731970658278469714</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZProfessors Under Pressure: Quality Over Quantity</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Toxic Comments Decrease Volunteer Activity on Wikipedia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A study examined the effects of toxic comments on volunteer engagement and activity on Wikipedia.</li>
<li>Toxic comments were found to decrease activity and increase the likelihood of editors leaving the project.</li>
<li>The study estimates the number of lost active days caused by toxic comments and emphasizes the need to address toxic speech on collaborative platforms.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://academic.oup.com/pnasnexus/article/2/12/pgad385/7457939</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZToxic Comments Decrease Volunteer Activity on Wikipedia</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Android 14 to Introduce AVF: Virtualizing Android Workloads for Enhanced Capabilities]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Android Virtualization Framework (AVF) will be introduced in Android 14 devices, offering new capabilities for platform developers.</li>
<li>AVF enables virtualization on Android, allowing for isolation of workloads and operating systems.</li>
<li>Developers can opt for one-way isolation, where Android controls the virtual machine, or two-way isolation, with complete isolation between Android and the virtual machine.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2023/12/virtual-machines-as-core-android-primitive.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-06T00:00:00.000ZAndroid 14 to Introduce AVF: Virtualizing Android Workloads for Enhanced Capabilities</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Harvard disbands team analyzing Facebook Files after $500M Zuckerberg donation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Harvard University disbanded its team of disinformation experts, led by Dr. Joan Donovan, after receiving a $500 million donation from the Chan Zuckerberg Initiative.</li>
<li>The team at Harvard&#39;s Technology and Social Change Research Project was investigating Facebook&#39;s awareness of the harm caused by its platform.</li>
<li>The whistleblower disclosure emphasizes the importance of protecting public interest research from powerful corporate interests and calls for an investigation into potential inappropriate influence at Harvard.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://live-whistleblower-aid.pantheonsite.io/joan-donovan-press-release/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZHarvard disbands team analyzing Facebook Files after $500M Zuckerberg donation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Decade of Monitor Your Data: Reflecting on Have I Been Pwned]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Have I Been Pwned is a website that helps users check if their personal information has been compromised in data breaches.</li>
<li>The website, created by Troy Hunt, celebrates its 10-year anniversary.</li>
<li>The article emphasizes the significance of secure passwords and online privacy in the current digital landscape.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.troyhunt.com/a-decade-of-have-i-been-pwned/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZA Decade of Monitor Your Data: Reflecting on Have I Been Pwned</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Django 5.0: New Features and Urged Upgrades]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Django 5.0 has been released, featuring new functionalities like database-computed default values, generated model fields, and field groups for form field rendering.</li>
<li>Django 4.2 has reached the end of mainstream support, so it&#39;s crucial for users to upgrade to ensure they receive security fixes.</li>
<li>Django 4.1 has also reached the end of extended support, making it necessary for users to upgrade to Django 4.2 or a later version.</li>
<li>DjangoCon Europe 2024 has been scheduled for June 5, 2024, in Vigo, Spain.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.djangoproject.com/weblog/2023/dec/04/django-50-released/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Django 5.0: New Features and Urged Upgrades</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Harvard Accused of Caving to Meta, Ousting Disinformation Scholar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Disinformation scholar Joan Donovan accuses Harvard University of firing her to appease Facebook and violating her right to free speech.</li>
<li>Donovan claims her dismissal was due to Harvard receiving a $500 million pledge from Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s charitable arm and her involvement with the Facebook Papers.</li>
<li>Harvard denies firing Donovan and asserts that she was offered a part-time adjunct lecturer position, prompting Donovan to file a legal statement with the Education Department and Massachusetts attorney general for an investigation into her dismissal and Harvard&#39;s alleged deception of donors.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2023/12/04/joan-donovan-harvard-dismissal-complaint/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZHarvard Accused of Caving to Meta, Ousting Disinformation Scholar</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decompiler Explorer: Open-Source Tool for Analyzing Binary Files]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Decompiler Explorer is an open-source tool that enables users to upload and analyze binary files.</li>
<li>It supports multiple samples and provides various decompilers for code exploration.</li>
<li>The tool is hosted on GitHub and can be easily forked for customization and collaboration.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dogbolt.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZDecompiler Explorer: Open-Source Tool for Analyzing Binary Files</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YouTuber gets 6 months in prison for obstructing plane crash probe]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>YouTuber pilot Trevor Daniel Jacob has been sentenced to six months in federal prison for obstructing a federal investigation into a plane crash that he deliberately caused for online views.</li>
<li>Jacob destroyed the wreckage of the airplane and lied to investigators about its location, while also monetizing the crash through a YouTube video promoting a wallet.</li>
<li>The investigation was conducted by the United States Department of Transportation – Office of Inspector General, with assistance from the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) and Federal Aviation Administration (FAA).</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/pr/santa-barbara-county-man-sentenced-6-months-prison-obstructing-federal-probe-plane</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZYouTuber gets 6 months in prison for obstructing plane crash probe</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch off settings that ruin your TV experience]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Certain settings on smart TVs, such as motion interpolation and dynamic contrast, can distort images and make movies look like soap operas.</li>
<li>The article provides alternative names for these settings and recommends switching them off for a better viewing experience.</li>
<li>It suggests using filmmaker mode if available and provides resources for optimizing TV settings and learning more about the topic.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://practicalbetterments.com/switch-off-bad-tv-settings/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZSwitch off settings that ruin your TV experience</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forecasts without error bars hinder accurate interpretation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The academic article criticized by the author provides crime rate forecasts without including prediction intervals.</li>
<li>The author demonstrates with ARIMA models in Python how reasonable forecast error intervals should be included for accurate interpretation of trends.</li>
<li>The author highlights the importance of including error bars and criticizes the original article for overfitting models and misinterpreting correlations. They conclude that macro-level crime forecasts are not useful for policy response and suggest alternative methods for allocating resources to address crime.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://andrewpwheeler.com/2023/11/19/forecasts-need-to-have-error-bars/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZForecasts without error bars hinder accurate interpretation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unveiling a Bot Logic Exploit in Magic: The Gathering Arena, Triggering Automatic Concessions]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author of the post found a way to make opponents concede in the game Magic: The Gathering Arena and informed the game developers about it.</li>
<li>The post explains why card games like Magic: The Gathering are generally more resistant to hacking.</li>
<li>The author discovered a bot logic within the game that runs locally on the player&#39;s machine and used it to make opponents automatically concede in a regular match. They shared the code and reported the issue to the game developers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mayer.cool/writings/I-Hacked-Magic-the-Gathering/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZUnveiling a Bot Logic Exploit in Magic: The Gathering Arena, Triggering Automatic Concessions</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Calculating Fibonacci number based on user input]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The program prompts the user to input a number between 0 and 20.</li>
<li>Users are advised to choose a number less than 20 to prevent any delays.</li>
<li>The program then asks the user to input a number greater than 0.</li>
<li>The output of the program is the nth Fibonacci number, where n is the user&#39;s input.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://html-lang.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZCalculating Fibonacci number based on user input</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google's Critique: A High Satisfaction Code Review Tool]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google&#39;s code review tool, Critique, is highly regarded and has a high satisfaction rate among software engineers.</li>
<li>The article discusses Google&#39;s guidelines for efficient code reviews and highlights the features of Critique, as well as recent advancements in AI-powered code review tools.</li>
<li>It provides insights into Google&#39;s code review process, including statistics on code review at the company, and concludes by highlighting the reasons why Critique is so highly regarded by Googlers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://engineercodex.substack.com/p/how-google-takes-the-pain-out-of</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZGoogle&apos;s Critique: A High Satisfaction Code Review Tool</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Judge denies Amazon's motion to dismiss in bathroom spycam lawsuit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A judge in West Virginia has denied Amazon&#39;s motion to dismiss a lawsuit brought against the company over a spy camera sold on its platform.</li>
<li>The plaintiff alleges that Amazon inspected the camera multiple times but failed to prevent it from being used to capture photos in her private bathroom.</li>
<li>The judge ruled that Amazon cannot claim shock as the product descriptions suggested using it to record private moments in a bathroom.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2023/12/amazon-faces-trial-after-selling-bathroom-spycam-used-to-abuse-minor/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZJudge denies Amazon&apos;s motion to dismiss in bathroom spycam lawsuit</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zen: Open-source ad-blocker and privacy guard for Mac, Windows, and Linux]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Zen is an open-source ad-blocker and privacy guard available for Windows, MacOS, and Linux.</li>
<li>It intercepts HTTP requests and blocks ads, tracking scripts, malware, and unwanted content.</li>
<li>Users can customize their filters and it offers system-level protection. It requires the installation of a root certificate for HTTPS interception.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/anfragment/zen</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZZen: Open-source ad-blocker and privacy guard for Mac, Windows, and Linux</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DoorDash Raises Minimum Pay to $29.93 per Hour for NYC Delivery Workers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DoorDash is implementing operational changes in response to new minimum pay requirements for food delivery workers in New York City.</li>
<li>Dashers will now receive a minimum of $29.93 per hour, excluding tips, which is nearly double the NYC minimum wage.</li>
<li>The option to tip in the app will be shifted after checkout to accommodate increased fees, and the Dasher Priority Access program will be temporarily paused. DoorDash will also continue to engage with policymakers and expects further operational adjustments.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://about.doordash.com/en-us/news/nyc-platform-experience</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZDoorDash Raises Minimum Pay to $29.93 per Hour for NYC Delivery Workers</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Implementing Long-Term Support (LTS) for Kubernetes: Simplifying Cluster Upgrades and Management]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Upgrading Kubernetes clusters can be challenging and complex, prompting the idea of implementing a long-term support (LTS) release with a fixed support period.</li>
<li>An LTS release could offer organizations a more manageable upgrade cycle and encourage better cluster management practices.</li>
<li>The revival of the LTS workgroup brings anticipation for potential progress in this area, which could benefit Kubernetes operators globally and simplify the third-party ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://matduggan.com/why-kubernetes-needs-an-lts/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-05T00:00:00.000ZImplementing Long-Term Support (LTS) for Kubernetes: Simplifying Cluster Upgrades and Management</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LLM Visualization Home: Unlocking the Power of Visualizing Master of Laws Data]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;LLM Visualization Home&quot; is a platform dedicated to visualizing data and information related to LLM (Master of Laws).</li>
<li>The website aims to provide visual representations and insights into LLM programs, trends, and statistics.</li>
<li>Users can access interactive visualizations and explore various aspects of LLM data to gain a better understanding of the field.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bbycroft.net/llm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZLLM Visualization Home: Unlocking the Power of Visualizing Master of Laws Data</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Modern JavaScript Frameworks: Building One to Understand Key Concepts]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author explores modern JavaScript frameworks and their shared foundational concepts like reactivity and cloned templates.</li>
<li>They explain the use of cloneNode to optimize performance and introduce other modern JavaScript APIs like Proxy.</li>
<li>The author discusses the process of creating a reactive system and DOM rendering, offering suggestions for improvement and comparing different framework approaches. They also highlight the benefits of their own framework.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nolanlawson.com/2023/12/02/lets-learn-how-modern-javascript-frameworks-work-by-building-one/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZExploring Modern JavaScript Frameworks: Building One to Understand Key Concepts</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Side Projects That Got You Hired: Share Your Success Stories!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The person is asking community members to share projects that have helped them secure a job, specifically if the project directly led to getting the job or played a role in the interview process.</li>
<li>They are also interested in knowing if the project was related to the job in any way.</li>
<li>Additionally, they want to find out if any companies are currently hiring.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38511280</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZSide Projects That Got You Hired: Share Your Success Stories!</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report Phone Spam – Stop Robocallers & Text Spammers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author has developed a free website that helps users identify the telecom carrier behind unsolicited phone calls or text spam.</li>
<li>By reporting the abuse to the carrier, users can potentially get the spammer&#39;s service terminated.</li>
<li>The aim is to assist reputable telecom carriers in disconnecting abusive customers by providing them with abuse-related information.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://reportphonespam.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZReport Phone Spam – Stop Robocallers &amp; Text Spammers</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lobsters Rails Project: Open-Source Codebase for lobste.rs Website]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Lobsters Rails Project is an open-source codebase for the website <a href="https://lobste.rs">https://lobste.rs</a>, built with Ruby on Rails and using a SQL backend.</li>
<li>It is available under a permissive license, allowing others to create similar websites.</li>
<li>The project welcomes contributions, bug reports, and provides instructions for setting up and managing the website.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/lobsters/lobsters</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZLobsters Rails Project: Open-Source Codebase for lobste.rs Website</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI to Buy $51M of Brain-Inspired Chips from Sam Altman-Backed Startup]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenAI, a prominent AI company, plans to purchase $51 million worth of brain-inspired chips, called neuromorphic processing units (NPUs), from Rain, a startup backed by OpenAI CEO Sam Altman.</li>
<li>The deal brings attention to potential conflicts of interest arising from Altman&#39;s personal investments and his role as OpenAI CEO.</li>
<li>OpenAI&#39;s investment in AI chips reflects its commitment to advancing AI technology.</li>
<li>Rain&#39;s chips, based on the RISC-V open-source architecture, offer the potential for increased computing power and energy efficiency compared to current graphics chips used in AI development.</li>
<li>Rain has faced challenges, including the removal of a Saudi Arabia-affiliated investor due to national security concerns.</li>
<li>Rain has claimed to be in advanced talks with tech giants like Google and Microsoft for chip systems.</li>
<li>The funding round for Rain was scrutinized by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), highlighting concerns about critical technology access and control.</li>
<li>OpenAI may need to find partners with significant financial backing to meet its hardware needs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wired.com/story/openai-buy-ai-chips-startup-sam-altman/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI to Buy $51M of Brain-Inspired Chips from Sam Altman-Backed Startup</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Challenges and Limitations of Using Jenkins for CI Pipelines]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author expresses dissatisfaction with using Jenkins for their CI pipeline, citing challenges with Groovy and lack of support for declarative pipelines.</li>
<li>They discuss issues with permissions, artifacts, and integrating Docker containers.</li>
<li>The author highlights helpful tools like the snippet generator and Github search. In a different company, they no longer have to manage CI and Jenkins as there is a dedicated team for it.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://twitchard.github.io/posts/2019-06-21-life-is-too-short-for-jenkins.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZThe Challenges and Limitations of Using Jenkins for CI Pipelines</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Steel: A User-Friendly and High-Performing Scheme Dialect Built in Rust]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Steel is a user-friendly and high-performing scheme dialect language built in Rust.</li>
<li>It has support for macros, integration with Rust functions, and built-in immutable data structures.</li>
<li>The language implements higher-order contracts for design by contract and shows promising performance benchmarks compared to Python.</li>
<li>The provided code demonstrates how to use the Steel virtual machine, register functions and structs, and interact with the outside world using the ExternalStruct class.</li>
<li>The program is available under specific licenses and has contribution guidelines.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/mattwparas/steel</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Steel: A User-Friendly and High-Performing Scheme Dialect Built in Rust</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GPT-4 Masterfully Deciphers Unnatural Scrambled Text]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper examines the ability of Large Language Models (LLMs), like GPT-4, to handle scrambled text.</li>
<li>The authors introduce the Scrambled Bench, a suite to evaluate LLMs&#39; capability in dealing with scrambled input.</li>
<li>The experimental findings reveal that GPT-4 can successfully reconstruct the original sentences from scrambled text, despite the complex nature of the task.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.18805</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZGPT-4 Masterfully Deciphers Unnatural Scrambled Text</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Transform JSON into discrete assignments with Gron]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Gron is a tool that converts JSON into discrete assignments, making it simpler to search for specific values and view their paths.</li>
<li>It is beneficial for exploring APIs with extensive JSON responses and inadequate documentation.</li>
<li>Gron can also convert filtered data back into JSON and can be easily installed and used in conjunction with grep and other tools.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/tomnomnom/gron</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZTransform JSON into discrete assignments with Gron</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Placeholder Girlfriend: Reflection, Revenge, and Resilience]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The narrator grapples with feeling like a temporary partner to someone they admire.</li>
<li>After discovering a spreadsheet rating their performance, they consider revenge but ultimately choose self-improvement.</li>
<li>The narrator confronts their girlfriend about their concerns, leading to the end of the relationship and the start of a new one.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://parhelia.conorbarnes.com/p/the-placeholder-girlfriend</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZThe Placeholder Girlfriend: Reflection, Revenge, and Resilience</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Curated Big Tech Interview Experiences]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Onsites.fyi is a platform that collects and shares interview experiences and insights from renowned tech companies such as Apple, Google, Meta, Microsoft, and Amazon.</li>
<li>The platform offers valuable preparation resources by reviewing real interview experiences, helping users get an idea of what to expect during the interview process.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to provide feedback on their own interview experiences, further enriching the platform&#39;s content and benefiting future job seekers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.onsites.fyi/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZCurated Big Tech Interview Experiences</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building a File System in Rust: Exploring GotenksFS and its Implementation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This article provides an overview of file system concepts and implementation, including organization of data, use of metadata and pointers, and file search optimization methods.</li>
<li>The author introduces their own file system called GotenksFS, based on ext4, explaining its on-disk structure, configuration options, and maximum file capacity.</li>
<li>The article covers the process of creating a directory and writing a file in GotenksFS, and includes additional resources for further reading and references used in the writing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.carlosgaldino.com/writing-a-file-system-from-scratch-in-rust.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-04T00:00:00.000ZBuilding a File System in Rust: Exploring GotenksFS and its Implementation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creating a Tiny Volumetric Display: DIY with LED Matrix and Pick & Place Machine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author has successfully built a small volumetric display using a LED matrix board and a pick and place machine.</li>
<li>They explain their decisions on selecting the microcontroller and battery for the project.</li>
<li>The author goes into detail about the assembly, wiring, and software setup for the prototype, as well as challenges they faced with the battery charger and rendering animations.</li>
<li>They provide suggestions for future improvements and offer the source code on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mitxela.com/projects/candle</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZCreating a Tiny Volumetric Display: DIY with LED Matrix and Pick &amp; Place Machine</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rejected as Not a Real Engineer: Mythical Abilities Not Enough]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author recounts receiving an email rejecting their application for an engineering role.</li>
<li>They use a metaphorical description of themselves as a mythical creature with impressive qualities.</li>
<li>The reason given for not being selected is that they were not considered technically proficient enough.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitchard.github.io/posts/2019-05-29-not-a-real-engineer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZRejected as Not a Real Engineer: Mythical Abilities Not Enough</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Singing to Babies Aids Language Learning via Rhythm and Tone]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Singing to babies is an important factor in helping them learn language, according to a study from the University of Cambridge.</li>
<li>The research indicates that infants initially understand language through rhythm and tone, rather than individual sounds.</li>
<li>The study challenges the belief that processing phonetic information is the primary aspect of language learning and suggests that dyslexia and developmental language disorder may be linked to rhythm perception.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2023/dec/01/singing-to-babies-is-vital-to-help-them-understand-language-say-scientists</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZSinging to Babies Aids Language Learning via Rhythm and Tone</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GQL: A Query Language for Git Files]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GQL is a query language that resembles SQL and enables querying .git files directly, eliminating the need for a separate database.</li>
<li>It offers a range of query operations including selection, aggregation, filtering, and ordering.</li>
<li>GQL is case-insensitive and has a syntax similar to SQL. The software is released under the MIT License.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/AmrDeveloper/GQL</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZGQL: A Query Language for Git Files</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Comparing Memory Management, Safety, and Adoption: Ada vs Rust]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Reddit post in the Rust programming language subreddit outlines the rules and guidelines for posting, along with a discussion on the differences between Ada and Rust.</li>
<li>The post seeks insights from individuals with knowledge in both programming languages, focusing on topics like memory management, safety features, performance, and adoption rates of Ada in different industries.</li>
<li>The comments and discussion shed light on the strengths, limitations, and future prospects of both Ada and Rust as programming languages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://old.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/17miqiu/is_ada_safer_than_rust/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZComparing Memory Management, Safety, and Adoption: Ada vs Rust</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fiber optic cables 'hear' loud cicadas, offer new insect monitoring method]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Scientists have found that fiber optic cables can pick up the sound of cicadas, leading to a potential new method for monitoring insect populations.</li>
<li>Using distributed acoustic sensing (DAS), researchers can analyze the light bouncing back from a laser fired through the cables to detect disturbances caused by loud sounds or seismic activity.</li>
<li>This technique could allow entomologists to remotely monitor cicadas and collect data on their population sizes and locations, using the already abundant fiber optic cables. However, monitoring quieter insect species with DAS may be more challenging.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wired.com/story/cicadas-are-so-loud-fiber-optic-cables-can-hear-them/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZFiber optic cables &apos;hear&apos; loud cicadas, offer new insect monitoring method</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bug Report: Sign-in Issue with FIDO2 Key on office.com via Firefox]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Users are experiencing difficulty signing in on office.com using Firefox browser with a FIDO2 key, according to a bug report.</li>
<li>The severity level of the bug is stated as low, and Microsoft has been notified about the issue.</li>
<li>The bug remains unresolved, and efforts are underway to prompt Microsoft to address it, with multiple users verifying that the problem persists. The bug report also references Microsoft&#39;s authentication systems as complex and inconsistent.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1824831</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZBug Report: Sign-in Issue with FIDO2 Key on office.com via Firefox</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clang's default behavior causes issue with running binaries on original Pi B+]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares their experience using clang to compile C++ programs on a Raspberry Pi B+.</li>
<li>Binaries built with clang cannot run on the B+ due to a default behavior change.</li>
<li>The author identifies a workaround by specifying the target architecture, but questions why this default behavior change went unnoticed and suggests that older Raspberry Pi models are not widely used anymore.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rachelbythebay.com/w/2023/11/30/armv6/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZClang&apos;s default behavior causes issue with running binaries on original Pi B+</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Excalidraw: The Open-Source Drawing Tool for Hand-Drawn Style Diagrams]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Excalidraw is an open-source virtual whiteboard for creating hand-drawn style diagrams and wireframes.</li>
<li>Features include an infinite canvas, customizable tools, image support, and end-to-end encrypted collaboration.</li>
<li>The Excalidraw.com app offers PWA support, real-time collaboration, and local-first functionality, while the Excalidraw npm package provides additional features. The project is sponsored and integrates with various platforms and services.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/excalidraw/excalidraw</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZExcalidraw: The Open-Source Drawing Tool for Hand-Drawn Style Diagrams</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unveiling Dark Patterns: Recognizing and Preventing UX Manipulation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Dark patterns are manipulative tactics used by companies in UX design to deceive and exploit users for their benefit.</li>
<li>Common types of dark patterns are identified, and their exploitation of human psychology for profit is explored.</li>
<li>The article emphasizes the importance of transparency, user control, and ethical design practices in avoiding dark patterns and maintaining user trust and engagement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dodonut.com/blog/10-dark-patterns-in-ux-design/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-03T00:00:00.000ZUnveiling Dark Patterns: Recognizing and Preventing UX Manipulation</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta Introduces Seamless Communication AI Models for Expressive and Fast Translation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta has created a collection of AI research models called Seamless Communication for language translation.</li>
<li>The models include SeamlessExpressive, which focuses on maintaining expression and nuances of speech, SeamlessStreaming for near real-time translations with low latency, and SeamlessM4T v2 as a foundational model for universal translation.</li>
<li>Meta prioritizes open research and collaboration and has taken steps to reduce toxicity in translations. Users can access additional resources and download the models.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ai.meta.com/research/seamless-communication/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZMeta Introduces Seamless Communication AI Models for Expressive and Fast Translation</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frontend Optimized Database Stack: Simplifying Data Management in Frontend Applications]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Caching data from APIs in frontend development is discussed as a common practice.</li>
<li>The use of Redux for managing API data caching is explored.</li>
<li>The concept of optimistic mutations and the challenges of maintaining consistency with the server are introduced.</li>
<li>SQLSync is presented as a solution, utilizing SQLite as a storage engine with features like durable cache and reactive queries.</li>
<li>SQLSync aims to simplify data management in frontend applications.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sqlsync.dev/posts/stop-building-databases/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZFrontend Optimized Database Stack: Simplifying Data Management in Frontend Applications</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Tech Companies Hiring Worldwide: December 2023]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post is requesting job listings that meet specific requirements for location, including remote options, and visa status for international candidates.</li>
<li>Only individuals from hiring companies are allowed to post job listings.</li>
<li>Job seekers are advised to search for job opportunities on recommended platforms and can find additional related threads on the topic.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38490811</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZTop Tech Companies Hiring Worldwide: December 2023</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Unexpected Power of Unconventional HTML Coding Techniques]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores a range of unconventional HTML coding techniques that defy expectations and still manage to work.</li>
<li>The author showcases ten different strategies, encompassing various aspects of HTML, including HTML tables, web design, and responsive design.</li>
<li>This article provides a unique and informative perspective on HTML coding, shedding light on unconventional techniques that may be helpful for web developers and designers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tedium.co/2023/11/24/weird-html-hacks-history/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZThe Unexpected Power of Unconventional HTML Coding Techniques</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Noiselith: Generate Images Offline with Ease]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Noiselith is a tool developed by VoyagerX, Inc. that enables users to generate images on their devices without relying on internet connectivity.</li>
<li>The tool offers privacy, unlimited image generation, and fast processing speed.</li>
<li>Noiselith has specific system requirements, including Windows or macOS, a compatible GPU, and sufficient RAM and storage space.</li>
<li>It is easy to install and use, with options for selecting and managing different models.</li>
<li>Noiselith is currently in beta, and its official release date has not been announced.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://noiselith.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZNoiselith: Generate Images Offline with Ease</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remote Work Becomes Permanent Fixture in U.S. Labor Market]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Remote work is becoming a permanent fixture in the U.S. labor market, with the proportion of workers being called back to the office plateauing.</li>
<li>The rate of paid work-from-home days has remained consistently high at around 28%, compared to the pre-pandemic level of 7%.</li>
<li>The shift towards remote work is driven by worker preferences for no commute, flexible schedules, and a better work-life balance, while companies enjoy reduced costs and improved worker retention. The prevalence of remote work is expected to grow further due to technological advancements and the preferences of younger CEOs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2023/11/30/return-to-office-is-dead-stanford-economist-says-heres-why.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZRemote Work Becomes Permanent Fixture in U.S. Labor Market</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Billionaires Amassing More Inheritance than Creating Wealth, Reports UBS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A survey by UBS reveals that billionaires are now accumulating more wealth through inheritance rather than wealth creation.</li>
<li>$141 billion was amassed by self-made billionaires in 2023, while $151 billion was inherited by heirs.</li>
<li>Over 1,000 billionaires are expected to pass $5.2 trillion to their children in the next 20 to 30 years, indicating that this trend will continue.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ft.com/content/3944234e-e3b4-46fa-8c2f-cadec780ecb4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZBillionaires Amassing More Inheritance than Creating Wealth, Reports UBS</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study finds link between tinnitus and hidden nerve damage]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Researchers at Massachusetts Eye and Ear have found a connection between tinnitus and undetected auditory nerve damage, challenging previous understandings of the condition.</li>
<li>The study shows that individuals with normal hearing tests can still experience auditory nerve loss, suggesting the potential for new treatments centered around nerve regeneration.</li>
<li>Tinnitus, which affects more than 10% of adults globally, can have a substantial impact on quality of life, leading to sleep disturbances, social withdrawal, anxiety, and depression. The researchers aim to develop treatments that target the root causes of tinnitus to alleviate its symptoms.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/tinnitus-linked-to-hidden-undetected-auditory-nerve-damage-a-step-towards-a-cure/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZStudy finds link between tinnitus and hidden nerve damage</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LLM Efficiency Challenge: 5x Faster Finetuning of Llama with QLoRA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author presents a project from the LLM Efficiency Challenge that enables 5x faster finetuning of Llama using QLoRA compared to Huggingface&#39;s original implementation.</li>
<li>The project includes features such as a manual autograd engine, faster algorithms, memory efficiency, GPU model compatibility, and no compromise on accuracy.</li>
<li>Support is also provided for Flash Attention and 4bit/16bit finetuning, with additional information on Unsloth Pro and Max for faster training available on a blog post.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/unslothai/unsloth</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZLLM Efficiency Challenge: 5x Faster Finetuning of Llama with QLoRA</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitbucket's Buggy Animation Causes High CPU Usage During Builds]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The BitBucket web UI has a glitchy animation that causes high CPU and GPU usage during builds.</li>
<li>The animation, which rotates a static SVG image, is poorly optimized and affects system performance.</li>
<li>Removing the animation resolves the problem, but the layout of the whole page is recomputed on each frame, leading to additional performance issues.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thehftguy.com/2023/11/21/buggy-animation-in-atlassian-bitbucket-is-wasting-half-a-cpu-core-at-all-times/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZBitbucket&apos;s Buggy Animation Causes High CPU Usage During Builds</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ravynOS: Blending macOS Finesse with FreeBSD Freedom]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>ravynOS is an open-source operating system that combines the sophistication of macOS with the flexibility of FreeBSD.</li>
<li>The system is compatible with macOS applications and does not have any hardware restrictions.</li>
<li>It aims to create a new user interface that aligns with its goals, while also supporting features like clean design, global menus, and drag-and-drop installs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ravynos.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZravynOS: Blending macOS Finesse with FreeBSD Freedom</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seeking Assistance for the Holidays: HN Community Offers Support for Financial Needs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The poster is starting an early thread to offer assistance to the Hacker News (HN) community.</li>
<li>Last year, they provided $20k worth of support and plan to fund the operation themselves this year.</li>
<li>They are asking for people&#39;s financial needs and general purpose to help as many people as possible, including holiday housing, gifts, food, travel assistance, medical expenses, or entertainment. They assure privacy and encourage those in need to ask for help.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38492378</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZSeeking Assistance for the Holidays: HN Community Offers Support for Financial Needs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Inside Story of Microsoft's Partnership with OpenAI]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft&#39;s partnership with OpenAI was at risk when OpenAI&#39;s CEO, Ilya Sutskever, was unexpectedly fired by the company&#39;s board without Microsoft&#39;s knowledge or input.</li>
<li>The firing of the CEO created tensions between OpenAI and Microsoft and raised concerns about the risks and benefits of artificial intelligence and the speed and safety of AI technology development.</li>
<li>Microsoft explored various options to stabilize the situation, including supporting the interim CEO or reinstating the fired CEO, but ultimately the CEO was reinstated due to employee unrest and threats of revolt.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/12/11/the-inside-story-of-microsofts-partnership-with-openai</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZThe Inside Story of Microsoft&apos;s Partnership with OpenAI</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mozilla Introduces Llamafile: Run LLMs Locally on Your Computer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mozilla&#39;s innovation group and Justine Tunney have created llamafile, a new method for running Large Language Models (LLMs) on your own computer.</li>
<li>A llamafile is a multi-GB file that contains both the model weights for an LLM and the required code to run the model.</li>
<li>Users can execute the llamafile using Cosmopolitan Libc, which compiles a single binary that works on multiple operating systems and hardware architectures.</li>
<li>By running the llamafile executable, users can start a web server and interact with the model in their browser, enabling local usage of LLMs without an internet connection.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://simonwillison.net/2023/Nov/29/llamafile/#atom-everything</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-02T00:00:00.000ZMozilla Introduces Llamafile: Run LLMs Locally on Your Computer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Generating Optical Illusions with Pretrained Diffusion Models]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The authors propose a method for generating multi-view optical illusions using pretrained diffusion models.</li>
<li>The method supports various transformations such as rotations, flips, color inversions, skews, jigsaw rearrangements, and random permutations.</li>
<li>The method involves aligning and averaging noise estimates from different views or transformations of an image to take a diffusion step.</li>
<li>The authors discuss the conditions that views must meet for the method to work, including linearity and statistical consistency.</li>
<li>Use of orthogonal transformations, particularly permutation matrices, can generate interpretable and visually meaningful optical illusions.</li>
<li>The paper provides examples and references related works in the field.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dangeng.github.io/visual_anagrams/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZGenerating Optical Illusions with Pretrained Diffusion Models</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon HR Insider Exposes Disturbing Reality of PIP Plans, Claims Company Focused on Eliminating Underperforming Employees]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A former HR staffer at Amazon shares their traumatic experience with the company&#39;s performance-improvement plan, Pivot, which led them to develop PTSD.</li>
<li>Pivot&#39;s focus was on eliminating employees who did not meet performance metrics, rather than improving their performance.</li>
<li>The process had a negative impact on employees, including visa-sponsored workers who were forced to leave the country.</li>
<li>Amazon disputes the account, claiming it contains inaccuracies and does not reflect the majority of employees&#39; experiences.</li>
<li>The individual eventually resigned from Amazon but secured a stock investment before leaving.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-hr-performance-improvement-plans-pip-pivot-had-to-quit-2023-11</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZAmazon HR Insider Exposes Disturbing Reality of PIP Plans, Claims Company Focused on Eliminating Underperforming Employees</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Animated GIF that Crashed Chrome: A Challenging Debugging Journey]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A team encountered a bug that caused Chrome to crash when using Gusto&#39;s internal software, sparking a debugging journey to identify and fix the issue.</li>
<li>By investigating different possibilities, the team found that a particular animated GIF was responsible for the crash when loaded on the webpage.</li>
<li>Despite the challenges and lack of expertise, the team&#39;s determination and collaboration ultimately led to successfully resolving the problem.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://engineering.gusto.com/the-weirdest-bug-ive-seen-yet/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZThe Animated GIF that Crashed Chrome: A Challenging Debugging Journey</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[European Parliament Rejects Mass Scanning of Private Messages, Protecting Digital Human Rights]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The European Parliament has rejected the proposal to mass scan private messages in the draft &#39;Regulation laying down rules to prevent and combat child sexual abuse&#39; (CSAR).</li>
<li>This decision is a positive development for human rights and a crucial step in the legislative process.</li>
<li>The rejection of mass scanning is a significant milestone in protecting digital human rights and ensuring the privacy of private messages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://edri.org/our-work/csar-european-parliament-rejects-mass-scanning-of-private-messages/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZEuropean Parliament Rejects Mass Scanning of Private Messages, Protecting Digital Human Rights</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stanisław Lem's 'The Invincible': Unveiling Artificial Life's Prophetic Vision]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;The Invincible&quot; by Stanisław Lem is a science fiction novel that delves into the concept of artificial life.</li>
<li>The story revolves around a space crew investigating a sister spaceship that has ceased communication with Earth.</li>
<li>They discover a planet where self-replicating machines have evolved into a unique form of life, raising questions about human knowledge, life&#39;s nature, and challenging anthropocentric assumptions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thereader.mitpress.mit.edu/stanislaw-lems-prescient-vision-of-artificial-life/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZStanisław Lem&apos;s &apos;The Invincible&apos;: Unveiling Artificial Life&apos;s Prophetic Vision</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple's computational photography missteps lead to mirrored selfie mishaps]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A woman in the U.K. found a glitch with her iPhone 15&#39;s camera that created three different poses of herself in a mirror.</li>
<li>Apple&#39;s computational photography algorithm failed to recognize the mirror reflection, resulting in a composite image with different poses in each mirror.</li>
<li>This glitch can be replicated on other recent iPhones and is popular among younger generations who use it for fun on social media.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://appleinsider.com/articles/23/11/30/a-bride-to-be-discovers-a-reality-bending-mistake-in-apples-computational-photography</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZApple&apos;s computational photography missteps lead to mirrored selfie mishaps</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ripgrep: A Faster and More Efficient Command Line Search Tool for Code]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article introduces ripgrep, a new command line search tool that outperforms other code search tools in terms of performance and usability.</li>
<li>It provides installation and usage instructions for different platforms and explores features like support for .gitignore and custom matching rules.</li>
<li>Benchmarks show that ripgrep consistently performs well in terms of speed, accuracy, and relevance of search results.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.burntsushi.net/ripgrep/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZRipgrep: A Faster and More Efficient Command Line Search Tool for Code</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turbo Pascal: Celebrating 40 Years of Groundbreaking Programming]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Turbo Pascal, a programming language and development environment, is commemorating its 40th anniversary, marking its significant impact on the tech industry and launching Borland as a company.</li>
<li>Turbo Pascal was the first widely-used integrated development environment (IDE) and is attributed by numerous individuals as their gateway to programming.</li>
<li>Embarcadero, the current developer of Turbo Pascal, recently released version 36 of the compiler, showcasing the enduring popularity of this pioneering language.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.marcocantu.com/blog/2023-november-turbopascal40.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZTurbo Pascal: Celebrating 40 Years of Groundbreaking Programming</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yabai: A Tiling Window Manager for macOS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Yabai is a window management utility for Mac that offers users control over windows, spaces, and displays with a command line interface and customizable keyboard shortcuts.</li>
<li>It primarily focuses on tiling window management to enhance concentration and productivity.</li>
<li>Yabai has additional features like focus-follows-mouse and the ability to create spaces beyond the default limit.</li>
<li>Specific operating system versions, accessibility API, and screen recording permissions are required to use Yabai.</li>
<li>Certain system settings and code signing requirements need to be met for Yabai to function properly.</li>
<li>Yabai is released under the MIT License, and users are advised to use it at their own risk.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/koekeishiya/yabai</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZYabai: A Tiling Window Manager for macOS</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Accelerating Generative AI with PyTorch: Faster Text Generation with GPU Optimization]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The PyTorch team has optimized generative AI models for text generation using GPU quantization and tensor parallelism.</li>
<li>These optimizations improve performance without sacrificing accuracy.</li>
<li>The article discusses the challenges of CPU overhead in deep learning systems and introduces torch.compile as a method to reduce CPU overhead and optimize GPU usage.</li>
<li>The use of compilation strategies, int8 quantization, and speculative decoding greatly enhance the performance of text generation tasks.</li>
<li>Running on multiple GPUs offers benefits such as increased memory bandwidth and better performance.</li>
<li>The code for implementation is available in a GitHub repository and the author acknowledges the support of the open-source community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pytorch.org/blog/accelerating-generative-ai-2/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZAccelerating Generative AI with PyTorch: Faster Text Generation with GPU Optimization</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Ripen and Store Avocados: Tips and Tricks]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The avocado industry aims to delay ripening, while home cooks usually want to speed up the process.</li>
<li>Ripening can be accelerated by storing avocados in a brown paper bag with a banana, which produces ethylene gas.</li>
<li>Microwaving avocados is not recommended as it cooks rather than ripens them, and ripe avocados can be stored in the refrigerator for up to five days.</li>
<li>To prevent browning, plastic wrap is not very effective, but submerging avocado pieces in water or using plastic wrap directly on mashed avocado can help delay oxidation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.seriouseats.com/how-to-ripen-avocados-7377071</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZHow to Ripen and Store Avocados: Tips and Tricks</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Generating Character Videos from Still Images: State-of-the-Art Synthesis for Character Animation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper introduces a framework for generating character videos from still images using diffusion models.</li>
<li>Novel techniques are employed to maintain consistency, control, and continuity in character animation.</li>
<li>The proposed approach outperforms existing methods and achieves state-of-the-art results in fashion video and human dance synthesis.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://humanaigc.github.io/animate-anyone/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZGenerating Character Videos from Still Images: State-of-the-Art Synthesis for Character Animation</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marker: Efficiently Convert PDF to Markdown with Higher Accuracy]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Marker is a tool that converts PDF, EPUB, and MOBI files to markdown.</li>
<li>It is faster and more accurate than the previous tool nougat, with a lower risk of errors.</li>
<li>Marker supports a range of PDF documents, removes headers/footers/artifacts, converts equations to latex, and formats code blocks and tables.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/VikParuchuri/marker</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZMarker: Efficiently Convert PDF to Markdown with Higher Accuracy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Large Language Models Lack Deep Insights or a Theory of Mind]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Vision-based large language models show proficiency in processing and interpreting visual data.</li>
<li>However, they still lag behind human capabilities in intuitive physics, causal reasoning, and intuitive psychology.</li>
<li>These models have a basic understanding of physical laws and causal relationships but lack deeper insights and fail in tasks requiring an intuitive theory of mind.</li>
<li>The study highlights the importance of integrating more robust mechanisms for understanding causality, physical dynamics, and social cognition into language models.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2311.16093</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-01T00:00:00.000ZLarge Language Models Lack Deep Insights or a Theory of Mind</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>