<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 10:08:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prominent Programming Pioneer Niklaus Wirth Passes Away]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Niklaus Wirth, a renowned figure in programming languages, software engineering, and hardware design, passed away on January 1.</li>
<li>Bertrand Meyer mourns the loss of Wirth and acknowledges his contributions as a pioneer and mentor.</li>
<li>Wirth&#39;s legacy includes his work on programming languages like Pascal and Modula, as well as his influence in software methodology and hardware design.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/Bertrand_Meyer/status/1742613897675178347</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZProminent Programming Pioneer Niklaus Wirth Passes Away</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meissner effect at room temperature? Study finds potential in copper-substituted lead apatite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The study examines the occurrence of the Meissner effect at room temperature in copper-substituted lead apatite.</li>
<li>Diamagnetic dc magnetization is observed under a magnetic field, and hysteresis loops are detected, indicating superconductivity below 250 K.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that the Meissner effect may be present in this material at room temperature, offering insights into potential applications of superconductivity at higher temperatures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00999</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZMeissner effect at room temperature? Study finds potential in copper-substituted lead apatite</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FrameOS: An OS for Single-Function Smart Frames]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FrameOS is an operating system specifically designed for single-function smart frames like smart home calendars and public advertisement screens.</li>
<li>It can run on a Raspberry Pi and supports both e-ink and traditional displays.</li>
<li>Some notable features of FrameOS include centralized deployment, efficient compilation, a drag-and-drop diagram editor, GPT4 support, and hardware guides. However, it is important to note that FrameOS is still in early development and does not have a stable release yet.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://frameos.net/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZFrameOS: An OS for Single-Function Smart Frames</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demystifying the Math Behind Transformers: A Comprehensive Overview and Implementation Guide]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text provides a thorough explanation of the transformer model, its components, and its implementation through code examples.</li>
<li>It covers tokenization, embedding, positional encoding, attention mechanisms, residual connections, and layer normalization.</li>
<li>The importance of masked self-attention and encoder-decoder attention in training is emphasized, along with the generation of output sequences using the transformer model.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://osanseviero.github.io/hackerllama/blog/posts/random_transformer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZDemystifying the Math Behind Transformers: A Comprehensive Overview and Implementation Guide</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enjoy the Fun and Benefits of Making Small Games]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores the benefits and enjoyment of creating small games that can be completed within 10 minutes and played on browsers.</li>
<li>The author shares their experience of creating over 350 small games and highlights the short development time required for such games.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the charm and unique qualities of small games and provides twelve thoughts on creating good small games, including fulfilling promises, reducing scope, and adding personal style.</li>
<li>Creating small games is not only a way to improve game development skills but also a rewarding and enjoyable experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://abagames.github.io/joys-of-small-game-development-en/fun_to_make_small_games.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZEnjoy the Fun and Benefits of Making Small Games</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Navigating the Post-Release Path: Tech Industry Opportunities for Felons]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The individual is seeking advice and opportunities to reenter the tech/startup industry after facing difficulties finding employment due to a felony conviction for assault.</li>
<li>They are looking for companies that are willing to give them a chance, despite their record not being related to computer/finance/fraud/selling drugs/physical violence.</li>
<li>They have provided a LinkedIn profile for further information about their background and qualifications.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38858075</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZNavigating the Post-Release Path: Tech Industry Opportunities for Felons</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vulnerability in Bitwarden's Windows Hello Leads to Remote Credential Theft]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A vulnerability in Bitwarden&#39;s Windows Hello implementation allowed remote stealing of credentials, but it has been fixed.</li>
<li>The article explains how the vulnerability was exploited using DPAPI backup keys and decrypting Bitwarden data files and credentials.</li>
<li>Microsoft was involved, and Bitwarden made changes to address the issue, including changes in the current version and the use of Impacket for vulnerability testing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.redteam-pentesting.de/2024/bitwarden-heist/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZVulnerability in Bitwarden&apos;s Windows Hello Leads to Remote Credential Theft</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Free, No-Nonsense Ambiphone App: Ambient Music and White Noise]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The individual created a free white noise app that is user-friendly and does not require login, contain ads, or offer in-app purchases.</li>
<li>The app was featured on The Economist&#39;s podcast, where the creator discussed their app and another project called Ambient ScotRail Beats.</li>
<li>The creator is regularly updating the app with new music and sounds and encourages user suggestions for further improvement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ambiph.one?hn</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZFree, No-Nonsense Ambiphone App: Ambient Music and White Noise</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Accused of Illegally Firing Workers Critical of Musk: NLRB]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The National Labor Relations Board has accused SpaceX of unlawfully terminating eight employees for criticizing Elon Musk.</li>
<li>The employees had shared a letter urging the company to distance itself from Musk&#39;s controversial social media comments and to clarify and enforce its harassment policies.</li>
<li>The labor board complaint alleges that SpaceX&#39;s president and other executives restricted the circulation of the letter, violating labor regulations.</li>
<li>The case will be presented to an administrative judge in March, unless a settlement is reached.</li>
<li>The labor board seeks remedies such as reinstatement and back pay for the affected employees.</li>
<li>This accusation adds to a series of labor and discrimination-related legal issues faced by both SpaceX and other companies led by Musk.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/03/business/spacex-elon-musk-nlrb-workers.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZSpaceX Accused of Illegally Firing Workers Critical of Musk: NLRB</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Age-Related Correlation Found in Backblaze Drive Failure Rates]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Backblaze, a data storage company, has conducted an analysis of drive failure rates in its storage servers, called Backblaze Vaults.</li>
<li>The analysis reveals that there is no connection between the age of the drives and the failure rates among different vault cohorts.</li>
<li>Backblaze intends to conduct more research to determine if specific drive models exhibit better performance in different vault cohorts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.backblaze.com/blog/the-drive-stats-of-backblaze-storage-pods/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZNo Age-Related Correlation Found in Backblaze Drive Failure Rates</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Linux's Desktop User Share Hits Nearly 4%, Surpassing macOS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Linux&#39;s desktop user share reached almost 4% in December 2023, indicating a significant upward trend in recent years.</li>
<li>When considering ChromeOS, which is built on Linux, the overall Linux user share amounts to 6.24%.</li>
<li>macOS experienced a 5% decline in users, while Windows saw a 3% increase. Efforts are being made to enable compatibility between ChromeOS and other Linux distributions, including plans to bring Steam and Steam games to ChromeOS. These findings highlight the increasing popularity of Linux as a desktop operating system.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gamingonlinux.com/2024/01/linux-hits-nearly-4-desktop-user-share-on-statcounter/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZLinux&apos;s Desktop User Share Hits Nearly 4%, Surpassing macOS</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[23andMe Faces Backlash Over Data Breach Blame Game]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Genetic testing company 23andMe blames customers for a data breach that exposed the genetic and ancestry data of 6.9 million users, stating that customers were at fault for not updating and recycling passwords.</li>
<li>Legal representatives for the victims argue that 23andMe should have implemented stronger security measures to protect customer data.</li>
<li>23andMe faces over 30 lawsuits from affected users and has changed its terms of service to make it more difficult for victims to file legal claims against the company.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/01/03/23andme-tells-victims-its-their-fault-that-their-data-was-breached/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000Z23andMe Faces Backlash Over Data Breach Blame Game</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Convert Containers to WASM with Container2wasm]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Container2wasm is an experimental software that converts container images into WebAssembly (WASM) images for running on WASI runtimes or in a browser.</li>
<li>It supports x86_64 and riscv64 containers and provides emulation for other platforms, with networking capabilities and access to directories mapped from the host machine.</li>
<li>Another project, Container2Wasi, focuses on emulating RISC-V CPUs on WASM and provides directory mapping, networking, and security features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ktock/container2wasm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZConvert Containers to WASM with Container2wasm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. cities embrace parking-free future]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Cities in the United States are eliminating off-street parking minimums to promote alternative transportation and increase housing affordability.</li>
<li>Over 50 cities and towns have already removed parking requirements, citing arbitrary rules and the negative impact of parking on housing costs and congestion.</li>
<li>The move towards eliminating parking mandates aims to encourage transit and reduce sprawl, with more cities considering following suit, including New York, Milwaukee, and Dallas.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.npr.org/2024/01/02/1221366173/u-s-cities-drop-parking-space-minimums-development</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZU.S. cities embrace parking-free future</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Efficient Multimodal Large Language Model: TinyGPT-V Overview]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The summary explains how to use TinyGPT-V, a large language model, by providing detailed instructions on code preparation, weight downloading, and model checkpoint launching.</li>
<li>It includes information on weight adjustment, training, and evaluation, allowing users to customize and improve the model.</li>
<li>The source code is freely available under the BSD 3-Clause License for users to access and utilize.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/DLYuanGod/TinyGPT-V</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-04T00:00:00.000ZEfficient Multimodal Large Language Model: TinyGPT-V Overview</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tetris player sets new world record, triggers game crash after 34 years]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tetris player Blue Scuti sets a new world record by reaching level 157 and triggering a game crash known as the &quot;True&quot; Killscreen.</li>
<li>This achievement surpasses previous records and techniques, showcasing advancements in gameplay and strategy.</li>
<li>The glitched color levels reached by an AI named stackrabbit and Blue Scuti&#39;s accidental passing of the game crash have revitalized the Tetris community, inspiring new strategies and record chases.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GuJ5UuknsHU</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZTetris player sets new world record, triggers game crash after 34 years</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DIY Blind Repair: Fix Your Blinds Easily with Replacement Parts and Instructional Videos]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The website offers a DIY blind repair service, providing replacement parts and instructional videos.</li>
<li>Over 1 million people have been assisted in fixing their blinds with the help of this website.</li>
<li>Customers appreciate the detailed parts list and quick delivery, as well as resources to understand how blinds work.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fixmyblinds.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZDIY Blind Repair: Fix Your Blinds Easily with Replacement Parts and Instructional Videos</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resurrecting the Dillo Browser: User revives project after domain expiration]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The host dillo.org expired in mid-2022, resulting in the downtime of the Dillo website, mercurial repo, mailing list, and email server for Dillo developers.</li>
<li>A user stepped in to prevent the project from dying by uploading a copy of the repo to GitHub, performing code maintenance, and creating a new webpage.</li>
<li>The user has made improvements to Dillo, such as adding support for multiple protocols and implementing proper CI with rendering tests. They plan to release version 3.1 after testing and are seeking feedback and contributions from users.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dillo-browser.github.io/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZResurrecting the Dillo Browser: User revives project after domain expiration</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rise of LLMs and Programming in 2024]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>LLMs (Master of Laws) programs and programming skills are gaining popularity in early 2024.</li>
<li>The article discusses the reasons behind the increased interest in LLMs and programming skills.</li>
<li>It provides insights into the benefits and potential career opportunities associated with these areas of study.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://antirez.com/news/140</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZThe Rise of LLMs and Programming in 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Calling All Job Seekers: January 2024 Hiring Opportunities - Remote work, internships, and visa sponsorship available]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The statement requests individuals to share job opportunities and disclose if remote work, internships, or visa sponsorship is available.</li>
<li>It advises against complaining about job posts and offers links to job search platforms.</li>
<li>It mentions other threads for those seeking employment or freelance opportunities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38842977</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZCalling All Job Seekers: January 2024 Hiring Opportunities - Remote work, internships, and visa sponsorship available</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mozilla CEO Gets 20% Raise Despite Declining Revenue, Focus on AI Raises Questions]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mozilla&#39;s CEO, Mitchell Baker, received a higher compensation despite declining revenues, prompting calls for a faster pace from the company.</li>
<li>The report identifies AI, particularly in the healthcare sector, as a major focus for Mozilla&#39;s future plans.</li>
<li>There are concerns whether the emphasis on AI will result in genuine innovation or just a shallow addition to the company&#39;s offerings. The report also emphasizes Mozilla&#39;s dedication to privacy, encryption, and data security.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2024/01/02/mozilla_in_2024_ai_privacy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZMozilla CEO Gets 20% Raise Despite Declining Revenue, Focus on AI Raises Questions</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Streamlining Payroll Deductions with a Dependency Chart: A Canadian Business Owner's Experience]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The writer shares their experience using the Canada Revenue Agency&#39;s &quot;Payroll Deductions Formulas&quot; document to calculate payroll deductions for their small business in Canada.</li>
<li>They describe the document as complex and requiring constant flipping between sections to find the necessary calculations.</li>
<li>To simplify the process, the writer created a dependency chart using GraphViz with 79 nodes, allowing them to prioritize calculations more effectively.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.daemonology.net/blog/2023-12-31-Canadian-payroll-dependency-chart.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZStreamlining Payroll Deductions with a Dependency Chart: A Canadian Business Owner&apos;s Experience</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Perform OCR on a Mac using CLI or Python for free]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares a guide on how to perform OCR on a Mac using the command line interface or Python, without any cost involved.</li>
<li>Step-by-step instructions are provided for setting up a local OCR service using the Shortcuts app and running OCR on an image using the created shortcut.</li>
<li>The post also includes a Python code snippet for executing OCR on a file.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.greg.technology/2024/01/02/how-do-you-ocr-on-a-mac.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZPerform OCR on a Mac using CLI or Python for free</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI's Misuse in Bug Bounty Program of curl and libcurl Leads to False Security Reports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Artificial intelligence (AI) is being misused in the bug bounty program of curl and libcurl, generating false security reports.</li>
<li>The author provides examples of AI-generated reports that appeared legitimate but were ultimately incorrect.</li>
<li>Better tools are needed to detect AI-generated reports, and the author suggests adding a human check to improve accuracy.</li>
<li>The author predicts an increase in AI-generated rubbish in their bug report inboxes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2024/01/02/the-i-in-llm-stands-for-intelligence/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZAI&apos;s Misuse in Bug Bounty Program of curl and libcurl Leads to False Security Reports</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Browsers could disrupt the mobile duopoly]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tech reporters are failing to adequately report on the potential disruption of the mobile app duopoly by browsers.</li>
<li>Apple and Google are impeding the growth of Progressive Web Apps, emphasizing the need for browser choice and competition.</li>
<li>The role of regulators in shaping legislation and the challenges faced by non-Chrome browsers are discussed, along with Apple&#39;s control over the web and its impact on developers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://infrequently.org/2024/01/the-web-is-the-app-store/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZBrowsers could disrupt the mobile duopoly</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JAL A350 collides with Coast Guard DH8C, igniting fire on Tokyo runway]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Japan Airlines Airbus A350 collided with a Japanese Coast Guard Dash 8-300 on the runway at Tokyo Haneda Airport, resulting in a fire and fatalities.</li>
<li>All 379 passengers on the A350 were safely evacuated, but unfortunately, 5 out of 6 occupants on the Dash 8 did not survive.</li>
<li>The cause of the accident is still under investigation, and discussions about air traffic control errors, aircraft safety, and resource allocation have been initiated.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://avherald.com/h?article=5132b9fe</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZJAL A350 collides with Coast Guard DH8C, igniting fire on Tokyo runway</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taking Action: The Path to Success]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The quote highlights the significance of taking initiative and embarking on a journey towards success, even if it&#39;s not flawless.</li>
<li>It implies that adjustments and enhancements can be made as progress is made.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/addyosmani/status/1739052802314539371</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZTaking Action: The Path to Success</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sea Wolf: Thomas Cochrane's Adventures in Naval Command and Political Activism]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Thomas Cochrane, the 10th Earl of Dundonald, had a remarkable career as a naval commander and political activist.</li>
<li>Despite a court-martial early in his career, Cochrane became known for his clever tactics and bold maneuvers in capturing enemy vessels.</li>
<li>Cochrane also engaged in political activities, campaigning against corruption and serving as a Member of Parliament.</li>
<li>Cochrane played a significant role in various wars of independence, including those of Chile, Brazil, and Greece.</li>
<li>Despite controversy, imprisonment, and personal setbacks, Cochrane&#39;s fearless character left a lasting legacy.</li>
<li>Cochrane&#39;s story teaches two key lessons: the wise use of explosives and the potential for success in seemingly hopeless endeavors.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sergey.substack.com/p/thomas-cochrane</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZThe Sea Wolf: Thomas Cochrane&apos;s Adventures in Naval Command and Political Activism</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japan Embraces AI Development: Copyrights Not Applicable for Training]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Japan&#39;s government will not enforce copyrights on data used in AI training to promote AI technology advancement.</li>
<li>The move aims to position Japan as an AI leader and potentially boost their GDP by 50% or more.</li>
<li>Artists and creators have concerns, while the academic and business sectors push for the relaxation of data laws to leverage the benefits. Japan also seeks to influence global AI regulations within the G-7 and access Western data resources for training purposes, contributing to the debate on global regulation and competition in AI development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.biia.com/japan-goes-all-in-copyright-doesnt-apply-to-ai-training/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-03T00:00:00.000ZJapan Embraces AI Development: Copyrights Not Applicable for Training</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creator Takes a Break: Reflecting on a Decade of YouTube Videos and Prioritizing Personal Life]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>After a decade of producing YouTube videos, the creator announces their decision to take a break from their regular upload schedule.</li>
<li>Reflecting on their journey and accomplishments, the creator expresses a desire for change and a need to prioritize their personal life.</li>
<li>While they may explore other formats or platforms for content creation, they emphasize the importance of taking a break and pursuing new interests, while expressing gratitude to their viewers and supporters.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7DKv5H5Frt0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZCreator Takes a Break: Reflecting on a Decade of YouTube Videos and Prioritizing Personal Life</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Perfectionism and Procrastination: The Complex Relationship Explained]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Perfectionism and procrastination are often linked because perfectionists have a fear of making mistakes and being criticized, causing them to delay tasks.</li>
<li>However, not all perfectionists procrastinate, as some are motivated to submit work on time in order to meet high standards.</li>
<li>The relationship between perfectionism and procrastination depends on factors like the type of perfectionism and self-efficacy. Anxiety, fear of failure, and depression can also contribute to procrastination, which may be associated with perfectionism.</li>
<li>To address perfectionistic procrastination, individuals can set realistic goals, focus on themselves, address their fears, consider the negative impact of perfectionism, and develop self-efficacy and self-compassion.</li>
<li>Various anti-procrastination techniques, such as breaking tasks into smaller steps and scheduling work according to productivity cycles, can also be effective in overcoming procrastination.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://solvingprocrastination.com/perfectionism/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZPerfectionism and Procrastination: The Complex Relationship Explained</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Public Domain Ebooks by Standard Ebooks]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Standard Ebooks is a volunteer-based project that produces free ebooks by improving the formatting, proofreading, and adding modern features to public domain works sourced from Project Gutenberg.</li>
<li>They provide comprehensive metadata, visually appealing covers, and use clean and reliable code as a foundation for other ebook producers.</li>
<li>All their efforts are released into the public domain, making their high-quality ebooks accessible to everyone.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://standardebooks.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZEnhanced Public Domain Ebooks by Standard Ebooks</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All DMCA Notices Against TorrentFreak in 2023 Were Baseless]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 2023 and 2024, TorrentFreak received multiple invalid DMCA notices from anti-piracy companies requesting the removal of their articles from Google search results.</li>
<li>Companies such as Disney and Cricket Australia were among those sending these erroneous takedown demands.</li>
<li>Despite TorrentFreak reaching out to these companies, their communications were ignored, indicating a lack of response and acknowledgement of the mistakes made against the site.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://torrentfreak.com/all-dmca-notices-filed-against-torrentfreak-in-2023-were-bogus-240101/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZAll DMCA Notices Against TorrentFreak in 2023 Were Baseless</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimize Videogame Path Finding with A* Algorithm and Tricks]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author discusses pathing techniques for monster AI in an 8-bit game, including linear pathing, Dijkstra&#39;s algorithm, and A* search algorithm.</li>
<li>The limitations of Dijkstra&#39;s algorithm are explained, and the benefits of A* search algorithm, along with tricks to enhance its speed and implementation ease.</li>
<li>The author explores the use of implicit graph data structure, geometry-informed heuristics, and iteration depth in the A* algorithm.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://timmastny.com/blog/a-star-tricks-for-videogame-path-finding/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZOptimize Videogame Path Finding with A* Algorithm and Tricks</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mathematical Introduction to Deep Learning: Algorithms, Architectures, and Theory]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This is a book review paper that offers a mathematical introduction to deep learning algorithms.</li>
<li>The paper covers key topics including neural network architectures, optimization algorithms, theoretical aspects, and approximation methods for partial differential equations.</li>
<li>It is intended for students, scientists, and practitioners seeking a solid mathematical understanding of deep learning.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.20360</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMathematical Introduction to Deep Learning: Algorithms, Architectures, and Theory</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenVoice: Versatile Voice Cloning for Multilingual Speech Generation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenVoice is a voice cloning approach that can replicate a reference speaker&#39;s voice and generate speech in multiple languages.</li>
<li>It provides control over voice styles like emotion, accent, rhythm, pauses, and intonation, and can clone voices into new languages with limited training data.</li>
<li>OpenVoice is computationally efficient, publicly accessible, and has been used millions of times worldwide. It serves as the backend of MyShell, and the source code and trained model are available for further research.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01479</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZOpenVoice: Versatile Voice Cloning for Multilingual Speech Generation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building a TrueType Font Renderer: A Deep Dive into Text Rendering with Technical Insights and Project Screenshots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author explores the TrueType font format and provides technical details about its features and functionality.</li>
<li>They delve into the intricacies of text rendering and explain how TrueType fonts are used to display text on screens.</li>
<li>The article includes screenshots of an ongoing renderer project, giving readers a visual depiction of the author&#39;s work.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://axleos.com/writing-a-truetype-font-renderer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZBuilding a TrueType Font Renderer: A Deep Dive into Text Rendering with Technical Insights and Project Screenshots</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Could Solve It All, If We Tried]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author believes that existing solutions to societal problems are often not implemented due to coordination failures and competing interests.</li>
<li>Examples of such problems include software vulnerabilities, healthcare issues, voting systems, and infrastructure development.</li>
<li>The author argues that societal systems prioritize profits over cooperation, and calls for action to address these coordination failures before they have a detrimental impact on civilization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/we-could-fix-everything-we-just-dont/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZWe Could Solve It All, If We Tried</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NERV Disaster Prevention: Real-time Alerts for Earthquakes, Tsunamis and More]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The NERV Disaster Prevention app provides real-time information and alerts for earthquakes, tsunamis, volcanic eruptions, and other disasters.</li>
<li>The app prioritizes user privacy and security, with no storage of location history and minimal impact on battery life.</li>
<li>It offers various disaster prevention information, push notifications for important updates, and customizable interface options. The app is licensed by the Japan Meteorological Agency and complies with relevant acts and policies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nerv.app/en/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZNERV Disaster Prevention: Real-time Alerts for Earthquakes, Tsunamis and More</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[uBlacklist: Block Sites in Google Search Results]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The uBlacklist extension enables users to block specific websites from appearing in their Google search results.</li>
<li>It supports multiple search engines and allows for synchronization of blocked sites across different devices.</li>
<li>Users have the option to subscribe to public rule sets or create their own.</li>
<li>The extension is available for Chrome, Firefox, and macOS and iOS devices.</li>
<li>It is licensed under the MIT License.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/iorate/ublacklist</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZuBlacklist: Block Sites in Google Search Results</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PyPy Migrates to GitHub for Improved Issue Tracking and Open Source Association]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>PyPy has migrated its repository and issue tracker from Heptapod to GitHub due to difficulties in issue searching and GitHub&#39;s association with Open Source.</li>
<li>The migration involved converting code and notes from Mercurial to Git and migrating issues and merge requests.</li>
<li>PyPy now adopts a more structured workflow and encourages users to contribute through pull requests on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pypy.org/posts/2023/12/pypy-moved-to-git-github.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZPyPy Migrates to GitHub for Improved Issue Tracking and Open Source Association</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring the Exciting World of Public Domain: Mickey Mouse, Notable Figures, and More]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The summary discusses the release of Mickey Mouse&#39;s first iteration into the public domain and works entering the public domain in different countries.</li>
<li>It includes information about books, films, and paintings from the early to mid-1900s and provides details about their creators and contributions.</li>
<li>The summary also mentions the significance of country music, the achievements of Pablo Picasso and J.R.R. Tolkien, and features provided by The Public Domain Review.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://publicdomainreview.org/blog/2024/01/public-domain-day-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZExploring the Exciting World of Public Domain: Mickey Mouse, Notable Figures, and More</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prioritizing Clarity and Scannability: The Subject-First Commit Message Style]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The subject-first commit message style used by the Eventide project emphasizes scannability and cognitive optimization for humans.</li>
<li>It prioritizes the change being made rather than the person making the change.</li>
<li>Although the author had reservations initially, they recognized the benefits of this style and now suggest giving it a try.</li>
<li>Guidelines are provided for subject-first commit messages, such as being brief and clear in describing actions and changes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/aaronjensen/software-development/blob/master/commit-messages.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-02T00:00:00.000ZPrioritizing Clarity and Scannability: The Subject-First Commit Message Style</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy New Year Hacker News: The Only Website Worth Visiting Multiple Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author acknowledges their excessive use of Hacker News (HN) but believes it&#39;s the only website worth frequenting.</li>
<li>The author sends well wishes for the year 2024.</li>
<li>No substantial or significant information is provided in the text.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38826283</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZHappy New Year Hacker News: The Only Website Worth Visiting Multiple Times</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Customizing SteamOS: Challenges, Updates, and Mods]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author discusses their experience with customizing SteamOS for their living room PC, outlining the difficulties they encountered.</li>
<li>They explain the partition system and update process used in SteamOS, providing instructions on modifying the Linux Neptune repository and obtaining the SteamOS root filesystem image for the SteamDeck.</li>
<li>The article also covers packaging custom software using pacman repositories and updating SteamOS installations. The author concludes by suggesting the need for an update to Valve&#39;s EULA.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://iliana.fyi/blog/build-your-own-steamos-updates/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZCustomizing SteamOS: Challenges, Updates, and Mods</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building a Low-Power Server/NAS: Achieving 7 Watts with Intel 12th/13th Gen]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares their experience in building a low-power server/NAS system using Intel processors and successfully achieves a power consumption of 7 watts.</li>
<li>Challenges in finding a motherboard with enough M.2 slots and recommendations for Intel chipsets over AMD for lower power consumption are discussed.</li>
<li>The article provides detailed choices of motherboard, CPU, memory, and storage components, tips for achieving low power consumption, and recommendations for measuring power consumption as well as future improvements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mattgadient.com/7-watts-idle-on-intel-12th-13th-gen-the-foundation-for-building-a-low-power-server-nas/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZBuilding a Low-Power Server/NAS: Achieving 7 Watts with Intel 12th/13th Gen</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bazzite: A Versatile OCI Image for Steam Deck and More, Resolving SteamOS Issues]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Bazzite is an OCI image that provides an alternative operating system for the Steam Deck and other devices, resolving issues with SteamOS.</li>
<li>It includes various features and customization options, support for AMD GPUs, and fixes for bugs in Source 1 engine games.</li>
<li>Bazzite supports Discord screensharing on Wayland, offers a Webapp Manager, and has different variants for desktop computers and the Steam Deck. It is a community-driven project with documentation and newsletters, and users can build their own custom version.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ublue-os/bazzite</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZBazzite: A Versatile OCI Image for Steam Deck and More, Resolving SteamOS Issues</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Using Email Addresses as "Permanent" Account IDs: A Flawed Approach]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Chris Siebenmann challenges the reliability of email addresses as permanent identifiers for user accounts.</li>
<li>Email addresses can change within organizations and can be reused or reassigned, making them unreliable for long-term identification.</li>
<li>Siebenmann recommends using internal IDs that are unique and meaningless for account identification, even if email addresses are used for account recovery purposes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/EmailAddressesBadPermanentIDs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZUsing Email Addresses as &quot;Permanent&quot; Account IDs: A Flawed Approach</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bluesky platform update includes styling rules, but Sony software update causes theater projector issues]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>@donohoe.dev made changes to the Bluesky platform, focusing on extending the react-native-web reset.</li>
<li>The changes include CSS styling rules, color theming, and additional styling hacks for different elements.</li>
<li>An incident involving a software update for projectors resulted in the cancellation of all movies at Alamo Drafthouse, highlighting potential impacts on other theaters.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bsky.app/profile/donohoe.dev/post/3khu7w2kz7l2b</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZBluesky platform update includes styling rules, but Sony software update causes theater projector issues</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Bun: A Fast JavaScript Runtime with Tail Call Optimization (TCO)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Bun is a new JavaScript runtime that is known for its speed and is built on JavaScriptCore, unlike Node and Deno which are built on V8.</li>
<li>JavaScriptCore has a niche optimization feature called Tail Call Optimization (TCO), which allows for recursion without exceeding the call stack.</li>
<li>While TCO can be implemented in Bun by rewriting functions and moving state to arguments, the TCO solution in Bun is slower than the original for loop solution. However, using mutation can achieve similar performance in a recursive solution.</li>
<li>TCO enables programmers to express complex and efficient programs without relying on imperative loops.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.onsclom.net/posts/javascript-tco</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Bun: A Fast JavaScript Runtime with Tail Call Optimization (TCO)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rediscovered Carolina African Runner Peanut Brings Excitement to Farmers and Chefs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Carolina African Runner peanut, previously thought to be extinct, has been rediscovered and is now being cultivated by farmers and chefs.</li>
<li>The peanut, brought to the American colonies in 1690, is smaller, sweeter, and has a higher oil content than modern peanuts.</li>
<li>Researchers obtained seeds from a breeding facility and successfully grew a commercial crop, leading to potential market opportunities for farmers and artisan food companies interested in growing and utilizing the Carolina African peanut.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nationalpeanutboard.org/news/a-1690s-peanut-is-reborn/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZRediscovered Carolina African Runner Peanut Brings Excitement to Farmers and Chefs</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sweden's Spectacular Solar System Model]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Sweden Solar System is a scale model of the Solar System located in Sweden.</li>
<li>It includes representations of the Sun, planets, moons, dwarf planets, and other celestial bodies.</li>
<li>The model is spread out across different locations in Sweden to depict the scale and distances in the Solar System.</li>
<li>It serves as both an educational tool and a popular tourist attraction.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweden_Solar_System</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZSweden&apos;s Spectacular Solar System Model</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside AMD's Vintage LANCE Ethernet Chip: Exploring Circuitry and Manufacturing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The blog post delves into a vintage Ethernet chip from 1982 and examines its circuitry, storage methods, and manufacturing procedures.</li>
<li>It explores latch circuits and the incorporation of static RAM in the chip, shedding light on the inner workings of the technology.</li>
<li>The article also divulges insights into the transistor construction of the chip as well as mentions two associated patents.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.righto.com/2023/12/amd-lance-ethernet-double-poly.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZInside AMD&apos;s Vintage LANCE Ethernet Chip: Exploring Circuitry and Manufacturing</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Harvard Honor Council Member Calls for President Gay's Resignation Over Plagiarism]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>An anonymous member of the Harvard College Honor Council has written an article criticizing President Claudine Gay for alleged plagiarism and demanding her resignation.</li>
<li>The author argues that the university&#39;s treatment of students accused of plagiarism is stricter than the treatment of the president, citing the Honor Council&#39;s procedures and sanctions as evidence.</li>
<li>The author calls on the Harvard Corporation to demand President Gay&#39;s resignation in order to address what they perceive as a double standard.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thecrimson.com/article/2023/12/31/honor-council-member-gay/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZHarvard Honor Council Member Calls for President Gay&apos;s Resignation Over Plagiarism</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWII hero's daughter sets record straight, reveals father's heroics]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The daughter of WWII hero Major Charles Carpenter, known as &quot;Bazooka Charlie,&quot; provides evidence through letters, photos, and documents to support her father&#39;s heroic actions during the war, after doubts were raised by war enthusiasts.</li>
<li>Her story catches the attention of a retired mechanical engineer who encourages her to write a book, leading to the recovery and restoration of her father&#39;s plane, which is now on display in a museum.</li>
<li>The book also explores the impact of the war on her father&#39;s health and the sacrifices made by her mother, garnering appreciation from veterans for her open sharing of her family&#39;s story.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dispatch.com/story/news/local/2023/12/31/bazooka-charlies-granville-daughter-shares-wwii-heroics-in-new-book/72033226007/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZWWII hero&apos;s daughter sets record straight, reveals father&apos;s heroics</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Build a Small Social Network: Emphasizing Community and User Control]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Running a small social network site offers benefits such as community building and user control.</li>
<li>Open-source software and tailored online environments are advantageous for small social networks.</li>
<li>Platforms like Mastodon and Dolphin Town are recommended for running a small social network.</li>
<li>Managing a small community comes with challenges and responsibilities, but maintaining a positive user experience is crucial.</li>
<li>Implementing code of conduct policies is important, and technical improvements in social network sites are needed.</li>
<li>The concept of &quot;neighborhoods&quot; in federated social networks is proposed for improved user experiences.</li>
<li>The future of social networks is discussed, acknowledging contributions from others.</li>
<li>The author provides their own affiliations and licensing information.</li>
<li>Note: This post discusses the benefits, challenges, and recommendations for running a small social network. It also highlights the importance of community management, code of conduct policies, and technical improvements in social network sites. The concept of &quot;neighborhoods&quot; in federated social networks is a new and exciting idea proposed by the author.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://runyourown.social/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-01-01T00:00:00.000ZHow to Build a Small Social Network: Emphasizing Community and User Control</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Author Victor Eijkhout Takes a Deep Dive into High-Performance Computing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Victor Eijkhout has written a series of textbooks covering different topics in high-performance computing (HPC).</li>
<li>The first two volumes provide an introduction to scientific computing and parallel programming using MPI and OpenMP.</li>
<li>The third and fourth volumes introduce C++17, Fortran2008, and other topics in the scientific computing ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://theartofhpc.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZAuthor Victor Eijkhout Takes a Deep Dive into High-Performance Computing</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Decline of SEO: Evaluating Search Engines and ChatGPT for Reliable Results]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The decline in search engine optimization (SEO) and the rise of content farms are discussed, underscoring the importance of improving search result quality.</li>
<li>The article examines the accuracy of search engines and ChatGPT in providing trustworthy answers, while addressing the issue of misleading content and fraudulent websites.</li>
<li>There is a bias towards advertising in search engines, and the article argues for the development of a transparent and competitive search engine.</li>
<li>Issues with specific queries like downloading YouTube videos and finding an ad blocker are explored, uncovering scam websites and deceptive practices.</li>
<li>The limitations of Google&#39;s search engine are highlighted, along with potential advantages of smaller search engines.</li>
<li>Problems with ad blockers and misinformation from various sources are also addressed, advocating for reliable information and awareness of scams.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://danluu.com/seo-spam/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZThe Decline of SEO: Evaluating Search Engines and ChatGPT for Reliable Results</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Challenges of Copyright Infringement in Generative AI]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Generative AI, such as OpenAI&#39;s chatbots and image software, poses challenges in relation to copyright infringement due to its ability to reproduce text and images almost identically.</li>
<li>The lack of transparency and attribution in generative AI systems raises concerns about potential legal issues for companies like OpenAI and Microsoft.</li>
<li>Tracking the provenance of generative text and images through a new architecture may be necessary to address copyright infringement in the future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://garymarcus.substack.com/p/things-are-about-to-get-a-lot-worse</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZChallenges of Copyright Infringement in Generative AI</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon's Silent Layoffs: Stock Problem Forces Job Cuts, Raises Concerns over Operational Practices]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Amazon has laid off over 27,000 employees, mostly in the retail sector, to reduce operational expenses.</li>
<li>Many employees, especially those in higher positions, want to leave due to compensation concerns.</li>
<li>The value of spending on Amazon&#39;s AWS is decreasing as customers cut costs, and the company is lagging behind in AI.</li>
<li>Amazon is giving away high-margin services for free and may shift to a more centralized organizational structure in the coming year.</li>
<li>Predictions suggest there may be a major AWS outage in 2024 due to the silent layoffs of employees.</li>
<li>Employees who have been laid off are not receiving severance packages, and the company is trying to retain headcount without officially announcing layoffs.</li>
<li>This practice may continue in 2024 as companies prioritize short-term profits.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://justingarrison.com/blog/2023-12-30-amazons-silent-sacking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZAmazon&apos;s Silent Layoffs: Stock Problem Forces Job Cuts, Raises Concerns over Operational Practices</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ugrep: A Powerful, Fast, and User-Friendly File Pattern Searcher with Advanced Features]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The ugrep file pattern searcher is a robust alternative to the grep command, providing powerful features and functionality.</li>
<li>ugrep can search nested archives, hexdump binary files, and search PDFs and other document types.</li>
<li>It offers various matching modes, search options, and output formatting capabilities, and supports standard POSIX ERE pattern syntax with added support for Unicode.</li>
<li>ugrep is a command-line tool that can be installed on different operating systems.</li>
<li>For faster searching in large file systems, the ugrep-indexer tool can be used to index directories.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ugrep.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZUgrep: A Powerful, Fast, and User-Friendly File Pattern Searcher with Advanced Features</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Approaching Low-Code Solutions with Skepticism and Caution]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author raises skepticism about low-code solutions, highlighting concerns about their ability to handle custom functionality and reliance on specialized talent.</li>
<li>Difficulties with upgrades and messy underlying databases are also mentioned as potential drawbacks of low-code solutions.</li>
<li>The author advises approaching these tools with caution and skepticism, acknowledging that they may have their advantages but also potential disadvantages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nick.scialli.me/blog/why-im-skeptical-of-low-code/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZApproaching Low-Code Solutions with Skepticism and Caution</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ScummVM: Play Classic Adventure Games and RPGs on Mac App Store]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>ScummVM is a Mac App Store app that lets users play classic graphical adventure games and RPGs.</li>
<li>Users need to provide their own game data files for the app to work.</li>
<li>The app is open source and does not collect any user data. It is best played with a controller.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/scummvm/id6446184412</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZScummVM: Play Classic Adventure Games and RPGs on Mac App Store</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Using Indents for Simpler UIs: A New Approach to Displaying Tree-Like Lists]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author proposes using indents instead of a parent-child structure to display tree-like lists in a user interface (UI).</li>
<li>They argue that the visual appearance of the tree is often more important than the actual relationship between items.</li>
<li>The author provides examples and pseudocode to help implement this technique, but also advises that it may not be suitable for all scenarios and suggests alternative methods for situations requiring a true tree structure.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ratfactor.com/cards/fake-trees</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZUsing Indents for Simpler UIs: A New Approach to Displaying Tree-Like Lists</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tether Partners with Secret Service and FBI, Demonstrates Commitment to Security]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tether has disclosed its collaborations with the Secret Service and FBI in a letter to the U.S. Senate, showcasing its focus on security and cooperation with law enforcement agencies.</li>
<li>The CEO, Paolo Ardoino, mentioned that Tether has helped in freezing wallets holding 435 million USDT tokens and has an ongoing partnership with the FBI.</li>
<li>By making these letters public, Tether intends to highlight its dedication to safeguarding the stability and trustworthiness of its stablecoin.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/tether-reveals-partnerships-secret-fbi-053041589.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZTether Partners with Secret Service and FBI, Demonstrates Commitment to Security</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unveiling the Hidden Gems of Moreutils: Execsnoop, Ts, Sponge, Vidir, Vipe, and Pee]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article highlights lesser-known command line utilities called moreutils, including tools like execsnoop, ts, sponge, vidir, vipe, and pee.</li>
<li>Execsnoop enables tracking program invocations with timestamps, while ts can convert timestamps into relative times.</li>
<li>Other utilities mentioned include sponge for saving modifications to a file, vidir for editing files and directories, vipe for editing output between pipes, and pee for passing data to multiple commands and collecting their output.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jpospisil.com/2023/12/19/the-hidden-gems-of-moreutils</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZUnveiling the Hidden Gems of Moreutils: Execsnoop, Ts, Sponge, Vidir, Vipe, and Pee</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK Museums Prohibited from Charging Reproduction Fees for Historic Artworks, Court of Appeal Rules]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Court of Appeal in the UK has ruled that museums cannot charge fees to reproduce historic artworks if the original work is out of copyright.</li>
<li>Museums have been using copyright to restrict the use of images and require expensive licenses, but the ruling confirms this practice as incorrect.</li>
<li>The ruling renders copyright symbols on UK museum websites and catalogues irrelevant for out-of-copyright artwork.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theartnewspaper.com/2023/12/29/court-of-appeal-ruling-will-prevent-uk-museums-from-charging-reproduction-feesat-last</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZUK Museums Prohibited from Charging Reproduction Fees for Historic Artworks, Court of Appeal Rules</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maersk ship hit by missile; US Navy successfully intercepts attackers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Maersk containership named Maersk Hangzhou was targeted by a missile in the Red Sea during its journey through the Southern Red Sea.</li>
<li>The ship promptly reported the incident and requested assistance, leading to the response of USS Gravely and USS Laboon.</li>
<li>The USS Gravely successfully intercepted and destroyed two anti-ship ballistic missiles fired from Houthi-controlled areas in Yemen, ensuring the safety of the vessel and crew.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gcaptain.com/maersk-ship-hit-by-missile-in-the-red-sea/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZMaersk ship hit by missile; US Navy successfully intercepts attackers</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing DRGS: Enhancing Output Variety with Deep Random Micro-Glitch Sampling]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DRGS is a repository that introduces a method called Deep Random Micro-Glitch Sampling (DRGS) to inject noise into transformer layers during inference, increasing output variety while maintaining coherence.</li>
<li>The repository currently supports LLaMA and mistral models, providing implementations and experimental data for four types of DRGs: Q, K, V, and A.</li>
<li>Potential negative side effects of DRGS are addressed with a &quot;cold_shower&quot; function included in the repository.</li>
<li>Visualizations are available to showcase the effects of injecting noise at different layers of the model.</li>
<li>Contributions and experimentation with DRGS are encouraged.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/EGjoni/DRUGS</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing DRGS: Enhancing Output Variety with Deep Random Micro-Glitch Sampling</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Accused of Selling Damaged Books, Prompting Legal Concerns]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The person is upset and seeking advice after discovering that someone purchased their returned and damaged copy from Amazon.</li>
<li>They are concerned about the legality of this situation and want to know how to handle it and prevent it from happening again in the future.</li>
<li>It is unclear what specific actions or details led to the person&#39;s anger and concern.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/joabaldwin/status/1741145625809559933</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-31T00:00:00.000ZAmazon Accused of Selling Damaged Books, Prompting Legal Concerns</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch to Firefox in 2024 for Privacy & Web Development]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author suggests switching to Firefox as a web browser for two main reasons in 2024: privacy and preventing a browser engine monopoly.</li>
<li>Firefox is the only major browser not associated with a company that profits from advertising and selling personal data.</li>
<li>The author warns against a single browser engine dominating the market, as it may hinder web development. They highlight Firefox&#39;s speed, user interface, and effectiveness, making it a valuable option for users, and encourage supporting Firefox to preserve the web.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://roytanck.com/2023/12/23/in-2024-please-switch-to-firefox/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZSwitch to Firefox in 2024 for Privacy &amp; Web Development</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turn your folder into a website with Blot]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Blot is a platform that transforms a folder into a website, turning the files within the folder into individual posts on the site.</li>
<li>Users can sync their folders with popular cloud storage services like Dropbox, Git, and Google Drive.</li>
<li>Users have control over which files become posts and can also restrict certain files from being published.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blot.im/how</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZTurn your folder into a website with Blot</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gentoo Linux now offers binary packages for easier installation and wider software availability]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Gentoo Linux, a source-based distribution, now provides binary packages for download and installation alongside source-based packages.</li>
<li>The binary packages are available for amd64 and arm64 architectures and offer a wide range of software.</li>
<li>Users can configure their existing Gentoo installation to use the binary packages by creating a configuration file.</li>
<li>Binary packages are compiled with specific settings for different architectures and profiles.</li>
<li>The packages are cryptographically signed, and users can verify the signatures before installation.</li>
<li>Binary packages can be used with a merged-usr system but not with other profile versions.</li>
<li>Currently, Gentoo does not have plans to offer binary packages for ~amd64.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to report any issues or bugs related to the binary package support.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gentoo.org/news/2023/12/29/Gentoo-binary.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZGentoo Linux now offers binary packages for easier installation and wider software availability</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seeking Advanced Programming Courses for Experienced Coders: Recommendations for Learning Elixir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The person is currently learning Elixir and is looking for resources that are more advanced and suitable for experienced coders.</li>
<li>They feel that the popular resources available are too beginner-focused and want to explore programming books or courses that cater to their level of expertise.</li>
<li>The individual is seeking recommendations for resources that can help them further their understanding and skills in Elixir as a more experienced programmer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38804603</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZSeeking Advanced Programming Courses for Experienced Coders: Recommendations for Learning Elixir</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Differences in Virtualization: Apple Silicon vs. Intel Macs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple has implemented device support in macOS using Virtio drivers, enabling efficient virtualization on Apple silicon Macs.</li>
<li>This approach provides Apple with more control over hardware and feature support, but it diminishes the commercial value for third-party virtualization vendors.</li>
<li>Virtualization on Apple silicon Macs offers flexibility for running older macOS versions and incompatible software, and the article suggests that the lightweight virtualization and Virtio could drive further growth in the field.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://eclecticlight.co/2023/12/29/why-are-apple-silicon-vms-so-different/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZDifferences in Virtualization: Apple Silicon vs. Intel Macs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Steel's Decline: Lacking Innovation and Falling Behind Minimills]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>US Steel has faced a decline in market share and profitability in the American steel industry.</li>
<li>Competition from low-cost steelmakers abroad and efficient minimills at home contributed to this decline.</li>
<li>US Steel struggled to adopt new technologies and faced challenges in terms of efficiency and innovation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.construction-physics.com/p/no-inventions-no-innovations-a-history</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZUS Steel&apos;s Decline: Lacking Innovation and Falling Behind Minimills</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Copyright: A Monetization Strategy, not a Moral Right]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Copyright is often viewed as a means to generate profit rather than as a moral entitlement, which can have implications for different business models.</li>
<li>Certain business models may benefit from copyright protection, while others may face obstacles or limitations.</li>
<li>The discussion around copyright highlights the tension between economic interests and ethical considerations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/Plinz/status/1740597001652461895</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZCopyright: A Monetization Strategy, not a Moral Right</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Linux Backdoor Attempt of 2003: A Deep Dive into Programming, Cybersecurity, and Open Source]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The passage covers topics such as attempted backdoor insertion into the Linux kernel and the importance of trusted systems in warfare.</li>
<li>It discusses concerns about cryptographic methods and the need for validation and tracking in open source development.</li>
<li>The author also talks about coding techniques, compiler behavior, and the use of if statements in programming languages, as well as the benefits of open source software and criticism of closed source code.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://freedom-to-tinker.com/2013/10/09/the-linux-backdoor-attempt-of-2003/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZThe Linux Backdoor Attempt of 2003: A Deep Dive into Programming, Cybersecurity, and Open Source</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How the append-only b+tree improves data storage and access efficiency]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The append-only b+tree is a data structure commonly used for efficient storage and retrieval of data.</li>
<li>It is made up of branch and leaf pages, with the leaf pages containing the actual data and keys.</li>
<li>Rather than supporting leaf chaining for sequential access, each update involves appending a new page to the file and updating the parent pages, ensuring a consistent snapshot of the database without the need for a transaction log. This approach is more efficient for writing consecutive pages to disk, but may waste disk space.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bzero.se/ldapd/btree.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZHow the append-only b+tree improves data storage and access efficiency</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Koka: Advanced Functional Language with Effect Types and Handlers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Koka is a strongly typed functional language that incorporates effect types and handlers.</li>
<li>The language offers advanced control abstractions and utilizes reference counting for efficient memory usage.</li>
<li>Although Koka has a complete compiler implementation and is stable, it is still in the research phase and not recommended for production use.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://koka-lang.github.io/koka/doc/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZKoka: Advanced Functional Language with Effect Types and Handlers</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK's Viking Link interconnector brings cheaper and greener power]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>National Grid has announced the completion of Viking Link, the world&#39;s longest land and subsea interconnector, stretching 475 miles between the UK and Denmark.</li>
<li>The 1.7 billion project has the capacity to power up to 2.5 million homes and is expected to save UK consumers over 500 million in the first ten years through cheaper imported power from Denmark.</li>
<li>Viking Link is also estimated to reduce carbon emissions by 600,000 tonnes in its first year of operation, while increasing security of supply and decreasing prices for consumers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nationalgrid.com/national-grid-announces-commercial-operations-viking-link-worlds-longest-land-and-subsea</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZUK&apos;s Viking Link interconnector brings cheaper and greener power</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Debunking the Myth: Roman Soldiers Were Not Paid in Salt]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This article debunks the popular myth that Roman soldiers were paid in salt, providing evidence that they were not actually compensated with it.</li>
<li>It explores the origins of the word &quot;salary&quot; and its connection to salt, shedding light on the historical use of salt as currency in Ethiopia and other cultures.</li>
<li>The article emphasizes the importance of knowledge and wisdom in debunking myths, and briefly mentions discussions and comments on related blog posts and social media accounts in the field of classical studies and ancient history.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://kiwihellenist.blogspot.com/2017/01/salt-and-salary.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZDebunking the Myth: Roman Soldiers Were Not Paid in Salt</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghosting in Tech Recruiting: Lack of Communication Leaves Candidates in Limbo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ghosting, the act of abruptly cutting off communication with candidates, is a prevalent issue in tech recruiting.</li>
<li>The author shares their personal experience of being ghosted by a company and the impact it had on them.</li>
<li>Lack of incentives and enforcement of a nonperformative policy contribute to the prevalence of ghosting in the tech industry.</li>
<li>The author argues for the importance of closing the loop with rejected candidates and treating them with dignity and respect.</li>
<li>Recruiters should be more aware and ensure that communication is maintained with candidates.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://medium.com/@k0ryk/everyones-getting-ghosted-dbf0fbaf161</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-30T00:00:00.000ZGhosting in Tech Recruiting: Lack of Communication Leaves Candidates in Limbo</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Evolution of Text-based IDEs: A Comparison to Modern IDEs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This article examines the transformation of text-based IDEs throughout three decades and compares them to contemporary IDEs.</li>
<li>The author shares their firsthand encounters with older IDEs such as SideKick Plus and Turbo Pascal, emphasizing their characteristics and user-friendliness.</li>
<li>Despite the decline in popularity of text-based user interfaces (TUIs) in software development due to graphical operating systems, TUI IDEs are making a resurgence with the introduction of the Language Server Protocol (LSP).</li>
<li>While some enhancements have been implemented in modern IDEs, the fundamental functionality has largely stayed the same.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blogsystem5.substack.com/p/the-ides-we-had-30-years-ago-and</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZThe Evolution of Text-based IDEs: A Comparison to Modern IDEs</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Warned by FDA for Undeclared Ingredients in Supplements]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The FDA has issued a warning letter to Amazon for distributing products that violate federal regulations.</li>
<li>The products contain undisclosed pharmaceutical ingredients, including sildenafil and tadalafil, which can have dangerous side effects.</li>
<li>The FDA considers these products to be unapproved drugs, as they do not meet the definition of dietary supplements, and has requested a written response from Amazon addressing the violations. Additionally, specific products stored in Amazon&#39;s fulfillment centers, such as WeFun Capsules, have been recalled due to the presence of undisclosed drug ingredients.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fda.gov/inspections-compliance-enforcement-and-criminal-investigations/warning-letters/amazoncom-inc-662503-12202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZAmazon Warned by FDA for Undeclared Ingredients in Supplements</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finding Stability: How Cold-Blooded Software Projects Adapt and Thrive]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author compares cold-blooded animals&#39; ability to adapt to their environment to software projects that use stable and reliable technology.</li>
<li>The author shares a personal experience with a successful software project that has remained functional for a long time and is expected to continue working in the future.</li>
<li>The parallel drawn highlights the importance of using stable technology in software development for long-term success.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dubroy.com/blog/cold-blooded-software/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZFinding Stability: How Cold-Blooded Software Projects Adapt and Thrive</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mozilla CEO compensation rises, Firefox market share falls, as company shifts focus to AI services]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Mozilla Foundation&#39;s 2023 annual report reveals that CEO compensation increased while revenue and Firefox market share decreased, potentially indicating a shift in focus towards artificial intelligence services.</li>
<li>The article discusses various topics including joining Lunduke.Locals.com for independent tech journalism, the Linux Foundation&#39;s reduced spending on Linux, the future of The Internet Archive, and openSUSE&#39;s refusal to allow the author to contribute.</li>
<li>The Linux Foundation has been allocating more funding to blockchain and AI projects, raising concerns about their priorities, while The Lunduke Journal offers gift subscriptions and a guide on anonymous information leaking. Additionally, the summary mentions options for sending files and recommends an anonymous file sharing tool.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lunduke.locals.com/post/5053290/mozilla-2023-annual-report-ceo-pay-skyrockets-while-firefox-marketshare-nosedives</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZMozilla CEO compensation rises, Firefox market share falls, as company shifts focus to AI services</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Configuring Lode Runner Web Game Canvas Position and Google Analytics Tracking]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The code snippet sets the position of the Lode Runner web game canvas to &quot;absolute&quot;, meaning it will be positioned relative to its closest positioned ancestor.</li>
<li>The canvas is positioned at the top left corner of the web page, ensuring it is displayed in the desired location.</li>
<li>In addition to positioning the canvas, the code also includes the initialization and configuration of Google Analytics tracking for the web page, allowing for analysis of user interactions and website performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://loderunnerwebgame.com/game/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZConfiguring Lode Runner Web Game Canvas Position and Google Analytics Tracking</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Simulating Artificial Life: Complexity Arises from Simplicity]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The summary discusses a program that simulates artificial life by using rules of attraction and repulsion among particles.</li>
<li>The program generates self-organizing life-like patterns and is available in C++, JavaScript, and Python.</li>
<li>It lacks collision detection, enabling real-time simulation of numerous particles, and allows for parameter exploration and fine-tuning.</li>
<li>Planned updates include adding features like saving and loading parameters, additional particle types, and improved computational efficiency.</li>
<li>The program aims to showcase how complexity can emerge from simplicity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/hunar4321/particle-life</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZSimulating Artificial Life: Complexity Arises from Simplicity</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Liero: The Ultimate Duel Game with Mods, Maps, and Online Multiplayer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Liero is a popular duel game that was originally released in 1998 and now has four versions available with different features.</li>
<li>Liero 1.33 is the original version from 2000, while Liero 1.36 is a high-fidelity clone that addresses bugs and introduces new features.</li>
<li>WebLiero offers an online multiplayer experience, and lierolibre is a project dedicated to distributing Liero freely. The game involves selecting weapons and engaging in combat on various maps. It has a vibrant modding community, and it can be played on modern computers and popular web browsers. Contact details are provided for additional inquiries.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://www.liero.be/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZLiero: The Ultimate Duel Game with Mods, Maps, and Online Multiplayer</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ideal Screen Rotation for Programmers: Exploring the Benefits of a 22 Angle in Coding]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author experiments with various screen orientations for software development, such as portrait mode and different angles of rotation.</li>
<li>After exploring the advantages and disadvantages, they determine that a 22 rotation offers the most optimal line lengths for coding.</li>
<li>The author introduces a tool called xrandr to rotate the screen and provides transformation matrix examples for different angles. They also offer a calculator to generate the xrandr command for specific inputs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sprocketfox.io/xssfox/2021/12/02/xrandr/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZIdeal Screen Rotation for Programmers: Exploring the Benefits of a 22 Angle in Coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Investigating the Randomness of xkcd: Unbiasedness and Pattern Perception]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author of this blog post investigates the randomness of the &quot;random&quot; button on the xkcd website using statistical tests.</li>
<li>The random number generator used by xkcd is confirmed to be unbiased and unpredictable.</li>
<li>The perception of bias may be due to human tendency to see patterns, despite the randomness of the generator.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hardmath123.github.io/xkcd-random.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZInvestigating the Randomness of xkcd: Unbiasedness and Pattern Perception</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Developers' refusal to support user requests causes frustration and highlights need for better guidance]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author expresses frustration with programming experiences they find insulting and condescending.</li>
<li>Examples like Python&#39;s exit command, formatting Rust files, and conflicts when vendoring Rust dependencies are given as instances where developers refused to allow users to do what they wanted, leaving them feeling unsupported and frustrated.</li>
<li>The author calls on developers to either fully support features or provide guidance for alternative solutions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bvisness.me/you-cant/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZDevelopers&apos; refusal to support user requests causes frustration and highlights need for better guidance</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foundations: Exploring Physics and Science Fiction in Greg Egan's Collection]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Foundations&quot; is a collection of articles by Greg Egan discussing the influence of twentieth-century physics theories on science fiction.</li>
<li>The articles explain the main concepts of each theory and their real-world predictions, aimed at lay readers with no advanced math background.</li>
<li>Topics covered include special relativity, general relativity, black holes, and quantum mechanics. The collection also includes Egan&#39;s fictional works.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gregegan.net/FOUNDATIONS/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-29T00:00:00.000ZFoundations: Exploring Physics and Science Fiction in Greg Egan&apos;s Collection</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First new U.S. nuclear reactor in 5 years begins operation at Vogtle plant]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Georgia Power&#39;s Vogtle nuclear power plant in Georgia has started commercial operation of a new nuclear reactor, the first in the United States since 2016.</li>
<li>The reactor, called Unit 3, has a capacity of 1,114 MW and will be joined by another reactor, Unit 4, expected to begin operation by March 2024.</li>
<li>The Vogtle plant will become the largest nuclear power plant in the country once both new reactors are operational and will help reduce carbon emissions in the power sector.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=61106</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZFirst new U.S. nuclear reactor in 5 years begins operation at Vogtle plant</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3D Mapping of Shinjuku Station's Indoor Spaces]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Ministry of Land, Infrastructure, Transport and Tourism has developed a control map for indoor areas around Shinjuku Station.</li>
<li>The map covers multiple floors and pedestrian networks, providing detailed information on the locations within the station.</li>
<li>This initiative aims to enhance navigation and accessibility within the station complex.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://satoshi7190.github.io/Shinjuku-indoor-threejs-demo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000Z3D Mapping of Shinjuku Station&apos;s Indoor Spaces</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NY Times Sues OpenAI & Microsoft for Copyright Infringement]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The New York Times has filed a lawsuit against OpenAI and Microsoft, accusing them of using millions of the newspaper&#39;s articles without permission to train their language models.</li>
<li>The Times argues that these AI models compete directly with its content, leading to a loss of revenue and damaging its relationship with readers.</li>
<li>The publication is seeking billions of dollars in damages and wants the court to prohibit OpenAI and Microsoft from using its content in their AI models. Other news outlets, like the BBC, CNN, and Reuters, have also blocked OpenAI&#39;s web crawler, while some publications, including Politico and the Associated Press, have reached agreements to allow their content to be used for AI training.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/27/24016212/new-york-times-openai-microsoft-lawsuit-copyright-infringement</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZNY Times Sues OpenAI &amp; Microsoft for Copyright Infringement</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rise and Fall of Goitres in Switzerland: A Triumph Over Iodine Deficiency]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In the early 20th century, goitres and related medical conditions were highly prevalent in Switzerland, causing swelling of the neck and significant health and economic impacts for families.</li>
<li>The cause of goitres was found to be iodine deficiency, and the solution was the introduction of iodised salt, although it faced initial opposition.</li>
<li>The implementation of iodised salt in Switzerland resulted in a significant reduction in goitre rates, but the achievements of those involved have been overshadowed by the opposition of Dr. Eugen Bircher.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.lrb.co.uk/the-paper/v45/n23/jonah-goodman/a-national-evil</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZThe Rise and Fall of Goitres in Switzerland: A Triumph Over Iodine Deficiency</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Triangulation" Campaign Backdoors iPhones and Uncovers Secret Apple Hardware Function]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The &quot;Triangulation&quot; campaign targeted and compromised numerous iPhones, including those owned by employees of Kaspersky, a security firm based in Moscow, over a period of four years.</li>
<li>The attackers exploited an undisclosed hardware feature to gain unprecedented access and installed spyware that transmitted sensitive data to attacker-controlled servers.</li>
<li>Apple has since patched the four critical zero-day vulnerabilities exploited by the campaign, but the secret hardware function used to bypass memory protections was also found in Apple&#39;s M1 and M2 CPUs, raising concerns about the security of other Apple devices.-</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2023/12/exploit-used-in-mass-iphone-infection-campaign-targeted-secret-hardware-feature/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000Z&quot;Triangulation&quot; Campaign Backdoors iPhones and Uncovers Secret Apple Hardware Function</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimizing Number Checking with if Statements in Python and Assembly]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author explores the problem of determining whether a number is odd or even using a large number of if statements.</li>
<li>They use a Python program to generate a C program that can handle this problem for 8-bit, 16-bit, and 32-bit integers.</li>
<li>However, they encounter limitations with the compiler and executable file size when scaling up.</li>
<li>To overcome these limitations, they manually write x86-64 assembly code and create a function to check if a 32-bit number is even or odd.</li>
<li>The program is shown to be performant and capable of handling a wide range of numbers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://andreasjhkarlsson.github.io//jekyll/update/2023/12/27/4-billion-if-statements.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZOptimizing Number Checking with if Statements in Python and Assembly</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Operation Triangulation: Researchers Uncover iOS Attack Chain Exploiting Zero-Day Vulnerabilities]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Researchers presented their findings on &quot;Operation Triangulation,&quot; an attack chain targeting iOS versions up to iOS 16.2.</li>
<li>The attack utilized zero-day vulnerabilities, including a remote code execution vulnerability in Apple&#39;s ADJUST TrueType font instruction and a JavaScript exploit to gain control of the device and run spyware.</li>
<li>The attackers bypassed hardware-based memory protection using an unknown hardware feature on Apple-designed SoCs, exploiting unknown MMIO blocks related to the GPU coprocessor and specific registers to control hardware features and interrupts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://securelist.com/operation-triangulation-the-last-hardware-mystery/111669/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZOperation Triangulation: Researchers Uncover iOS Attack Chain Exploiting Zero-Day Vulnerabilities</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Combat Won the Roach Wars: From Decline to Resurgence]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In the 1980s, a roach-control product called Combat successfully reduced the cockroach population, especially in government buildings.</li>
<li>Researchers have created a new bait product that is effective against cockroaches resistant to traditional insecticides.</li>
<li>The decline in cockroaches during that time coincided with the end of the Cold War, symbolizing concerns about nuclear war. Now, cockroaches are making a comeback due to their resistance to baits.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/podcasts/archive/2023/11/cockroach-bait-invention-combat/676167/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZHow Combat Won the Roach Wars: From Decline to Resurgence</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Expanding ChatGPT: Leveraging Structured Data with API]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores the usage of OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT model and structured data.</li>
<li>It discusses the benefits of the paid ChatGPT API for controlling the model&#39;s output and techniques like prompt engineering.</li>
<li>The article highlights the use of the Pydantic library for generating JSON Schemas and working with structured data, covering various topics such as function calling, nested schemas, Union typing, and the importance of system prompts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://minimaxir.com/2023/12/chatgpt-structured-data/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZExpanding ChatGPT: Leveraging Structured Data with API</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valetudo: Local-Only Operation for Vacuum Robots with Open-Source Software]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Valetudo is an open-source software that eliminates the need for cloud functionality in vacuum robots, enabling local-only operation.</li>
<li>Managed by Sren Beye, Valetudo has gained a significant user base and offers extensive documentation and a Telegram group for support.</li>
<li>Licensed under Apache-2.0, Valetudo encourages code visibility and modification, providing users with ownership and control over their devices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://valetudo.cloud/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZValetudo: Local-Only Operation for Vacuum Robots with Open-Source Software</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No secure iOS: Vulnerability in Chrome for iOS raises concerns]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple is still providing security updates for older devices like the iPhone 6S, but they only address certain security issues.</li>
<li>A vulnerability in Google Chrome&#39;s Blink rendering engine that can expose system files is also present in Chrome for iOS.</li>
<li>Exploiting this vulnerability on the latest version of iOS allows attackers to steal internal system files, including contact information, call and SMS history, browsing history, and cookies.</li>
<li>Apple&#39;s response implies they may only patch vulnerabilities in older iOS versions if they are actively being exploited.</li>
<li>This raises concerns about the effectiveness of iOS security updates for older devices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://joshua.hu/apple-ios-patched-unpatched-vulnerabilities</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZNo secure iOS: Vulnerability in Chrome for iOS raises concerns</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reverse Engineering Train Control System: Analyzing Malfunctions in Modern Trains [37c3 Event]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The 37c3 event in 2023 will feature a talk on reverse engineering a train control system to analyze a malfunction.</li>
<li>The presentation will discuss both technical and non-technical aspects of the analysis and provide insights into the operation of modern trains.</li>
<li>The talk will be downloadable in multiple formats and languages for easy access.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://streaming.media.ccc.de/37c3/relive/12142</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZReverse Engineering Train Control System: Analyzing Malfunctions in Modern Trains [37c3 Event]</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-Source Rem: Revolutionary Solution for Locally Recording Computer Activity on Apple Silicon Devices]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The concept of locally recording all computer activity on Apple Silicon devices is proposed as an open-source solution.</li>
<li>This idea aims to revolutionize computer interaction by prioritizing privacy and security, ensuring that no information leaves the laptop.</li>
<li>It is suggested that even logging to Sentry, a popular monitoring tool, may risk leaking private information.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/jasonjmcghee/rem</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZOpen-Source Rem: Revolutionary Solution for Locally Recording Computer Activity on Apple Silicon Devices</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Deterioration of Quality: A Look Into Disposable Products]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article highlights the decline in the quality of products that we purchase, using personal anecdotes as examples of appliances and household items that quickly malfunction or break.</li>
<li>The author explores the frustration and disappointment caused by these experiences and discusses the environmental impact and the perception it creates for the future.</li>
<li>The potential role of planned obsolescence and differing opinions on economic factors contributing to the decline in quality are also mentioned.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://walterkirn.substack.com/p/generation-junk</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZThe Deterioration of Quality: A Look Into Disposable Products</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[High Myopia Increasing Rates in Taiwan and Asian Countries: A Leading Cause of Blindness]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Myopia (nearsightedness) rates are increasing in Taiwan and other parts of the world due to factors like lifestyle changes and limited outdoor time.</li>
<li>Spending more time outdoors has been found to reduce the risk of myopia, according to research by Professor Ian Morgan.</li>
<li>Taiwan has implemented programs to address myopia, but the COVID-19 pandemic has disrupted these efforts. Potential solutions include glass-walled classrooms and red light therapy.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wired.com/story/taiwan-epicenter-of-world-myopia-epidemic/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-28T00:00:00.000ZHigh Myopia Increasing Rates in Taiwan and Asian Countries: A Leading Cause of Blindness</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japan Moves to Break Apple and Google App Store Monopolies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Japan is planning to introduce regulations that would compel tech giants such as Apple and Google to allow third-party app stores and alternate payment options on their mobile operating systems.</li>
<li>The aim is to address the alleged abuse of their dominant market position in Japan.</li>
<li>The legislation, which will cover app stores and payments, search, browsers, and operating systems, is anticipated to be presented in parliament by 2024.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Technology/Japan-to-crack-down-on-Apple-and-Google-app-store-monopolies</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZJapan Moves to Break Apple and Google App Store Monopolies</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Comprehensive Guide to Hacker News's Hidden Features and Behaviors]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores the features, behaviors, and guidelines on the Hacker News platform, including moderators, downvoting comments, and flagging behavior.</li>
<li>It mentions bonus features such as Hacker News Classic and Hacker News Lists.</li>
<li>The article also discusses the availability of the Hacker News dataset on BigQuery for data analysis and machine learning, as well as official RSS feeds, the HN Search feature, and content filtering on Hacker News.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/minimaxir/hacker-news-undocumented/blob/master/README.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZA Comprehensive Guide to Hacker News&apos;s Hidden Features and Behaviors</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[mRNA-4157 cancer vaccine boosts Keytruda treatment, reduces recurrence by 49%: Phase 2b study]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Moderna and Merck have collaborated to develop an mRNA-based cancer vaccine called mRNA-4157.</li>
<li>The vaccine has shown promising results in preventing melanoma recurrence or death when combined with Merck&#39;s Keytruda treatment.</li>
<li>In a phase 2b study, the combination therapy reduced the risk of recurrence or death by 49% after three years compared to Keytruda alone.</li>
<li>These positive findings have led to the launch of a phase 3 trial for the combination therapy.</li>
<li>The vaccine may potentially be available for accelerated approval in some countries by 2025.</li>
<li>Moderna and Merck are also exploring the use of the vaccine in other types of cancer, such as non-small cell lung cancer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freethink.com/health/cancer-vaccine</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZmRNA-4157 cancer vaccine boosts Keytruda treatment, reduces recurrence by 49%: Phase 2b study</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Online Shopping Frustration: Website Chaos and Unclear Filters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The speaker expresses frustration with the overwhelming number of options and lack of organization on various websites.</li>
<li>They question the value of having so many choices and are puzzled by unclear categories and filters.</li>
<li>Specific examples are provided, such as issues with Costco, Lazada, and Nintendo.com.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.openmymind.net/Your-Website-Search-Hurts-My-Feelings/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZOnline Shopping Frustration: Website Chaos and Unclear Filters</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Video to Introduce Ads, Charge Extra for Ad-Free Experience]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Starting from January 29th, Amazon Prime Video will introduce limited advertisements, unless customers opt for an ad-free experience by paying an extra $2.99 per month.</li>
<li>The purpose of this move is to enable Amazon to invest in content and better compete with other streaming services.</li>
<li>While the monthly cost of Amazon Prime will remain the same, the ad-free streaming option will increase the total cost to just under $18, aligning with the approaches of other streaming services like Disney Plus and Netflix, which include ads on their cheaper plans.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/26/24015595/amazon-prime-video-ads-coming-january-29</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZAmazon Prime Video to Introduce Ads, Charge Extra for Ad-Free Experience</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apollo 11 Guidance Computer vs. Anker PowerPort Atom PD 2: A Comparison of Processing Power and Features]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Anker PowerPort Atom PD 2 charger has a significantly faster CPU compared to the Apollo 11 Guidance Computer, estimated to be 563 times faster.</li>
<li>The Anker charger also offers more program storage space than the Apollo 11 computer.</li>
<li>However, it is unclear if the dedicated hardware capabilities of the Apollo 11 computer can be replicated in software, requiring further analysis.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://forrestheller.com/Apollo-11-Computer-vs-USB-C-chargers.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZApollo 11 Guidance Computer vs. Anker PowerPort Atom PD 2: A Comparison of Processing Power and Features</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimizing Learning for Software Developers: Research-backed Strategies and Practical Implications]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article highlights the significance of continuous learning for software developers and presents research-backed insights on human memory and learning that are applicable to the field.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the need to match instructional methods with the content being taught and offers practical implications for enhancing learning outcomes.</li>
<li>The article addresses challenges in programming ability and provides recommendations for recruiting and training individuals, while stressing the importance of maintaining a growth mindset and goal orientation to overcome setbacks and failures. It also underscores the value of providing honest feedback and support to foster skill development and a growth mindset.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://cacm.acm.org/magazines/2024/1/278891-10-things-software-developers-should-learn-about-learning/fulltext</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZOptimizing Learning for Software Developers: Research-backed Strategies and Practical Implications</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Boy Color: Improvements and Innovation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Game Boy, a portable version of the NES, was released in 1989 and gained popularity.</li>
<li>It had revisions and two generations, including the monochrome Game Boy and the Game Boy Color.</li>
<li>The Game Boy Color featured a doubled clock speed, backwards compatibility, and added features like bank switching and extended memory.</li>
<li>The system had limited graphics capabilities but included palettes and tiles for visual effects.</li>
<li>It had an audio system with four channels for different waveforms.</li>
<li>The boot process involved initializing RAM, copying logos, and checking cartridges.</li>
<li>The Game Boy Color had different modes for running games and could communicate with other consoles.</li>
<li>Anti-piracy measures were implemented to control distribution.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/game-boy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZThe Game Boy Color: Improvements and Innovation</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Piece Table: The Most Elegant and Efficient Data Structure for a Text Editor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author is developing a text editor and evaluating different data structures for the core API.</li>
<li>Options examined include an array, a rope (a binary tree structure), a gap buffer, and a piece table.</li>
<li>The author concludes that the piece table is the best choice due to its elegance and efficiency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.averylaird.com/programming/the%20text%20editor/2017/09/30/the-piece-table.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZThe Piece Table: The Most Elegant and Efficient Data Structure for a Text Editor</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Private equity acquisitions harm patient care, study finds]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A nationwide study conducted by Harvard Medical School reveals that the quality of care diminishes after hospitals are acquired by private equity firms.</li>
<li>Patients in these hospitals are at a higher risk of preventable conditions and adverse outcomes, such as falls and infections.</li>
<li>The findings highlight the potential conflict between profit-driven motives and patient care and safety, raising concerns about the impact of private equity in healthcare.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2023-12-quality-declines-private-equity-hospitals.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZPrivate equity acquisitions harm patient care, study finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK Achieves Historic Carbon Emission Reduction, Unnoticed by Public and Politicians]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The UK has become the first major country in the G20 to cut its carbon emissions in half, with its current output below 320 million tonnes.</li>
<li>This achievement is significant as it demonstrates the country&#39;s progress in reducing its carbon footprint, despite having a larger population and economy.</li>
<li>Surprisingly, this accomplishment has received little attention from campaign groups and politicians, and is not being actively promoted. The data can be accessed on The Spectator data hub, tracked by the Global Carbon Project.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/uk-becomes-first-g20-country-to-halve-its-carbon-emissions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZUK Achieves Historic Carbon Emission Reduction, Unnoticed by Public and Politicians</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get Unique Activity Ideas for the Holiday Break with Whataaabout.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author has developed a website called whataaabout.com with the purpose of offering ideas for quick and distinctive experiences.</li>
<li>The website aims to introduce variety into the author&#39;s daily routine and foster a mindset of lifelong learning.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to provide feedback and suggestions on the activities organized on the website.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.whataaabout.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZGet Unique Activity Ideas for the Holiday Break with Whataaabout.com</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Using Make: Simplifying the Makefile Process in Linux]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The make(1) command in Linux can be used to build C, C++, and Fortran files without the need for a Makefile.</li>
<li>Environment variables like CFLAGS and LDLIBS can be used to pass compiler and linker flags to the make command.</li>
<li>Including a rule in the Makefile allows for automatic rebuilding of source files when header files change, and adding a clean target can remove object files and binaries.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://text.causal.agency/001-make.txt</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZUsing Make: Simplifying the Makefile Process in Linux</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The SAT's Misleading Question: Counting Rotations & Brilliant Online Learning]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 1982, there was a mistake on the SAT exam where students discovered an incorrect answer to a test question.</li>
<li>The article introduces the concept of counting rotations, explaining its applications in fields like astronomy.</li>
<li>It discusses the diminishing importance of standardized testing and recommends the online learning platform, Brilliant, for enhancing critical thinking and problem-solving skills. The article offers a free trial and acknowledges Brilliant for sponsoring the video.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FUHkTs-Ipfg</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZThe SAT&apos;s Misleading Question: Counting Rotations &amp; Brilliant Online Learning</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Interactive Map Makes Chicago's Zoning Code More Accessible]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>2nd City Zoning is an interactive map designed to simplify Chicago&#39;s zoning code, inspired by Sim City 2000 and utilizing color-coded zoning districts.</li>
<li>Users can navigate the map to understand zoning patterns, determine their building&#39;s zoning status, and identify ideal locations for their business.</li>
<li>The project was developed collaboratively by DataMade, Derek Eder, and Juan-Pablo Velez, and features graphics, sounds, and music to enhance user engagement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://secondcityzoning.org</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-27T00:00:00.000ZInteractive Map Makes Chicago&apos;s Zoning Code More Accessible</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stirling-PDF: A Feature-Packed PDF Manipulation Tool for Local Use]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Stirling-PDF is a locally hosted web-based tool for manipulating PDF files, offering features like splitting, merging, converting, and more.</li>
<li>The tool ensures the security and privacy of files, without making outbound calls for tracking or record keeping.</li>
<li>It utilizes technologies like Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, PDFBox, LibreOffice, and more, and can be accessed through a hosted instance or run locally using Docker or Podman.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Frooodle/Stirling-PDF</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZStirling-PDF: A Feature-Packed PDF Manipulation Tool for Local Use</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Challenging Projects for Programmers: Text Editor, Game, Compiler, OS, Spreadsheet, Emulator]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Austin Z. Henley suggests a variety of challenging software projects for programmers to try, such as building a text editor, a 2D game like Space Invaders, a Tiny BASIC compiler, a mini operating system, a spreadsheet, and a video game console emulator.</li>
<li>Through these projects, programmers can gain valuable knowledge and skills in key concepts.</li>
<li>Henley provides further reading recommendations for each project and includes a list of additional project ideas from readers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://austinhenley.com/blog/challengingprojects.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZChallenging Projects for Programmers: Text Editor, Game, Compiler, OS, Spreadsheet, Emulator</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Software Blog Posts of 2023: Scaling systems, optimizing architectures, programming languages, and more!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The person is seeking software engineering blog posts covering topics like system scaling, architectures, optimization, programming languages, and cool features.</li>
<li>They are open to recommendations from open-source projects, companies, or individuals.</li>
<li>They also extend holiday greetings.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38765176</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZTop Software Blog Posts of 2023: Scaling systems, optimizing architectures, programming languages, and more!</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Retired engineer wins First Amendment case against state board]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A retired engineer in North Carolina, Wayne Nutt, has won a First Amendment case against the state&#39;s Board of Examiners and Surveyors.</li>
<li>Nutt was told by the board to stop sharing his engineering opinions online without a state license.</li>
<li>The court ruled in Nutt&#39;s favor, stating that the state violated his First Amendment rights, setting an important precedent for others in similar situations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wect.com/2023/12/20/federal-court-decides-favor-retired-engineer-told-by-state-not-talk-about-math-public/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZRetired engineer wins First Amendment case against state board</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improving SSH Password Authentication with a Password Manager and Zsh Wrapper]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article explores non-interactive SSH password authentication and offers a Zsh wrapper for retrieving passwords from a password manager.</li>
<li>It presents a method to make scp utilize the custom ssh function.</li>
<li>The post highlights the benefits of using public keys instead of passwords and discusses the challenges associated with certificate-based authentication and more granular authorization methods.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://vincent.bernat.ch/en/blog/2023-sshpass-without-sshpass</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZImproving SSH Password Authentication with a Password Manager and Zsh Wrapper</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Software update renders vehicle undrivable, owner advised to contact support]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A vehicle&#39;s software update has failed, causing the vehicle to be unusable.</li>
<li>The owner is urged to reach out to customer support for assistance.</li>
<li>The post does not provide any further details regarding the specific issue or how it can be resolved.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/danluu/status/1739387245034139692</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZSoftware update renders vehicle undrivable, owner advised to contact support</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inflight WiFi glitch caused by crowded network with 55 connected devices]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The individual encountered problems with the inflight wifi, which were attributed to a lack of DHCP lease.</li>
<li>At the time of the issue, there were 55 devices connected to the wifi network.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/erratarob/status/1739132876732674539?s=46&amp;t=FFxXRm_qmWG4nJwsccRUbA</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZInflight WiFi glitch caused by crowded network with 55 connected devices</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Contest Factory Uses Broad Software Patents to Sue Online Contest Organizers, Challenged by EFF]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Contest Factory has filed multiple lawsuits against companies organizing online contests, asserting that their patents cover a broad range of online contests.</li>
<li>The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) argues that these software patents harm people&#39;s right to express themselves and participate in online culture.</li>
<li>The EFF believes that such patents should not have been granted and advocates for a more accessible process to challenge these patents.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2023/12/stupid-patent-month-selfie-contests</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZContest Factory Uses Broad Software Patents to Sue Online Contest Organizers, Challenged by EFF</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TKey: The USB Stick Computer for Secure Applications]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Tillitis TKey is a USB stick computer specifically made for running secure applications that offer various security features like encryption and token generation.</li>
<li>It comes with a 32-bit RISC-V CPU, hardware-assisted address randomization and RAM scrambling, and no persistent storage.</li>
<li>The device ensures the integrity of the loaded application by measuring it using a Unique Device Secret (UDS) and a Compound Device Identifier (CDI), and all of its software and hardware designs are open source.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dev.tillitis.se/intro/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZTKey: The USB Stick Computer for Secure Applications</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Achieving Reproducibility in Git Backups by Forcing Single-Threaded Execution]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author encountered issues with non-deterministic behavior when backing up git repositories.</li>
<li>They identified the bundling process as the cause and resolved it by enforcing single-threaded operation in git.</li>
<li>The trade-off in performance resulted in deterministic output, enabling reproducibility in the backups.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://baecher.dev/stdout/reproducible-git-bundles/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZAchieving Reproducibility in Git Backups by Forcing Single-Threaded Execution</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German Courts Affirm User Freedom: Ad-blockers and Copyright Laws]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Recent court cases in Germany have upheld the right of internet users to use ad-blockers as a means of avoiding intrusive advertising.</li>
<li>The court rulings state that using ad-blockers does not violate copyright laws, giving users legal protection.</li>
<li>However, the court also ruled that companies can choose to exclude users with ad-blockers from accessing their content or implement a paid access model.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fsfe.org/news/2023/news-20231220-01.en.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZGerman Courts Affirm User Freedom: Ad-blockers and Copyright Laws</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Build Your Own Night Clock Projector: Easy DIY Guide (2018)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The DIY Night Clock Projector is a project that involves building a clock projector that can project the time onto a ceiling at night.</li>
<li>The project utilizes a small negative LCD screen and calculates the image size based on the focal length.</li>
<li>It includes two PCBs designed for the electronics construction and offers various case options. Additionally, downloadable files for schematics, layout, bill of materials, and 3D STL files are provided.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://microengineer.eu/2018/05/01/diy-night-clock-projector/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZBuild Your Own Night Clock Projector: Easy DIY Guide (2018)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rise of Affordable Computing: From Mainframes to Microcomputers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This article challenges the idea of progress in computing and highlights the development of simpler and cheaper models of computers throughout history.</li>
<li>It explores the evolution of computers from mainframes to microcomputers in the 1980s and the trade-offs made for simplicity and affordability.</li>
<li>It discusses the development, capabilities, and decline of the Newton, Lisp, and Smalltalk machines, as well as various operating systems. It also raises questions about the use of multiple programming languages and the advantages of dedicated hardware.</li>
<li>The article mentions different design approaches in software development and the decline of Lisp in favor of inexpensive and interchangeable software.</li>
<li>It concludes by listing various software, technologies, and topics mentioned, such as Microsoft Office, Visual Studio, open source software, programming languages, and education.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2023/12/25/the_war_of_the_workstations/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2023-12-26T00:00:00.000ZThe Rise of Affordable Computing: From Mainframes to Microcomputers</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>