<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 19:11:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Susan Wojcicki has died]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/sundarpichai/status/1822132667959386588</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZSusan Wojcicki has died</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Defcon stiffs badge HW vendor, drags FW author offstage during talk]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Defcon allegedly failed to pay the hardware company responsible for this year&#39;s badges.</li>
<li>The software developer who included a mention of this issue in an easter egg was reportedly expelled from the event.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/mightymogomra/status/1822119942281650278</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZDefcon stiffs badge HW vendor, drags FW author offstage during talk</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A wonderful coincidence or an expected connection: why π² ≈ g]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>π² (approximately 9.87) and the acceleration due to gravity, g (9.81 m/s²), are intriguingly close in value, but not exactly equal.</li>
<li>The discrepancy arises from historical changes in the definition of the meter, which has evolved from human-based measurements to a precise scientific standard based on the speed of light.</li>
<li>The near-equality of π² and g is not a mere coincidence but a result of historical and scientific developments in measurement standards.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://roitman.io/blog/91</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZA wonderful coincidence or an expected connection: why π² ≈ g</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Urchin Software Corp: The unlikely origin story of Google Analytics (2016)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Urchin Software Corporation, founded in 1995, evolved from building websites to developing web analytics software, leading to its acquisition by Google in 2005 and the creation of Google Analytics.</li>
<li>Key milestones include the development of the first log analyzer, rebranding in 2001, and achieving cashflow positivity by 2003 despite financial struggles.</li>
<li>Google Analytics, launched in November 2005, quickly became a dominant web analytics tool, with the Urchin team integrating into Google and continuing to enhance the product.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://urchin.biz/urchin-software-corp-89a1f5292999</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZUrchin Software Corp: The unlikely origin story of Google Analytics (2016)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building a highly-available web service without a database]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article proposes a novel architecture for building web services without traditional databases, leveraging advancements in RAM, disk storage, and the Raft Consensus algorithm.</li>
<li>For startups, using RAM as a database simplifies architecture, speeds up data retrieval, and eases debugging, with periodic snapshots and transaction logs for crash recovery.</li>
<li>High availability and scalability are achieved through the Raft Consensus Protocol for replication and sharding for clustering, as demonstrated by Screenshotbot&#39;s use of Common Lisp, BKNR Datastore, and EFS.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://blog.screenshotbot.io/2024/08/10/building-a-highly-available-web-service-without-a-database/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZBuilding a highly-available web service without a database</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DARPA wants to bypass the thermal middleman in nuclear power systems]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DARPA is investigating direct energy conversion from nuclear power, bypassing traditional steam turbines, to convert radiation directly into electricity.</li>
<li>This initiative could transform nuclear power systems, from small batteries to large grid-scale plants, driven by advancements in radiation-tolerant materials and small nuclear technologies.</li>
<li>DARPA aims to develop efficient, durable radiovoltaics for diverse applications, including space missions, with responses to their request for information due by August 30.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.ans.org/news/article-6276/darpa-wants-to-bypass-the-thermal-middleman-in-nuclear-power-systems/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZDARPA wants to bypass the thermal middleman in nuclear power systems</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ladybird browser to start using Swift language this fall]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Ladybird Browser team is considering Swift as a potential successor to C++ for their project.</li>
<li>Andreas Kling has been testing various languages by having contributors rewrite parts of the project in different languages over the past few months.</li>
<li>Swift has emerged as the most suitable option among the evaluated languages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/awesomekling/status/1822236888188498031</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZLadybird browser to start using Swift language this fall</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenSnitch is a GNU/Linux interactive application firewall]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenSnitch is a GNU/Linux application firewall offering features like interactive outbound connections filtering, system-wide ad/tracker/malware blocking, and GUI-based system firewall configuration.</li>
<li>It supports managing multiple nodes and Security Information and Event Management (SIEM) integration, making it a robust tool for network security.</li>
<li>The project has gained attention from notable publications such as PenTest Magazine, It&#39;s Foss, and Linux Format, highlighting its relevance and utility in the tech community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/evilsocket/opensnitch</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZOpenSnitch is a GNU/Linux interactive application firewall</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Susan Wojcicki has died]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Dennis Troper announced the passing of his wife, Susan Wojcicki, after a 2-year battle with non-small cell lung cancer.</li>
<li>Susan Wojcicki, married to Dennis for 26 years and mother of five, was remembered as a brilliant mind and loving mother.</li>
<li>The family is heartbroken but thankful for the time they had with her, with friends and family offering condolences and support.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.facebook.com/share/p/qe2ZMcs9Bz4K1SPt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZSusan Wojcicki has died</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rivian reduced electrical wiring by 1.6 miles and 44 pounds]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Rivian has introduced its second-generation R1T pickup and R1S SUV, featuring a new zonal electrical architecture that reduces wiring by 1.6 miles and weight by 44 pounds.</li>
<li>The new system, developed in-house, simplifies software and hardware, cuts material costs by 20%, and reduces the carbon footprint by 15%.</li>
<li>The switch from domain-based to zonal architecture consolidates functions into fewer, more powerful ECUs, enhancing scalability and reducing complexity, positioning Rivian for growth, including a joint venture with Volkswagen.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.popsci.com/technology/rivian-zonal-electrical-architecture/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZRivian reduced electrical wiring by 1.6 miles and 44 pounds</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deep Live Cam: Real-time face swapping and one-click video deepfake tool]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Deep Live Cam is an advanced AI tool for real-time face swapping and video deepfakes, requiring only a single image for high-quality results.</li>
<li>It supports multiple platforms, including CPU, NVIDIA CUDA, and Apple Silicon, and features ethical safeguards to prevent misuse.</li>
<li>The tool is open-source, offers instant previews, and is optimized for faster processing, making it accessible for both personal and commercial use.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://deeplive.cam</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZDeep Live Cam: Real-time face swapping and one-click video deepfake tool</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Caltech Develops First Noninvasive Method to Continually Measure Blood Pressure]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Caltech team has developed a noninvasive method called resonance sonomanometry to continually measure true blood pressure using sound waves and ultrasound imaging.</li>
<li>The device, tested in a small clinical study, produced results comparable to standard blood pressure cuffs and can be used in various settings, including hospitals and remote locations.</li>
<li>The new device, developed by Esperto Medical, is small, inexpensive, and offers continuous monitoring, potentially replacing traditional blood pressure cuffs and improving medication dosing precision.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.caltech.edu/about/news/caltech-team-develops-first-noninvasive-method-to-continually-measure-true-blood-pressure</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZCaltech Develops First Noninvasive Method to Continually Measure Blood Pressure</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grace Hopper, Nvidia's Halfway APU]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nvidia and AMD are leading the high-performance GPU market, with AMD leveraging its CPU capabilities to compete effectively.</li>
<li>Nvidia&#39;s new Grace Hopper (GH200) combines a server-level CPU with its top-tier H100 datacenter GPU, featuring 72 Neoverse V2 cores, 480 GB of LPDDR5X memory, and 96 GB of HBM3 memory.</li>
<li>GH200 aims to compete with AMD’s MI300A, showcasing Nvidia&#39;s strong entry into the CPU/GPU integration space, despite some performance issues and system instability during testing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chipsandcheese.com/2024/07/31/grace-hopper-nvidias-halfway-apu/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZGrace Hopper, Nvidia&apos;s Halfway APU</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hal Hickel on Creating Tarkin for Rogue One]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hal Hickel, Animation Supervisor for &quot;Rogue One,&quot; detailed the creation process of the digital character Grand Moff Tarkin, clarifying misconceptions about its CGI.</li>
<li>The process involved filming an actor, Guy Henry, in costume and replacing his head with a CG Tarkin head, using facial performance capture and a life cast of Peter Cushing’s face.</li>
<li>This explanation highlights the intricate work of many artists and technicians at ILM (Industrial Light &amp; Magic) to achieve a realistic digital human character, which many viewers did not realize was CGI.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://fxrant.blogspot.com/2024/06/hal-hickel-on-creating-tarkin.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZHal Hickel on Creating Tarkin for Rogue One</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larry Wall's Very Own Home Page]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Larry Wall, the creator of the Perl programming language, has a personal website under construction, sharing his interests and personal updates.</li>
<li>Wall&#39;s site includes links to his notable talks, such as the &quot;State of the Onion&quot; addresses at Perl Conferences and his views on Perl as a postmodern computer language.</li>
<li>He provides updates on his personal life, including a diary about his cornea transplant, and offers resources and recommendations related to Perl and other software tools.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://wall.org/%7Elarry/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-10T00:00:00.000ZLarry Wall&apos;s Very Own Home Page</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jake Seliger has died]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/08/jake-seliger-is-dead.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZJake Seliger has died</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OTranscribe: A free and open tool for transcribing audio interviews]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>oTranscribe is a free web app that simplifies transcribing recorded interviews, designed for desktop use with keyboard controls for pausing, rewinding, and fast-forwarding.</li>
<li>The app includes features like interactive timestamps, automatic saving, and privacy by keeping files on your computer, and allows exporting transcripts to Markdown, plain text, and Google Docs.</li>
<li>It supports video files, is open source under the MIT license, and was created by Elliot Bentley, featured by the MuckRock Foundation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://otranscribe.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZOTranscribe: A free and open tool for transcribing audio interviews</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[USPS text scammers duped his wife, so he hacked their operation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A person, referred to as s1n, retaliated against scammers by exploiting vulnerabilities in their fake USPS site using tools like nmap and Burp Suite.</li>
<li>S1n identified a Local File Inclusion (LFI) exploit and an SQL injection vulnerability, gaining access to the scammers&#39; database and revealing admin and victim details.</li>
<li>The original poster plans to report the findings to internet crime authorities, highlighting the ethical considerations and potential legal implications of hacking back.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.smithsecurity.biz/hacking-the-scammers</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZUSPS text scammers duped his wife, so he hacked their operation</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Recent Performance Improvements in Function Calls in CPython]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Recent optimizations in CPython have significantly improved the performance of function calls, built-ins, and inlining, making Python faster and more efficient.</li>
<li>Key improvements include the introduction of super instructions, bytecode instruction specialization, and the vectorcall method for built-ins.</li>
<li>Benchmarks show notable performance gains in simple computations, calling built-in functions, and reducing Python function call overhead.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.codingconfessions.com/p/are-function-calls-still-slow-in-python</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZRecent Performance Improvements in Function Calls in CPython</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel's Immiseration]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thechipletter.substack.com/p/intels-immiseration</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZIntel&apos;s Immiseration</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple is America's semiconductor problem]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The 2022 CHIPS Act was introduced to bring semiconductor chip fabrication back to the US, addressing the dependency on international supply chains exposed by Covid-era shortages.</li>
<li>In 1990, the US produced 37% of the world&#39;s chips, but this dropped to 12% by 2020, with Apple playing a significant role in this decline by pushing production to East Asia.</li>
<li>Despite some efforts to source chips domestically, Apple continues to rely heavily on foreign suppliers, and the Department of Justice is investigating its monopolistic practices to support the CHIPS Act&#39;s goals.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/apple-is-americas-semiconductor-problem/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZApple is America&apos;s semiconductor problem</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic Pi: Ruby as a Composition Tool]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Sonic Pi is a software synthesizer controlled by code, created by Sam Aaron, that uses a domain-specific language extending Ruby to map music and audio concepts.</li>
<li>The tool allows users to compose music by writing code, making it a unique intersection of programming and audio engineering, ideal for those with interests in both fields.</li>
<li>Sonic Pi supports advanced features like parallel execution with <code>in_thread</code> and continuous loops with <code>live_loop</code>, enabling complex musical compositions through coding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bhmt.dev/blog/sonic_pi/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZSonic Pi: Ruby as a Composition Tool</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Startup CEO Says VC Firm Punished Her for Reporting Sex Assault]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-08-08/startup-ceo-says-vc-firm-punished-her-for-reporting-sex-assault</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZStartup CEO Says VC Firm Punished Her for Reporting Sex Assault</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LLM Aided OCR (Correcting Tesseract OCR Errors with LLMs)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A project initially using Llama2 to improve Tesseract OCR has evolved with the availability of faster, affordable models like OpenAI&#39;s GPT4o-mini and Anthropic&#39;s Claude3-Haiku.</li>
<li>The new models enable efficient, cost-effective document processing by breaking text into chunks and using a multi-stage correction process, significantly improving OCR error correction and text reformatting.</li>
<li>The project demonstrates impressive results in converting old scanned books into readable formats, showing potential for further improvements in the coming year.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Dicklesworthstone/llm_aided_ocr</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZLLM Aided OCR (Correcting Tesseract OCR Errors with LLMs)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[National Park Service Will Cite AWD Drivers for Driving on 4WD-Only Trails]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Subaru Crosstrek owner received a warning for driving on a 4WD-only road in Canyonlands National Park, highlighting the difference between AWD and 4WD.</li>
<li>AWD is suitable for light off-roading but lacks the off-road traction of 4WD systems with locking differentials, which are necessary for challenging trails.</li>
<li>The National Park Service enforces these restrictions to ensure visitor safety, with penalties for violations including fines up to $5,000 and imprisonment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jalopnik.com/national-park-service-will-cite-drivers-of-awd-cars-for-1851617315</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZNational Park Service Will Cite AWD Drivers for Driving on 4WD-Only Trails</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SQLite FTS5 Extension]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SQLite&#39;s FTS5 (Full-Text Search 5) extension provides advanced full-text search capabilities for database applications, allowing efficient searches across large document collections.</li>
<li>FTS5 supports various query types, including prefix queries, NEAR queries, and boolean operators, enhancing search flexibility and precision.</li>
<li>The extension can be built as part of SQLite or as a loadable extension, offering developers multiple integration options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sqlite.org/fts5.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZSQLite FTS5 Extension</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forest Service orders Arrowhead bottled water to shut down California pipeline]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The U.S. Forest Service has ordered BlueTriton Brands to cease water extraction operations in the San Bernardino Mountains after denying their permit application.</li>
<li>Environmental activists claim the operations have harmed the environment, leading to a lawsuit, while BlueTriton disputes these claims and has challenged the decision in court.</li>
<li>The Forest Service&#39;s order includes removing all infrastructure from federal land, but BlueTriton has secured a temporary stay to continue supplying water to the San Manuel Band of Mission Indians.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.latimes.com/environment/story/2024-08-07/arrowhead-bottled-water-permit</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZForest Service orders Arrowhead bottled water to shut down California pipeline</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Base 3 Computing Beats Binary]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Base 3 computing, or ternary, uses three digits (0, 1, 2) and is more efficient than binary, as two ternary &quot;trits&quot; can represent nine numbers compared to four numbers by two binary bits.</li>
<li>Ternary computing has a lower radix economy for large numbers, making it the most economical integer base, and can answer questions with three possible outcomes, reducing the number of queries needed.</li>
<li>Despite its efficiency, ternary computing never gained widespread use due to the dominance of binary hardware and software, but recent advancements suggest potential applications in cybersecurity with lower error rates.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/how-base-3-computing-beats-binary-20240809/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZBase 3 Computing Beats Binary</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Non-Smart AI Pendant (NotFriend)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The NotFriend is a plastic circle that serves no functional purpose but is marketed as a fashion accessory.</li>
<li>It boasts features like unparalleled simplicity, timeless design, and eco-friendliness, making it a unique conversation starter.</li>
<li>The product is humorously presented with customer reviews and a lifetime warranty, emphasizing its novelty and non-functional nature.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://notfriend.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZThe First Non-Smart AI Pendant (NotFriend)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GPUDrive: Data-driven, multi-agent driving simulation at 1M FPS]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GPUDrive is a GPU-accelerated simulator built on the Madrona Game Engine, capable of generating over a million steps per second for multi-agent learning algorithms.</li>
<li>It uses C++ and CUDA to optimize complex agent behaviors, significantly reducing the time required to train reinforcement learning agents using the Waymo Motion dataset.</li>
<li>The simulator achieves goal-reaching agents in minutes and generally capable agents in hours, with trained agents available in the code base for further research and development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.01584</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-09T00:00:00.000ZGPUDrive: Data-driven, multi-agent driving simulation at 1M FPS</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prevention of HIV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.science.org/content/blog-post/prevention-hiv</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZPrevention of HIV</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google and Meta struck secret ads deal to target teenagers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ft.com/content/b3bb80f4-4e01-4ce6-8358-f4f8638790f8</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZGoogle and Meta struck secret ads deal to target teenagers</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Says Boeing Starliner Astronauts May Fly Home on SpaceX in 2025]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NASA has acknowledged that Boeing&#39;s Starliner spacecraft issues may be more severe than initially thought, potentially requiring astronauts Suni Williams and Butch Wilmore to return to Earth on SpaceX&#39;s Crew Dragon in 2025.</li>
<li>The astronauts&#39; stay at the International Space Station (ISS) could extend into next year, with NASA considering launching the next Crew Dragon with only two astronauts to accommodate Williams and Wilmore for a six-month stay.</li>
<li>Boeing has faced multiple setbacks with the Starliner program, including a $125 million write-off, and NASA&#39;s decision on the matter is expected by mid-August, with the Crew Dragon launch delayed to no earlier than Sept. 24.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/07/science/boeing-starliner-nasa-spacex.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZNASA Says Boeing Starliner Astronauts May Fly Home on SpaceX in 2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RLHF is just barely RL]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) is the last significant phase in training large language models, coming after pretraining and supervised finetuning.</li>
<li>The critique suggests that RLHF scarcely meets the criteria to be considered true reinforcement learning.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/karpathy/status/1821277264996352246</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZRLHF is just barely RL</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Firefox Sidebar and Vertical tabs: try them out]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Firefox Nightly 131 introduces vertical tabs and a new sidebar experience, aimed at improving context-switching and multitasking.</li>
<li>Users can enable these features by updating to the latest Nightly, navigating to Settings &gt; Firefox Labs, and activating the Sidebar and Vertical tabs experiments.</li>
<li>The community is encouraged to test these features and provide feedback on Mozilla Connect, with web extension developers advised to check compatibility.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://blog.nightly.mozilla.org/2024/08/07/firefox-sidebar-and-vertical-tabs-try-them-out-in-nightly-firefox-labs-131/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZFirefox Sidebar and Vertical tabs: try them out</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I got almost all of my wishes granted with RP2350]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The RP2350 microcontroller addresses many limitations of its predecessor, the RP2040, including better core performance, more DMA channels, and enhanced PIO units.</li>
<li>Key features of the RP2350 include dual Cortex-M33F cores, stable overclocking at 300MHz, doubled RAM, and reliable QSPI PSRAM support.</li>
<li>The RP2350 was showcased in the DEFCON 32 badge project, highlighting its capabilities and suggesting it as a superior alternative to the STM32H7 series for better performance and reliability.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dmitry.gr/?r=06.%20Thoughts&amp;proj=11.%20RP2350</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZI got almost all of my wishes granted with RP2350</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Pico 2, our new $5 microcontroller board, on sale now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.raspberrypi.com/news/raspberry-pi-pico-2-our-new-5-microcontroller-board-on-sale-now/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZRaspberry Pi Pico 2, our new $5 microcontroller board, on sale now</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cosmic: A New Desktop Environment]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>COSMIC is a new software platform for designing user experiences with a modular desktop environment, currently in its first alpha release, COSMIC Epoch 1.</li>
<li>The platform is available for testing on Pop!_OS 24.04 LTS alpha and other Linux distributions, with a focus on customization and advanced functionality.</li>
<li>Key features include customizable panels, auto-tiling windows, enhanced theming, and independent applets, all written in Rust for stability and performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://system76.com/cosmic</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZCosmic: A New Desktop Environment</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GPT-4 LLM simulates people well enough to replicate social science experiments]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The demo showcases a tool that uses GPT-4o-mini to predict social science experimental results, specifically treatment effects on U.S. adults.</li>
<li>The tool is approximately 70-80% accurate in predicting the direction of contrasts between conditions, with a strong correlation (r = .85) between predicted and actual effect sizes.</li>
<li>Applications include intervention design, minimizing participant harm, pilot testing study materials, and predicting subgroup effects, though caution is advised due to potential biases.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.treatmenteffect.app/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZGPT-4 LLM simulates people well enough to replicate social science experiments</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How we found and fixed an eBPF Linux kernel vulnerability]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The blog discusses CVE-2023-2163, a newly discovered vulnerability in the eBPF (extended Berkeley Packet Filter) subsystem of the Linux kernel.</li>
<li>It details the discovery process, potential impacts, and the steps taken to fix the vulnerability, providing valuable insights for security professionals and developers.</li>
<li>This post is significant as it highlights ongoing efforts to secure the Linux kernel, a critical component in many systems, and emphasizes the importance of proactive vulnerability management.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://bughunters.google.com/blog/6303226026131456/a-deep-dive-into-cve-2023-2163-how-we-found-and-fixed-an-ebpf-linux-kernel-vulnerability</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZHow we found and fixed an eBPF Linux kernel vulnerability</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FlexAttention: The Flexibility of PyTorch with the Performance of FlashAttention]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FlexAttention is a new PyTorch API designed to simplify the implementation of various attention mechanisms in machine learning models, addressing the limitations of existing optimized implementations like FlashAttention.</li>
<li>It allows researchers to implement attention variants with minimal code, ensuring competitive performance without extra memory usage, and supports user-defined functions for modifying attention scores before softmax.</li>
<li>FlexAttention is available in PyTorch nightly releases and will be a prototype feature in version 2.5.0, with future improvements planned for performance and additional support features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pytorch.org/blog/flexattention/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZFlexAttention: The Flexibility of PyTorch with the Performance of FlashAttention</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Argdown, like Markdown for argument mapping]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Argdown v1.8.2 was released in February 2022, offering a simple syntax for complex argumentation, making it easy to write pros and cons like a Twitter message.</li>
<li>Argdown can be used within Markdown to create argument maps, which can be published as PDFs, embedded in webpages, or exported as images.</li>
<li>Tools for Argdown include a browser sandbox, a VS Code extension with live preview and syntax highlighting, and a command-line tool for custom processes and multiple exports.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://argdown.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZArgdown, like Markdown for argument mapping</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mistral Agents]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mistral AI announces advancements in model customization, allowing developers to tailor models like Mistral Large 2 and Codestral using base prompts, few-shot prompting, or fine-tuning with their own datasets.</li>
<li>An alpha release of Agents introduces models wrapped with additional context and instructions, enabling custom behaviors and workflows on Le Chat or API.</li>
<li>The stable version of the mistralai library, mistralai 1.0, is now available for Python and Typescript, enhancing usability and consistency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mistral.ai/news/build-tweak-repeat/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZMistral Agents</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The News Is Information Junk Food (2022)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author argues that reducing news consumption has significantly decreased their anxiety and freed up time for other interests, suggesting that modern news is more about entertainment than information.</li>
<li>They highlight that a few companies control most media, leading to biased stories focused on clicks and ad revenue, which can provoke emotional reactions and reinforce existing biases.</li>
<li>The author advocates for a selective approach to information consumption, emphasizing long-form reading and meaningful activities over the 24-hour news cycle to achieve a healthier mental state and more productive use of time.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chuck.is/news/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZThe News Is Information Junk Food (2022)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Employers used return-to-office to make workers quit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thehill.com/opinion/technology/4800828-office-mandates-cause-attrition/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-08T00:00:00.000ZEmployers used return-to-office to make workers quit</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Medieval]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Teenage Engineering has announced new products for August 2024, including audio &amp; synthesizers and wireless speakers.</li>
<li>The company emphasizes high-quality, functional designs using advanced engineering to enhance music enjoyment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://teenage.engineering/products/ep-1320</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZMedieval</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Please do not attempt to simplify this code]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Kubernetes PersistentVolume (PV) controller code is intentionally verbose and follows a &quot;space shuttle style&quot; to ensure every condition is accounted for, similar to NASA&#39;s coding practices.</li>
<li>This design emphasizes the bi-directional relationship between PersistentVolumes (PVs) and PersistentVolumeClaims (PVCs), which is crucial for maintaining consistent behavior in a transactionless system.</li>
<li>The code includes detailed comments and explicit branches to help future maintainers understand the complexities of the binding behavior, ensuring robust and reliable volume management.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/blob/60c4c2b2521fb454ce69dee737e3eb91a25e0535/pkg/controller/volume/persistentvolume/pv_controller.go</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZPlease do not attempt to simplify this code</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How French Drains Work]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Oroville Dam spillway damage in 2017 highlighted the importance of effective drainage systems to prevent structural damage from water pressure.</li>
<li>French drains, named after Henry French, are subsurface systems using gravel-filled trenches and perforated pipes to manage water flow and prevent soil erosion.</li>
<li>Properly designed French drains use filters like geotextile fabric to prevent clogging and are crucial for structures such as dams, retaining walls, and agricultural fields.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://practical.engineering/blog/2024/8/6/how-french-drains-work</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZHow French Drains Work</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I've spent nearly 5y on a web app that creates 3D apartments]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The showcase highlights the creation of stunning visualizations for homes and offices, including interactive spaces, 3D plans, images, video tours, and AI interior design.</li>
<li>The fast 3D technology is compatible with most mobile and VR devices, enhancing accessibility and user experience.</li>
<li>A &quot;Try It Out&quot; feature is coming soon, indicating upcoming interactive opportunities for users to engage with the technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://roometron.com</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZI&apos;ve spent nearly 5y on a web app that creates 3D apartments</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[70% of new NPM packages in last 6 months were spam]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In April 2024, the Phylum Research Team identified a surge of spam packages in npm linked to the Tea protocol, which rewards developers in cryptocurrency for open-source contributions.</li>
<li>Approximately 70% of new npm packages published between February and August 2024 were identified as Tea-related spam, posing risks such as skewed AI training and obscured malicious packages.</li>
<li>Despite efforts by the Tea protocol and npm to address the issue, the rate of spam package publication remains high, prompting ongoing research and mitigation efforts by Phylum.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.phylum.io/the-great-npm-garbage-patch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-07T00:00:00.000Z70% of new NPM packages in last 6 months were spam</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YC is doing a first ever Fall batch – applications due by 8/27]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Y Combinator (YC) has opened applications for its Fall 2024 batch, with a deadline of 8/27 at 9 PM PT.</li>
<li>The Fall 2024 batch starts on 9/29 in San Francisco, offering a $500,000 investment and over $1M in exclusive credits from partners like Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure, and AWS.</li>
<li>This batch aims to meet the growing opportunities for startups, with fewer companies but similar terms to other batches; Winter 2025 applications will open in early October.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ycombinator.com/blog/yc-fall-2024#</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZYC is doing a first ever Fall batch – applications due by 8/27</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Uber tests payments in production]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Uber tests its payment systems directly in production to catch unknown issues quickly, a method that contrasts with the more common use of staging environments.</li>
<li>This approach involves incremental rollouts in small, representative regions and uses tools like Cerberus and Deputy for transparency and monitoring.</li>
<li>Uber&#39;s strategy focuses on resilience and quick rollbacks, ensuring high-quality software by addressing real-world issues, as demonstrated by their successful GooglePay rollout in Portugal.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.alvaroduran.com/p/cringey-but-true-how-uber-tests-payments</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZHow Uber tests payments in production</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BudgetFlow – Budget planning using interactive Sankey diagrams]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>BudgetFlow is a new app in beta that helps users manage their budgets visually using flow charts, specifically sankey diagrams.</li>
<li>Features include Smart Pockets for automatic cash transfers, and Shared Budgets for collaboration, making it easier to manage finances with others.</li>
<li>The app allows users to create and visualize budgets on various time scales (daily, weekly, monthly, yearly) and categorize expenses and income sources.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.budgetflow.cc/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZBudgetFlow – Budget planning using interactive Sankey diagrams</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Carvings at Gobekli Tepe may be oldest calendar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/1751696X.2024.2373876#abstract</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZCarvings at Gobekli Tepe may be oldest calendar</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MNT Pocket Reform first impressions and hardware]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The MNT Pocket Reform is a 7-inch portable Linux system with open hardware, designed for hackers and tinkerers.</li>
<li>It features a solid construction, ortholinear keyboard, responsive trackball, and various ports, including USB-C and micro-HDMI.</li>
<li>Despite some issues like a problematic NVMe SSD and corrupted uboot, the open-source community has been supportive, making it a promising device for further exploration.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://andypiper.co.uk/2024/08/06/mnt-pocket-reform-first-impressions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZMNT Pocket Reform first impressions and hardware</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jeremy Rowley resigns from DigiCert due to mass-revocation incident]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DigiCert identified a DNS-based validation issue with CNAME records lacking an underscore prefix, potentially leading to certificate mis-issuance, affecting 83,267 certificates and 6,807 subscribers.</li>
<li>The root cause was a system update error due to siloed teams and insufficient compliance checks; immediate actions included revoking all affected certificates and planning to open-source their domain validation system.</li>
<li>As a result, DigiCert&#39;s compliance head resigned, and a task force was established to enhance technical compliance controls.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1910322</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZJeremy Rowley resigns from DigiCert due to mass-revocation incident</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tony Hawk's Pro Strcpy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post details Ryan Miceli&#39;s journey in hacking the original Xbox using game save exploits, focusing on Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 4 to achieve code execution through buffer overflows.</li>
<li>It describes the progression from local exploits to remote code execution and the development of the first software-only exploit for the Xbox 360, showcasing the impact of a single bug across multiple platforms.</li>
<li>The post highlights the educational value of these exploits, with full source code and patched game save files available on GitHub, emphasizing the importance of understanding older security vulnerabilities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://icode4.coffee/?p=954</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZTony Hawk&apos;s Pro Strcpy</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD Ryzen 5 9600X and Ryzen 7 9700X Offer Excellent Linux Performance]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>AMD is launching the Ryzen 5 9600X and Ryzen 7 9700X, which show significant performance improvements, especially in single-threaded Linux workloads.</li>
<li>These Zen 5 processors outperform Intel&#39;s 14th Gen Core CPUs across nearly 400 benchmarks and are competitively priced at $279 USD and $359 USD, respectively.</li>
<li>Despite minor issues like the lack of mainlined RAPL/PowerCap sysfs monitoring and delayed compiler support in LLVM/Clang, the overall Linux performance and support for the Ryzen 9000 series are excellent.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.phoronix.com/review/ryzen-9600x-9700x</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZAMD Ryzen 5 9600X and Ryzen 7 9700X Offer Excellent Linux Performance</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to let go: Jake's life ends as his daughter's begins]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jakeseliger.com/2024/08/06/how-to-let-go-one-life-ends-while-another-begins/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZHow to let go: Jake&apos;s life ends as his daughter&apos;s begins</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gear Acquisition Syndrome]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://library.oapen.org/handle/20.500.12657/48282</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-07T00:00:00.000ZGear Acquisition Syndrome</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ending production of Chromecast]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Chromecast, a popular streaming device, is ending production after 11 years and over 100 million units sold.</li>
<li>Google is introducing the Google TV Streamer, a premium device aimed at modern entertainment and smart home integration, marking a transition from Chromecast.</li>
<li>Chromecast&#39;s legacy includes its 2013 launch and the 2020 introduction of Chromecast with Google TV, highlighting its impact on TV streaming technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.google/products/google-nest/chromecast-history/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZEnding production of Chromecast</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Salt]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jakeseliger.com/2024/08/05/no-salt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZNo Salt</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI co-founder John Schulman says he will leave and join rival Anthropic]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenAI co-founder John Schulman is leaving the company to join Anthropic, an AI startup funded by Amazon, to focus on AI alignment.</li>
<li>Schulman, who played a key role in refining models for OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT, emphasized that his departure was not due to a lack of support at OpenAI.</li>
<li>This move is part of a broader trend of key figures leaving OpenAI, including the temporary exit of co-founder Greg Brockman, amid significant changes at the company.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/06/openai-co-founder-john-schulman-says-he-will-join-rival-anthropic.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI co-founder John Schulman says he will leave and join rival Anthropic</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can we stop the decline of monarch butterflies and other pollinators?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Monarch butterflies and other pollinators in Wisconsin are experiencing a significant decline, as observed by conservationists and researchers.</li>
<li>Factors contributing to this decline include extreme weather, habitat loss, predators, droughts, climate change, and insecticides, with a study from Michigan State University emphasizing the impact of insecticides.</li>
<li>The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service recommends planting native flowers, reducing pesticide use, and creating pollinator-friendly environments to support these essential species.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.wisfarmer.com/story/news/2024/08/05/can-we-stop-the-decline-of-monarch-butterflies-and-other-pollinators/74638545007/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZCan we stop the decline of monarch butterflies and other pollinators?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Soul of Maintaining a New Machine]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In the 1980s, Xerox technicians relied on social interactions and storytelling to maintain complex photocopiers, as formal documentation was insufficient.</li>
<li>Anthropologist Julian Orr&#39;s study led to the Eureka project, a database for sharing tips among technicians, which improved service efficiency and fostered a community of practice.</li>
<li>Despite Eureka&#39;s success in France and Canada, Xerox struggled to integrate this informal knowledge into broader company practices, missing a chance to reorient towards service.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://books.worksinprogress.co/book/maintenance-of-everything/communities-of-practice/the-soul-of-maintaining-a-new-machine/1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZThe Soul of Maintaining a New Machine</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Debugging a rustc segfault on Illumos]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Oxide uses Helios, an illumos-based OS, for their cloud computers, and recently debugged a segmentation fault in the Rust compiler on illumos.</li>
<li>The crash occurred during the stage 0 build process of the Rust standard library, specifically in the cranelift-codegen component, due to stacker library&#39;s inability to detect stack size on illumos.</li>
<li>Key takeaways include the need for better stack size detection in stacker on illumos, improved error reporting, and the collaborative effort in debugging using illumos tools like coreadm and mdb.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sunshowers.io/posts/rustc-segfault-illumos/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZDebugging a rustc segfault on Illumos</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[X is closing San Francisco HQ and relocating staffers to San Jose]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>X, formerly known as Twitter, is closing its San Francisco headquarters and relocating staff to San Jose and a shared space with x.AI in Palo Alto, as per a leaked email from CEO Linda Yaccarino.</li>
<li>The San Francisco office, Twitter&#39;s global HQ since 2012, will be closed in the coming weeks, aligning with Elon Musk&#39;s earlier hints of a potential move to Texas.</li>
<li>This relocation is part of a broader strategy to establish new primary locations in the Bay Area, amidst San Francisco&#39;s ongoing challenges to rejuvenate its downtown and commercial real estate market.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://fortune.com/2024/08/05/x-closing-san-francisco-hq-relocating-staffers-san-jose-palo-alto-shared-space-with-x-ai-linda-yaccarino-leaked-email/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZX is closing San Francisco HQ and relocating staffers to San Jose</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building rqlite 9.0: Cutting disk usage by half]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>rqlite 9.0, an open-source distributed relational database, aims to cut disk usage by 50% through a high-level design overhaul.</li>
<li>The new design, called Referential Snapshotting, eliminates the need to store a snapshotted copy of the working SQLite database, reducing disk usage and improving efficiency.</li>
<li>This update will also bring faster snapshotting and node restart times, with further details on SQLite Write-Ahead Log (WAL) management and seamless upgrades to follow.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.philipotoole.com/building-rqlite-9-0-cutting-disk-usage-by-half/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZBuilding rqlite 9.0: Cutting disk usage by half</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Structured Outputs in the API]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openai.com/index/introducing-structured-outputs-in-the-api/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Structured Outputs in the API</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WordStar 7, the last ever DOS version, is re-released for free]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>WordStar 7, the last DOS version of the word processor, has been re-released for free by Canadian science fiction writer Robert J Sawyer.</li>
<li>This version, used by notable authors like Arthur C Clarke and George R R Martin, includes DOS emulators (DOSbox-X and vDosPlus) for compatibility with modern Windows systems.</li>
<li>Despite being last updated in 1992 and considered abandonware, WordStar remains popular among writers for its simplicity and functionality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2024/08/06/wordstar_7_the_last_ever/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZWordStar 7, the last ever DOS version, is re-released for free</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twitter kills its San Francisco headquarters, will relocate to South Bay]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Business X is closing its San Francisco headquarters and relocating employees to the South Bay, with engineering staff moving to Palo Alto and other employees to San Jose&#39;s Santana Row.</li>
<li>The decision follows Elon Musk&#39;s 2022 acquisition, which resulted in mass layoffs and a shift to full-time office work.</li>
<li>The company is also subleasing its Mid-Market offices, marking the end of an era for the area that had benefited from special tax incentives to attract tech companies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://sfstandard.com/2024/08/05/x-officially-kills-its-san-francisco-headquarters-will-relocate-workers-to-south-bay/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZTwitter kills its San Francisco headquarters, will relocate to South Bay</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dell lays off 12,500 people]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Dell has initiated significant layoffs, affecting approximately 12,500 employees, reducing its workforce from 120,000 to below 100,000.</li>
<li>The company states the layoffs are part of a reorganization to become leaner and focus on modern IT and AI, with many positions cut from the sales division.</li>
<li>Severance packages include two months&#39; wages plus a week per year served, and some employees suspect the return-to-office mandate is a stealth layoff.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2024/08/06/dell_layoffs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZDell lays off 12,500 people</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Replacing Liquid Metal on an Asus Zephyrus G15's CPU]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Asus ROG Zephyrus G15, a gaming laptop, uses a thermal interface material (TIM) for cooling, with recent models incorporating liquid metal TIM for better performance.</li>
<li>Liquid metal TIM, while effective, is electrically conductive and can move, posing risks; Asus mitigates this with a silicone seal and foam barrier.</li>
<li>Replacing the liquid metal TIM with Honeywell’s PTM7950 phase-change TIM, which is solid at room temperature and liquifies at operating temperature, resolved thermal throttling issues and improved cooling performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flemesre.github.io/posts/liquid-metal-replacement/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZReplacing Liquid Metal on an Asus Zephyrus G15&apos;s CPU</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I built a simple, open-source tool to manage servers and SSH keys]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Viking is a tool designed for simple remote machine management, particularly for bare metal servers, offering full control and freedom.</li>
<li>Key features include managing SSH keys, executing shell commands, and handling machine configurations, all through a command-line interface.</li>
<li>The tool is available for installation on Unix and Windows systems, and it supports custom configuration directories and SSH key management.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/d3witt/viking</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZI built a simple, open-source tool to manage servers and SSH keys</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Writing a tile server in Python]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Developed a tileset based on OpenStreetMap data, optimized for batch rendering using a modified &quot;generate_tiles&quot; script.</li>
<li>Implemented a Master thread and rendering threads to manage rendering tasks, queues, and cache usage efficiently.</li>
<li>Created a non-blocking loop using Python&#39;s selector API to handle client connections and rendering jobs, supporting multiple clients and efficient rendering.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.grulic.org.ar/~mdione/glob/posts/writing-a-tile-server-in-python/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-06T00:00:00.000ZWriting a tile server in Python</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starting Hospice]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jakeseliger.com/2024/08/04/starting-hospice-the-end/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZStarting Hospice</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stop Killing Games]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://eci.ec.europa.eu/045/public/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZStop Killing Games</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Free e-book about WebGPU Programming]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author has launched an e-book focused on Graphics/WebGPU programming, a significant resource for those interested in this field.</li>
<li>The project includes additional tools such as a code playground and a static site generator, enhancing the learning experience.</li>
<li>Despite challenges like burnout and the book feeling incomplete, the author decided to release it to avoid abandoning the project.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://shi-yan.github.io/webgpuunleashed/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZFree e-book about WebGPU Programming</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Postgres stores data on disk – this one's a page turner]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post aims to demystify database engines, specifically focusing on PostgreSQL, a popular database among developers.</li>
<li>It explains how PostgreSQL stores data on disk, detailing the structure and purpose of various directories and files within the data directory.</li>
<li>Key concepts such as Multiversion Concurrency Control (MVCC), heap storage, and the use of the pageinspect extension for inspecting data storage are discussed to help understand and optimize database performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://drew.silcock.dev/blog/how-postgres-stores-data-on-disk/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZHow Postgres stores data on disk – this one&apos;s a page turner</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How I Program in 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author reflects on their evolving programming practices from 2015 to 2024, highlighting a shift from heavy reliance on tests and version control to a more minimalist approach.</li>
<li>In 2024, the author deleted all tests and reworked their text editor without version control, resulting in a better program and challenging their previous beliefs about software development.</li>
<li>The author now advocates for building software with few dependencies and no auto-updates, using tools like types, abstractions, tests, and versions sparingly to avoid tech debt and complexity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://akkartik.name/post/programming-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZHow I Program in 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building Lego Machines to Destroy Tall Lego Towers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Brick Technology&#39;s new video showcases powerful Lego machines designed to topple tall Lego towers, emphasizing science, engineering, and the iterative process of trial and error.</li>
<li>The video highlights the application of these principles to any creative endeavor, making complex engineering concepts accessible and engaging.</li>
<li>The rapid progression from concept to execution in the video may inspire viewers to experiment with Lego Technic and Mindstorms kits themselves.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://kottke.org/24/07/building-lego-machines-to-destroy-tall-lego-towers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZBuilding Lego Machines to Destroy Tall Lego Towers</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Age is a simple, modern and secure file encryption tool, format, and Go library]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Age is a modern, secure file encryption tool and Go library, featuring small explicit keys, no configuration options, and UNIX-style composability.</li>
<li>It supports various installation methods across multiple operating systems, including Homebrew, MacPorts, and package managers for Linux distributions and Windows.</li>
<li>Age supports hardware PIV tokens like YubiKeys, passphrase-protected files, SSH keys, and even encrypting to a GitHub user, making it versatile for different encryption needs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/FiloSottile/age</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZAge is a simple, modern and secure file encryption tool, format, and Go library</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Andy Warhol's lost Amiga art found]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Andy Warhol’s lost digital art created on the Amiga 1000 in 1985 has resurfaced after 39 years and is now for sale.</li>
<li>The discovery includes a famous portrait of Debbie Harry and highlights Warhol&#39;s experimentation with digital techniques, despite his struggles with computer use.</li>
<li>This reemergence underscores the advanced graphics capabilities of the Amiga 1000 and marks a significant moment in the intersection of art and technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dfarq.homeip.net/andy-warhols-lost-amiga-art-found/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZAndy Warhol&apos;s lost Amiga art found</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Intelligence beta flagged a phishing email as "Priority"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://social.panic.com/@cabel/112905175504595751</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZApple Intelligence beta flagged a phishing email as &quot;Priority&quot;</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Puget Systems' Perspective on Intel CPU Instability Issues]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Intel Core 13th and 14th Gen desktop processors have been experiencing instability issues, potentially due to physical degradation, with some failure rates reported as high as 50%.</li>
<li>Intel plans to release a microcode patch by mid-August to prevent further degradation, though it won&#39;t reverse existing damage.</li>
<li>Puget Systems has experienced fewer issues due to their conservative power management approach and plans to validate Intel&#39;s update, extend warranties, and upgrade affected customers if necessary.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.pugetsystems.com/blog/2024/08/02/puget-systems-perspective-on-intel-cpu-instability-issues/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZPuget Systems&apos; Perspective on Intel CPU Instability Issues</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uncovered Euripides fragments are 'kind of a big deal']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>CU Boulder Classics scholars have discovered significant new fragments of two lost tragedies by the Greek playwright Euripides.</li>
<li>The fragments, from the plays Polyidus and Ino, were identified after months of study by Yvona Trnka-Amrhein and John Gibert.</li>
<li>This discovery, considered the most significant in over fifty years, will be presented at the Ninth Fountain Symposium on the CU Boulder campus.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.colorado.edu/asmagazine/2024/08/01/uncovered-euripides-fragments-are-kind-big-deal</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZUncovered Euripides fragments are &apos;kind of a big deal&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cortex A73's Not-So-Infinite Reordering Capacity]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Cortex A73 addresses power and thermal issues in Arm’s early 64-bit cores, focusing on efficiency and the smartphone CPU market.</li>
<li>A unique out-of-order retirement mechanism allows the CPU to calculate results without waiting for instruction execution confirmation, preserving the illusion of in-order execution.</li>
<li>The A73 can handle 50 in-flight loads but only 11 in-flight stores after an unresolved branch, showing a regression from A72, yet it achieves competitive performance at lower power by balancing IPC (Instructions Per Cycle) and clock speed.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chipsandcheese.com/2024/08/04/cortex-a73s-not-so-infinite-reordering-capacity/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZCortex A73&apos;s Not-So-Infinite Reordering Capacity</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zero regrets: Firefox power user kept 7,500 tabs open for two years]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A software engineer named Hazel managed to keep nearly 7,500 tabs open in Firefox for two years, showcasing the browser&#39;s capability to handle extensive tab usage.</li>
<li>Despite initial issues, Hazel restored her tabs using Firefox&#39;s profile cache, with the session file being only around 70MB, indicating minimal memory impact.</li>
<li>Mozilla confirmed that having many tabs open consumes &quot;practically no memory&quot; and announced upcoming tab management tools expected later in 2024, enhancing user experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techspot.com/news/102871-zero-regrets-firefox-power-user-kept-7500-tabs.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZZero regrets: Firefox power user kept 7,500 tabs open for two years</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japan stocks plunge as much as 7% as Asia shares extend sell-off]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Japan&#39;s Nikkei index had its worst day since the 1987 Black Monday crash, plummeting 12.4% and wiping out all gains for the year.</li>
<li>The yen surged to its highest level against the dollar since January, while the Topix index dropped 12.23%, and major trading houses like Mitsubishi and Mitsui faced significant losses.</li>
<li>South Korea&#39;s Kospi and Kosdaq also experienced sharp declines, falling 8.77% and 11.3%, respectively, triggering circuit breakers; investors are closely watching upcoming trade data from China and Taiwan, and central bank decisions from Australia and India.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/05/asia-markets.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZJapan stocks plunge as much as 7% as Asia shares extend sell-off</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japan's Nikkei Posts Biggest Single-Day Fall Since 1987 After Weak U.S. Data]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.wsj.com/finance/stocks/japan-stocks-fall-sharply-after-weak-u-s-jobs-data-yen-strengthening-3903689f</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-05T00:00:00.000ZJapan&apos;s Nikkei Posts Biggest Single-Day Fall Since 1987 After Weak U.S. Data</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open Source Farming Robot]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FarmBot offers a highly automated, easy-to-assemble gardening robot that simplifies growing food at home, in schools, and even in space.</li>
<li>It is used by over 500 educational institutions and organizations like NASA, promoting STEM education and innovative agricultural practices.</li>
<li>FarmBot models, Genesis and Genesis XL, provide sustainable food production with lower CO2 emissions and are designed for various scales, from individual to family needs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://farm.bot/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZOpen Source Farming Robot</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to build quickly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Outline speedrunning involves creating a detailed recursive outline, quickly filling it in, and perfecting it only after completion, which is significantly faster than traditional methods.</li>
<li>Key steps include making an outline, breaking down each item, filling them in rapidly, and refining details afterward, avoiding the common mistake of perfecting as you go.</li>
<li>This method is applicable to various tasks like writing and programming, enhancing both speed and quality by maintaining momentum and reducing stress.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://learnhowtolearn.org/how-to-build-extremely-quickly/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZHow to build quickly</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Make your electronics tamper-evident]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tamper-evident measures are essential to detect unauthorized physical access to electronic devices, protecting against &#39;evil maid&#39; attacks.</li>
<li>Techniques include using unique seals, glitter nail polish on screws, tamper-evident firmware like Heads and Auditor, and physical intrusion detection with apps like Haven.</li>
<li>Combining multiple layers of security, such as tamper-evident storage and video surveillance, significantly enhances device protection.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.anarsec.guide/posts/tamper/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZMake your electronics tamper-evident</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Porting My JavaScript Game Engine to C for No Reason]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>high_impact is a new 2D game engine written in C, inspired by the 2010 Impact JavaScript game engine, and supports multiple platforms including Windows, Mac, Linux, and WebAssembly (WASM).</li>
<li>The engine features comprehensive support for game development, including tile-maps, game objects, physics, collisions, animations, text, and sound, with a focus on simplicity and extensibility.</li>
<li>The project includes a port of the original Biolab Disaster game and an updated level editor, Weltmeister, showcasing the engine&#39;s capabilities and inviting contributions for further development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://phoboslab.org/log/2024/08/high_impact</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZPorting My JavaScript Game Engine to C for No Reason</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia reportedly delays its next AI chip due to a design flaw]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nvidia has delayed the production of its next AI chip, the &quot;Blackwell&quot; B200, due to a design flaw discovered late in the process.</li>
<li>The delay will push production back by at least three months, with large shipments now expected in the first quarter of next year.</li>
<li>Major tech companies like Microsoft, Google, and Meta have already placed significant orders, highlighting the high demand and importance of these AI chips.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/3/24212518/nvidia-ai-chip-delay-blackwell-b200-microsoft-amazon-google-openai-meta-artificial-intelligence</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZNvidia reportedly delays its next AI chip due to a design flaw</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How I Use "AI"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nicholas.carlini.com/writing/2024/how-i-use-ai.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZHow I Use &quot;AI&quot;</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega Jet Rocket: The '70s arcade game with no computer or screen]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Sega&#39;s Jet Rocket, released in 1970, was a pioneering arcade game that simulated flight and combat without using a computer or screen.</li>
<li>The game used a mechanical system involving a conveyor-belt-like canvas, mirrors, and lights to simulate rocket launches and detect hits.</li>
<li>Despite its initial popularity, unlicensed copies affected its sales in North America, and today, few functional units exist, with restored versions valued for their historical significance and mechanical ingenuity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://newatlas.com/games/sega-jet-rocket-arcade-game/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZSega Jet Rocket: The &apos;70s arcade game with no computer or screen</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can reading make you happier? (2015)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Bibliotherapy, the practice of using books for therapeutic purposes, has historical roots dating back to ancient Greece and gained prominence after World War I.</li>
<li>Research indicates that reading fiction can enhance empathy and social skills by stimulating brain regions associated with experiencing events firsthand.</li>
<li>Despite some skepticism about its real-life impact, bibliotherapy offers personal health benefits, such as reduced stress and improved sleep, and helps individuals navigate their reading choices for emotional comfort.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/can-reading-make-you-happier</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZCan reading make you happier? (2015)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TPU transformation: A look back at 10 years of our AI-specialized chips]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google has been at the forefront of AI and chip development for over a decade, leading to the creation of Tensor Processing Units (TPUs) to meet increasing AI compute demands.</li>
<li>TPUs, first deployed in 2015, have evolved significantly, with the latest generation, Trillium, enhancing power and efficiency for advanced AI models.</li>
<li>Google launched Cloud TPUs in 2018, enabling customers to accelerate AI workloads, with over 60% of funded generative AI startups now using Google Cloud’s AI infrastructure.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://cloud.google.com/blog/transform/ai-specialized-chips-tpu-history-gen-ai</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZTPU transformation: A look back at 10 years of our AI-specialized chips</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monetagium – monetary extortion in feudal Europe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Monetagium was a medieval practice where the public paid a fee to avoid the debasement of coinage, which would cause inflation and financial instability.</li>
<li>Introduced to England by William the Conqueror, it evolved into a triennial renewal of coinage, which was unpopular and eventually abolished by Henry I.</li>
<li>Similar practices existed in Denmark with the &quot;plough tax,&quot; and modern democracies face analogous revenue challenges, though they rely on taxes instead of debasement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://jpkoning.blogspot.com/2024/05/monetagium.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZMonetagium – monetary extortion in feudal Europe</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Untold Story of How US Spies Sabotaged Soviet Technology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2024/08/04/us-spies-soviet-technology-00164126</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZThe Untold Story of How US Spies Sabotaged Soviet Technology</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LLM as Database Administrator (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>D-Bot is a new system leveraging Large Language Models (LLMs) for database diagnosis, aimed at assisting Database Administrators (DBAs) by automating knowledge extraction and report generation.</li>
<li>The system includes advanced techniques such as offline knowledge extraction, automatic prompt generation, and root cause analysis using tree search, outperforming traditional methods and models like GPT-4.</li>
<li>Tested on real benchmarks, D-Bot can generate diagnosis reports within 10 minutes, showcasing its efficiency and effectiveness in handling complex database anomalies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.01454</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZLLM as Database Administrator (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Written by a 16 year old, a book on how computers work]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;RAM-a-thon&quot; is a guide aimed at simplifying the complexities of computers for users.</li>
<li>The author emphasizes the importance of understanding computer components, highlighting that CPUs are fundamentally made from sand.</li>
<li>The guide is a result of extensive research and aims to educate users who have used computers without fully understanding their workings.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/hackclub/RAM-a-thon</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZWritten by a 16 year old, a book on how computers work</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Evaluating a class of infinite sums in closed form]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post discusses evaluating a class of infinite sums in closed form, particularly when k is a non-negative integer and c is a rational number with |c| &gt; 1.</li>
<li>It introduces the polylogarithm function Lis(z) and explains that while evaluating Lis(z) in closed form is generally challenging, it is feasible when s is a negative integer.</li>
<li>The post provides an example where the sum equals Li−3(1/2), resulting in 26, and notes that the sum is always rational and occasionally an integer for specific values of c.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2024/08/03/polylog/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZEvaluating a class of infinite sums in closed form</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[USB Sniffer Lite for RP2040]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>USB Sniffer Lite for RP2040 is a simple USB sniffer based on the Raspberry Pi RP2040, supporting Low Speed and Full Speed modes, and requires no additional software.</li>
<li>It connects directly to MCU pins and can be set up using a UF2 file and the bin2uf2 tool, with detailed hardware connections and settings provided.</li>
<li>A dedicated board with an integrated FE8.1 USB HUB simplifies the setup, and various capture settings and commands are available for flexible usage.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ataradov/usb-sniffer-lite</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-04T00:00:00.000ZUSB Sniffer Lite for RP2040</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We ran out of columns]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Jimmy Miller&#39;s &quot;We ran out of columns&quot; describes his first software job&#39;s chaotic yet fascinating codebase, highlighting a database table called Merchants that ran out of columns, leading to the creation of Merchants2.</li>
<li>The codebase was a mix of VB, C#, various JavaScript frameworks, and numerous SOAP services, with notable issues like a developer not checking in code, causing hard-to-trace bugs.</li>
<li>Despite the messiness, the codebase allowed for creative problem-solving, with developers carving out their own solutions, leading to a decoupled system and a unique, direct connection with users.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jimmyhmiller.github.io/ugliest-beautiful-codebase</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZWe ran out of columns</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[p5.js]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The p5.js library offers a range of examples and community sketches to help users learn and explore its capabilities.</li>
<li>Notable projects include Geodata Weaving, Slime Molds, Generative Succulents, Padrão Geométrico, Zen Pots, and Glitch animation, showcasing the library&#39;s versatility.</li>
<li>Users can support the p5.js library through donations or by downloading it for their own use.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://p5js.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-03T00:00:00.000Zp5.js</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tauri 2.0 Release Candidate]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tauri 2.0 Release Candidate is announced, with a stable release expected by the end of August, focusing on finalizing documentation and fixing critical bugs.</li>
<li>Tauri 2.0 introduces foundational support for mobile development, though it does not yet match desktop feature parity, and includes breaking changes like a fixed namespace for core plugins and a Rust API refactor.</li>
<li>An external security audit has been completed with all issues fixed, and the full report will be published soon; the community is encouraged to contribute to documentation and issue resolution.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://v2.tauri.app/blog/tauri-2-0-0-release-candidate/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZTauri 2.0 Release Candidate</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The future of kdb+?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>kdb+ is a powerful technology for historical market data storage and analysis, but alternatives like Clickhouse, QuestDB, Bigquery, and Redshift are now competitive in speed.</li>
<li>For local quantitative analysis, Python with DuckDB, Polars, or PyKX is preferred due to accessibility and cost-effectiveness.</li>
<li>kdb+&#39;s real-time streaming and distributed computing capabilities are underutilized, with technologies like Kafka and Flink gaining more popularity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timestored.com/b/the-future-of-kdb/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZThe future of kdb+?</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hanon Pro – piano technique and exercises for the digital age]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hanon Pro is a modern piano practice app for iPhone, iPad, and Mac, offering features like progress tracking, feedback, and practice habit building.</li>
<li>Advanced functionalities include performance analysis, automatic page turning, and interactive features when connected to a MIDI keyboard via Bluetooth or USB.</li>
<li>The app supports iCloud sync, daily practice reminders, and achievements, and is built with SwiftUI and Core MIDI, compatible with iOS 17.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://furnacecreek.org/hanon/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZHanon Pro – piano technique and exercises for the digital age</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lisp with GC in 436 Bytes]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SectorLISP now includes garbage collection, fitting a high-level garbage collected programming language into the 512-byte boot sector of a floppy disk, using only 436 bytes.</li>
<li>This makes LISP the smallest programming language, surpassing FORTH and BASIC, and it is compatible with all PC models since 1981 with at least 64kb of RAM.</li>
<li>The project showcases significant optimization, reducing the i8086 assembly implementation by another hundred bytes, and includes a 40-byte garbage collector, with binaries and source code available on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://justine.lol/sectorlisp2/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZLisp with GC in 436 Bytes</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Made an Extended Version of Vimtutor – Introducing Vimtutor Sequel]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Vimtutor Sequel&quot; offers advanced Vim lessons, including commands, techniques, step-by-step tutorials, and interactive exercises.</li>
<li>Installation can be done via Homebrew or by cloning the repository from GitHub, with detailed instructions provided for both methods.</li>
<li>The tool is licensed under the MIT License, and contributions are welcomed as per the guidelines in CONTRIBUTING.md.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/micahkepe/vimtutor-sequel</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZI Made an Extended Version of Vimtutor – Introducing Vimtutor Sequel</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1991 WWW-NeXT Implementation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>This GitHub repository mirrors Tim Berners-Lee&#39;s original WorldWideWeb application for NeXT, showcasing the first prototype Hypertext browser/editor.</li>
<li>The application allows access to Hypertext servers, files, and news, providing a glimpse into the early web&#39;s functionality.</li>
<li>The repository includes a historic changelog, with commit dates backdated to the last-modified day for each file, preserving the original timeline.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/simonw/1991-WWW-NeXT-Implementation</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-03T00:00:00.000Z1991 WWW-NeXT Implementation</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Researchers develop treatment that can kill glioblastoma cells in brain pathway]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Researchers from McMaster University and other institutions have identified a new brain pathway used by glioblastoma cells and developed a promising therapy to block and kill these tumors.</li>
<li>The study, published in Nature Medicine on August 2, 2024, demonstrates that targeting this pathway with CAR T cells and a drug significantly improves survival in preclinical models.</li>
<li>The therapy, focusing on the ROBO1 protein, doubled survival time in three cancer models and eradicated tumors in 50% of cases for two of the diseases, offering hope for glioblastoma and other invasive brain cancers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-08-therapy-treatment-glioblastoma-cells-newly.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZResearchers develop treatment that can kill glioblastoma cells in brain pathway</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Common I/O Tasks in Modern Java]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article by Cay Horstmann discusses common I/O tasks in Java, particularly for web applications, such as reading/writing text files, handling JSON, and working with ZIP files.</li>
<li>It highlights API improvements since Java 8, including UTF-8 as the default encoding from Java 18 and enhancements to the <code>java.nio.file.Files</code> and <code>java.io.InputStream</code> classes.</li>
<li>The article provides practical code examples for reading and writing text files, handling input streams, and working with directories and ZIP files, emphasizing the use of modern <code>Files</code> methods over the legacy <code>File</code> class.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dev.java/learn/modernio/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZCommon I/O Tasks in Modern Java</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Judges suspends FCC net neutrality restoration rule]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.inc.com/bruce-crumley/judges-suspend-fcc-net-neutrality-restoration-rule.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZJudges suspends FCC net neutrality restoration rule</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magnetically levitated space elevator to low-earth orbit (2001) [pdf]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://publications.anl.gov/anlpubs/2001/07/39886.pdf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZMagnetically levitated space elevator to low-earth orbit (2001) [pdf]</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A year of Meta's news ban in Canada]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta&#39;s news ban in Canada, in response to Bill C-18, has led to an 85% drop in engagement for Canadian news outlets on Facebook and Instagram, resulting in an overall 43% decrease in engagement.</li>
<li>Approximately 30% of local news outlets have become inactive on social media, and only 22% of Canadians are aware of the ban.</li>
<li>Despite the ban, 36% of users still encounter news content through work-arounds, but Canadians are seeing 11 million fewer news views per day on these platforms, consuming less news overall and through a more biased lens.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.mediaecosystemobservatory.com/press-releases/old-news-new-reality-a-year-of-metas-news-ban-in-canada</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZA year of Meta&apos;s news ban in Canada</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Towards userspaceification of POSIX – part I: signal handling and IO]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Redox OS has received an NGI Zero grant to implement POSIX signal handling and process management in userspace, allowing a year-long focus on kernel and component improvements.</li>
<li>Enhancements in the scheme packet format and new syscalls (SYS_PREAD2 and SYS_PWRITE2) have increased RedoxFS copy performance by 63%, similar to the efficiency of io_uring.</li>
<li>The project aims to move more POSIX logic to userspace, with improvements in signal handling and future plans to develop a userspace process manager and further kernel enhancements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.redox-os.org/news/kernel-11/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZTowards userspaceification of POSIX – part I: signal handling and IO</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Primitive Recursive Functions for a Working Programmer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article emphasizes the importance of understanding Turing completeness and primitive recursive functions, often overlooked in computer science education.</li>
<li>It highlights that many practical problems can be implemented in non-Turing complete languages, which offer benefits like determinism and security.</li>
<li>The discussion includes the differences between Finite State Machines, Turing Machines, and Primitive Recursive Functions, noting that PRFs always terminate and can compute many practical functions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://matklad.github.io/2024/08/01/primitive-recursive-functions.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-03T00:00:00.000ZPrimitive Recursive Functions for a Working Programmer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CrowdStrike representatives issue trademark infringement notice to ClownStrike]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Clown Services Company, a parody site, faced a takedown notice from CrowdStrike, leading to CloudFlare removing the site.</li>
<li>The site owner argues that the DMCA is often misused by corporations to remove legal content, particularly parody, which is protected under Fair Use.</li>
<li>Despite the takedown, the site gained significant attention, making it to the top of Hacker News, highlighting issues with DMCA misuse and corporate influence.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://clownstrike.lol/crowdmad/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZCrowdStrike representatives issue trademark infringement notice to ClownStrike</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russ Cox is stepping down as the Go tech lead]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Russ Cox announced that Austin Clements will become the tech lead of the Go project starting September 1, with Cherry Mui assuming Austin&#39;s previous responsibilities.</li>
<li>Leadership changes are intended to bring fresh perspectives, with Russ Cox remaining involved as an individual contributor and focusing on new projects like Gaby and Oscar.</li>
<li>Community members expressed gratitude for Russ&#39;s leadership and suggested resuming compiler and runtime meeting notes and office hours for better transparency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://groups.google.com/g/golang-dev/c/0OqBkS2RzWw</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZRuss Cox is stepping down as the Go tech lead</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The upstream cause of the youth mental health crisis is the loss of community]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The youth mental health crisis is attributed to the weakening of real-world communities due to technological advancements, leading to increased loneliness and mental distress among youth.</li>
<li>Experts Jonathan Haidt and Zach Rausch highlight the decline in community and play-based childhood, alongside the rise of phone-based childhood, as significant factors.</li>
<li>Seth Kaplan stresses the importance of rebuilding strong local communities, emphasizing that real-world interactions offer support and security that virtual connections cannot.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.afterbabel.com/p/the-upstream-cause-of-the-youth-mental</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZThe upstream cause of the youth mental health crisis is the loss of community</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hackberry-Pi_Zero – A handheld Linux terminal using Raspberry Pi Zero 2W]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hackberry-Pi_Zero is a handheld Linux terminal built using a Raspberry Pi Zero 2W, featuring a 4&quot; 720x720 TFT display and a BlackBerry keyboard.</li>
<li>Key features include dual swappable Nokia BL-5C batteries, customizable keymap via VIAL, and support for multiple operating systems like Kali and Raspberry Pi OS.</li>
<li>The device offers 3 USB 2.0 ports, a Stemma I2C port, and a TF card slot, making it versatile for various applications.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ZitaoTech/Hackberry-Pi_Zero</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZHackberry-Pi_Zero – A handheld Linux terminal using Raspberry Pi Zero 2W</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Peerfetch – Peer-to-Peer HTTP over WebRTC]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Peerfetch is a peer-to-peer HTTP solution over WebRTC, allowing direct, secure access from web browsers to edge devices behind firewalls.</li>
<li>It features end-to-end encryption, requires no custom VPN setup, cloud middleman, dynamic DNS service, or custom firewall rules, and is available in JavaScript and Python.</li>
<li>Use cases include direct access to private home security cameras, IoT device mesh communication, personal web apps sharing data without a public IP, and federated learning with local user data.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ambianic/peerfetch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZPeerfetch – Peer-to-Peer HTTP over WebRTC</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YC closes deal with Google for dedicated compute cluster for AI startups]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google Cloud is providing Y Combinator startups with access to a dedicated, subsidized cluster of Nvidia GPUs and Google TPUs to develop AI models.</li>
<li>The initiative includes $350,000 in cloud credits over two years and additional support, aiming to attract early-stage AI startups to Google Cloud.</li>
<li>This partnership seeks to build long-term relationships with startups, addressing common issues like limited compute resources and aligning with trends of accelerators and VCs offering GPU clusters to attract AI startups.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/01/google-cloud-now-has-a-dedicated-cluster-of-nvidia-gpus-for-y-combinator-startups/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZYC closes deal with Google for dedicated compute cluster for AI startups</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marshmallow Test Fails to Replicate]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://srcd.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cdev.14129</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZMarshmallow Test Fails to Replicate</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Null-Restricted and Nullable Types]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bugs.openjdk.org/browse/JDK-8303099</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZNull-Restricted and Nullable Types</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SQLite vector search extension that runs anywhere]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>sqlite-vec is a new SQLite extension for vector search, compatible with multiple platforms including Linux, MacOS, Windows, browsers with WebAssembly (WASM), and Raspberry Pis.</li>
<li>It supports storing and querying float, int8, and binary vectors in virtual tables, written in pure C with no dependencies, and is backed by notable sponsors like Mozilla Builders and Fly.io.</li>
<li>Installation is versatile, supporting various package managers such as pip for Python, npm for Node.js, gem for Ruby, go get for Go, cargo for Rust, and plugins for Datasette and sqlite-utils.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/asg017/sqlite-vec</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZSQLite vector search extension that runs anywhere</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oscar, an open-source contributor agent architecture]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Oscar is an open-source project designed to automate software maintenance tasks using large language models (LLMs) for semantic analysis and natural language processing.</li>
<li>Unlike other LLM applications, Oscar focuses on non-coding tasks such as processing issues and matching questions to documentation, aiming to reduce the workload on maintainers.</li>
<li>The first prototype, @gabyhelp, has been successfully tested in the Go issue tracker, and future plans include expanding capabilities and integrating with other tools and platforms.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://go.googlesource.com/oscar/+/refs/heads/master/README.md</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZOscar, an open-source contributor agent architecture</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GitOpper: GitOps Without Kubernetes]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Gitopper is a tool designed for non-Kubernetes environments to watch a remote git repository, pull changes, and reload server processes using a HUP signal.</li>
<li>It supports a GitOps workflow without Kubernetes, performing sparse git checkouts and setting up bind mounts for service access, with authentication via SSH keys.</li>
<li>Key features include metrics for rollout tracking, diff detection, out-of-band rollbacks, and canarying, which allows assigning different branches to services.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/miekg/gitopper</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZGitOpper: GitOps Without Kubernetes</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel is laying off over 10k employees]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Intel is laying off over 15,000 employees and halting non-essential work to cut $10 billion in costs by 2025.</li>
<li>The company will reduce R&amp;D and marketing spend, cut capital expenditures by over 20%, and review all active projects, following a $1.6 billion loss in Q2 2024.</li>
<li>Despite stable sales in its PC and server businesses, Intel&#39;s stock has underperformed, prompting CEO Pat Gelsinger to emphasize the need for a leaner, more efficient operation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/1/24210656/intel-is-laying-off-over-10000-employees-and-will-cut-10-billion-in-costs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZIntel is laying off over 10k employees</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ell – A command-line interface for LLMs written in Bash]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A new CLI tool named &quot;ell&quot; has been created for interacting with Large Language Models (LLMs) directly from the terminal, adhering to the Unix philosophy of simplicity and modularity.</li>
<li>&quot;Ell&quot; allows easy integration with other tools through piping, and supports customization via templates and hook-based plugins, making it highly adaptable.</li>
<li>Developed in almost pure Bash with minimal dependencies, it can read past terminal output as context, enabling direct assistance from an LLM; however, it has some limitations like reliance on jq, curl, and Perl, and imperfect Markdown syntax highlighting.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/simonmysun/ell</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZEll – A command-line interface for LLMs written in Bash</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[xdg-override: change default application temporarily on Linux]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>xdg-open is a GNU/Linux tool that opens files and URLs in the user&#39;s preferred applications, ensuring consistent behavior across different environments.</li>
<li>xdg-override allows users to temporarily change the default application for specific tasks without altering system settings, useful for scenarios like using a different browser for certain applications.</li>
<li>Installation can be done via Nix or by placing the script manually, and it offers options to override specific mimetypes, enhancing flexibility in application handling.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/koiuo/xdg-override</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-02T00:00:00.000Zxdg-override: change default application temporarily on Linux</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel Reports Second Quarter 2024 Financial Results]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Intel reported Q2 2024 revenue of $12.8 billion, a 1% decrease year-over-year, with GAAP EPS at $(0.38) and non-GAAP EPS at $0.02.</li>
<li>The company announced a $10 billion cost reduction plan, including a 15% headcount reduction and suspension of dividends starting Q4 2024.</li>
<li>Key milestones include the release of the Intel 18A Process Design Kit and the power-on of new products, with leadership emphasizing actions to improve efficiency and profitability.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.intc.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1704/intel-reports-second-quarter-2024-financial-results</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-02T00:00:00.000ZIntel Reports Second Quarter 2024 Financial Results</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suspicious data pattern in recent Venezuelan election]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://statmodeling.stat.columbia.edu/2024/07/31/suspicious-data-pattern-in-recent-venezuelan-election/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZSuspicious data pattern in recent Venezuelan election</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How I got my laser eye injury]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Phil B. recounts a series of poor decisions leading to a laser eye injury while working at a laser company in 1999.</li>
<li>A Quanta-Ray laser was improperly set up for a sales demo, causing safety violations and damage to a VP&#39;s car.</li>
<li>The incident highlighted severe safety lapses, resulting in the firing of a sales engineer and underscoring the importance of proper laser safety protocols.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.funraniumlabs.com/2024/07/how-i-got-my-laser-eye-injury/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZHow I got my laser eye injury</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Just Disconnect the Internet]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A security vendor, ClownStrike, hypothetically disrupts their Windows install base with a faulty update, sparking discussions on the feasibility of disconnecting systems from the internet for security.</li>
<li>Disconnecting systems from the internet is impractical for modern businesses due to the need for real-time communication, maintenance, updates, and monitoring.</li>
<li>Enhancing security within connected environments through restrictive network policies and designing software with offline capabilities is a more effective approach than complete disconnection.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://computer.rip/2024-07-31-just-disconnect-the-internet.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZJust Disconnect the Internet</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breakthrough a step toward revealing hidden structure of prime numbers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.science.org/content/article/sensational-breakthrough-marks-step-toward-revealing-hidden-structure-prime-numbers</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZBreakthrough a step toward revealing hidden structure of prime numbers</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foobar2000]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>foobar2000, a freeware audio player for Windows, has released bug fixes for versions 1.5 and 1.6, with versions 1.6.18 and 1.5.12 now available for download.</li>
<li>foobar2000 mobile v1.5 has been released, featuring a new editable skin file format, with the Android APK available for download.</li>
<li>foobar2000 v2.1 final and foobar2000 for Mac v2.6 final were released in December 2023.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.foobar2000.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZFoobar2000</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stop Killing Games – European Citizens' Initiative]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A movement is advocating for a new EU law to ensure video games remain functional even after publishers end support, preserving them as an art form.</li>
<li>The proposal includes ensuring no required connections to the publisher post-support and not interfering with business practices during active support.</li>
<li>EU citizens are encouraged to sign the Citizens&#39; Initiative to support this cause.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.stopkillinggames.com/eci</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZStop Killing Games – European Citizens&apos; Initiative</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I recreated Shazam's algorithm with Go]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NotShazam is a song recognition tool similar to Shazam, utilizing Spotify and YouTube APIs.</li>
<li>The project requires Golang, FFmpeg, MongoDB, and NPM for installation and setup.</li>
<li>Users can clone the repository, install dependencies, and run commands to download songs, find matches, and manage fingerprints.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/cgzirim/not-shazam</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZI recreated Shazam&apos;s algorithm with Go</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PyTorch – Torchchat: Chat with LLMs Everywhere]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Torchchat is a versatile codebase enabling seamless execution of large language models (LLMs) across platforms like Python, C/C++, iOS, and Android.</li>
<li>Key features include interactive chat in CLI or browser, desktop/server execution without Python, faster execution with AOT Inductor, and mobile deployment.</li>
<li>Supported models include Llama 3, Llama 2, Stories, and Mistral, with a focus on usability, simplicity, extensibility, and correctness, backed by extensive unit tests and community contributions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/pytorch/torchchat</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZPyTorch – Torchchat: Chat with LLMs Everywhere</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SnowflakeOS: Beginner friendly and GUI focused NixOS variant]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SnowflakeOS is a new, beginner-friendly Linux distribution based on NixOS, designed to simplify the user experience.</li>
<li>The project is currently in its alpha stage, indicating it is not yet stable or suitable for daily use.</li>
<li>Users and developers can connect and contribute through platforms like GitHub, Discord, Matrix, Twitter, and Mastodon.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://snowflakeos.org/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZSnowflakeOS: Beginner friendly and GUI focused NixOS variant</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stable Fast 3D: Rapid 3D Asset Generation from Single Images]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Stable Fast 3D generates high-quality 3D assets from a single image in just 0.5 seconds, making it highly efficient for various industries like gaming, VR, retail, and architecture.</li>
<li>Built on TripoSR, it features significant improvements, including fast textured mesh creation and reduced illumination entanglement, and is available under the Stability AI Community License on Hugging Face.</li>
<li>Accessible via Stability AI API and Stable Assistant chatbot, it allows users to share and play with 3D creations in Augmented Reality, with model code on GitHub and demo on Hugging Face.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://stability.ai/news/introducing-stable-fast-3d</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZStable Fast 3D: Rapid 3D Asset Generation from Single Images</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flux: Open-source text-to-image model with 12B parameters]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Black Forest Labs has announced Flux, a new text-to-image model with 12 billion parameters, available on fal.</li>
<li>Flux offers three variations: FLUX.1 [dev] (open-source, non-commercial), FLUX.1 [schnell] (distilled, faster, Apache 2 Licensed), and FLUX.1 [pro] (closed-source, API access).</li>
<li>Key features include enhanced image quality, advanced human anatomy and photorealism, improved prompt adherence, and exceptional speed, making it suitable for high-demand applications.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.fal.ai/flux-the-largest-open-sourced-text2img-model-now-available-on-fal/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZFlux: Open-source text-to-image model with 12B parameters</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coinbase awarded a $500k bug bounty]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hackerone.com/coinbase/hacktivity</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZCoinbase awarded a $500k bug bounty</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don’t Let Your Domain Name Become a “Sitting Duck”]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Over a million domain names, including those from Fortune 100 companies, are vulnerable to cybercriminal takeover due to authentication weaknesses at major web hosting providers and domain registrars.</li>
<li>Research by Infoblox and Eclypsium highlights that many large hosting and DNS providers still have this vulnerability, allowing cybercriminals to hijack domains and conduct phishing attacks.</li>
<li>Solutions being explored include using random name servers and ensuring new name server hosts do not match previous assignments, but better cooperation among stakeholders is needed to mitigate these risks.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/07/dont-let-your-domain-name-become-a-sitting-duck/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZDon’t Let Your Domain Name Become a “Sitting Duck”</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study: Consumers Actively Turned Off by AI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A study in the Journal of Hospitality Marketing &amp; Management found that mentioning &quot;artificial intelligence&quot; in marketing decreases consumer trust and purchase intentions.</li>
<li>Researchers surveyed 1,000 respondents and noted that AI-labeled products were less popular, especially for high-risk purchases like expensive electronics or medical devices.</li>
<li>The study advises companies to focus on product features and benefits rather than emphasizing AI, highlighting a broader trend of consumer fatigue with AI hype.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/study-consumers-turned-off-products-ai</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZStudy: Consumers Actively Turned Off by AI</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cardie – An open source business card designer and sharing platform]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Cardie allows users to design, share, print, and save business or information cards, with features like analytics and privacy settings.</li>
<li>The project is currently in open alpha, meaning it is subject to rapid changes and potential bugs.</li>
<li>Installation involves cloning the repository, setting up a virtual environment, installing dependencies, and configuring a Django server.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/nfoert/cardie</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-08-01T00:00:00.000ZCardie – An open source business card designer and sharing platform</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
