<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 19:08:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Huly – Open-source project management platform]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Huly Platform is a comprehensive framework designed to accelerate the development of business applications, including CRM, HRM, and ATS systems.</li>
<li>The platform supports self-hosting using Docker and requires Node.js, Docker, and Docker Compose for setup, with Microsoft&#39;s Rush facilitating installation.</li>
<li>It supports development on amd64 and arm64 architectures for Linux and macOS, and includes unit and UI tests, though local installations lack email functionalities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/hcengineering/platform</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZHuly – Open-source project management platform</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CRLF is obsolete and should be abolished]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>CRLF (Carriage Return Line Feed) line endings are considered outdated, originating from mechanical teletypes, and are seen as unnecessary in modern systems where a single NL (New Line, U+000a) is preferred.</li>
<li>Although a proposal to eliminate CRLF was withdrawn, the initiative highlighted and resolved various software issues, emphasizing the need for systems to adapt to using only NL.</li>
<li>The post advocates for the cessation of CRLF usage, encouraging developers to update software that still requires CR before NL and to adopt the term &quot;newline&quot; for U+000a.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fossil-scm.org/home/ext/crlf-harmful.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZCRLF is obsolete and should be abolished</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Busy Status Bar from Flipper Devices]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Busy Status Bar is a productivity tool featuring an LED pixel screen for displaying custom busy messages and includes a Pomodoro timer.- It is open-source and developer-friendly, supporting multiple programming languages like Python, JavaScript, and Go, and integrates with popular apps such as Zoom and Discord.- Designed by Flipper Devices Inc., it offers cloud control via API and MQTT, supports IoT integrations, and is compatible with Windows, macOS, and Linux.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://busy.bar/?hn</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZBusy Status Bar from Flipper Devices</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Python client for the $20 Colmi R02 smart ring]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Colmi R02 Client is an open-source Python tool designed for accessing data from Colmi R02 Smart Rings, which are budget-friendly fitness wearables.</li>
<li>The tool operates offline, enabling users to interact with the smart ring via Bluetooth for features like real-time heart rate monitoring and step logging.</li>
<li>Users can install the client using pipx, a Python package manager, and utilize various commands for data retrieval and device settings through Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) communication.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tahnok.github.io/colmi_r02_client/colmi_r02_client.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZPython client for the $20 Colmi R02 smart ring</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zero-latency SQLite storage in every Durable Object]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Cloudflare&#39;s Durable Object platform now incorporates a full relational system using SQLite, optimizing it for real-time collaborative applications by colocating application logic with data for enhanced performance.</li>
<li>The platform operates each Durable Object on a single thread, with the ability to create more objects to manage increased traffic, exemplified by a flight booking system assigning each flight a dedicated Durable Object with its own SQLite database.</li>
<li>A Storage Relay Service ensures durability by streaming Write-Ahead Logging (WAL) entries to object storage and replicating writes across data centers, with a JavaScript API designed for fast, single-threaded operations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://simonwillison.net/2024/Oct/13/zero-latency-sqlite-storage-in-every-durable-object/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZZero-latency SQLite storage in every Durable Object</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Counterintuitive Properties of High Dimensional Space (2018)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In higher dimensions, objects like cubes and spheres exhibit properties that defy our three-dimensional intuition, such as the inner sphere&#39;s radius extending beyond the cube.</li>
<li>The volume of a unit 𝑑-sphere decreases with increasing dimensions, and most of the sphere&#39;s surface area is concentrated near the equator.</li>
<li>The &quot;kissing number,&quot; or the maximum number of spheres that can touch another without overlapping, is precisely known in only a few dimensions, with solutions in eight and twenty-four dimensions using special lattice structures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://people.eecs.berkeley.edu/~jrs/highd/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZCounterintuitive Properties of High Dimensional Space (2018)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why does FM sound better than AM?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FM radio is superior to AM radio in terms of sound quality because it is less susceptible to noise interference.- FM operates by varying frequency, whereas AM varies amplitude, making FM less affected by noise, which primarily impacts amplitude.- Edwin Howard Armstrong, the inventor of FM, anticipated that FM would reduce noise, a significant advantage over AM systems that struggle to eliminate noise without message loss.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2024/10/13/why-does-fm-sound-better-than-am/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZWhy does FM sound better than AM?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A VSCode Extension to edit HTML visually in real-time]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Web Visual Editor is a tool for real-time visual editing of HTML files, offering features like direct HTML element editing and instant preview of changes.</li>
<li>It integrates seamlessly with Visual Studio Code, allowing synchronized selection of HTML elements and text, along with functionalities like zoom, element movement, alignment, and script management.</li>
<li>The tool is similar to microsoft/vscode-livepreview but emphasizes synchronized code and visual selection, with minimal functionality for easy expansion, and is available under the MIT License.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/urin/vscode-web-visual-editor</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZA VSCode Extension to edit HTML visually in real-time</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Our New Name]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Minetest has rebranded to &quot;Luanti,&quot; a name inspired by the Finnish word for &quot;creation&quot; and the Lua programming language, highlighting its focus on content creation.</li>
<li>Luanti aims to differentiate itself from its origins as a Minecraft clone by offering an approachable API, easy scripting, and support for community-created games and mods.</li>
<li>The rebranding involves changes to repositories and community hubs, while the core engine remains unchanged, positioning Luanti as a growing platform for creativity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.minetest.net/2024/10/13/Introducing-Our-New-Name/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZIntroducing Our New Name</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upgrading Uber's MySQL Fleet]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Uber upgraded its MySQL database from version 5.7 to 8.0, addressing end-of-life concerns and enhancing performance and features.</li>
<li>The upgrade involved over 2,100 clusters and 16,000 nodes, using a side-by-side approach to minimize downtime and risk.</li>
<li>The transition improved performance, reduced database lock time, and enhanced query efficiency, highlighting Uber&#39;s focus on innovation and reliability.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.uber.com/en-JO/blog/upgrading-ubers-mysql-fleet/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZUpgrading Uber&apos;s MySQL Fleet</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embedded Rust in Production?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Michael Lohr from STABL Energy discusses using Rust for embedded systems on the ESP32 platform, highlighting its reliability over C for connecting battery storage systems to the cloud.</li>
<li>The transition to Rust began in 2022 due to reliability issues with C, and despite longer development times, Rust required minimal debugging and has been bug-free in production for over a year.</li>
<li>A challenge remains in finding developers skilled in both Rust and C, but Rust is considered a viable choice for embedded projects, with Lohr favoring it over C.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.lohr.dev/embedded-rust</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZEmbedded Rust in Production?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[X11 tool to share a screen area in any video meeting]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Clipscreen is an app that creates a virtual monitor to mirror a specific part of your screen, useful for sharing in video conferencing tools like Google Meet or Microsoft Teams.</li>
<li>It requires X11 development libraries, the Cairo graphics library, and a C++ compiler to compile, and it operates on Linux with xorg.</li>
<li>The app is licensed under a permissive free software license, allowing for broad usage and modification.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/splitbrain/clipscreen</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZX11 tool to share a screen area in any video meeting</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why pay for a search engine]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Search advertising is increasingly aggressive, making it difficult to differentiate from organic results, with spending projected to grow significantly from $185.35 billion in 2022 to $261 billion by 2028.</li>
<li>Kagi presents an alternative search engine model by charging users a fee, offering faster, more accurate, and privacy-focused search results without ads or invasive tracking.</li>
<li>Unlike ad-supported search engines like Google, which earns approximately $277 per user annually from ads, Kagi&#39;s subscription model aligns its incentives with user privacy and experience, starting at $5 per month.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://help.kagi.com/kagi/why-kagi/why-pay-for-search.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZWhy pay for a search engine</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Faster convergence for diffusion models]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Generative models, particularly diffusion models, are effective for creating complex visual data, but training them is challenging due to the need for high-quality internal representations.- The study introduces REPresentation Alignment (REPA), a regularization technique that aligns diffusion model representations with high-quality external representations, improving training efficiency and generation quality.- REPA enhances performance by reducing the semantic gap in representations, allowing diffusion transformers to focus on high-frequency details, and demonstrates scalability and efficiency, outperforming traditional models in speed and quality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sihyun.me/REPA/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZFaster convergence for diffusion models</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blocking the "Sign in with Google" Prompt (2023)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://superuser.com/questions/1773208/how-can-i-block-the-sign-in-with-google-prompt-on-websites</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-14T00:00:00.000ZBlocking the &quot;Sign in with Google&quot; Prompt (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starship Flight 5: Launch and booster catch [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1845152255944819015</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZStarship Flight 5: Launch and booster catch [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diffusion for World Modeling]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DIAMOND is a reinforcement learning agent utilizing a diffusion world model to enhance visual detail and performance, particularly in image generation.</li>
<li>It achieves a mean human-normalized score of 1.46 on the Atari 100k benchmark, surpassing traditional discrete token-based models like IRIS in visual detail capture.</li>
<li>The model employs EDM (Efficient Diffusion Models) for stable trajectories with fewer denoising steps, improving speed and consistency in simulations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://diamond-wm.github.io/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZDiffusion for World Modeling</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PayPal (USA) will automatically share data about you to participating stores]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>PayPal is updating its agreements and policies, with changes automatically taking effect on specified dates; users must review these updates to continue using the services or close their accounts to decline.</li>
<li>Key updates include a new Privacy Statement allowing information sharing with merchants for personalized shopping, changes to the Seller Protection Program, introduction of ACH payments for merchants, and the discontinuation of the PayPal Fundraisers Program.</li>
<li>Users in California, North Dakota, or Vermont are exempt from automatic information sharing unless they opt-in, and all users can opt-out via account settings.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.paypal.com/us/legalhub/upcoming-policies-full</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZPayPal (USA) will automatically share data about you to participating stores</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Large language models reduce public knowledge sharing on online Q&A platforms]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The introduction of ChatGPT, a large language model, has resulted in a 25% reduction in activity on Stack Overflow, a major platform for programmers.- This decline indicates that LLMs are replacing traditional human-generated content, which could affect the quality of training data for future AI models.- The study underscores the importance of understanding the broader effects of LLM adoption on online knowledge sharing and the sustainability of digital public goods.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://academic.oup.com/pnasnexus/article/3/9/pgae400/7754871</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZLarge language models reduce public knowledge sharing on online Q&amp;A platforms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WordPress.org's latest move involves taking control of a WP Engine plugin]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>WordPress.org has taken control of the WP Engine plugin, creating a fork called &quot;Secure Custom Fields,&quot; to remove commercial upsells and address a security issue.</li>
<li>This action follows a lawsuit by WP Engine against WordPress co-founder Matt Mullenweg and Automattic, marking a rare instance of WordPress forcibly taking a plugin without consent.</li>
<li>Users not associated with WP Engine, Flywheel, or ACF Pro are advised to download the genuine version from the ACF site for updates.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/12/24268637/wordpress-org-matt-mullenweg-acf-fork-secure-custom-fields-wp-engine</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZWordPress.org&apos;s latest move involves taking control of a WP Engine plugin</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ACF has been hijacked]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Automattic took control of the Advanced Custom Fields (ACF) plugin, a significant tool for WordPress developers, which was owned by WP Engine.</li>
<li>The takeover was justified by a minor vulnerability and a restriction on WP Engine employees, leading to concerns about trust and control over WordPress plugins.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to reassess their dependency on WordPress in light of these events.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://anderegg.ca/2024/10/13/acf-has-been-hijacked</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZACF has been hijacked</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FLUX is fast and it's open source]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FLUX has been optimized for faster performance on Replicate, with significant speed improvements at various resolutions, such as 0.29 seconds for 512x512 and 0.72 seconds for 1024x1024.</li>
<li>The enhancements, developed in collaboration with Black Forest Labs, include model optimization and a new synchronous HTTP API, and the code is open-source for community collaboration.</li>
<li>FLUX aims to address the common issue of slow open-source models by sharing these optimizations, allowing users to fine-tune, edit, and deploy custom versions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://replicate.com/blog/flux-is-fast-and-open-source</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZFLUX is fast and it&apos;s open source</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eating less can lead to a longer life: study in mice shows why]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A comprehensive study on nearly 1,000 mice indicates that reduced calorie intake can extend lifespan, but not primarily due to weight loss or metabolic changes.- The research found that factors such as immune health, genetics, and stress resilience are more crucial in determining lifespan extension than metabolic improvements.- This study challenges the traditional belief that metabolic changes directly correlate with longer life, emphasizing the complexity of dietary restriction&#39;s impact on longevity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-03277-6</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZEating less can lead to a longer life: study in mice shows why</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 1/8th Sleep]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The 1/8th Sleep is a DIY project that serves as a cost-effective alternative to the expensive Eight Sleep self-cooling mattress.- The homemade cooling system costs $382 and includes a mattress topper, fish tank cooler, pump, and smart plug, offering customization options like adding ice for extra cooling.- While it lacks the aesthetics, heating capability, and built-in sleep tracking of the Eight Sleep, the author uses an Apple Watch for sleep tracking, making it suitable for those with a DIY mindset.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://near.blog/the-1-8th-sleep/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZThe 1/8th Sleep</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Quiet Art of Attention]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The concept of attention emphasizes controlling the mind by focusing on the present and observing thoughts without judgment, which leads to intentional responses rather than impulsive reactions.</li>
<li>Lasting change is achieved through small, deliberate actions rather than dramatic shifts, promoting clarity, peace, and freedom.</li>
<li>Mindful engagement, akin to tending a garden, enriches experiences and slows the perception of time, encouraging a focus on what truly matters.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://billwear.github.io/art-of-attention.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZThe Quiet Art of Attention</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Omni SenseVoice: High-Speed Speech Recognition with Words Timestamps]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Omni SenseVoice is an advanced speech recognition tool designed for rapid transcription and accurate timestamps, installable via Python&#39;s package manager, pip.</li>
<li>It offers features such as language detection, text normalization, device selection, and model quantization, enhancing its versatility and performance.</li>
<li>Users can achieve up to 50 times faster processing speeds without compromising accuracy, making it a significant tool for efficient audio transcription.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/lifeiteng/OmniSenseVoice</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZOmni SenseVoice: High-Speed Speech Recognition with Words Timestamps</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Greenhouse Gas Plumes Detected with NASA-Designed Instrument]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NASA&#39;s Tanager-1 satellite, launched in August 2024, is part of the Carbon Mapper Coalition, aiming to track global greenhouse gas emissions using advanced imaging technology.</li>
<li>The satellite has successfully detected methane emissions in Pakistan and Texas, and a carbon dioxide plume in South Africa, contributing valuable data for emission reduction efforts.</li>
<li>This initiative is a collaboration between Planet Labs, NASA&#39;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL), and other partners, with funding from philanthropic organizations, providing public data to support global environmental goals.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/first-greenhouse-gas-plumes-detected-with-nasa-designed-instrument/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZFirst Greenhouse Gas Plumes Detected with NASA-Designed Instrument</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If you were rewriting Emacs from scratch, what would you do differently?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41821545</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZIf you were rewriting Emacs from scratch, what would you do differently?</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AOO – C++ library for real-time audio streaming and messaging]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>AOO is a lightweight, flexible peer-to-peer audio streaming and messaging solution designed for real-time and on-demand communication over local and public networks.- The C/C++ library can be embedded in host applications or plugins and is compatible with devices like the ESP32, including integrations with Pure Data and SuperCollider.- Developed since 2020 and utilized in art projects, AOO is now seeking broader public feedback before its final release.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://aoo.iem.sh/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZAOO – C++ library for real-time audio streaming and messaging</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ward Christensen (of BBS and XMODEM fame) has died]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ward Christensen co-founded the first bulletin board system (BBS), CBBS, in 1978 with Randy Suess, marking a significant milestone in the history of online communication.</li>
<li>He is known for developing XMODEM, a protocol for file transfer, and has been recognized with awards like the 1992 Dvorak Awards and the 1993 EFF Pioneer Award for his contributions to PC telecommunications.</li>
<li>Christensen&#39;s career at IBM spanned from 1968 to 2012, and he was featured in &quot;BBS: The Documentary&quot; in 2005, highlighting his impact on the tech industry.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ward_Christensen</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-13T00:00:00.000ZWard Christensen (of BBS and XMODEM fame) has died</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1 bug, $50k in bounties, a Zendesk backdoor]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A 15-year-old programmer discovered a significant security vulnerability in Zendesk, affecting over half of the Fortune 500 companies, by exploiting email spoofing to access support tickets.- Despite reporting the issue, Zendesk initially dismissed it as &quot;out of scope,&quot; but later fixed the vulnerability after the researcher demonstrated its potential to access private Slack workspaces.- The researcher earned over $50,000 in bounties from individual companies, although Zendesk did not award a bounty due to disclosure guideline breaches, highlighting the complexities of bug hunting and responsible disclosure.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gist.github.com/hackermondev/68ec8ed145fcee49d2f5e2b9d2cf2e52</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-12T00:00:00.000Z1 bug, $50k in bounties, a Zendesk backdoor</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Working from home is powering productivity]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Remote work has increased significantly since the pandemic, enhancing economic growth and productivity by saving commuting time and increasing labor supply, particularly for individuals with disabilities or childcare responsibilities.</li>
<li>The shift to remote work has spurred technological innovation, creating a positive feedback loop for growth, while also reducing the need for office space and commuting infrastructure, thus freeing up resources.</li>
<li>Although city centers face challenges, converting office spaces to residential use could make urban living more affordable, and the overall benefits of remote work present an optimistic outlook for economists.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.imf.org/en/Publications/fandd/issues/2024/09/working-from-home-is-powering-productivity-bloom</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZWorking from home is powering productivity</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How I animate 3Blue1Brown [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rbu7Zu5X1zI</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZHow I animate 3Blue1Brown [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD's Turin: 5th Gen EPYC Launched]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>AMD has introduced its 5th Gen EPYC &quot;Turin&quot; server CPUs, including the EPYC 9575F, which showcases significant improvements in memory bandwidth and latency compared to previous models.- The EPYC 9575F supports DDR5-6400MT/s memory speeds and enhanced GMI links, achieving nearly 99% of its theoretical memory bandwidth and consistent latency performance.- With a high core count and frequency, reaching up to 5GHz in single-threaded tests, Turin is a generational update that provides substantial value for hyperscalers and traditional enterprises in a competitive market.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chipsandcheese.com/p/amds-turin-5th-gen-epyc-launched</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZAMD&apos;s Turin: 5th Gen EPYC Launched</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Psilocybin bests SSRI for major depression in first long-term comparison]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A long-term study presented at the ECNP Congress and published in The Lancet eClinicalMedicine found psilocybin to be more effective than the SSRI escitalopram in treating moderate to severe major depressive disorder (MDD).</li>
<li>Psilocybin showed greater improvements in overall well-being, life meaning, and social functioning, despite both treatments reducing depressive symptoms similarly.</li>
<li>The study highlights psilocybin&#39;s potential for a holistic approach to depression treatment, though it notes limitations such as diverse follow-up treatments and potential biases.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/psilocybin-bests-ssri-major-depression-first-long-term-2024a1000h77</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZPsilocybin bests SSRI for major depression in first long-term comparison</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve says Steam users don't own a thing, GOG says its games can't be taken away]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Valve reminds Steam users that purchasing games grants a license to use, not ownership, highlighting a key difference in digital game distribution.- GOG emphasizes its DRM-free (Digital Rights Management) model, providing offline installers to ensure game accessibility even if the storefront closes.- A new California law will mandate clearer communication about digital purchases, underscoring the importance of understanding digital ownership rights.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.gamesradar.com/games/valve-reminds-steam-users-they-dont-actually-own-a-darn-thing-they-buy-gog-pounces-and-says-its-games-cannot-be-taken-away-from-you-thanks-to-offline-installers/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZValve says Steam users don&apos;t own a thing, GOG says its games can&apos;t be taken away</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An exoskeleton let a paralyzed man walk, then its maker refused repairs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Michael Straight, a paraplegic from a horse racing accident, regained mobility using an exoskeleton, walking over half a million steps in 10 years.- Lifeward, the exoskeleton manufacturer, initially refused to repair his device due to its age, but reversed their decision after media coverage, providing a replacement part.- Straight&#39;s journey highlights the importance of exoskeletons for physical health and independence, despite challenges with manufacturer support.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2024/10/08/exoskeleton-paralyzed-repairs-michael-straight/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZAn exoskeleton let a paralyzed man walk, then its maker refused repairs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kagi Snaps]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Snaps is a search tool that allows users to limit search results to a specific website using the &quot;@&quot; symbol and a short code, similar to using &quot;site:&quot; in search engines.</li>
<li>The Bangs feature, using &quot;!&quot;, redirects users to a website&#39;s internal search, providing a different method for targeted searches.</li>
<li>Snaps is open source, and users can contribute by submitting pull requests to add or update short codes, enhancing the tool&#39;s functionality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://help.kagi.com/kagi/features/snaps.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZKagi Snaps</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google is preparing to let you run Linux apps on Android, just like Chrome OS]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google is creating a Linux terminal app for Android, enabling users to run Debian in a virtual machine, initially targeting Chromebooks but potentially extending to mobile devices.- The app is part of the Android Virtualization Framework, with plans to simplify Linux VM configuration and add features like disk resizing and port forwarding.- This development could make Android more appealing to developers by enhancing its capabilities as a desktop-class platform, possibly debuting in the Android 16 update.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.androidauthority.com/android-linux-terminal-app-3489887/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZGoogle is preparing to let you run Linux apps on Android, just like Chrome OS</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swarm, a new agent framework by OpenAI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Swarm is an experimental educational framework designed for exploring ergonomic, lightweight multi-agent orchestration, not intended for production use and lacking official support.- It utilizes Python 3.10+ and is available for installation via GitHub, focusing on agent coordination using the Chat Completions API, with a stateless design between calls.- Swarm is ideal for educational scenarios involving numerous independent capabilities, supporting function calling, context variable updates, and streaming responses, with contributions from several core developers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/openai/swarm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZSwarm, a new agent framework by OpenAI</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PostgreSQL Streaming Replication (WAL); What It Is and How to Configure One]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text discusses PostgreSQL streaming replication, a technique for creating a real-time replica of a primary database on standby servers, enhancing database availability and scalability.- It provides a detailed guide on configuring PostgreSQL files and setting up Docker for replication, including a Docker Compose example for a master-replica environment.- The article highlights the role of configuration files like <code>postgresql.conf</code> and <code>pg_hba.conf</code>, and explains the significance of WAL (Write-Ahead Log) records in the replication process.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://mindhub365.com/sql/postgresql-streaming-replication-wal-what-it-is-and-how-to-configure-one/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZPostgreSQL Streaming Replication (WAL); What It Is and How to Configure One</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Windows 11 24H2 hoards 8.63 GB of junk you can't delete]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Windows 11 24H2 users are facing a problem where 8.63 GB of &quot;Windows Update Cleanup&quot; data remains undeletable, even with cleanup tools.</li>
<li>The issue may be related to the new checkpoint cumulative updates system in Windows 11 24H2, which necessitates a checkpoint for updates.</li>
<li>Although users can manually delete these files, doing so might lead to complications with future updates, and Microsoft has not yet addressed the issue.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2024/10/11/windows_update_cleanup/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZWindows 11 24H2 hoards 8.63 GB of junk you can&apos;t delete</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In SSRI withdrawal, brain zaps go from overlooked symptom to center stage (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Brain zaps are unsettling sensations resembling electrical shocks in the brain, associated with stopping SSRIs (Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitors), a type of antidepressant.- These symptoms are part of Antidepressant Discontinuation Syndrome (ADS) and can lead to anxiety, vertigo, and other issues, making it challenging to stop antidepressant use.- Strategies like gradual tapering, switching to fluoxetine (another antidepressant), and cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) can help alleviate symptoms, but no definitive cure exists, and some individuals may experience symptoms for extended periods.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.psychiatrist.com/news/brain-zaps-go-from-overlooked-symptom-to-center-stage-in-ssri-withdrawal/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZIn SSRI withdrawal, brain zaps go from overlooked symptom to center stage (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My WordPress Slack Ban]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A user was banned from the WordPress community Slack after expressing concerns about a new mandatory checkbox on the wordpress.org sign-in page, which requires users to declare no affiliation.</li>
<li>The checkbox has raised legal concerns, particularly for those with connections to WP Engine, leading to hesitancy among community members to log in without legal clarification.</li>
<li>The ban underscores broader issues within the WordPress community, with hopes for a resolution that fosters healing and continued positive contributions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://linuxjedi.co.uk/my-wordpress-slack-ban/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZMy WordPress Slack Ban</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The phone ban has had a big impact on school work]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Öldutún School&#39;s phone ban, initiated in 2019, has been well-received by both students and parents, enhancing the school&#39;s environment and reducing cyberbullying.- The ban has indirectly increased students&#39; interest in reading, aligning with research suggesting that less screen time boosts reading interest.- The policy was developed with community input, and while phones aren&#39;t confiscated, parents are encouraged to keep them at home if rules are violated, leading to more student engagement in activities like table tennis and chess.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://icelandmonitor.mbl.is/news/news/2024/10/09/the_phone_ban_has_had_a_big_impact_on_school_work/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-12T00:00:00.000ZThe phone ban has had a big impact on school work</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[$2 H100s: How the GPU Rental Bubble Burst]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The GPU market has experienced a significant price drop, with H100 GPUs decreasing from $8/hr to under $2/hr due to oversupply and changing demand dynamics.- Factors contributing to this shift include reserved compute resales, open model fine-tuning, and a reduction in new foundation model companies, making renting GPUs more favorable than purchasing.- The emergence of open-weight models and more affordable alternatives, such as AMD and Intel GPUs, is influencing the market, with a growing emphasis on AI inference and fine-tuning, supported by platforms like Featherless.AI offering cost-effective AI solutions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.latent.space/p/gpu-bubble</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-11T00:00:00.000Z$2 H100s: How the GPU Rental Bubble Burst</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tesla Robotaxi]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tesla.com/we-robot</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZTesla Robotaxi</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Begin disabling installed extensions still using Manifest V2 in Chrome stable]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google is phasing out Manifest V2 for Chrome extensions, with warnings and disabling of these extensions starting on pre-stable channels as of October 9, 2024.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to transition to Manifest V3 alternatives, with enterprises having until June 2025 to complete the transition using the ExtensionManifestV2Availability policy.</li>
<li>The phase-out process began on June 3, 2024, and the Chrome Web Store has not accepted new Manifest V2 extensions since June 2022 for private and January 2022 for public or unlisted extensions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://developer.chrome.com/docs/extensions/develop/migrate/mv2-deprecation-timeline</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZBegin disabling installed extensions still using Manifest V2 in Chrome stable</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Lisp compiler to RISC-V written in Lisp]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>uLisp is a version of the Lisp programming language designed for microcontrollers, supporting platforms like Arduino, Raspberry Pi, and ESP32.- It includes features such as debugging, SD card interface, and I2C/SPI serial interfaces, with examples for applications like LED blinking and data logging.- A significant feature is the Lisp compiler for RISC-V, which compiles Lisp functions into machine code, supporting recursive functions and tail-call optimization for improved performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://www.ulisp.com/show?4Y20</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZA Lisp compiler to RISC-V written in Lisp</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nobel Peace Prize for 2024 awarded to Nihon Hidankyo]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The 2024 Nobel Peace Prize has been awarded to Nihon Hidankyo, a Japanese organization of atomic bomb survivors, known as Hibakusha, for their advocacy for a nuclear-free world.- The Hibakusha have significantly contributed to establishing the &quot;nuclear taboo,&quot; a global norm against the use of nuclear weapons, through their impactful testimonies.- This recognition aligns with Alfred Nobel&#39;s vision of honoring efforts that benefit humanity and continues to inspire new generations towards nuclear disarmament.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nobelprize.org/press-release-peace-2024/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZNobel Peace Prize for 2024 awarded to Nihon Hidankyo</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WordPress Alternatives]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article has been updated to include more Content Management System (CMS) alternatives due to increased interest, particularly in light of the current WordPress situation.- The list features downloadable CMS options like Ghost, Kirby, Indiekit, Craft CMS, ClassicPress, Statamic, Wagtail, and Textpattern, excluding API and git-based CMSs.- Notable mentions include Ghost for its built-in email features, Kirby for its file-based approach, and ClassicPress as a community-led WordPress fork, while some CMSs like Anchor are no longer maintained.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://darn.es/wordpress-alternatives/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZWordPress Alternatives</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Play killed my game and won't tell me why]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tukkun, an indie game developer, has been working on &quot;Anti-Idle: Reborn,&quot; which was approved by Google and Apple, and has been in Closed Beta for a month.- On October 7, 2024, Google terminated Tukkun&#39;s account citing &quot;prior violations&quot; and &quot;High Risk Behavior,&quot; but did not provide a clear explanation, impacting his work and income.- This situation highlights a broader issue where developers experience vague account terminations, prompting calls for more transparency and clarity from platforms like Google.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://antiidlereborn.com/news/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZGoogle Play killed my game and won&apos;t tell me why</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nurdle Patrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nurdlepatrol.org/app/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZNurdle Patrol</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Initial CUDA Performance Lessons]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Malte Skarupke discusses his experience learning CUDA, noting that it is essentially C++ with additional features for parallel computing.</li>
<li>Key lessons for optimizing CUDA performance include memory coalescing, understanding various memory types, and maximizing parallelism by using many threads and separating tasks into different kernels.</li>
<li>Skarupke emphasizes that writing CUDA is akin to solving a puzzle, where the primary focus should be on running tasks in parallel before optimizing for speed.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://probablydance.com/2024/10/07/initial-cuda-performance-lessons/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZInitial CUDA Performance Lessons</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The FBI created a coin to investigate crypto pump-and-dump schemes]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The FBI developed an Ethereum-based cryptocurrency, NexFundAI, to investigate and expose crypto pump-and-dump schemes, leading to significant legal actions.- Charges were filed against 18 individuals and entities for fraud and market manipulation, with the Securities and Exchange Commission targeting three market makers and nine others for inflating crypto asset prices.- The Department of Justice successfully recovered $25 million in fraudulent proceeds, which will be returned to investors, highlighting the operation&#39;s effectiveness in combating crypto fraud.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/10/24267098/fbi-coin-crypto-token-nexgenai-sec-doj-fraud-investigation</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZThe FBI created a coin to investigate crypto pump-and-dump schemes</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NotesHub: cross-platform, Markdown-based note-taking app]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The app is available across multiple platforms, including iOS, Android, Windows, Mac, Apple Vision Pro, and the Web, with the Web version being a free Progressive Web App that works offline.- Notes can be stored in Git repositories, with the best integration with GitHub, and also support self-hosted options like Gitea, file systems, or iCloud Drive.- The app supports rich Markdown syntax with extensions for creating Kanban boards, Excalidraw-based whiteboards, and includes features like Mermaid and ABC music notation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://about.noteshub.app</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZNotesHub: cross-platform, Markdown-based note-taking app</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead man's switch without reliance on your infra]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A new Go project, Deadcheck, has been developed to function as a dead man&#39;s switch without relying on cron jobs, timers, or databases.- Deadcheck integrates with PagerDuty, a popular incident management platform, to keep incidents snoozed until a check-in is missed, at which point it triggers an alert.- This project is notable for its innovative approach to managing alerts and incidents without traditional scheduling or database dependencies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/adamdecaf/deadcheck</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZDead man&apos;s switch without reliance on your infra</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Understanding the Limitations of Mathematical Reasoning in Large Language Models]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;GSM-Symbolic&quot; by Iman Mirzadeh et al. investigates the mathematical reasoning capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) using the GSM8K benchmark.- The authors introduce GSM-Symbolic, a new benchmark with symbolic templates, showing that LLMs struggle with variations in numerical values and additional clauses in questions.- The study suggests that LLMs may replicate reasoning from training data rather than performing genuine logical reasoning, highlighting their limitations in mathematical reasoning.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05229</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZUnderstanding the Limitations of Mathematical Reasoning in Large Language Models</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARIA: An Open Multimodal Native Mixture-of-Experts Model]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Aria is an open multimodal native AI model that integrates diverse real-world information for a comprehensive understanding, surpassing models like Pixtral-12B and Llama3.2-11B in performance.- It is a mixture-of-expert model with 3.9 billion and 3.5 billion activated parameters per visual and text token, respectively, enhancing its language and multimodal capabilities.- The model&#39;s weights and codebase are open-sourced, facilitating easy adoption and adaptation by developers and researchers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05993</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-11T00:00:00.000ZARIA: An Open Multimodal Native Mixture-of-Experts Model</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Internet Archive: Security breach alert]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Internet Archive experienced a security breach, compromising information for 31 million accounts, including email addresses and other data.</li>
<li>The breach was confirmed by Have I Been Pwned? (HIBP), with 54% of the affected accounts already present in its database from previous incidents.</li>
<li>In addition to the breach, the Internet Archive faced a Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack, leading to service disruptions, and is now working on upgrading its security measures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/9/24266419/internet-archive-ddos-attack-pop-up-message</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZInternet Archive: Security breach alert</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helping wikis move away from Fandom]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Weird Gloop is now hosting the official League of Legends Wiki, transitioning it from Fandom to foster better community-driven and developer-friendly wikis.</li>
<li>This move addresses issues with Fandom, such as retaining outdated wiki versions, and benefits from Google&#39;s increased support for independent wikis, which helps regain traffic.</li>
<li>The transition can potentially double contributors and allow for custom technical projects, with Weird Gloop providing guidance for those interested in moving their wikis from Fandom.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://weirdgloop.org/blog/why-were-helping-more-wikis-move-away-from-fandom</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZHelping wikis move away from Fandom</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Gov.uk's Exit this Page component doesn't use the Escape key]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GOV.UK&#39;s &quot;Exit this Page&quot; component avoids using the Escape key due to its potential to stop page loading and its use in other operating system functions.- The Shift key is used instead for JavaScript redirection, as it provides more consistent functionality despite its limitations.- The component redirects users to BBC Weather to ensure a neutral, content-rich page, aiding users in quickly leaving a page in potentially dangerous situations, such as domestic abuse.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://beeps.website/blog/2024-10-09-why-govuk-exit-this-page-doesnt-use-escape/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZWhy Gov.uk&apos;s Exit this Page component doesn&apos;t use the Escape key</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian entrepreneur, industrialist, and philanthropist, Ratan Tata, dead at 86]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ratan_Tata</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZIndian entrepreneur, industrialist, and philanthropist, Ratan Tata, dead at 86</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WASM Is the New CGI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>WebAssembly (Wasm) is revolutionizing web applications by offering high-performance and easily maintainable interactive websites, surpassing the traditional CGI model.</li>
<li>Wasm enables code execution in both browsers and servers, providing a lightweight isolation model for untrusted code and supporting multiple programming languages.</li>
<li>Despite some tradeoffs, such as limited threading and JIT (Just-In-Time) compilation, Wasm&#39;s performance and security advantages make it a promising technology for future web development, potentially transforming web development constraints and enabling new possibilities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://roborooter.com/post/wasm-is-the-new-cgi/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZWASM Is the New CGI</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Don’t Know Jack about Bandwidth]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Internet Service Providers (ISPs) facing customer dissatisfaction due to poor Internet performance can address the issue of high latency, often caused by outdated router software, rather than insufficient bandwidth.- The problem, known as bufferbloat, can be mitigated using modern software solutions like LibreQoS, developed by the creators of fq_codel and CAKE, which enhance data flow and reduce delays.- Implementing such software allows ISPs to optimize their current infrastructure, improving service quality and customer satisfaction without the need for additional bandwidth investment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://cacm.acm.org/practice/you-dont-know-jack-about-bandwidth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZYou Don’t Know Jack about Bandwidth</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Software Engineer Pay Heatmap Across the US]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>An interactive heatmap is available, showcasing software engineer salary ranges across the U.S., categorized by Designated Market Area (DMA) regions.</li>
<li>The heatmap provides insights into salary percentiles, total compensation details, and highlights top-paying companies, with pay ranging from $50,000 to over $300,000.</li>
<li>Users are encouraged to provide feedback on additional features or data they would like to see included in the heatmap.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://levels.fyi/heatmap</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZSoftware Engineer Pay Heatmap Across the US</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tenno – Markdown and JavaScript = a hybrid of Word and Excel]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tenno is a web application designed for creating Markdown documents with computational cells, combining features of Word and Excel for &quot;literate programming.&quot;</li>
<li>The app is in its early stages and is seeking user feedback on potential features, with a Docs and examples page available to demonstrate its capabilities.</li>
<li>Tenno aims to simplify data analysis and visualization, allowing for function definitions, multi-dimensional plotting, and dashboard creation by integrating data from APIs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tenno.app</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZTenno – Markdown and JavaScript = a hybrid of Word and Excel</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My negative views on Rust (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author acknowledges Rust&#39;s strengths, such as macros, type-classes, and pattern matching, but expresses concerns about its complexity and certain features like &quot;unsafe&quot; and &quot;panic&quot; that can lead to confusing compile errors.</li>
<li>Rust&#39;s focus on efficient memory representation and the lack of a built-in asynchronous runtime are highlighted as challenges, with the author skeptical about its use as a general-purpose language.</li>
<li>Despite Rust&#39;s excellent tooling, the author is cautious about investing in it for personal projects, though they might consider it for single-threaded C replacements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chrisdone.com/posts/rust/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZMy negative views on Rust (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DeskPad – A virtual monitor for screen sharing]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DeskPad is a virtual monitor application designed for seamless full-screen screen sharing, creating a mirrored display within its app window for easy sharing.</li>
<li>Installation options include downloading the latest release or using Homebrew, a package manager for macOS, with the command &#39;brew install deskpad&#39;.</li>
<li>DeskPad operates like a physical monitor, allowing users to adjust display resolution in system preferences, and highlights its title bar in blue when the cursor moves to the virtual display.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Stengo/DeskPad</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZDeskPad – A virtual monitor for screen sharing</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mozilla fixes Firefox zero-day actively exploited in attacks]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mozilla has issued an emergency update for Firefox to address a critical use-after-free vulnerability, identified as CVE-2024-9680, which is currently being exploited.- The vulnerability is located in Animation timelines and allows attackers to execute code using freed memory, posing a significant security risk.- Users are strongly advised to update to Firefox 131.0.2, Firefox ESR 115.16.1, or Firefox ESR 128.3.1 to protect against potential attacks.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/mozilla-fixes-firefox-zero-day-actively-exploited-in-attacks/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZMozilla fixes Firefox zero-day actively exploited in attacks</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to make Product give a shit about your architecture proposal]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>When proposing architecture changes, present them as a comprehensive &quot;platinum package&quot; to help product teams understand the complexity and negotiate on scope and time.</li>
<li>Focus on Return on Investment (ROI) and potential risks when suggesting new ideas, ensuring alignment with team goals and priorities.</li>
<li>Use available time to work on improvements that enhance quality and deliver valuable solutions, emphasizing effective negotiation and prioritization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://gieseanw.wordpress.com/2024/10/09/how-to-make-product-give-a-shit-about-your-architecture-proposal/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZHow to make Product give a shit about your architecture proposal</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Geoffrey Hinton says he's proud Ilya Sutskever 'fired Sam Altman']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Geoffrey Hinton, a prominent figure in artificial intelligence, was awarded a Nobel Prize for his contributions to artificial neural networks.</li>
<li>In his acceptance speech, Hinton acknowledged Ilya Sutskever, his former student, for influencing the dismissal of OpenAI&#39;s CEO, Sam Altman, in 2023, which he considered a win for AI safety.</li>
<li>Despite the initial firing, Sam Altman eventually regained more control over OpenAI, indicating ongoing dynamics in the leadership of AI organizations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2024/10/09/after-winning-nobel-for-foundational-ai-work-geoffrey-hinton-says-hes-proud-ilya-sutskever-fired-sam-altman/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZGeoffrey Hinton says he&apos;s proud Ilya Sutskever &apos;fired Sam Altman&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Press Conference: Professor Geoffrey Hinton, Nobel Prize in Physics 2024 [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H7DgMFqrON0</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZPress Conference: Professor Geoffrey Hinton, Nobel Prize in Physics 2024 [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Command Line Tools I Like (2022)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post highlights modern command line tools, many written in Rust, that enhance efficiency and usability for developers, particularly iOS developers.</li>
<li>Featured tools include Neovim for advanced text editing, fzf for fuzzy searching, bat for syntax-highlighted file viewing, and exa for colorful directory listing.</li>
<li>Other notable tools are ripgrep for fast file content searching, fd for filename searching, delta for improved git diff visualization, tldr for concise command help, zoxide for smarter directory navigation, and HTTPie for user-friendly HTTP requests.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rwblickhan.org/newsletters/command-line-tools-i-like-2022/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-10T00:00:00.000ZCommand Line Tools I Like (2022)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chemistry Nobel: Computational protein design and protein structure prediction]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The 2024 Nobel Prize in Chemistry was awarded to David Baker for his work in computational protein design and to Demis Hassabis and John M. Jumper for their development of AlphaFold2, an AI model for protein structure prediction.- These advancements have significant scientific implications, such as aiding in the understanding of antibiotic resistance and developing enzymes to break down plastic.- The prize is divided, with Baker receiving half, while Hassabis and Jumper share the remaining half.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nobelprize.org/prizes/chemistry/2024/press-release/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZChemistry Nobel: Computational protein design and protein structure prediction</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cognizant found guilty of discriminating against non-Indian employees]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A jury determined that Cognizant discriminated against non-Indian employees, favoring Indian workers on H-1B visas, leading to claims of unfair treatment and termination.</li>
<li>Cognizant intends to appeal the verdict, asserting its commitment to diversity and non-discrimination, despite the jury&#39;s recommendation for punitive damages.</li>
<li>The case underscores concerns with the H-1B visa process, including allegations of securing visas for non-existent jobs, potentially disadvantaging U.S. workers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.siliconvalley.com/2024/10/07/h-1b-visa-company-supplying-thousands-of-tech-workers-to-silicon-valley-discriminated-against-non-indians-jury-finds/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZCognizant found guilty of discriminating against non-Indian employees</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On the Nature of Time]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post explores the computational view of time, suggesting that time is the universe&#39;s ongoing computation, and due to computational irreducibility, we cannot predict the future or &quot;jump ahead&quot; in time.</li>
<li>It discusses how our perception of time as linear is due to our computational limits, while fundamentally, time may be multithreaded, and our experience is shaped by our bounded exploration of the ruliad, a concept representing the entangled limit of all computations.</li>
<li>The conclusion challenges traditional concepts like time travel, aligning the computational view of time with the Second Law of thermodynamics, which states that entropy, or disorder, tends to increase over time.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://writings.stephenwolfram.com/2024/10/on-the-nature-of-time/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZOn the Nature of Time</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A modest critique of Htmx]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A critique of Htmx identifies several issues, including problematic property inheritance, which is implicit and inconsistent, leading to confusion and necessitating explicit declarations.- Htmx faces challenges with DOM element replacement, state storage, and queuing mode, which can result in loss of browser-local state, flawed state storage, and unintuitive request handling.- Despite integration issues with React, Htmx offers benefits when used with server-side languages, potentially eliminating the need for TypeScript, serialization, and GraphQL, with a suggestion to re-implement Htmx in React to address these concerns.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chrisdone.com/posts/htmx-critique/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZA modest critique of Htmx</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Addition Is All You Need for Energy-Efficient Language Models]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;Addition is All You Need for Energy-efficient Language Models&quot; presents the L-Mul algorithm, which uses integer addition to approximate floating point multiplication, reducing computation and energy costs.- L-Mul achieves higher precision than 8-bit floating point multiplication and can reduce energy costs by up to 95% for element-wise tensor multiplications and 80% for dot products.- Testing on various tasks showed that L-Mul maintains precision comparable to traditional methods, making it a viable replacement in transformer models.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.00907</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZAddition Is All You Need for Energy-Efficient Language Models</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Practices of Reliable Software Design]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Practices of Reliable Software Design&quot; by kqr presents eight essential practices for developing reliable software, focusing on creating a fast, in-memory cache.- Key practices include using off-the-shelf solutions like Redis, prioritizing cost and reliability over features, and deploying minimal features quickly to learn what is necessary.- Additional practices involve using simple data structures, reserving resources early, setting maximums to prevent performance issues, making testing easy, and embedding performance counters to track system behavior.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://entropicthoughts.com/practices-of-reliable-software-design</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZPractices of Reliable Software Design</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't let dicts spoil your code]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Dictionaries (dicts) in Python are mutable and opaque, which can complicate code maintenance and extension.- It is recommended to convert dicts into structured data models using tools like dataclasses or Pydantic for better code management.- For legacy code, TypedDicts can be used to add structure, and Mapping annotations are suggested for key-value stores to prevent technical debt.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://roman.pt/posts/dont-let-dicts-spoil-your-code/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZDon&apos;t let dicts spoil your code</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US weighs Google break-up in landmark antitrust case]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ft.com/content/f6e84608-e0e5-48c5-a0eb-dde7675fb608</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZUS weighs Google break-up in landmark antitrust case</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I made an SSH tunnel manager to learn Go]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Boring Tunnel Manager is a lightweight command line tool for managing SSH (Secure Shell) tunnels, supporting both local and remote connections.</li>
<li>Users configure tunnels using a TOML (Tom&#39;s Obvious, Minimal Language) file, with options for specifying details like host, user, and port.</li>
<li>The tool is compatible with macOS and Linux, and offers features like automatic reconnection and integration with ssh-agent for secure authentication.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/alebeck/boring</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZI made an SSH tunnel manager to learn Go</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Germans decry influence of English as 'idiot's apostrophe' gets approval]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Germany has relaxed its rules on using apostrophes for possession, allowing forms like &quot;Rosi&#39;s Bar,&quot; which was not traditionally correct in German.- The Council for German Orthography now permits the use of the apostrophe to separate the genitive &#39;s&#39; in proper names, sparking debate over English&#39;s influence on the German language.- This change has led to discussions on international influences on German, with some advocating for German alternatives to English terms.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/oct/07/germany-influence-of-english-idiots-apostrophe</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZGermans decry influence of English as &apos;idiot&apos;s apostrophe&apos; gets approval</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Is LibreDrive (2019)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>LibreDrive is a mode for optical disc drives that allows direct data access without firmware restrictions, enabling the reading of UHD discs and bypassing AACS host revocation.</li>
<li>It uses a firmware extension stored in volatile memory, ensuring no trace is left after power-off, and is supported by the open-source LibDriveIO library.</li>
<li>This approach allows for universal tools that are not dependent on specific drive models or firmware versions, enhancing compatibility with software like MakeMKV.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://forum.makemkv.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=18856</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZWhat Is LibreDrive (2019)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PEP 760: No more bare excepts]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>PEP 760, proposed by Pablo Galindo Salgado and Brett Cannon, suggests disallowing bare <code>except:</code> clauses in Python to enhance error handling precision.- The proposal aims to prevent broad exception handling that can obscure significant errors by mandating explicit exception types.- The PEP encourages developers to adopt more precise error handling practices, with further details available on deprecation, tooling, and rejected ideas.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://discuss.python.org/t/pep-760-no-more-bare-excepts/67182</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZPEP 760: No more bare excepts</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lunar Lake's iGPU: Debut of Intel's Xe2 Architecture]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Intel&#39;s Lunar Lake introduces the Xe2 graphics architecture, significantly enhancing efficiency and performance for integrated GPUs in thin and light laptops.- The Xe2 architecture features eight Xe Cores divided into two Render Slices, with improvements in caching, Vector Engines, and raytracing capabilities, showing notable performance gains over its predecessor, Meteor Lake.- Intel&#39;s strategy emphasizes efficiency and power optimization, using more cache to reduce DRAM access, and previews the upcoming Battlemage discrete GPUs, indicating a strong focus on advancing GPU performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chipsandcheese.com/p/lunar-lakes-igpu-debut-of-intels</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZLunar Lake&apos;s iGPU: Debut of Intel&apos;s Xe2 Architecture</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An n-ball Between n-balls]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article presents a geometric thought experiment illustrating the surprising properties of high-dimensional shapes, starting with a 2D square and extending to higher dimensions.- It reveals that in higher dimensions, the central sphere (or n-ball) can extend beyond the surrounding shape, challenging intuitive expectations about space and volume.- The discussion includes mathematical properties of n-balls, showing that as dimensions increase, the space around them grows faster than the n-balls themselves, supported by interactive visualizations and further analysis.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arnaldur.be/writing/about/an-n-ball-between-n-balls</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-09T00:00:00.000ZAn n-ball Between n-balls</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nobel Prize in Physics awarded to John Hopfield and Geoffrey Hinton [pdf]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nobelprize.org/uploads/2024/09/advanced-physicsprize2024.pdf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZNobel Prize in Physics awarded to John Hopfield and Geoffrey Hinton [pdf]</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Differential Transformer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Differential Transformer introduces a novel attention mechanism that enhances focus on relevant context while minimizing noise, using a differential attention approach that subtracts two softmax attention maps to encourage sparse attention patterns.</li>
<li>Experimental results indicate that the Diff Transformer surpasses traditional Transformers in language modeling, particularly excelling in long-context modeling, key information retrieval, and reducing hallucinations, thereby improving accuracy and robustness in in-context learning.</li>
<li>This development positions the Diff Transformer as a promising architecture for advancing large language models, with potential applications in computation and language, as well as machine learning.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05258</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZDifferential Transformer</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[uBlock Origin CNAME uncloaking now supports filtering by IP address]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The update enhances uBlock&#39;s DNS resolution code, improving its ability to filter by CNAME (Canonical Name) and IP address.</li>
<li>A new feature allows the <code>ipaddress=</code> option to block root documents if the IP is extracted before the first request, though it uses the first IP from the DNS list, which may differ from the browser&#39;s choice.</li>
<li>The commit involves changes across multiple files, with 153 lines added and 96 lines removed, indicating a significant code update.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/commit/6acf97bf51</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZuBlock Origin CNAME uncloaking now supports filtering by IP address</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kotlin Money]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Kotlin Money is a new library designed for precise monetary calculations and allocations, addressing common issues like rounding errors in financial operations.</li>
<li>The library supports a wide range of currencies, including 306 traditional currencies and 2283 cryptocurrencies, and is set to expand for Android development and serialization.</li>
<li>It ensures accurate distribution of amounts, preventing financial discrepancies such as losses or overcharges, and supports various mathematical and percentage operations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.eriksen.com.br/en/introducing-kotlin-money</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZKotlin Money</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An illustrated proof of the CAP theorem (2018)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The CAP Theorem in distributed systems posits that a system can only achieve two out of three properties: Consistency, Availability, and Partition Tolerance.- Consistency ensures that any read after a write returns the latest value, Availability guarantees responses from non-failing nodes, and Partition Tolerance allows operation despite network message losses.- The theorem, proven by Gilbert and Lynch, demonstrates that a system cannot maintain all three properties simultaneously, as network partitions can lead to inconsistencies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mwhittaker.github.io/blog/an_illustrated_proof_of_the_cap_theorem/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZAn illustrated proof of the CAP theorem (2018)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video Surveillance with YOLO+llava]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>MACHINA CCTV Viewer is a work-in-progress project utilizing LLAVA YOLO 11 and OpenCV for real-time object tagging from high-resolution RTSP streams.</li>
<li>The system processes frames with a 20ms interference time using a YOLO 11 small model on a GTX 1060, with a mechanism to handle stream delays and idle detection.</li>
<li>The project aims to develop a headless security system leveraging modern vision and object detection models, inviting contributions from the community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/PsyChip/machina</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZVideo Surveillance with YOLO+llava</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is the attack helicopter dead?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The relevance of attack helicopters is being questioned in the context of the Russian invasion of Ukraine, where small drones have effectively targeted armored units.</li>
<li>The conflict has exposed vulnerabilities in both helicopters and heavy armor, with precision artillery and drones posing significant threats.</li>
<li>The future of attack helicopters may hinge on integrating advanced intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance systems, and developing countermeasures against drones and missiles, highlighting the growing importance of intelligence and communications in modern warfare.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hushkit.net/2024/10/07/is-the-attack-helicopter-dead/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZIs the attack helicopter dead?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[John Hopfield and Geoff Hinton Win Physics Nobel Prize [pdf]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nobelprize.org/uploads/2024/10/press-physicsprize2024.pdf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZJohn Hopfield and Geoff Hinton Win Physics Nobel Prize [pdf]</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sam Altman Goes Full Emperor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nonzero.substack.com/p/sam-altman-goes-full-emperor</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZSam Altman Goes Full Emperor</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rust is rolling off the Volvo assembly line]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Volvo has integrated the Rust programming language into its assembly line, specifically for the low-power processor ECU in electric cars, due to its reliability and reduced memory-related bugs compared to C and C++.- Julius Gustavsson, a software architect at Volvo, has played a key role in this integration since 2019, leading to successful outcomes and high-quality products.- Despite initial challenges, Volvo plans to expand Rust&#39;s use, viewing it as a valuable asset for projects requiring strict reliability, although improvements in tooling are still needed.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tweedegolf.nl/en/blog/137/rust-is-rolling-off-the-volvo-assembly-line</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZRust is rolling off the Volvo assembly line</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The costs of the i386 to x86-64 upgrade]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blogsystem5.substack.com/p/x86-64-programming-models</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZThe costs of the i386 to x86-64 upgrade</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How private intelligence companies became the new spymasters]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Private intelligence companies are increasingly competing with state agencies, transforming espionage into a tech-driven arms race by leveraging vast digital data.</li>
<li>Unlike state agencies, these firms operate openly, sharing findings and fostering a community of learning, but face legal and ethical challenges in data collection.</li>
<li>The rise of private intelligence underscores the need for collaboration between governments and the private sector to protect national interests, reshaping the future of espionage.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://engelsbergideas.com/essays/private-intelligence/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZHow private intelligence companies became the new spymasters</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smart TVs are like "a digital Trojan Horse" in people's homes]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Center for Digital Democracy (CDD) has urged the FTC (Federal Trade Commission) and FCC (Federal Communications Commission) to investigate the data collection practices of the connected TV industry, describing smart TVs as &quot;digital Trojan Horses&quot; due to their invasive tracking.</li>
<li>The report raises privacy concerns, emphasizing that streaming services and devices gather sensitive data, which could affect consumer privacy and influence political campaigns.</li>
<li>The CDD calls for stronger regulations to protect consumers, especially minority communities, from discriminatory data practices and suggests antitrust investigations into major industry players.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/streaming-industry-has-unprecedented-surveillance-manipulation-capabilities/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZSmart TVs are like &quot;a digital Trojan Horse&quot; in people&apos;s homes</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FTX creditors will make money on bankruptcy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Delaware bankruptcy judge has approved FTX&#39;s reorganization plan, which allows creditors to receive $1.19 for every dollar claimed, indicating a surplus in collected funds.</li>
<li>FTX has gathered between $14.7 billion and $16.5 billion to distribute, surpassing the $11.2 billion owed, ensuring that 98% of creditors will profit.</li>
<li>The funds were raised through asset sales, including a stake in AI startup Anthropic, and the payout plan&#39;s start date will be announced later.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/07/ftx-bankruptcy-judge-approves-more-than-14-billion-payback-plan.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZFTX creditors will make money on bankruptcy</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is AWS S3 having an outage?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41770111</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-08T00:00:00.000ZIs AWS S3 having an outage?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sq.io: jq for databases and more]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;sq&quot; is a free, open-source tool designed for data wrangling tasks such as inspecting, querying, joining, importing, and exporting data, similar to &quot;jq&quot; but for databases and documents.</li>
<li>It offers versatile installation options, including Homebrew, curl, and scoop, with additional support for package managers like apt, yum, apk, pacman, and yay.</li>
<li>Key features include diffing database tables, importing Excel files to PostgreSQL, viewing database metadata, and executing SQL queries, with support for various data formats like Excel, CSV, JSON, and output options to databases or formats like XML and Markdown.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sq.io</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZSq.io: jq for databases and more</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google’s AI thinks I left a Gatorade bottle on the moon]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google&#39;s AI, NotebookLLM, is capable of generating podcasts from web pages or documents, but it can be easily deceived by manipulated content.</li>
<li>The author demonstrated this by altering their website to present false information to the AI, illustrating the potential vulnerability of AI to &quot;AI Only&quot; content.</li>
<li>The manipulation involved detecting the GoogleOther user agent to serve specific data, but this could impact other Google services, leading the author to remove the fake content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://edwardbenson.com/2024/10/google-ai-thinks-i-left-gatorade-on-the-moon</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZGoogle’s AI thinks I left a Gatorade bottle on the moon</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What's New in Ruby on Rails 8]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ruby on Rails 8 has released its first beta, featuring integration with Kamal 2 for simplified deployments, Propshaft as the new default asset pipeline, and significant ActiveRecord enhancements.</li>
<li>SQLite integration upgrades make it suitable for production environments, and Solid Adapters reduce the need for additional services by utilizing SQLite.</li>
<li>Kamal 2 offers zero-downtime deployments with HTTP/2 support, while Propshaft modernizes the asset pipeline, replacing Sprockets, and built-in authentication is streamlined.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.appsignal.com/2024/10/07/whats-new-in-ruby-on-rails-8.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZWhat&apos;s New in Ruby on Rails 8</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can you get root with only a cigarette lighter?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post discusses using a piezo-electric BBQ lighter for low-cost electromagnetic fault injection (EMFI) to exploit hardware vulnerabilities.</li>
<li>Experiments were conducted on a Samsung S3520 laptop, targeting the DDR bus to induce memory errors, leading to local privilege escalation in CPython and Linux.</li>
<li>The method shows potential for bypassing security measures like TPM (Trusted Platform Module) in gaming PCs, with future research planned for newer technologies and platforms.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.da.vidbuchanan.co.uk/blog/dram-emfi.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZCan you get root with only a cigarette lighter?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rust needs a web framework]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Rust web development currently lacks a comprehensive framework that bundles essential features, making it more complex compared to frameworks like Django.</li>
<li>The ecosystem is fragmented, with many libraries but lacking integration, leading to a need for significant manual setup.</li>
<li>The author is developing &quot;nicole&#39;s web toolkit&quot; (newt) to simplify Rust web projects by combining necessary features with good documentation and community support.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ntietz.com/blog/rust-needs-a-web-framework-for-lazy-developers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZRust needs a web framework</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nearly all of the Google images results for "baby peacock" are AI generated]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/notengoprisa/status/1842550658102079556</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZNearly all of the Google images results for &quot;baby peacock&quot; are AI generated</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How do HTTP servers figure out Content-Length?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In Go&#39;s http package, the Content-Length is automatically set for responses that fit into a single buffer, while larger responses use &quot;chunked transfer encoding&quot; to send data in chunks without knowing the total size.</li>
<li>Chunked transfer encoding is efficient for transferring data of unknown lengths and is supported by HTTP 1.1, with each chunk prefixed by its size in hexadecimal.</li>
<li>HTTP/2 and HTTP/3 use different streaming mechanisms and do not support chunked encoding, but the Go http.ResponseWriter interface simplifies handling headers and content type.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://aarol.dev/posts/go-contentlength/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZHow do HTTP servers figure out Content-Length?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hetzner Object Storage]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The document provides an overview of storage options, including supported actions, frequently asked questions (FAQ), and details on beta testing.</li>
<li>It includes instructions on generating S3 credentials, using S3 API tools, and creating storage Buckets using MinIO or Terraform Provider.</li>
<li>The guide is aimed at helping users get started with managing storage effectively using these tools and services.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://docs.hetzner.com/storage/object-storage/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZHetzner Object Storage</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fast B-Trees]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text compares the performance of different data structures, specifically focusing on Rust&#39;s HashMap and BTreeMap, and Zig&#39;s HashMap and B+Tree, using various benchmarks.</li>
<li>Hashmaps are shown to benefit from speculative execution, providing consistent performance, whereas B-trees face challenges with string keys and higher memory usage.</li>
<li>In WebAssembly (WASM), hash functions are slower due to limited vector instructions, making hashmaps generally more favorable despite their vulnerabilities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scattered-thoughts.net/writing/smolderingly-fast-btrees/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZFast B-Trees</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silicon Valley, the new lobbying monster]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Silicon Valley has emerged as a significant political force, utilizing super PACs like Fairshake to sway elections and pressure politicians into supporting tech-friendly policies.</li>
<li>The tech industry, especially the cryptocurrency sector, is investing millions in political campaigns to safeguard its interests, exemplified by the targeting of California politician Katie Porter for her anti-crypto stance.</li>
<li>Led by figures such as Chris Lehane, the tech industry&#39;s political engagement has positioned it as one of the largest corporate donors in American politics, using financial power to influence legislation and protect its interests.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2024/10/14/silicon-valley-the-new-lobbying-monster</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZSilicon Valley, the new lobbying monster</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Python 3.13.0 Is Released]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Python 3.13 introduces a better interactive interpreter, enhanced error messages, and experimental support for free-threaded CPython and a just-in-time (JIT) compiler.</li>
<li>Key updates include defined mutation semantics for <code>locals()</code>, support for mobile platforms, and significant updates to the standard library.</li>
<li>The release also features optimizations, changes to the C API, removal of deprecated modules and APIs, and new deprecations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://docs.python.org/3.13/whatsnew/3.13.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZPython 3.13.0 Is Released</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Visualization of website accessibility tree]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author developed an accessibility tool during the COVID-19 pandemic to address frustrations with existing tools and improve WCAG (Web Content Accessibility Guidelines) compliance.</li>
<li>Despite its initial popularity, the tool has been mostly abandoned, and the author seeks collaboration with a company in the accessibility testing industry to enhance it.</li>
<li>The post highlights the ongoing need for effective accessibility tools and the potential for innovation in this space.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/aria-devtools/dneemiigcbbgbdjlcdjjnianlikimpck</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZVisualization of website accessibility tree</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Photos of an e-waste dumping ground]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Agbogbloshie Scrapyard in Accra, Ghana, was a major site for processing e-waste, handling 15,000 tons annually, and attracting workers like Emmanuel Akatire seeking economic opportunities despite health risks.</li>
<li>A photojournalism project titled &quot;E-Waste in Ghana: Tracing Transboundary Flows&quot; sheds light on the dual nature of e-waste as both a danger and an economic opportunity, highlighting the informal recycling economies and the exposure to harmful chemicals faced by workers.</li>
<li>The project aims to raise awareness about the global e-waste issue, emphasizing the impact on communities and the challenges posed by lax enforcement of international laws against non-functional e-waste trafficking.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.npr.org/sections/goats-and-soda/2024/10/05/g-s1-6411/electronics-public-health-waste-ghana-phones-computers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZPhotos of an e-waste dumping ground</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building a single-page app with Htmx]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>htmx is presented as a simpler alternative to complex single-page applications (SPAs) like those built with React, combining elements of traditional multi-page and single-page apps to create hypermedia-driven applications.</li>
<li>The author built a todo list app using htmx and service workers, which allows for offline functionality and persistent data storage via IndexedDB, though it faces challenges like limited developer tool support and ES module compatibility issues in Firefox.</li>
<li>While htmx facilitates dynamic content loading and interaction, it is not essential for fully client-side apps, where frameworks like React might offer more straightforward data and UI synchronization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jakelazaroff.com/words/building-a-single-page-app-with-htmx/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZBuilding a single-page app with Htmx</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AT&T, Verizon reportedly hacked to target US govt wiretapping platform]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Chinese hacking group named Salt Typhoon reportedly breached AT&amp;T, Verizon, and Lumen Technologies, targeting a U.S. government wiretapping platform for intelligence collection.- The breach potentially allowed access to systems used for court-authorized wiretapping, with the intrusion possibly lasting for months.- Salt Typhoon, active since 2019, exploits vulnerabilities in government and telecom sectors, including those in Microsoft Exchange Server, prompting investigations by the U.S. government and private security experts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/atandt-verizon-reportedly-hacked-to-target-us-govt-wiretapping-platform/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-07T00:00:00.000ZAT&amp;T, Verizon reportedly hacked to target US govt wiretapping platform</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arthur Whitney's one liner sudoku solver (2011)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text explains solving Sudoku puzzles using APL and other programming languages, focusing on algorithms and code snippets contributed by various authors.</li>
<li>It details the structure of a standard Sudoku puzzle and addresses the challenge of filling in missing numbers without repeats in rows, columns, and boxes.</li>
<li>The text also covers handling non-standard Sudoku shapes and provides examples, solutions, and links to additional resources and demonstrations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dfns.dyalog.com/n_sudoku.htm</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZArthur Whitney&apos;s one liner sudoku solver (2011)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HPy – A better C API for Python]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>HPy is a new C API designed to extend Python, offering zero overhead on CPython and improved performance on alternatives like PyPy.</li>
<li>It supports universal binaries, provides a migration path for legacy C-API, includes a debug mode, and offers a modern, consistent API.</li>
<li>HPy is actively developed, with version 0.9.0 recently released, and aims to support major packages like NumPy and Matplotlib.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hpyproject.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZHPy – A better C API for Python</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[So thieves broke into your storage unit again]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The repeated break-ins at storage units emphasize the vulnerability of storing valuable vintage computing items, particularly in climate-controlled units.- Insurance provided by storage facilities may be inadequate, with cumbersome claims processes requiring detailed documentation that may not be readily available.- Lessons learned include selecting secure storage facilities, using disc locks, and avoiding storing irreplaceable items, as well as the importance of improved security measures by the facility.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://oldvcr.blogspot.com/2024/10/so-thieves-broke-into-your-storage-unit.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZSo thieves broke into your storage unit again</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We need a real GNU/Linux (not Android) smartphone ecosystem]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://old.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1fx5fq0/we_need_a_real_gnulinux_not_android_smartphone/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZWe need a real GNU/Linux (not Android) smartphone ecosystem</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Book of Kells, now digitized and available online]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Book of Kells, a famous medieval illuminated manuscript, has been digitized and is accessible online via Trinity College Library.- Created around 806 on the Scottish island of Iona, the manuscript is renowned for its intricate artwork and contains the four gospels.- The digitized version provides high-resolution images, enabling worldwide access, and Trinity College offers a free online course on its history and significance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.openculture.com/2024/09/the-medieval-masterpiece-the-book-of-kells-is-now-digitized-and-available-online.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZThe Book of Kells, now digitized and available online</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is the history of the use of "foo" and "bar" in source code examples? (2012)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Foo&quot; and &quot;bar&quot; are commonly used placeholders in programming, originating from the military acronym FUBAR, and have been part of programming culture since early computing days at MIT and DEC.</li>
<li>These terms are used to represent unknown values in code examples, helping programmers focus on concepts rather than specific content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://softwareengineering.stackexchange.com/questions/69788/what-is-the-history-of-the-use-of-foo-and-bar-in-source-code-examples</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZWhat is the history of the use of &quot;foo&quot; and &quot;bar&quot; in source code examples? (2012)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ByteDance is abusing the free video downloading service Cobalt for mass scraping]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A significant increase in traffic to the Cobalt API was observed, resembling a Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack.</li>
<li>The source of the traffic was identified as Bytedance, but the specific videos or original request sources remain unidentified due to bypassed limiters.</li>
<li>Despite the inability to pinpoint exact sources, a discernible pattern in the traffic was noted.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/uwukko/status/1842538843720868016</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZByteDance is abusing the free video downloading service Cobalt for mass scraping</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WiFi4EU initiative provides free Wi-Fi in public spaces across Europe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The WiFi4EU app provides access to free Wi-Fi in public spaces across Europe, connecting users to over 93,000 hotspots.</li>
<li>The app features a user-friendly map for easy hotspot location and offers high-speed internet without data charges or tracking.</li>
<li>Available for download on the App Store and Google Play, with more information accessible via the WiFi4EU portal or the European Commission&#39;s website.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://hadea.ec.europa.eu/programmes/connecting-europe-facility/wifi4eu/download-wifi4eu-app_en</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZWiFi4EU initiative provides free Wi-Fi in public spaces across Europe</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wi-Fi Goes Long Range on New WiLo Standard]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The new WiLo (Wi-Fi Long Range) standard is designed to extend the range of Wi-Fi connectivity, making it suitable for broader applications.</li>
<li>This advancement is particularly beneficial for agricultural sensor networks and smart cities, where long-range connectivity is crucial for efficient data transmission.</li>
<li>The introduction of WiLo represents a significant step forward in wireless technology, potentially transforming how remote and urban areas manage connectivity and data collection.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/wi-fi-lora-hybrid</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZWi-Fi Goes Long Range on New WiLo Standard</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gokapi: Lightweight selfhosted Firefox Send alternative with AWS S3 support]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Gokapi is a lightweight file-sharing server designed for Bare Metal and Docker environments, allowing only administrators to upload files, with expiration based on downloads or time.</li>
<li>It offers features like deduplication, an API, support for AWS S3 and Backblaze B2, and customizable HTML/CSS, along with encryption options, including end-to-end encryption.</li>
<li>The server is easy to install, comes with comprehensive documentation, and is licensed under AGPL3, encouraging contributions and donations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Forceu/Gokapi</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZGokapi: Lightweight selfhosted Firefox Send alternative with AWS S3 support</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The importance of local development]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Local development is essential for efficient software creation, offering faster iteration, improved debugging, and consistency between local and production environments.</li>
<li>A good developer experience (DX) enhances productivity, reduces cognitive load, and increases developer satisfaction, which can lead to higher code quality and talent retention.</li>
<li>Tools such as Draft, Skaffold, Tilt, or Garden facilitate the creation of effective local development environments, crucial for avoiding DX-debt, especially in larger teams.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://fastpaced.com/articles/local-development/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZThe importance of local development</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Router Security]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Router Security Website by Michael Horowitz offers a detailed guide on improving router security through configuration changes and selecting secure routers.- Key recommendations include changing default passwords, disabling features like WPS (Wi-Fi Protected Setup) and UPnP (Universal Plug and Play), and keeping firmware updated.- The site is ad-free, prioritizes user privacy, and provides resources and tests for ensuring router safety, emphasizing the importance of ongoing maintenance and detecting hacked routers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://routersecurity.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZRouter Security</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Students who use AI as a crutch don't learn anything]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ethan Mollick, a professor at the University of Pennsylvania, has released a book titled &quot;Co-Intelligence: Living and Working with AI,&quot; focusing on the effective integration of AI into daily life.</li>
<li>Mollick emphasizes the strategic use of AI as a co-intelligence tool, enhancing human capabilities rather than serving as a crutch that could impede learning.</li>
<li>The book discusses AI&#39;s potential in education, advocating for active learning and personalized tutoring, while addressing misconceptions and encouraging a balanced understanding of AI&#39;s possibilities and limitations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://english.elpais.com/technology/2024-10-03/ethan-mollick-analyst-students-who-use-ai-as-a-crutch-dont-learn-anything.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZStudents who use AI as a crutch don&apos;t learn anything</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We're excited about our new roundabout]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>WSDOT has introduced a new compact roundabout on SR 203, featuring a unique design with a long, skinny island and a circular island separated by a pass-through lane.</li>
<li>The roundabout is designed to slow traffic, improve flow, and reduce crash risks while accommodating large vehicles and fitting the existing space.</li>
<li>Despite its unique design, the roundabout has already enhanced safety by reducing high-speed approaches and crash risks, and WSDOT encourages drivers to adapt to it for improved safety and traffic flow.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://wsdotblog.blogspot.com/2024/10/in-case-you-cant-tell-were-really.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZWe&apos;re excited about our new roundabout</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When Earth Had Rings]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nautil.us/when-earth-had-rings-920177/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-06T00:00:00.000ZWhen Earth Had Rings</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's Time to Stop Taking Sam Altman at His Word]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenAI has raised $6.6 billion, reaching a valuation of $157 billion, despite incurring significant annual expenses of $7 billion.</li>
<li>CEO Sam Altman envisions AI as a transformative force capable of solving global issues and achieving superintelligence, though this optimism is reminiscent of previous Silicon Valley hype cycles.</li>
<li>Critics suggest that the focus should be on the tangible impact of AI technologies, like ChatGPT and DALL-E, rather than their speculative future potential.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2024/10/sam-altman-mythmaking/680152/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZIt&apos;s Time to Stop Taking Sam Altman at His Word</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Linux from Scratch]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Linux From Scratch (LFS) offers detailed guidance for creating a personalized Linux system from source code, catering to users interested in understanding the inner workings of Linux.</li>
<li>The organization encompasses several resources: LFS (main guide), BLFS (Beyond LFS for additional features), ALFS (automation tools), Hints (enhancements), Patches (repository), and a Museum for historical versions.</li>
<li>This initiative, established by Gerard Beekmans, is supported by a community and provides a comprehensive learning experience for those new to Linux system building.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.linuxfromscratch.org/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZLinux from Scratch</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't squander public trust on bullshit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://livboeree.substack.com/p/dont-squander-public-trust-on-bullshit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZDon&apos;t squander public trust on bullshit</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How were 70s versions of games like Pong built without a programmable computer?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Retrocomputing is a community focused on vintage computing topics, including discussions on how early games like Pong were implemented without programmable computers.</li>
<li>A recent discussion highlighted that 1970s games used electronic logic and hardware, such as timers and logic gates, to manage game elements, bypassing traditional computing methods.</li>
<li>Resources like Steven Hugg&#39;s &quot;Designing Video Game Hardware in Verilog&quot; and online emulations provide further insights into the hardware-based game design of that era.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://retrocomputing.stackexchange.com/questions/30698/how-were-the-70s-versions-of-pong-and-similar-games-implemented-without-a-progra</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZHow were 70s versions of games like Pong built without a programmable computer?</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LLMs, Theory of Mind, and Cheryl's Birthday]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The repository &quot;norvig/pytudes&quot; is a public project with significant community interest, evidenced by its 2.4k forks and 22.7k stars on GitHub.</li>
<li>It includes a notable file, &quot;CherylMind.ipynb,&quot; which is a Jupyter Notebook containing 700 lines of code, indicating a substantial amount of content for analysis or study.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/norvig/pytudes/blob/main/ipynb/CherylMind.ipynb</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZLLMs, Theory of Mind, and Cheryl&apos;s Birthday</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cloudflare beats patent troll so badly it basically gives up]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Cloudflare successfully defended itself against Sable Networks, a company often labeled as a &quot;patent troll,&quot; which sued Cloudflare in 2021 over outdated patents.</li>
<li>Unlike other companies that settled, Cloudflare contested the lawsuit and won, invalidating Sable&#39;s patent by demonstrating prior art.</li>
<li>As a result, Sable agreed to pay Cloudflare $225,000, provide a royalty-free license, and abandon its patents, showcasing Cloudflare&#39;s dedication to challenging baseless patent claims.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2024/10/03/patent_shakedown_fails_as_troll/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZCloudflare beats patent troll so badly it basically gives up</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The profit-obsessed monster destroying American emergency rooms]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Private equity firms have acquired numerous American emergency rooms, focusing on profit maximization at the expense of patient care quality.- This acquisition has led to reduced doctor hours, increased patient costs, and pressured doctors to make quick, potentially harmful decisions.- Although the No Surprises Act was introduced to shield patients from unexpected bills, existing loopholes necessitate patients to be informed about their rights and opt for in-network care.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.vox.com/health-care/374820/emergency-rooms-private-equity-hospitals-profits-no-surprises</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZThe profit-obsessed monster destroying American emergency rooms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max Schrems wins privacy case against Meta over data on sexual orientation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apnews.com/article/facebook-meta-schrems-privacy-80fd4e6c59f48a3b583d6665af3ede86</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZMax Schrems wins privacy case against Meta over data on sexual orientation</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Globus INK: a mechanical navigation computer for Soviet spaceflight]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ken Shirriff&#39;s blog delves into the Globus INK, a mechanical navigation computer used in Soviet Soyuz spacecraft, highlighting its engineering significance.- The Globus, an electromechanical analog device, used gears and cams to predict the spacecraft&#39;s position over Earth, featuring a rotating globe and dials for latitude and longitude.- Despite lacking real-time data and requiring manual configuration, the Globus was an impressive engineering feat, and Shirriff is reverse-engineering it to gain deeper insights into its operation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.righto.com/2023/01/inside-globus-ink-mechanical-navigation.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZThe Globus INK: a mechanical navigation computer for Soviet spaceflight</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We only learnt of our son's online life after he died at 20]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mats Steen, who passed away at 20 due to a muscle-wasting disorder, was believed by his parents to have led a lonely life, but they discovered he had a vibrant social life in the online game World of Warcraft.</li>
<li>Known as &quot;Ibelin&quot; in the game, Mats formed deep friendships and even romantic connections, demonstrating the significant impact of online communities.</li>
<li>His story is featured in the documentary &quot;The Remarkable Life of Ibelin,&quot; highlighting how online relationships can be deeply meaningful and transformative.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.thetimes.com/life-style/parenting/article/we-only-learnt-of-our-sons-secret-online-life-after-he-died-at-20-rj3bqfnqn</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZWe only learnt of our son&apos;s online life after he died at 20</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple releases Depth Pro, an AI model that rewrites the rules of 3D vision]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s AI team has introduced Depth Pro, a model that generates detailed 3D depth maps from single 2D images in just 0.3 seconds, without relying on traditional camera data.</li>
<li>This innovation in monocular depth estimation could significantly impact industries such as augmented reality (AR), autonomous vehicles, e-commerce, and automotive by enhancing spatial awareness and precision.</li>
<li>Depth Pro is open-source and available on GitHub, marking a notable advancement in AI depth perception with potential applications across various fields.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://venturebeat.com/ai/apple-releases-depth-pro-an-ai-model-that-rewrites-the-rules-of-3d-vision/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZApple releases Depth Pro, an AI model that rewrites the rules of 3D vision</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gen AI Makes Legal Action Cheap – and Companies Need to Prepare]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Generative AI is enabling cheaper and more accessible legal actions, akin to internet &quot;phishing&quot; attacks, which can overwhelm businesses similar to distributed denial of service (DDoS) attacks.- Companies are advised to proactively address vulnerabilities, understand emerging threats, and develop risk-mitigation and communication strategies to handle these challenges.- The U.S. Treasury&#39;s proposed cryptocurrency disclosure rule faced resistance, underscoring the importance for businesses to be prepared for regulatory challenges in this evolving landscape.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hbr.org/2024/10/gen-ai-makes-legal-action-cheap-and-companies-need-to-prepare</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZGen AI Makes Legal Action Cheap – and Companies Need to Prepare</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rune: A Local Music Player Reviving Zune's Classic Aesthetic with Modern Tech]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Rune Player combines classic design with modern technology, utilizing Flutter and Rust for a contemporary music management experience.</li>
<li>It offers features like audio analysis and dynamic playlists that adapt to user preferences, though it is still in early development and requires a development environment setup.</li>
<li>Contributions are encouraged, with discussions on proposals welcomed, but feature requests are not accepted; the project is licensed under the Mozilla Public License (MPL).</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Losses/rune</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZRune: A Local Music Player Reviving Zune&apos;s Classic Aesthetic with Modern Tech</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bureaucrat Mode]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://andrewchen.substack.com/p/bureaucrat-mode</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZBureaucrat Mode</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Teenage hacker became a legend attacking companies, then his rivals attacked him]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wsj.com/tech/cybersecurity/arion-kurtaj-hacker-468e6cad</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-10-05T00:00:00.000ZTeenage hacker became a legend attacking companies, then his rivals attacked him</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
